Alright, here we go, guys.
Welcome.
Mark, how's it going, dude?
Hey, I'm doing good. Doing good. How
about yourself, Tim?
I'm good, dude. A little cold. It's still
cold but I got my coffee now.
I'm good.
I had a little coffee incident this
morning and I forgot to close the lid and
so all the water just evaporated instead
of making me coffee.
Oh no.
I had to correct that.
So we got a guest today, Pepper, the
anonymous. What's going on Pepper? How's
it going dude?
Hey, hi Tim. Hi Mark. Thanks for inviting
me on today.
Yeah, I'm really good. Mark, it's
obviously taking a little bit of a dump
this time of recording at the moment, but
Ergo overall has been doing really well.
The ecosystem seems to be flourishing. So
yeah, I'm just keen to sort of kick some
things around with you, discuss Pepper,
discuss meme coins, discuss Ergo, and go
from there, really.
Yeah, for sure. Well, thanks. Thanks for
joining. It's really cool to have another
guest on.
I know Mark's probably tired of talking
to me, listening to me talk.
Oh, stop. No way.
I was thinking about vice versa.
No, but it's still so.
Some cool stuff happened recently, like
the quantum computing benchmark was
surpassed or whatever. Do you all have any
thoughts about the quantum computing and
how that might impact blockchain or not?
Yeah, I always see AI and obviously fast
computing speeds as being something that
humans can work with, I don't necessarily
think that it's going to affect the
security of Bitcoin because just around
the difficulty adjustment with SHA256.
However, in terms of helping people
produce better code or better blockchains,
then yeah, sure. I think this is a great
thing to have in our arsenal.
Yeah. And I'd say for me, I'm not really
too sure. I haven't really looked too much
into it. I think isn't there the notion,
like the biggest thing that would be
worried about right from a quantum
computing perspective is just the quantum
computers being able to essentially
generate your keys. And then it's like
your pass phrase.
Yeah. Right. Yeah. I, you're more
technical than me, Mark, but just like, I
really enjoyed watching Christian kind of
talk about it.
And he was just like, nah, you know, all
we have to do is make the hash function
just a little bit more difficult. And then
it gets exponentially more difficult to
solve. And there's still like several
steps away from even approaching where
Bitcoin is currently.
So it's just not something to worry
about. And then I actually saw another
post today where dude was like, Satoshi
was talking about what you need to do in
2009. And it's the same thing. Like you
just increase the difficulty a little bit
and it's fine.
Okay. Yeah, seems overblown.
Yeah, okay. Interesting. How does the
difficulty correlate, I guess, with the
brute force of the keys? You know, because
isn't that like, I guess the concern?
I don't think it means like not like
mining difficulty, like not like the
number of hashes required to find it, but
actually the length of the hash function
maybe is a little bit longer. And so the
more digits you would add to that, the
more difficult it would be to solve.
Okay, right. Now that makes sense. So
yeah, then it's because it probably gets
very, hopefully, right logarithmic in some
sense where it's just like, or I don't
know if that's the right one.
Exponential, yes.
Yeah, exponential, yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, interesting. I saw a kushti tweet
about it, and he was like, oh, we're not,
like you were saying, it's like, yeah, we
don't really need to worry about this. So
I was like, okay, cool, I'll just go back
into my cave, so to speak, and continue
doing my thing.
Yeah, if any big brain listeners have
some more details, let us know. I'm super
interested to learn and I don't know.
All right, so can I just call you Pepe
because PepERG is a little bit difficult
to say.
Yeah. Can you tell me about yourself?
What's up, man?
Yeah, absolutely. So yeah, thanks again
for inviting me on, especially just to
give you just a brief precis of my
background.
So I've come from a business background
myself. I own a couple of companies, a
development company as well. And I suppose
that's one of the reasons why I'm not
really keen to dox is that in terms of
employees and partners that work with me,
I've seen come back.
I think you don't want your parents to
see.
Yeah, yeah.
It's the online backlash that you get
from, yeah, we had it early days in one of
our competitions around somebody didn't
quite follow the rules. We're always
really prescriptive on the rules of games
and, you know, rage dumping off the
competitions is fine, but any kind of sort
of backlash from anybody else affects
people's daily lives.
Yeah, it's not worth it. So in terms of,
I suppose in terms of myself, I've been in
crypto actively since around about mid
2017.
Initial exposure to Bitcoin was, you
know, six, seven years before that. But
like many people, I didn't immediately
engage. Obviously, I wish I did, but I
didn't at the time. It was, you know,
funny internet money. So I kind of
dismissed it.
It was really in that run of 2017 when
Ethereum really came to life. And I
suppose I started really picking up on
major podcasters like Andreas Antonopoulos
and some of his lectures that I really
kind of understood, wow, this is going to
change the world.
For me, really, it was actually executing
a smart contract. I don't know if you guys
were around at the time, but EOS were
doing an ICO, and you basically had to
knit a couple of ERC20 contracts together.
I can remember executing that, obviously
self-taught. I'm not a technical
background myself. I thought, yeah, this
is going to take off.
I think one of the most important things
in crypto, and I think Sigmanauts,
especially guys like this and people who
have been within our community for months,
will know that you stay engaged in the
market during busts.
When it's dead, that's when you build.
That seems central to our philosophy.
I stayed very much within that bear
market, discovered Cardano, following
Charles quite deeply, seeing obviously the
boom of Cardano, seeing the boom of
decentralized exchanges, Uniswap Pancakes,
Sushi were doing well, and going down the
Cardano native token route and found
Spectrum DEX.
I thought, what is this? And then I
looked into, obviously, I found Ergo, and
I immediately thought, okay, so this is
fair launch. There's that amazing graph
that you see on X sometimes, which has got
the distributions of early tokens to
founders and pre-seed, and you've got Ergo
with this thin slice.
and the rest for mining. And I just
thought, okay, I'll buy into that.
I'll buy into proof of work for reasons
that Joe Armeanio has spoken about in
terms of market entry without KYC. I
personally massively believe in that. I've
got a network in West Africa and I see
these guys that they don't have bank
accounts, they don't have IDs, but they do
have sunshine.
They do potentially have and all bits of
hardware so entering into that ecosystem
cryptocurrency is really for is for micro
tipping it's for giving people access to
financial services so that piece obviously
the proof of work element around grid
management and power balancing I can also
see huge legs in so
Seeing proof of work and then seeing what
Ergo was about the ethos and then some of
the principles that they had around
decentralized fairness and the open source
development piece.
I just thought was really strong and I
was like, this is one I can, I understand
why it's not been marketed, why it's not
been pushed. Because it's about a huge
group of people coming together,
dedicating their time, just like you guys
are today, dedicating their time and
building something.
So, you know, pre-PepERG, I was very much
active on Twitter, evangelizing Ergo. I
went under RedDragon the Sigmanauts,
probably had 300, 400 organic followers.
You can look back in the Twitter history
around that, and then essentially launched
PepERG back in what July 20, 2023. And
yeah, and here we are today.
Okay, man. Yeah, thanks. Thanks for the
rundown. Sounds like you're on the team,
you know, you have a lot of the same
opinions as many of us do.
So yeah, right on. And it's a pleasure to
meet you really.
Yeah, absolutely. I think today it's
going to be interesting to talk about
obviously meme tokens and meme coins and
because I think the interesting thing that
I found about Ergo is that why I don't
actually think that meme tokens have been
hugely pervasive on our chain is because
people seem to be more interested in
actually building real
real life stuff and useful applications,
mostly. So I think we will see a huge
growth of meme coins and meme tokens on
Ergo though. So I think there is going to
be that to come.
So alright, so I'm going to do a couple
of things right now. First is the KYA, you
know, if anybody listening has not
noticed. I don't know, Pepper, this person
we're interviewing, glad to have you on.
But I think it's a healthy thing to just
like be a little bit skeptical of things
in the crypto space.
And I want to start at the bottom, like,
what is a meme token? Like, what does meme
token? Let's start there. Because, you
know, we talk about coins, you know, ERG
is a coin that gets mined.
It's the utility token of Ergo, like the
main thing. And then there's native tokens
where, you know, we have some governance
tokens or project tokens that may or may
not be useful.
But what is a meme token? What does that
mean?
If we talk about the history of meme
tokens and meme coins, and I use the
phrase interchangeably because I think
there is a difference. And so I think most
people would agree that Dogecoin was
probably the first original meme coin.
OK. And what maybe people aren't too
aware of is that Dogecoin fork of Bitcoin
in 2013 less energy intensive consensus
algorithm. It has implemented a lot of the
upgrades that Bitcoin has been through,
specifically Taproot in 2021.
That has now actually sprouted its own
native ecosystems around DRC20 tokens,
runes, you get NFTs now based on that
platform.
You've got, whilst people think of
Dogecoin as a meme, it's actually a pretty
powerful legacy blockchain protocol which
can be used for various different
applications.
It's an incredibly strong referencing
system and everything really that Bitcoin
is in a way obviously, albeit having an
inflationary supply,
Meme tokens, I think are probably, they
came in a bit later. I think really when
we saw the real growth of meme tokens was
probably in Shiba Inu.
That was an ERC-20 token that was
essentially pre-printed, not mined,
pre-printed, put into circulation. We had
some pools of liquidity and then the hype
was just created and then it obviously
grew exponentially.
So I think meme tokens really are more
synonymous with a speculative token,
something that doesn't actually have a
specific use case other than hoping to buy
it and sell it at a higher price.
I think what we're seeing as well is that
we've gone from this kind of animal meta
over the last sort of four or five years
and we seem to be edging into this like
food meta and even like a clothing and I
think there'll be places and people and
politicians exactly and we've seen a
massive overproduction of meme coins so
there's around about I say meme coins meme
tokens around about 10,000 new meme tokens
daily across the entirety of crypto so
They have developed though, I think, in
terms of some of their primary use cases.
I mentioned there about price speculation,
obviously, tippings and payments. People
within Ergo, we use it as a tipping
method.
You've got things like community
engagement. We tend to run a lot of
competitions. I know that Comet does a
similar thing and has been involved in
decentralized app testing.
And also I think that, specifically in
Ergo actually, because we are a relatively
small and tight-knit ecosystem, it has
allowed people to create and sort of
develop their own brands or capitalize on
existing popular culture brands as well.
So there is a lot to unpack there, to be
honest with you, because you could also
talk about Yeah, the dearth of religion.
And this goes on to some of the things
that have been publicized more recently
around, you know, people are thinking, you
know, I need something I want a cult to
attach some sort of belief and interest
in.
And that's where people are looking at
meme tokens as something to serve that
purpose.
Yeah, would you? Would you say, you know,
kind of comparing meme tokens, meme coins,
right? Just playing devil's advocate here.
But, you know, wouldn't you say meme
tokens are sort of like the antithesis of
like cryptocurrency just because it's kind
of like in some sense, right? Right. There
is a fixed supply, but also it's in some
sense, it's easy money if in comparison to
Bitcoin or even Dogecoin, because it's
Like, because you can mine it there's
assets that you have to then emit this
token, whereas meme tokens, there, it's
all emitted. And then from there, it's
based upon the founder and things like
that to distribute it to lock it and then
you got to inherently sort of have to
trust the other person on the other end.
versus, you know, trusting the consensus
algorithm. So it's more of like a social
consensus mechanism compared to sort of a
trustless thing. So it's inherently
permissioned, right? So I don't know, what
are your thoughts kind of on that?
Yeah, I think that traditional ERC 20
meme coins were like that. And I think
that presents some problems and some
opportunities, I think,
From a problem perspective, it's about
distribution. Yeah, when I started Pepper,
it was a joke, right? I wanted to show my
friend how to use it off the back of an
Ergoversary video.
And I thought, why not bring Pepe to
Ergo? Like, I love Pepe. I love Ergo.
Let's create this.
And then suddenly, immediately, you're
hit by, okay, I've got 100% of these
tokens in my wallet. How do we then
distribute it? Okay, I've got to put money
into a liquidity pool. Okay, right, now
people are starting to ask about
tokenomics. And you kind of do it on the
fly. Obviously, a lot of other people are
much more planned about it in terms of how
they go about it.
I think you are seeing though, in terms
of, And maybe they sit somewhere between
meme tokens and meme coins. But when
you're talking about Bitcoin native meme
coins or Dogecoin native ones, they've got
methods of essentially effectively minting
them.
So you would have 100% of the supply that
you're able to mint. You essentially pay a
production cost to send a mint, a
transaction. I'll execute a transaction,
then you get a certain amount of tokens.
That way essentially enables you to better
distribute the token amongst holders,
which is much more organic.
But what I've seen, and I think Ergo can
also relate to this really, is that
without having a central treasury or
having somebody who is pushing and making
decisions specifically, because a lot of
people rely on that, to be honest with
you, and they want that.
That's why leadership is a thing. Then
they can struggle to grow sometimes
because if you've got 100% minted out to
your holders, then how are you going to
get bounties for competitions? How are you
going to afford listing fees? You say,
well, let's all contribute together, but
it rarely happens.
Yeah, I agree with everything both of you
just said. I guess first I'd say, I think
there is a little bit of a divide between
the ethos of meme tokens and I would say
authentic crypto projects where it's like,
you know, we've said this before, Mark,
like the purpose of crypto is not to make
you rich, it's to make people free.
And, you know, the first thing we said
here was like, yeah, you know, we're
hoping to buy this token and then sell it
for more. And so in that regard, it's much
more PVP than it is people working
together to make the pie bigger for
everyone.
And so, that's my first opinion. And it's
not that I'm against gambling. But I like
gambling. I like gambling on things like
UFC fights that I where I have like
knowledge and I can make an informed
decision and when it comes to me gambling
about like whether People are gonna buy
Joe Biden or not I have no idea, you know,
I just have no idea and so that is my
hesitance, but I think as long as people
are actually
acknowledging what they're doing and not
just like, oh, yeah, well, Shiba Inu is
going to go to a dollar. Like, probably
not. They can be responsible and have fun
with the memes.
And that's kind of where it all starts,
especially on Ergo. That's really where it
started. Do you know the very first meme
token on Ergo?
I'm pretty sure, correct me if I'm wrong,
I thought it was Erdoge, but it may be
Erdoge.
No, it's Erdos. And the whole point of
that was that one of the developers asked
a community member to try out the token
minting utility.
And so he tried it out, you know, just
made a token and put no thought into any
of it and Now there's a 500,000 supply
token called Erdos and the founder just
literally gave it all away as like this
educational thing.
Like, like, Hey, here's how you make
transactions. Do test transactions with
this instead of your ERGs, because this is
not valuable. And if you screw it up, like
who cares?
And so I actually love the Erdos. You
know, it's like the whole thing, like just
don't buy it. Don't spend any money on it.
Send it around. Try to collect them, you
know, I got a few and I've had some fun
doing that.
And it's nice to see some other things
come up and there are other schemes, you
know, like there was one called Bass, were
you around for the Bass token?
Yeah, sure. That came out literally just
before I launched Pepper and there was
speculation that I was the Bass guy, but
just in a different form, which I was
like, whoa,
To be honest with you guys, I was not
part of, I was on Twitter. I was, and I
followed the YouTube videos and the weekly
updates, but I was not across Telegram, I
was not across Discord. So I was unaware
completely of these things before
obviously launching Pepper.
Don't worry about it. I just thought it
was fun. It's like, oh yeah, you get a
random amount of tokens for your deposit.
That's a fun thing. And it ended up being
kind of cool, got big. What always
happens, you know.
Yeah.
Well, I think that was a slow rug. If
that's the thing. But I completely agree
with your sentiment about And this is my
experience as well with blockchains is
that people join them.
And this can be even noobs. They learn
about Bitcoin and then they go, no, no,
no. And then they actually then they look
at it further, they engage in it, and then
they suddenly get into an ecosystem and
then they suddenly want to use their
tokens and test out the ecosystem.
It literally happens across every single
layer one ever. And meme coins are
brilliant for, meme tokens are brilliant
for like Comet's done a great job in terms
of that testing.
They've been involved in loads of
different projects, Rosen Bridge,
specifically. They've worked on things
like decentralized lotteries. They've
worked on the token locking, refundable
ICOs. They've been like a test guinea pig
case because you're right, people don't
care so much about losing it.
I think also from an educational point of
view, we've got something coming up this
Thursday, Friday. We call it a snipe
competition, where you have to buy a very
specific amount of PepERG from MewFinance
or any other DEX alternative, and it's got
to be exactly 30,000 PepERG on the nose.
People are actually trying to do that,
and they're noticing things like slippage.
And to play that game, you're thinking,
oh, I missed that. Well, why did I miss
that? Oh, well, actually, maybe you need
to look at the things or slippage, like
reduce your thing down to 1%.
And so these kinds of things, learning
about blockchain, learning about how
markets work, they can be good. But like
you say, it should be about it really
should be about the educational piece
rather than just solely making money.
But yeah, the way that this world works
is that, you know, people want to make
money and they want to emulate the early
gains of Bitcoin and Dogecoin.
Yeah, it's like memes are some emergent
property of blockchain. It's kind of fun.
That's cool. I like it. You know, another
one that was cool.
And also, like, I learned about game
theory and just how our DEXs work was
Heisenberg. Did you see those? Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I've seen them.
So they locked, you know, it was like,
oh, we put in $5,000 worth of or 5,000 ERG
worth of liquidity. But the way it was set
up, like the founder would never lose
those ERG. You know, it's just like he's
just locking 5000 ERG and is going to
collect transaction fees because he has
all the LP and other people can gamble on
on, you know, whether or not this is going
to go up or down.
And he can't rug because it's locked, you
know, up to a point. You know, if everyone
sells their tokens back into the LP, it's
fine. Nobody's really losing a meaningful
amount of money. And the guy is going to
collect whatever the LP fee is going to
be.
I thought it was cool and kind of a fun
discovery for me.
I think that kind of leads on to things
around about what you're talking about,
knowing your assumptions, actually. So
there are, I'd say, first of all, there
are lots of different ways to launch
token.
There are, like we talked about in terms
of Bitcoin minting mechanisms or like kind
of like a faucet mechanism. or there was
this distribution mechanism.
One that I've seen do it really well,
I've been really impressed with and shout
out to Mav. He was really supportive when
I started Pepper back a year and a half
ago, and then he started Boba.
in March 2024. He has meticulously
planned and thought out those tokenomics.
He has got a great use case around the
utilities and competitions he puts
together and it's a small market cap,
yeah.
But in terms of how he's actually making
money from it, it's just not his primary
motive. He just wants a good token that's
well structured.
So that, for me, looking at things like
tokenomics and launch strategy is a key
part of it as well.
Yeah, absolutely. Are there any other
things you guys would recommend to people
who are like, I'm considering buying this
meme token? What kind of categories of
things would they look at?
So we said, tokenomics, distribution.
What else would somebody want to look at
to make sure that they're, I don't know,
giving themselves a fighting chance in
this gamble that they're taking?
Yeah, sure. I suppose I would look at
the, I would look at the history and the
actions of the developer or the leader of
the particular meme token.
I think I've had experience of rug pulls,
sketchy launches, they're often small,
they're inactive. and they usually end up
being a case of getting in a little bit of
liquidity and then they just dump the
whole supply on you.
So when things aren't laid out clearly,
then that would be a big flag for me. If
the Twitter accounts and the X accounts
and there's no website, then again, that's
a little bit of a flag to me.
I think one of the reasons why Pepper was
so successful so quickly was I was already
embedded in the community. I had hundreds
of followers on X.
So when I started to airdrop the token, I
got lots of replies. People were involved.
People reached out to me and had
conversations. And I was always open,
transparent, wanting to cooperate with
those individuals right from the very
start, asking for advice, et cetera.
So when you see that and you hear about
that, then you can probably think, OK,
this one's a little bit more legit. I
think you touched on it, Tim, around
locked liquidity.
So for instance, I've locked 6,000 ERG
into a liquidity pool for four or five
years. There's decent commitment there. in
terms of wanting the project to obviously
succeed and be there for the longer term.
So no locked liquidity, big problem. I
think when people said, oh, you should
throw away the keys to that ERG, I think
in, well, I don't want to do that, man.
This is good ERG. This is money here for
the future.
Why would I do that? The whole point is
really is that it grows to a point, and
we've seen this with so many of the meme
coins, is that it grows to a point where
there's so much new interest and money
coming in that essentially it supports
itself.
It's no longer reliant on one single
individual. So those are probably a couple
of things that I would look for
personally.
Yeah, I would say kind of some of the
similar things would be like, yeah, the
community, right, go in the chat, see how
active there are people are, you know, is
it one person or is like multiple people,
like, for example, right, you know,
hopefully this never happens.
But what happens if you get hit by a bus
tomorrow, you know, is everything still
going to be running on kind of full steam
ahead, so to speak. But I guess from an
investment perspective, I agree kind of
with Tim, this is more of a gamble.
And, and that's just my sort of look on
things. And so I'm not really willing to,
I'll buy some, you know, here and there,
but I'm not really willing to kind of put
a bunch of ERGs, I guess, into some of
these tokens, just because of the whole,
just, you know, there's gonna be human
manipulation involved inherently.
And so you know, like, what if you lost
your keys, for example, or, you know, or
there's some maybe alternative motives
that we don't know. And, you know, after
five years, maybe you rug it, you know
what I mean? I don't know, right? Not to
say you will not trying to, you know, that
inherently is like, is out there.
There's an attack vector, right? So I
mean, whereas if you were to maybe put it
through, like, some sort of emission
protocol.
So like I developed the minor rights
protocol and we're working on that. And so
maybe starting a meme token through that.
So then we can kind of bootstrap the Ergo
blockchain with the distribution of the
token.
And then that way the tokens are in a
proxy contract. They get distributed
through the miners and then it's sort of a
proxy, I guess, in some sense to how Doge
was without actually having to start a
whole new chain. and things like that.
But yeah, I think it's like kind of a
gamble. And so for me, you know, I make
decent money and I don't really gamble in
general. And so yeah, in general is almost
kind of a gamble. And so putting any more
money into that.
So it's all speculation. But of course,
you know, to each their own, you know, no
judgments by any means.
Yeah, I think the re-emission contracts
or the emission contracts type mechanism
with a meme coin, I think that is going to
be a major trend actually going forward.
So I work across a couple of different
ecosystems, the Bitcoin ecosystem I'm
pretty heavily into, and you've got
innovations around, it's called DMT-NAP,
so digital matter theory, where they're
essentially looking at the bits in a
certain block
that will essentially get mined and
there's generally between sort of 2 to 400
bits per block on a decreasing scale and
essentially the miner that explodes that
block
wins those bits, which is essentially,
it's called NAT token, is a corresponding.
So that is a way that miners can further
profit from mining. They can sell this
into the open market.
And that, quote unquote, meme token has a
fairer distribution and emission. So I
think that is going to be a subsector of
meme coins and meme tokens.
I think in terms of the gambling aspect,
then yeah, sure. It's gambling to a
certain extent. I think pretty much
everything in life is gambling. You have
to take a risk. You always have to do
something like that.
That's what I tell my students. Literally
everything is a risk. Everything is a
trade-off, including doing nothing.
Yeah, massive. Opportunity cost is
absolutely massive. I personally, being
close to memes generally across several
different ecosystems and developing a
sense for it, I know what I'm looking for.
I know what I'm looking at. And
therefore, I believe that I have an edge
in terms of actually picking these ones.
And sometimes you'll pick ones and you're
thinking, well, look, my expected return
is like 100 to 1000X.
That's pretty good. That's better than a
roulette table for sure. And I feel like
I've got an edge to sometimes knowing your
assumptions totally can actually just
reduce risk.
So it's just about what you're
comfortable with. I would put to answer a
question of something around, you know,
why should people care about I would say
you shouldn't care about them necessarily.
They serve entirely as an optional part
of cryptocurrency. You're better focused
spending your time on products that
actually add a tangible value.
However, the market is massively
expanding for memes. We're looking at
around about 150 to 170 billion dollar
market capitalization within a 3.8
trillion dollar crypto market.
That's three, four percent. I can see it
hitting a trillion that you're looking
around about maybe 10% market
capitalization. And if you look at Big
Pepe, which I managed to get into pretty
early and really enjoyed sharing some of
those memes and jokes with my friends, and
it was a great laugh.
They can do really, really well. So I
think it's a bit of a... Sometimes it can
be a mistake to ignore them. I wish that I
bought way more Dogecoin back in 2017. God
damn it.
Yeah, no, that's interesting.
Yeah, go ahead, Tom.
To your point, you know, there's all
these things coming out and we enjoy the
memes. And I think everybody probably has
a favorite meme that they send. Yeah, I
know it's fun.
So I'm wondering, like, how do you how do
you judge which meme is going to do better
than the other? Is it like How clever is
the graphic? Is it the name? Is it timing?
Is it all of those things?
How do you pick up on these social cues
that indicate a successful meme token? Or
is that just a little bit on the top, and
the rest of it is the tokenomics? Or is it
all of that? How do you think about it?
I think I look at meme coins in different
camps. Yeah, it's disgusting now, right?
That meme coin that comes out, that's a
flash in the pan.
This feels like an orchestrated team.
That's a cash grab. Like if you didn't see
that coming, then you just haven't been
around in the space long enough.
Something like some other ones that have
done relatively well. Fart coin I saw a
few weeks ago. seem to be doing pretty
well. That for me is obscene.
It's not that funny. It's not that
meme-able. I want good meme-ability. I
want to be able to open my phone and
there'd be a huge collection of variety of
memes adapted by people that I can share
with my friends that are people in
different circumstances.
That's why I think Pepe was so strong.
and I think, I've said this, I think this
will be the major meme token of this cycle
because Pepe's hilarious.
You've got so many different, you've got
literally, open your phone, you put Pepe
farmer, you put Pepe fishing, you put Pepe
shooting, you put Pepe anything, and you
have many, many, many, many, many, many
memes that you can send.
I look at the cultural significance in
terms of, okay, what have these done? And
then I think about those ones, I suppose
I'm more interested in.
And then to be honest with you, I'm
looking at things like liquidity. So which
chain is this on? And if it's a new chain,
or if it's something coming.
So a matter that I'll share with you
guys, and I've spoken about it already,
but I'm really excited about Dogecoin meme
coins, because you've got Dogecoin is the
absolute number one meme coin in the
world.
It's undisputed. You have a whole fleet,
Dogecoin being the number one. I think
it's about a 25 million dollar market cap.
It's sat there as number one. It's about
to get integrated into MyDoge wallet.
which is essentially the largest Dogecoin
wallet. Every noob that you know has
bought Dogecoin back in 2017, 2018, 2019,
whatever.
So that is going to be a case of the easy
access to on-ramps liquidity into the
space. Those are the big winners. I'm not
necessarily, I'm not a meme coin trader.
I'm not on pump.fun.
I'm not interested in flash in the pan.
I'm looking at the big movers that are
gonna have cultural significance and are
gonna bring in liquidity and bring
community.
And I monitor things like X. I'm looking
at the number of hashtags and tweets that
these coins are getting, how long they've
been around for, looking at good
distribution. I'm looking at, okay, have
they even got listings yet? What are the
on-ramps for that?
There's a few things that go in there,
but I'd always say in investing generally
is that you just want to pick the big
winners and sit. That's my strategy with
meme coins tokens.
Yeah, it's interesting. It's like meme
coins have this emergent property where
it's like, You know, like you're saying
these cultural aspects and now there's
this new emerging capability with like
blockchain and now tying value to the
specific meme itself.
And then, you know, and that's just kind
of fascinating. And then I love the idea
with respect to meme tokens and things
like that with the educational things to
where, you know, like you were just
talking about a little bit ago with like
the slippage and kind of understanding
that and,
You know, kind of bringing in as like an
on ramp to people to kind of facilitate
maybe a little bit of hopium right that
it's going to go up, but but also kind of
again, teaching them sort of the
fundamentals of like how to use a
decentralized exchange and then also
specifics of like kind of you were saying
like well.
you know, whether it's a token in
general, whether it's a meme token or just
generally, you know, well, what is the
market cap? What does liquidity look like?
Because it might not be a meme token, it
could just be a regular utility token.
But you know, somebody might rug pull,
you know, and that's happened before. So
it's like, you know, in some aspects,
it's, it's a great, what's the word, like,
you know, just to kind of throw, not into
the fire, but crucible, right?
Just put people into the arena, kind of
let them learn. Hopefully they make some
money out of it and don't, you know, get
too greedy in some aspects where they put
in like a bunch of money and then they
could just get, you know, extremely
rugged.
But I think it's a great way to kind of,
from an educational perspective, to kind
of facilitate and get more users within
you know the main chain Ergo in particular
and then as to why you know Ergo is kind
of cool you know compared to the other
yeah yeah yeah definitely i think more
and more people As they spend longer in
crypto, they look at altcoin token
distributions and they go, wait a minute.
So you've got all of these tokens for
founders, for teams, for all this sort of
stuff. And they become less enthusiastic
about it, I think, because you do have
these inevitable dumps and these
inevitable unlocks.
And there's a huge amount of access and
pre-seed rounds to early investors and all
these kinds of elements. And
realistically, you want something that's a
bit more open and sometimes and some
specific meme tokens and categories of
meme coins.
They are allowing and I think what you
said, Mark around that the emission
contract thesis would be a really great
idea as a great equalizer. I would also
say as well that if and when you do make
any money on meme coins, it's the funnest
money you've ever made in your life.
You know, you go out, you buy yourself a
watch. You're like, this is my frog watch.
This is my this, you know, like it's it's
funny, it's light-hearted, so I wouldn't
say it's a career choice, but it should
just be something on the side.
Totally. And then I would say just, if
you don't mind sharing, you know, from
like a transparency perspective, you know,
the reason why I guess you do want to kind
of hide your identity, you know, is it
kind of the idea that's shrouded behind
like meme tokens and like, you know, you
don't want, you know, your business to be
associated with that per se, or is it
maybe more of like the blockchain type of
nature where people, you know, what, like,
why are you anonymous in that sense?
Like, is it because of like, What do you
think?
Well, to be pretty plain, I run a
professional services company and it's a
pretty serious business to be in with
serious clients and I am that person to
them and I've got guys that work with me
who rely on me to be like that.
This has always been an absolute passion
of mine but because that is my main
breadwinner, I can't overlap. I
potentially might lose credibility or
whatever. And then like I said about
people sort of dumping on, it takes two
minutes to write a negative Google review.
And again, it shouldn't be impacting
people. So that's part of the reason. I
also think that that there is, you know,
I'm Pepper to people on X and on Telegram
and nobody seems to have an issue with
that.
I think, you know, you bind to that
mystique essentially around it as well.
And it's just part of the narrative that
we have.
Yeah, right. Well, if if you end up
getting fired over this, then you could
just you could just put all your money in
Pepper and it'll double for sure.
Yeah, literally. I don't think I'll be
able to get it out, though.
Yeah, right.
Is there anything else you wanted to talk
about the project before we get to our
grand finale for this episode?
Raffle, yeah, sure. Look, I think we've
covered quite a lot of ground. People
who've been following Pepper since the
start know that we
We started off, like I said, I was lying
on the sofa and I made this and people
from the community have reached out,
helped me devise economics, helped me
devise activities, competitions during a
30-day promo period.
More recently, we've got a yield farm, so
around about $30,000 large yield farm on
on Ergo we've got a really nice deep pool
around about fifty thousand dollars of
liquidity i've always said liquidity
liquidity liquidity it's all about
liquidity we want to make it nice and deep
for people to be able to come in and trade
and and not have these slippage problems
So that's been our ethos in terms of what
we're, I suppose what we're looking to do
is, you know, it's ultimately, I've been
an evangelist of Ergo, you'll see some of
the content that we put out on X and
Telegram.
We're always trying to educate people
about Ergo as much as we can do. and
ultimately our strategic positioning piece
as well is to reach out to Pepe, other
Pepe community members in other chains,
bring them into Ergo, which we think is a
very good bulletproof blockchain and get
them excited about these concepts that
we've talked about, about the good things
about Ergo.
So we want to be ultimately here, right
front and center. So when we get a US
exchange listing, when we bring more
liquidity in through Rosen Bridge, then we
are amongst things like Comet and some of
the other main meme tokens to benefit from
it and make sure our earlier Ergo holders
benefit from it as well.
That's been our goal and that's what
we'll continue to do.
All right. Right on, brother. Thank you.
Any info about this raffle? I'm going to
share my screen and if you want to talk
about the raffle, what's it for? What are
you raffling?
Yeah, sure. So we had a competition
around about the end of about a week ago.
Oh, no, not a week, a couple of days ago,
might be a week from filming.
Essentially, what this was, was this was
a snipe competition. To enter you had to
go on to MewFinance or any other DEX,
though I think MewFinance is great, so
shout out to Aco and HQx.
In terms of this raffle to qualify and to
win a lot, so there are eight groups of
lots. There is obviously 10 lots per
group. To qualify, you need to buy between
9,700 and 9,800 PepERG.
It drove some really great volume. People
were missing the pain in the game, as I
call it, because of slippage. But people
were essentially hitting some of those.
When they're hitting that margin, they
were winning that place. In terms of the
prizes, so for the first three lots for
early competitors, we said we're going to
give you a 40x your stake.
So everybody has effectively staked
$9,750 PepERG. and the winner of a raffle
will receive 40x for the first three
groups, and then 20x for the remaining
five groups.
That PepERG has come from our community
fund. We enjoy putting it back in the
community. People have been obviously
staying with PepERG and stuff like that.
It'd be great to get you guys to run the
raffle. Thanks so much for this. We can
talk through some of the winners.
Yeah, no problem. Okay, so I'm just going
to run the number one through 10 for each
of these lots and I'll go through and
highlight the winning number.
Yeah, slot.
Alright, so here we go. First, first.
Oh, just for context, people. So the
winner will receive 195. So for these 40x
slots, it's 390,000 PepERG, which I
believe is around about, I need to check
actually because of the exchange, but it's
a few hundred dollars, you know, this
isn't, it's maybe even a thousand dollars
actually.
Should we just check what that is? Should
we just, let me just check. Because it's
not a small amount. And I think, We run
competitions with really good prizes.
We've got a 400 ERG prize pool for our
next comp, which is in ERG.
It's already there. And I think because
we've managed to boost our marketing and
treasury, just after my treasury
management, we've managed to get some of
these good funds.
So I'm looking forward to distributing
it. Let's just see how much it is. I'll
just work it out. So we've got at current
rates, obviously, everyone might have
changed.
Now you're watching this. inevitably. So
we're looking at for the winners. We're
looking at for the winners of the first
three lots. It's about $760. So just over
400 ERG per winner and then around about
$380 for the remaining ones, which is
pretty cool.
Sick. Yeah, nice. Decent price pools.
Let's go. Let's let it rip.
Yeah.
Five.
Number five.
Four. Four. Nice.
Nine FD. Yeah. Number four.
That'd be cool with some of your guys's
community funds. Maybe think about doing a
hackathon, you know, that's all based on
memes. You know what I mean?
And that's a great idea. Yeah. I would
love to do that. And I'd love to support
your idea about the emission piece because
I think that's brilliant.
That's why we pay you the big bucks,
Mark. Great idea.
So these three winners from the 40X
stake, it's great, they're all different
addresses, which I'm pleased about. So
thanks for committing everybody in those
first three.
Yeah, Tim actually made random.org and
these are all his addresses.
Number one.
Okay, great guys. So we've got HGPZZ.
Okay, winner of last one with a 40x stake.
Okay, so you won again two lots in a row.
Pretty impressive. That's a total that you
know you've managed to he's managed to net
600 equivalent PepERG.
Number one, nine FAD. So look at that
guy. Did he win the first lot?
He won this one here.
Okay. So we got We've got some big
winners there.
OK. And what's the origin of Pepe? Kind
of just like it's an entirety. Like, I'm
not too familiar with like, I mean,
obviously, I know the meme and, you know,
I'll go on like Instagram and things like
that and, you know, see the frog guys and
stuff. But like, where did it originate?
Yeah, sure. So we It originated around
about in the mid-2000s. I think Matt Fury
was a comic developer and author. He
created it and then kind of hit mainstream
attention and then it kind of then became
a little bit controversial, I believe.
It got used by some right groups. It just
gained kind of internet notoriety
specifically through Reddit. It came into
crypto actually. So there are rare Pepe
trading cards. They're like, they go for
about a thousand bucks, a hundred thousand
bucks each on Ethereum.
Cool.
And people were missing it by like one or
they'll go a bit early. And it was great.
Someone netted it and they won 420,000
PepERG. And they haven't dumped it.
I think that just shows to be honest with
you that people realize what is coming and
they're enjoying it and they want to get
positioned well. So, you know, if we can
help people do that, then let's do it.
Yeah. All right. Well, congrats to all
the winners. PepERG, thanks for joining
and dropping some knowledge about your
project and just shooting the breeze with
us generally. So appreciate it, man.
Yeah, absolutely, guys. Yeah, definitely.
And let's keep in touch. Absolutely. And
let's see where all this goes. And I think
the ErgoHack is a great idea. So let's
pick up on that in the future, too.
Yeah, do some digging, come up with some
ideas on how you wanna do that and maybe
you can come on the podcast and announce
it if that's what you guys end up wanting
to do.
Yeah, it could be interesting for sure.
Yeah, thanks for that. Cool.
All right, have a good day everybody.
Thanks for watching.
All right, cheers.