Hello and welcome to the Ergo AMA.
How are you doing, kushti?
Good morning.
Yeah, hello everyone.
Yeah, I'm good.
I'm drinking some tea with a cookie.
So yeah, actually a lot of things to talk
about.
So maybe let's start with you.
And then I will take a lot of time.
So yeah, let's start with smaller.
No problem.
So what do we do?
Let's see, on a personal front, I've
successfully deployed our blockchain to
one of our main systems here at Cornell.
So I think I've talked about it before.
We have a fairly large system that I
built that allows students to submit files
for large format printing.
And we do about
It's been going around for about four or
five years now.
We have about 65,000 rows in the
database.
So that's a lot of like, you know, 60
inch by 42 inch large format plots that go
through the system.
So the idea would be in the past, they
used to have the ability to leave for the
students to pay in cash, but that got
taken away when Cornell went to a new
system.
And so that's when we branched off on our
own and built our own system.
And so right now, they're only allowed to
be billed through the bursar.
They're only available for that.
So the idea was to give them a different
avenue of billing methods, because you
have a lot of professional students that
come in that are like, I don't want to use
a bursar system, as well as create some
sort of LETS system.
That's a double thing.
Some sort of LETS ability for people to
develop some sort of local economy, right?
So last week I built into the BRICK
token.
We had a discussion about it around the
IT table here about what would be the best
name to name this token for an
architecture, city planning and art
department combined and the idea I guess
was BRICK, you know, it's a building block
for everything there so
We called it BRICK and it's a Cornell
BRICK and that's going to be our LETS
token essentially.
So the idea is that I tried to think of a
way that would possibly allow students to
interact with the blockchain with the
least barrier of entry.
And what better way to do that than
Luivatra's tipper bot, right?
Because we're already running a huge
discord where most of our students are
already in it and it's how they
communicate with IT.
It's how they communicate with the desk
when they're using our systems and that
kind of thing.
So what we did, what I did over the last
couple of days and a little bit last week
is I integrated a Nautilus wallet
integration on the front end portal where
you submit your large format prints.
You can click a button that says
blockchain payment.
and it then automatically pings you in
Discord, our Discord server.
And it says, Hey, qx(), it looks like you
sent out plot 5,728.
It's 32 inches by 48 inches.
It's $7.80 in US dollars.
If you need to pay this much and it
lists, it has a code copy block for all
the tipper code for ERGs.
So it'd be like 2.2 or 3.3 ERGs.
And then underneath that, there's another
code block that says, if you want to pay
in BRICK,
It's going to be, we're giving like,
we're rounding down for BRICK payments, so
it's cheaper.
So it'd be seven BRICK.
So you just hit the copy block, you
paste, you enter.
And in the backend system, my system is
watching the wallet.
And when it sees that exact payment, then
it releases your print to our backend
portal, where then it can be printed in
the large format print.
So the idea was to let's get these kids
involved in
They're, you know, try to jump their own
economy.
There's so many like tools that are
passed around between the semester.
There's so many books and other things.
Why not create some sort of system of
value where these kids can have something
that's valuable to them?
I mean, a lot of these guys are spending
two, $300 a semester on plots and that's
quite a bit for a student.
So if there's this kind of incentive to
utilize this token that can help them out
in the future for selling their old tools
or handing off their stuff to freshmen,
then we're hoping to hit that.
And that will eventually trickle into the
DAO as well and work from there.
So that's one thing.
The other thing, if you guys are watching
MewFinance, you'll notice that we
We sold four Mac Pros on MewFinance the
other day.
These are 2000, I think they're 2013
through 2019.
Those trash can Mac Pros, you know,
they're little round circles kind of
thing.
We put them up for 65 ERGs on MewFinance
and one day before that sold pretty quick.
And then three the next day, and those
sold really, really fast, fast enough to
where people had to resubmit their
transactions because they were competing
with other people.
So that was a lot of fun to see that.
That money will go right into the Cornell
DAO Treasury to help fund airdropping
BRICK to student wallets and tipping to
student wallets and that kind of thing as
well.
So that's another cool thing that we're
doing.
We may have some other stuff up in there
as we clear out our IT closet of old
stuff.
We have a stack of like Mac minis that
are i5s and i7s that maybe we'll put up.
There's an iMac back there too, that kind
of thing.
So we'll see how that goes.
But that's a lot of fun to use something
like MewFinance, the physical side of the
store to sell actual goods, just like
eBay.
It's super, super neat.
What else?
In the community, we got our multisig
transaction from the old multisig for the
Sigmanauts to the new multisig for the
Sigmanauts.
That took a while, but it showed up.
That was great.
So we have all our ERGs in the new
multisig.
We're working on getting the community
tokens from the old multisig to the new
one.
As most of you know, we're on the new
Paideia as well.
So eventually those funds will hopefully
go into Paideia where we can fully manage
them there.
Let's see, I'll think of it as I'm
talking, kushti, but why don't you jump in
too?
What's new for you?
All right, so yeah, in the first place, I
promised to talk about quantum resistance.
Quantum resistance, yeah.
Yeah, so that's why it's a popular topic
these days.
Right.
So I've heard.
So with the hype with the Google's
machine, right there, the problem solving
looks very impressive, but it's
essentially a useless solution, right?
A problem to solve.
And these qubit machines are quite a bit
far away from where we think of, you know,
full blockchain breaking encryption.
Yeah.
So still we are decades away from quantum
computers capable to break cryptography,
right, modern cryptography.
Well, at least, right, so there are very
different opinions here, actually.
So there are opinions even that it's not
possible to build such quantum computers.
And yeah, I'm talking about folks working
in the space, so not just amateurs, well,
cryptographers even.
folks actually working in quantum
hardware engineering.
So yeah, there are very different
opinions.
right and so it's not quite clear when we
will see such quantum computers but yeah
at least decades away it seems but yeah
well it's important to address those
issues anyway right because we are kind of
building a cathedral here right so we are
trying to build something which will last
for generations to come right because
Otherwise, it's not that interesting,
right?
I mean, to build just something for one
day.
And so, yeah, then what do we have?
So here we have Ergo proof of work
consensus right which is secure against
quantum computers because well it's based
on hash functions and yeah well it's
secure unlike most of proof-of-stake
consensus algorithms right which are
relying on signature schemes and some
other primitives based on well
problems which are hard for classical
computers, but not for quantum computers.
All right, then yeah, it's possible to
update proof of stake algorithms and so on
to
post-quantum options, but it's not
efficient.
Proof-of-work is already the most
efficient consensus algorithm.
Every miner is working on its own.
When you are mining using Sigmanauts
mining pool, right?
Or doing solo mining.
So you are not talking with other miners,
right?
So you are just doing your work
asynchronously.
So you just need to know tip of the
blockchain and that's it.
So that's the only shared medium.
So you are not exchanging messages like
in BFT algorithms and so on.
And yeah, so proof of work is not just
the most efficient consensus algorithm,
right?
But it's also, well, post-quantum
already, because yeah, hash functions are
secure in the presence of quantum
computers.
I mean, all the hard problems in hash
functions.
Then, yeah, we have digital signatures
right here and also we have Sigma
protocols and here we don't have quantum
resistance, right?
So like for every blockchain, there is no
quantum resistance.
So, there is need to consider
alternatives, right?
But the issue is that there are not so
many standardized post-quantum schemes to
start with, right?
And all of them are inefficient.
So we will lose like 10x to 100x in TPS
immediately, right?
By switching to post-quantum
cryptography.
But still we need to consider
alternatives, right?
So there are some post-quantum sigma
protocols that exist, but yeah, it's hard
to predict when they will be standardized.
Then, we have what? We have post-quantum
signatures, but yeah, just a few options,
right?
And yeah, they're inefficient.
So, yeah, it's time to consider
alternatives, right?
But slowly and yeah, well, watching the
space and also considering, well, the
possible options for upgrade, right?
So, I don't know, maybe it could be a
side chain, right?
It's kind of a flexible side chain.
maybe other options, maybe starting from
some version of the protocol.
Yeah, we may, for example, allow for, but
we need to consider some options.
So about the side chain idea, so, I mean,
that's, that sounds great for like slow
development of it and testing, you know,
before we hit that mark where perhaps
quantum computing can crack cryptography.
But doesn't that mean that.
I mean, I think of that as more of an
insurance chain in the meantime, right?
So if you're worried about the Ergo
security or any other chain breaking down,
you have the side chain, perhaps you move
most of your stored value over to that
quantum resistant side chain.
But doesn't that mean as soon as
something's broken, then the value of the
original chain is toast.
So essentially the side chain becomes the
only real store of value at that point.
And anything that was on the old chain is
toast.
Not necessarily.
I mean, for original blockchain, you can
have some post-quantum contracts as well.
For example, signatureless contracts like
DEX contracts and so on, so that they
would be secure, as secure as consensus, I
mean post-quantum also.
It means Spectrum DEX and so on.
Already quantum resistant, right?
Because they're not relying on
signatures.
Unlike actually most of DEXs, right?
On other chains which do have admin keys
and so on.
So those admin keys are not quantum
resistant for starters.
What if you utilize the quantum side
chain, quantum resistant side chain to
roll up and provide verifications to smart
contracts on the current Ergo side, on the
current Ergo chain?
So a smart contract couldn't execute
unless it got a verification from
something on the quantum resistant side
chain.
So your store value still sits on the
main Ergo layer one, but it's waiting for
some sort of confirmation or proofs from
the quantum side chain before it can fully
act.
So even if something was cracked on the
Ergo chain it couldn't act until the proof
was sent over from the quantum side so no
real store of value on the quantum side
just for signatures in computing or
security is that something that's possible
We also may develop some post-quantum
wallet contracts.
There are actually some works in this
direction, but usually they rely on some
well, exotic cryptographic schemes such as
witness encryption.
So there is a paper from our friends
Dionysia on some lightweight post-quantum
wallet contract but yeah it relies on
witness encryption so kind of cryptography
which is not around yet basically which is
very exotic yet but yeah in future i
believe there could be such options
We may have post-quantum contracts, like
hash-based signatures may be done in
contracts.
There are some roll-up options, like
STARKs, so they are quantum resistant.
STARKs, they're not efficient, not very
efficient, but yeah, quantum resistant.
So, yeah, well, you can use, for example,
STARK-based roll-up, right?
Quantum-resistant roll-up.
What about, and this may be a stupid
question, but what about the mining side
of this?
So why not develop a qubit machine to
mine the hell out of Autolykos too and
steal the hash rate, get 99% of the hash
rate?
Is that something that we were worried
about at all?
If in the future, those quantum machines
can be cloned to deliver that kind of
power?
So sorry, what exact attack?
Well, let's say you're right, because
quantum machines, from what I understand,
they don't need the CPU can be used for
both memory and for processing or
something like that.
The bits can be an on, off, and a
substate, essentially.
So it makes it super, super efficient
there.
The question was, what are the
possibilities of quantum machines being
honed or developed to, instead of breaking
cryptography, do some crazy hash rate,
like go against ASIC miners and replace
those or, you know, be honed towards
Autolykos too and just take over the hash.
Like, you don't need to break
cryptography if you can build a machine
that can just immediately, you know,
dominate the hash rate of any chain.
But yeah, so we are talking about Ergo
proof of work, right?
So it's based on hash problem and it's
So it's quantum resistant, right, to the
best of modern knowledge.
So it's still a hard problem for quantum
computers.
And then, yeah, it's also based on a hash
function, but yeah, it's also hard for
quantum computers, right?
So you cannot find a collision.
And so on.
So, I mean, there is some speed up, but
it's not significant, right?
So still, and yes, okay, some problem.
Well, I've checked recently, actually.
And yeah, so there is some speed up, but
yeah, it's not negligible.
So yeah, it's still yeah, well, about the
exponential time, right, just with a bit
better coefficient.
So yeah, I mean, proof of work is secure,
right?
So then the only issue is about
signatures, but there are many options
right here to consider.
There is no rush.
So yeah, well, then we could be quite
optimistic, I guess, still, yeah, about
all those things.
There is a need to slowly consider
alternatives and discuss them, but there
is no rush talking about implementation.
Still, we have many years to come.
Yeah, I think every five years, kushti,
there's some announcement about some huge
breakthrough in quantum computing and it
still has been, mediocre announcements,
you know, way hyped up for what it
actually is or does.
So this is a cycle.
Yeah.
Every breakthrough is about adding like
five qubits and yeah, we need thousands
here, right?
Still.
And so this Google's new chip, so it's
still very tiny, right, its capabilities.
And yeah, it's not quite clear even if
it's possible to build systems with a
certain number of qubits because of some
issues with quantum physics.
But yeah, it's better to talk with guys
proficient in all that stuff.
What else is new, kushti?
What have you been working on?
Yeah, so then I recorded also talk for
the upcoming art events, upcoming modern
art events, which will show in particular,
which will be Ergo-centric rights to some
degree.
And then it will be about using Ergo
tooling for different things, so artists
will get to use Ergo tooling right for
their needs.
And yeah, I recorded the talk so it will
be released after 21st on property rights
in the age of programmable money, right?
So well, the talk is connecting different
dots within the space, right?
Starting from Tornado Cash decision,
recent one, to programmable money and then
tokenization of real world assets of art
and so on.
So, let's see.
So, yeah, well, there is a forum post,
right, made recently on that money
ownership in the age of programmable
money.
Yeah, but yeah, this talk for artists, so
it's about property rights and therefore
art objects, some thoughts about art
objects specifically, right, the
tokenization and so on.
And then, yeah, it's also about how Ergo
tooling rights could be useful for, well,
for doing different experiments.
So with property rights, at least, are we
talking about like, with a physical art
piece, right?
Something on-chain verifying, minted by
the artist.
You can trace it back to the artist and
see that the new owner of it has the
actual certification or that traces back
to the original minting wallet of the
artist, verifying ownership and that kind
of thing.
Is that what we're talking about?
Yeah, so it could be physical, right?
It could be digital.
So we can have NFT rights and that NFT
could belong to you, for example, but
yeah, it could be minted by contract,
right?
So its transfer sheet could be defined by
contract and so on.
If we are talking about physical art,
Then, yeah, it also can be tokenized with
NFT or with multiple tokens, right?
And then, yeah, for the latter option,
you may have very different options, like
20% of picture can belong to its author,
right?
Painter.
And then 80%, for example, can be sent to
auction contract, right?
To create auctions periodically, like one
token a week, one percent a week, for
example.
You can also bundle it in ChainCash too,
right?
Yeah, so you can actually airdrop to
miners or whatever, right?
So you may have digitized arts being
distributed to Sigmanauts and so on.
I think there could be a lot of very
unique things here, right?
When we are talking about, well, work of
artists combined with work of hardware,
for example, right?
So you may have, for example, painter
doing picture first, right?
And then, yeah, well, miners, they were
doing their work to get the right shares
of it.
So that's kind of art and hardware work,
right, combined and so on.
And yeah, I mean, so such events already
per se, I mean, like art events, right,
could be considered like that, like
performance, maybe art performance, right,
where you have mining along with the work
of humans done all together and combined
via on-chain contracts and so on.
So there are very different options here.
And yeah, so that's maybe a small piece,
but I think it's very important to work
through this piece and then jump on other
chapters talking about real-world
adoption.
kushti, you met with some developers, was
it last week?
One of our Sigmanauts pool miners as well
was there.
What was that chat about?
Yeah, so that was a local developers
meetup, so there was a talk about, I don't
know, 2024, right?
And I was kind of a blockchain expert,
right?
So, well, I did my best to explain what
happened in the space to the general
public.
So one of the guys there was Netam who's
an avid miner in our pool and speaking of
the Sigmanauts pool before I forget I
believe Mark is now fully pushing the
bonus tokens and I think a storage rent
payment went out as well they decided to
do storage rent payments based on the
block that they were found in since the
pool is already doing PPLNS based on that
block all you have to do is find the ratio
of payment for that specific block and
then distribute the storage rent based on
that and It works out perfectly.
Super super easy to do that But it's neat
the last I think the week before last we
got some big storage rent payments I think
we got
a couple ERG in one payment, almost an
ERG in several more.
So we're doing pretty well in the storage
rent payments.
But why?
So have you collected some big boxes
maybe?
Yeah, we got some, it must have been some
big boxes exactly.
Yep.
All right.
So yeah, I've checked recently and yeah,
it seems now a collection going on for
some initial tests for Oracle Pools.
So yeah, that could be some big boxes
there.
Yep.
We got, we've gotten some funky tokens
that we have no idea what they are and
some no name tokens and then some Oracle
test tokens as well, that we scoop up.
You know, it's fun to see.
It's fun to see the history.
It's like you're an archeologist and
you're kind of just digging up the chain
and seeing what pops up.
Yeah, so you are basically digging
dinosaur bones, right?
Yeah, that's really cool.
And actually, so you can put such tokens
on auctions, right?
Exactly.
I think CannonQ put out a vote on the
Sigmanauts mining thing for the PHP token
that they found and I believe he's going
to do something with that airdrop it or
some sort of thing or put it out as bonus.
But that vote was up in the Sigmanauts
mining pool now.
Super neat.
All right.
So anything else to discuss?
Well, we have, I don't know if I
mentioned this before, maybe I did, but
Cyberverse was in the top of the polling.
So they won their poll over at Ronin.
And if people didn't notice, there's now
a wallet connector for Ronin on the login
screen of Cyberverse.
So there's Ronin, Ergo, and Cardano.
And they just made it so that most or all
of the goods like the skins or the crate
boxes you buy with CYPX now no matter what
chain you're coming in on.
So I bought a Cardano skin with CYPX
that's only on Ergo and it went to my
Cardano wallet even though I paid for it
in Ergo CYPX.
So it's really cool.
So it incentivized coming to Ergo,
getting CYPX, and then spending it in game
to have your NFT go to whatever wallet
your chain of origin is.
So if it's on that chain.
They're minting Ronin NFT.
Did you see the kushti NFT in the Ronin
suit?
I think it's like a Ronin suit that I
posted in chat yesterday.
Yeah, I've no idea what Ronin is even.
So what's that?
Ronin is like a gaming chain,
essentially.
It's gamer focused for that.
So yeah, so they were branching into
that.
Is it some roll up layer 2 or what?
I imagine, I don't know.
I pay a little bit of attention to that
kind of thing, but yeah.
So that's great to see CYPX branching out
there.
And yes, Maverick, I did mint a Bobber
emote crate.
I got the crying Bobber with the tears
coming out.
You have the laughing Bobber.
I'm not sure which one that is.
I already mentioned MewFinance, which is
great.
And yeah, let's see a few questions.
Yeah, so also some Twitter spaces coming
from UTXO Alliance details will be shared
soon.
So it's with, yeah, UTXO Alliance
members, some Twitter spaces to join.
Then, yeah, so, probably after New Year,
we'll do new videos.
And yeah, I think we'll visit consensus
conference in Hong Kong also.
But yeah, let's see.
Then, yeah, so we are actually thinking
about doing maybe some meetups and so on.
In Hong Kong?
We'll check possibilities, maybe
Thailand, Vietnam, something like that,
but let's see.
There is a lot of development, so it's a
bit...
For node development, we just finished
the rework and versioning in 6.0, so there
will be a new release candidate this week.
Hopefully, we are already quite close to
the release, so yeah, well, after some
testing, so it will be under testing for
like a few days and then, yeah, we will be
released maybe around Saturday, right?
So if I will start testing today.
Then, yeah, well, 5.0 release is coming
as now it's approved.
And yeah, so Sigma interpreter release
next week, probably.
So yeah, a lot of things are going on
development wise.
And yeah, well, starting from, I don't
know, maybe next week even.
So we can have regular discussions on
sub-blocks, right?
Because well, I'm back on this and yeah
I'm doing already some stuff and yeah we
can start this actually a lot of things to
get done there right for sure so yeah well
contributors are welcomed well for like
from formalizing security writing tests
updating exploiters and so on.
Then for Ledger, well, there are final
conditions about audits, so it should be
studied.
I don't know.
But yes, not sure about next week because
it's Christmas, right?
But let's see.
But final talks already with third party
company authorized by Ledger.
Yeah, well, there are a lot of
developments, Oracle Pools, finally done,
and so on.
Yeah.
Well, probably please check developers
chats.
Yeah.
A lot of things there like, interesting
updates from Nautilus, right?
Then Oracle Pools.
What else?
That's great.
Finally, yeah, there is progress with
Kestrel, also deterministic signature
support done.
Yes, so there is no issue with randomness
anymore for the limited hardware.
Then what else, what else?
Yeah, well, a lot of updates as usual,
right?
And yeah, so for community discussion, do
you have any plans like Twitter space,
community calls, anything?
With them?
Yeah.
You take so alive.
It would be with...
Yeah.
I'm for community chats and the start of
the new year, right?
Let's do it.
Let's do it after the new year at some
point, maybe mid January.
That was fun.
Either a zoom or, I prefer the zoom to
the spaces, but but yeah, either one.
No, we can also comment about, well, as
usual, real world adoption value
proposition.
There are books, so I can open source,
the current drafts, right.
Which is mostly about structure still,
but yeah.
Have you found a couple of people, I see
you've invited a few people to write for
you from the book already.
You invited Luivatra to talk about
storage rent.
Yeah, Joe or Luis Grayman.
Yeah.
So we have already a few folks willing to
talk.
So well, Joe will put some manifests.
the rights of grassroots manifests, the
new one.
And yeah, so some other writing.
So yeah, we can reuse some old writing.
And then that there is need to combine
all writings and publish them.
All right, so let's jump on the
questions.
All right, let's see what we have.
Well, some more things about property
rights from Luis Grayman.
He says, kushti, most important property
right is to our own identity.
But now that is just about protecting a
seed phrase.
Please comment on how to make this soul
bound.
But it's like what a problem from the
90s, right?
It's not even an issue, right?
In the digital world, what do you have?
Well, numbers, right?
Well, you may have a secret number.
secret key some very big number right and
yeah well when you use seed so actually
you are using a big number in this seed,
right?
So it's a secret key from your seed.
And then, yeah, so that's what you do
have in the digital world.
And then is the whole big issue of how to
connect IDs in the real world, right, with
those numbers in the digital world.
So that's public key infrastructure,
right?
So, well, in addition to a secret, so you
have some public image of a public key,
right?
And then you may declare the public key
is yours, but then that's how to verify
that, right?
Especially if we are talking about
decentralized settings.
So that's actually how, well, the
Cypherpunk period, right?
So initially it was about different
attempts to develop infrastructure for
public keys, right?
Decentralized infrastructure.
So some trust and so on.
So there are just like web of trust,
right?
And it's also as well as many other.
Well, the initial setting was to do some
key exchange rights, then exchange emails.
For example, there is some person you
have to exchange emails with.
Yeah, so you are using public key
writing.
The problem is how can you be sure that
some public published on the web is all
right?
So, well, it could be a fake website or
whatever, then you end up with sending
email to some fake person.
possibly revealing some secret sensitive
data.
And then, yeah, there are a lot of
attempts to overcome this, well, by using
trusted parties, like you're using
certificates on the internet, right, with
trusted issuers.
There is somewhat federated approach web
of trust, right, when you trust Joe,
right, which is authorized my key, for
example, right, so first Joe needs to meet
me, gets
some certification of my public key and
then tell you that this public key is
trusted by Joe and then you trust Joe,
right?
And you are using my public key because
of that and so on.
You know, if after 30 years, it's the
same issue, basically, that means the
issue is hard, right?
Well, it will remain hard, I believe,
because brightest minds, well, in
cryptography, practical cryptography, and
not only, well, are working on that for
like 30 years to the moment.
Still, you know, the progress is very
limited.
And yeah, well, blockchain in some
settings may help, right?
But still, the problem remains.
All right, let's see.
We've got, CannonQ wanted to mention
Cyberverse and DuckPools, and I forgot to
mention DuckPools.
He says, they're two different projects.
Both are attractive to the outside chains
if marketed and supported by the
ecosystem.
So yeah, guys, DuckPools is, I think
their sale is almost up, or a couple more
days for their round.
DuckPools is, as many know, or many not
know watching this,
a lending pool protocol.
So for example, the Sigmanauts had about
2,500 SigmaUSD that we were lending, that
we were paying to Rare Evo earmarked for
that.
So we put it in DuckPools while we waited
and into the SigmaUSD lending pool.
And when we pulled it out, it was $3,000.
So the thought is, you know, these
protocols exist.
If you have SigmaUSD, if that's your
thing, if that's your jam to mitigate risk
by having some of your portfolio on that,
then why not put it in a lending program
like DuckPools and make some yield off it
while it just sits there for other people
that want to take a bigger risk by maybe
shorting or longing ERG at that point.
So yeah, DuckPools is great.
Check out their IDO.
it's essentially you get a staking token
and the quacks are airdropped to you every
month or every week or something like
that, depending on how much you bought, in
that percentage.
So super, super cool.
They have their own DAO built in
separate, completely separate of Paideia,
Kaspa built that.
So yeah, check that out.
Let's see what else we have here.
We have.
Wombo says, qx(), any worries on creating
BRICK?
Is there any possibility of problems in
trying to create a currency for the
school?
Cornell already has something called Big
Red Bucks, which is actually digitized.
It's on the Cornell student cards.
Students get paid in it, I think, for
some of the work they do, and then they
can spend it at different places on
campus.
So they already have a system of value
like that.
I don't see how this is any different.
We're not putting it on a DEX, so we're
not putting any monetary value on it as
far as physical real things.
Now that being said, I'm sure, you know,
smart savvy kids might, you know, try to
create liquidity pool on Spectrum DEX.
It's doubtful, but it's possible.
Yeah, no, I'm not worried about that
Wombo.
All right.
Our guest Kent says, do we have any way
of measuring awareness or engagement with
Rosen Bridge among users of other chains,
i.e.
Cardano?
Does anyone outside of the Ergo community
know about it?
I would say that from my experience at
Rare Evo, Rosen Bridge is a very
well-known name throughout Cardano, at
least.
I can't speak to Ethereum, Bitcoin, or
CKB, where they may go next.
But yes, I'd say it's very well known.
They'd come to us and they'd see Ergo and
then they'd see Rosen Bridge over in the
corner and they'd be like, oh, you guys
are with Rosen Bridge or you guys are
with, you know, and we're like, oh, no,
we're Sigmanauts with Ergo, Rosen Bridge
is on Ergo and that kind of thing.
So yeah, I'd say in Cardano it's well
known.
I think they're doing a great job of slow
burning their marketing system through,
you know, proof of work exactly, you know,
proof of work, they're showing a system
that works well and is trusted.
And I think that's working well for them
to spread across as they go from ecosystem
to ecosystem.
The people you talked to, the dev people
you talked to last week, the local dev
meetup, they're familiar with Rosen
Bridge.
So, they're not very familiar with
blockchains even, right?
Well, I even didn't talk much about the
panel.
2024 in blockchain insights and so on.
Well, after I had a talk with developers
in a coffee shop nearby, well, mostly I
presented just the idea of programmable
money.
Because for developers it's even more
understandable, like what to do.
and where do you inject program, what's
execution context and so on.
And so yeah, got some folks excited, some
want more talks just on that, so the idea
of programmable money.
And well, there are folks now who are
interested in, well, how to contribute,
but well, I need to provide more details.
Because for developers interested in
compilers, right, interpreters and so on,
well, the idea to make, well, money,
right, programmable it's more
understandable than smart contracts,
engineering wise, as well.
Yeah, so that concept wasn't made by
engineers back then, back in 2014.
All the engineers kept writing about all
that stuff, so it was predictable.
like them, that's decentralized computer,
but to say a fully replicated programmable
computer would be overloaded, right, even
with some trivial load, like we have
Ethereum blockchain.
So, well, the world talked about that
back in 2014.
Right, but well, here, well, the idea, do
some work, well, they do that to engineers
at least.
All right.
Let's see.
We're getting near time.
We have a question from Wombo for you,
kushti.
Can you speak about umbrella tokens and
explain the pattern a bit?
How you plan to use ChainCash?
So, yeah, well, let's see whether it will
be used, right?
But the basic idea that you have some
parent token, right?
And you have contracts, which is allowing
you to issue, well, new token, right?
Some certificate issued, right?
Well, in that case, parent's tokens,
right?
And by using that, so you can, well,
different tokens, you may issue under some
parent token, right?
You can certify basically, and that
certification can be later used in
contracts.
I mean well ChainCash example so what I'm
thinking about is to have a well a reserve
track which is issuing well which is
having reserve tokens right and well those
reserve tokens can be put on issuing note
to some reserve right with
It was due to a contract-based
certification that the token was actually
issued by calling the contract, right.
And, yeah, well, it seems a similar
design pattern, well, can be used in other
cases as well.
Well, I got a hard stop.
I got to run across campus to another
meeting.
So this seems like a good place to end.
All right.
Already.
So do we have any questions from previous
AMA?
Because yeah, we promised to answer, me
and Joe.
What was the previous questions?
Do we have any other, maybe any sign
about this?
I don't see any, no, I don't see anything
commenting about last week.
All right.
So folks, well, if you want questions
from last week, answered.
So send them next week.
Did you guys chat too long last week and
forgot to answer questions, kushti?
Is that what happened?
Oh, there are a lot of questions.
So yeah, we didn't answer them all.
So yeah, we suggested folks resubmit.
And yeah, well folks, you can resubmit
them next week then.
Nice.
Well, there is nothing to hide, so every
question will be answered.
Maybe just time is the most important.
All right.
Yeah, let's wrap up with this.
We'll see you around the ecosystem.
Yeah.
Yeah, let's continue our text chat.
Sounds good.
Thanks so much, everybody.
Have a great weekend.
Bye, everyone.