Hello and welcome to the Ergo AMA, weekly
AMA.
It is Wednesday, February 12th in sunny
New York and dark Japan. You can see it's
very dark in Japan because Dan is, it's
dark there in this picture and he's very
frozen. Dan had to do a reboot of his
machine like 10 minutes ago, but I think
he's still on one of those IBM or HP Intel
486s so it's taking him at least 30
minutes to reboot so we're gonna kick this
off without him today and you may be
wondering why is this on Wednesday and
that's because our amazing AV person is
traveling tomorrow. So we decided to move
this a little earlier.
So it's my job to start this for you
before Dan gets here. That's great. Maybe
we can cover everything. And then by the
time Dan gets here, he won't even have to
talk and he can just go. So start popping
your questions in the side there to give
me something to chat about as well, but as
far as Ergo goes everything's going great
everybody right we have Binance some
progress on Binance for Rosen Bridge and I
love how Rosen Bridge is getting more I
don't want to say balls here, but they're
getting more obvious with their major goal
here, right? And that's to backdoor all
these central exchanges.
And a lot of you may have been following
a couple weeks ago, maybe a month ago,
where we are trying to backdoor Kraken,
right, with Rosen-ERG. So we applied for
both. We threw both in a couple weeks ago
when Peter asked us to and I mean we'll
take what we can get we have enough
liquidity on Cardano I think as much or
more than some of the exchanges on the
Ergo side So I think any idea there will
be would be great either way. So looking
forward to that. We should see the guard
code coming soon. We'll apply that to the
guards. Make sure that's all hunky-dory
and then you should see a watcher update
there as well.
One thing I want to tell you, I think I
said it in the dev update the other day,
the way the Watcher and Guard software
work is it's through Docker, right? So
there are repositories that are registered
on Docker. And part of those repositories
aren't Rosen Bridge repositories, right?
They are like the PostgreSQL program,
which actually stores a database. So what
happened is the main official repository
for that SQL software I think was pulled.
So if you're restarting a watcher or
getting ready to spin up a watcher for
Binance or just anything like that or
moving your watchers, you're going to get
an error there unless you follow the
instructions, the new instructions in the
list. So if you're trying to use the same
software, the same folder that you did
before and you're trying to pull it, you
need to do a little bit of research just
to read the instructions again. There's
just another SQL, PostgreSQL repository
that we're using now that works just fine.
And it's no different there. In the
guards, we had to migrate our database
over to do it. When I did it for my
watcher first, I just bombed it through
without a migration. So it just had to
pull new stuff down. But yeah, so be aware
of that when you're prepping for that kind
of stuff, if you're going to run a binance
or you're moving your watchers around.
Well, I had more to say, Dan, and you
showed up. I was expecting it to be like
30 minutes late.
Oh, it's okay.
It just seems that I'm 30 minutes early
because you're talking about watchers and
stalking and whatever you're talking about
right now.
How's it going, Dan? Big stuff in
Cardano, right? In Cardano land with your
token, right? No?
Well, soon, yeah, it's going to be
launching. So we're planning to do for
probably later this month. So that is on
the horizon. And yes, we're going to be
using the Rosen Bridge heavily to, you
were just talking about Rosen Bridge,
right? You weren't really talking about,
you know, watchers and stocking and things
like that. Yep. I hope not. No, no, no.
Any more weirdness from you qx().
Anything's expected, I guess. Right.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah, so we're going to be
using Rosen Bridge pretty heavily. So
yeah, right now we're actually planning to
use it. Well, of course, Cardano and Ergo,
we have assets that are going to be moved
to Ergo from Cardano. We also have assets
that are going to be moved to EVM. So
we're going to do the multi-chain launch
to have a situation and it's going to be
really interesting how that pans out. Our
market makers are going to have a lot of
fun with that.
What's this? Can you fit me in then? You
know, I'm on Twitter. It's a guy who go
through breaks on Twitter sometimes. But
you're having a CEX listing. Is that what
I saw? A CEX and a DEX listing?
Yeah. So we actually got several in the
oven right now. Yeah. And so we're going
to be, of course, going into the biggest
DEXes. And we also have a couple of CEXes
already in the pipeline. And we're going
to be signing with more. We're just kind
of trying to, I guess, plan it out well
strategically so that we have deep
liquidity versus just thinning it out over
a bunch of different exchanges. Because
actually, there's quite a few exchanges
that you can just sign with and get listed
if you have the money. And I mean, they
have kind of have volume, you know, some
of them is a little it's kind of fake.
Some of them, it's organic. Some of them,
it's a mix of organic and fake. But in the
end is just kind of like, okay, so where
do you want to concentrate your liquidity,
you know, because we're like, for example,
we had well, I still have the opportunity
to sign with a pretty major one, but it
costs a bunch of money. And so the choice
that I made was, well, instead of spending
hundreds of thousands of dollars to list
on this thing right now, I'll spend that
$100,000 or $200,000 to bring liquidity
and to bring support to the actual token.
They just made more sense like that have
more control over where it goes and you
know, that's just seems like a better
plan. Yeah, so that's going to be later
this month. Yeah, applying that we're
going to that pretty soon.
Yeah, yeah, I agree. I think I think
strategically distributing your liquidity
is wise, you know, as long as you're not
suffering for access, right? Because
there's a trade off. Do you do you spread
liquidity over several different places so
that there's more access to more people?
Or do you maybe take a hit on access and
make your liquidity quite deeper so that
the people that want to buy can really
invest in your token without too much
damage to their price impact or slippage
kind of thing? So yeah, that's got to be a
tough thing to work out.
That's really the bottom line here, is to
say you want to have really stable trading
when you just launch. because there's
going to be quite a few people coming in
there for the trading side of it, and
there's going to be some unlocks
happening. So you want it to be really
smooth. You don't want it to have really
low volume and then have these ridiculous
spikes and then really I mean, even if it
spikes up, you still can't really do
anything with that if you're a trader,
right? Because there's no volume. And if
there's no volume, well, then it's like,
well, as soon as you try to do anything
with that, it's going to dump the price.
So that's basically the plan here is that
we're going to strategically use only a
couple of sectors at first to bring pretty
deep volume in or significant volume in.
have it stabilize, and then we can branch
out from there. We signed with a very good
market maker, a really prominent one. One
of the things is they actually you know,
have a strategy for us to, you know, it's
like, okay, so we should do this and this
and this and for your pathway to, you
know, if you want to get it on a tier one
exchange. Oh, and so we, I got a question
here actually from, from big 3D asking is,
will RSPalm be listed on a CEX at launch?
So I'd like to, but the thing is that I
need support for RSPalm at a CEX. We're
going to try to get that on the ones we
have one, actually we have a couple that
are very flexible about what they can do.
They're not huge exchanges, but they're
flexible so we can potentially integrate
RSPalm there. So that's something that
will come a little further down the line,
but not at launch. Yeah, that's been my
world in the past few weeks.
Oh, and yeah, so if anybody is going to
Hong Kong, what is it? I guess next week.
I'm not going to be there, unfortunately.
I have some family things to attend to,
but Sam is going to be there. Nice yeah,
you're gonna be hanging out with with
kushti because kushti is gonna be there.
So, if you guys, anybody's there, you
know, and you see Sam, you know, ask him
like the tough questions, like, for
example, why did he wear those short
shorts? The first time I represented
Palmyra at that, you know, whatever it
was, the consensus in Austin, he did that,
you know, and the first time my company
was represented and he wore these super
short shorts that I forbid him to ever
wear again.
Were they jean shorts like from?
no no they weren't jean shorts they were
like they had this like like no no they
were like some some like design on them or
something like it was like fishes or
something i forgot it was just really
awkward and yeah and they were like a
little too short like they call them i i
think in australia they were like like
budgie smugglers
They're not like Tobias's little jean
shorts from Arrested Development.
No. Okay, darn it. I can see that because
I was picturing that and I was getting,
you know, that was, I may have had to shut
off the camera at that point thinking
about that. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's great. Sam's going to be with
kushti.
Yeah, yeah, he's going to be with kushti.
Is this a booth event? Do you have booths
to just kind of just hang out, walk
around, shake hands, kiss puppies?
Yeah, kiss puppies, kiss children that
look like puppies and whatnot. They're
actually going to be doing some combined
Palmyra Ergo work over there, talking to
some potential funds and some exchanges
that could potentially, again, do listings
for Ergo and Ergo assets. Yes, they're
going to have a pretty full pretty full
schedule over there. Well, you catch them
at the at the event And we're actually
been really working really fleshing out
the Lithos index as well Right. So that's
also been yeah actually Sam's been doing a
lot of the a lot of the work over there
and the he's been working with kushti and
on really kind of try to flesh out exactly
how the thing works. So I mean, you know
Oracle two up and that kind of stuff,
right?
Do you gotta Push the input, you know
kushti is actually very proactive on it
He's actually trying to get more and more
input, which is of course, you know, very
very welcome I mean, it's great
Does Sam ever get a vacation, Dan? How
often do you let him out?
I don't. He's not old enough to have a
vacation yet. No, sorry. It has to be at
least in his mid-30s and losing much more
hair. Then he gets a vacation, maybe,
maybe. Poor Sam. Yeah, we'll see. We'll
see. We'll see how much hair he loses in a
couple of years and then we'll weigh
against PTO and whatnot.
You're at least putting him on a flight
to Hong Kong, not a boat, right?
Well, so, you know, this is actually,
he's not going on a boat, but he might as
well be because, you know, like I tell
him, you know, just get yourself a nice
flight. Yeah. I mean, it's like a four
hour flight, but still it's four hours,
you know, four hours of sitting. And, you
know, and I tell them, you know, Cathay
Pacific, it's not expensive, but it's
nice, you know, and it's not, you know,
it's not cheap, but it's not expensive and
it's nice. And they get good location at
the airport and, you know, it's a Hong
Kong airline and everything's like, so he
sends me a list of these like super cheap,
like budget airlines out of which I only
know one. You know, it's like, you know,
we fly, you know, the like an airline is
that it's like, it's called like we fly
you and don't crash air or something. It's
just some really like, I don't know. I
don't know. He likes that kind of stuff.
I try to Dan, that's what you want for a
CEO. You want somebody that is price
conscious and sacrificing themselves.
Look, we're price conscious enough. All
right. I mean, my, the last hotel I stayed
in in Singapore was in the middle of the
red light district.
I'm sure that was an accident, Dan.
Yeah, it was definitely an accident. It
was actually in the tranny part,
apparently in the tranny part of the Red
Light District. So that was even a bigger
accident. Yeah, because I was telling you,
I was driving down in a taxi back to the
hotel from the conference. And, you know,
I had one of those like, you know, see the
sights, my friend type of taxi drivers
where he was just telling me, he's like,
well, over here to the left, they have
this and you have over here to the right,
you have this. And he's just like, oh
yeah, well, so. None of these are like and
he just points out you see all those like
yeah, none of them are girls. I'm like, oh
great You know, so like anyways And then
my my hotel room had no windows zero no
windows And the sacrifices you make for
this company, Den
Well, sacrifices that I make for our
investors as well, because we'll bathe in
luxury when we're bathing in massive
profits. Well, you don't want to bathe in
lithium. It's toxic.
Well, on-chain lithium, I guess. Lithos
peg stablecoin.
That's nice. Yeah, so it's, yeah, it's
not the most pleasant thing, but you know,
like some things, I mean, like I got that
hotel because it was actually the cheapest
hotel I could find that was not like, you
know, like a hostel or, you know, like an
hour away from the conference, you know,
and it was still, you know, relatively
good rating because, yeah usually you know
usually try not to be super cheap hotels
you know i usually like to kind of look
for something that's comfortable
comfortable and conveniently located so
that i can you know i can just Got to do
the business and not worry about it. I
mean, I don't mean lap of luxury, but I
don't know. I don't want to be sleeping in
a shack either. So Sam likes that. You
know, Sam, Sam was like, you know, he was,
he was trying to get me to share a room
with him the other, like, in Tokyo. I'm
like, no, man, you're getting your own
room.
Maybe he's just scared of being alone
then.
Look, I've seen him in his underwear
enough, okay, in the past several years.
We shared enough rooms. I'm like, look,
man, we're somewhat funded now. We can
afford another room. We can afford to pay
another 150 bucks for you to have your own
room and for me to have my freaking
privacy, man. I'm 47 years old. I need my
privacy. I'm cranky.
That's very sweet. Dan, I'm looking
through the Hong Kong. There's a lot of
speakers here. I'm wondering if, Dan, if
you're sending Sam with a bunch of Ergo
stickers that you stole from us, you
should send them with them so they can
reach them all over.
Yeah, we have Ergo stickers in the
office. I'll make sure I'll load them up
with Ergo stickers so they can be
represented over there.
This is a huge conference. I'm still I'm
still scrolling the whole time. You're
talking about you sleeping habits. I've
been scrolling through the speaker list.
Yes It's a shame I can't go but yeah,
it's you know, I am You know, my mom is in
town. So I I can't go. Yeah Yeah, so but
yes He's gonna go to all these parties,
he's gonna have all this fun. To me, you
know, most of these parties, I go in
there, I'm like, all right, where's the
food and why is it so fricking loud? Yeah,
I am. You know, cause some of these, like
you have to know which ones to go to,
because there's gonna be a bunch of
parties, there's gonna be literally just
clubs. You know, just people go clubbing
from these things. And I'm just like, no,
man, I don't wanna go clubbing. I wanna
talk to some people and do some
networking.
All right, Dan, I'm scanning here. I got
a guy here. I wanted to ask you a question
here. What? And maybe that'll lead into
something else. We got Edgy and Yago from
BitcoinOS. Is that the same BitcoinOS that
was a big hype in Cardano a couple months
ago?
Yeah, yeah. Yago.
Yeah, you know him? You know the guy?
Best friend?
Not personally, but I know.
What happened to that? What happened to
that hype and the blow down and the blow
up?
I know an evil parod that was named that,
but anyway. You know, let's keep on that.
Well, so I look at these products and
people say oh these competing with Rosen
Bridge is this competing with this, you
know, is you know Why you judge one? Well,
so I look at these things and I'm like,
okay Rosen Bridge is so far from Any
centralized thing that these that anybody
creates like this that it's not even the
same I mean sure it gets a similar thing
done, right? Well, not Bitcoin OS, but
let's say other bridges gets a similar
thing done, but it's just such a different
I mean Like I explain it to people even at
conferences and they're like wait what you
know you have like 200 watchers you have
you know this many guards and there's
gonna be a hundred guards doing this it's
not like some dude and five of his friends
with a bunch of keys that they're they're
doing kind of thing so it's like just a
totally different animal so
Well, some of these products are
competing. I don't feel that Rosen Bridge
is in competition with Bitcoin OS at all.
I mean, it's just a different approach. It
solves many different issues. It handles
data transfers differently. It's a
different animal. I just don't feel that
it's like a direct competition. And the
same with But with CKB, CKB has got a
similar product and it's RGB++, and that's
not really...I don't think it's competing
with it. I think it's actually a really
good complement to RGB. what Rosen Bridge
does. I think people who say that, they
don't really understand the real use cases
for this thing. I just think that because
like Rosen Bridge is actually pretty damn
unique in the way it does things. That's
why we use it so much and that's why we
decided to incubate it when it needed to
get that boost. And that's why we're going
to keep using it. And of course, it
doesn't mean that we're not going to use
other ones. But again, for example, I have
these other ones that were offered to me,
and they were just centralized. Like, oh,
we have a centralized bridge that can do
this for you. I'm like, well, I don't want
a centralized bridge. I don't want that.
To me, it feels dirty.
I mean, it's like it's with those kind of
things. It's like it's not if it's like
when right when's that?
I Mean I I can't afford that like, you
know for One of my main jobs is to
minimize risk, you know to minimize the
risk.
Sorry Dan 10% of your supply is now, you
know wash because
And yeah, I can't have that. I can't have
that. That's irresponsible for me to do
and for the people that are in my
ecosystem. So I try to decentralize as
much as possible. And whenever we actually
are looking for other solutions with the
different products that we have, we also
try to do as much decentralization as
possible. Because number one, it is
obviously a safer and more robust
ecosystem, and it's also financially
viable for us because it eliminates pain
points like security issues that we would
have to deal with if it was centralized,
amongst other things like auditing, for
example. If you've got a centralized
ecosystem with open source, you can talk
about this before you have community
auditing of the source code. So again,
you're You're reducing risk like that as a
company, so it just makes sense to me. So
yeah, like I said, I don't feel like it's
any kind of real competition, like
head-butt competition, just different
flavors and whatever works for you for
your particular use case is what you use.
Yeah. I feel like Rosen's a Swiss army
knife that you can download from the
internet and 3D print and have a fully
functional backdoor to everything. Oh,
look at that.
Yeah, actually, I got this at the Swiss
Army store in Zurich.
Wow. Was it like 50 bucks?
I forgot how much it was because you know
who bought this for me?
Sam.
No, Charles Hoskinson.
Wow Yeah Actually, this is not the only
one he bought for me and I actually don't
have it here I should I'll bring it to the
next day. I may be trying to send you a
message then He was trying to send me a
message. It's like do more shit And he
actually actually I have it downstairs and
is this like Like just like just this big
bulky thing, but he bought me the largest
Like well accessory wise Swiss Army knife
they make I'm one of those big fat guys.
It's like this wide.
It's like this wide has got you know,
it's got like a 12 piece socket set on it
and ironing board Yeah ironing board and
you know French seasoning Like it's just,
yeah, this crazy thing. I have it
downstairs. I, I, I don't think I ever
used it. I'm just like, like, cause the
thing is like weird to hold, you know,
because the blade is about this big, but
the handle is like this wide. But you
know, it was, it was, it was a good
thought and it was a nice memory. This was
back in, uh,
Back in the old days, Dan.
Yeah, like back in the old days, yeah.
So I'm looking at Testnet right now, and
kushti had me push. He just had a new jar
up for 6.0 RC2. I think there was a little
tweak to RC2 we had to do. And we put it
in, and I recognize why. If anybody's
watching the Dev Update, You'd have seen
kushti say, why the hell is testnet so
irregular qx()? And it was because I was
mining from a rig down in my basement that
obviously needed a reboot. So I put on a
temporary thing after I updated and we're
getting, let's see. The last 32 blocks
were 16.77 seconds each. So testnet's
burning through until it gets up to the
good difficulty where it'll slow down a
little bit, but we've got faster than
sub-blocks testnet going on right now for
kushti to test sub-blocks on and Unreal to
test his front-ends on that he's working
on. So that's good. That's up. If anybody
wants to join testnet, please do. Reach
out to me, I'll give you the config file,
I'll give you the jar file. The more
people we have running it, the better.
That means I can reduce my GPU pointing to
it.
The rough thing about Testnet, Dan, is
that in one person, let's say I'm mining
it and I'm mining it with a 3090, you
know, and that's getting 250, 300 mega
hash at it. If I do that for a couple
days, the difficulty is going to be pretty
high. And if somebody comes in to help out
in mines with their CPU, they're going to
be hard luck finding a block for a while
until the difficulty goes down. So the
more people we have on testnet, the
better. So if you're up for it and you
want to run a little machine, you have
like an old 1050 or something like that
that you want to do GPU-based mining. I'll
feel for you. Even if you don't want to
set up Mining core anything like that
Spreading the hash is still good. I have a
mining core test that you can point to
that that does that as well So just
offering out there to everybody Dan It's
very sweet of you
What else is there to talk about? You
following US at all? US crypto, that kind
of stuff? There's so much speculation
going on. It's like hard to keep track,
Dan. I feel like there's like shock things
thrown out there on the wall to see what's
going to stick and see what people are
going to freak out about and not freak out
about. So I don't know if it's all a test
or whatnot.
But the thing about it is that, you know,
I think actually we talked about this
maybe on the last AMA. I remember having
this conversation, but actually, no, it
was actually another AMA that wasn't Ergo.
But, you know, I've been doing so many of
these that it just looks a blur in my
mind.
It's just so famous.
Yeah, I hear you, Dan.
I'm so famous. I'm infamous.
Yeah.
You know, nobody gets that reference. Do
you get the reference?
I'm infamous.
Yeah. He's so famous. He's infamous.
Steve Martin Yeah, I know that one.
Yeah. Yeah. See I got I still got it damn
Well, yeah, you still have that was a good
movie That's great Yeah
Yes.
So hold on. So basically, what are we
looking at? What are we experiencing right
now in the U.S.? We're basically
experiencing this like thing that happens
to Google Meet when your connection slows
down and then it catches up and then like
it, you know, so it has like, you know
what it does? Like when like everybody
starts talking super fast because your
connection is trying to catch up to the
present. The same thing is happening in
the US. This was supposed to start in
2016. It was 2015-2016 is when it was
supposed to start, really, in reality. It
didn't because Trump was elected and
instead of focusing on legislation and
regulations, everybody started focusing on
Trump. and from all sides. And so, you
know, and that's what happened. It was
just kind of left to be the wild, wild
west because everybody was just so
obsessed with Trump. And so now what we
have is a delayed reaction. And that's why
it's so intense. That's why it's so like
archaic, because now they know that
they're already late, They know that they
had four years of Gensler just toppling
his way through it, and that pissed off a
lot of people and drove a lot of business
out. They're desperately trying to get the
business back and the momentum back
because so much crypto is American,
because people are dissing Trump's like,
oh, American cryptos, how do you say it?
kind of you know he's a he's a character
but he doesn't just like with like with
business i just don't feel i feel pretty
much everything that he blurs out even as
as like as crazy as it always sounds, it's
always part of some plan, right?
Well, that's what worries me, Dan.
That's what worries me. The thing about
American Crypto is, and again, this is
speculation, but what I think he's doing
is he understands that a lot of this
business was driven out of the US. It was
just driven out. It was pushed out. ICOs
were pushed out. Crypto companies are
pushed out. Everybody went to Singapore,
Seychelles, parts of Europe, Estonia.
Everybody just kind of scattered out of
the US because of this, like I said, of
the Gary Gensler Gestapo, because nobody
wanted to go to prison for this kind of
stuff, because the government can't decide
how much money they want to keep of yours.
So, but now what he says, okay, look, you
know, we want you back. We want you back
because what it also does, it has thinned
out the pool that is needed to create
sensible regulation. because they pushed
out so much business right now, they look
at it like, okay, so how do we make it
happen? Because we don't really have a
good like sandbox for these regulations
because there's just not enough proper
businesses operating out of the US because
everybody avoids is like the plague.
because it's just because of all these
regulations. So he says, okay, American
crypto, blah, blah, blah. Yeah, I mean,
yeah, it sounds crazy from the outside to
some people, but to me, it sounds like
he's trying to get these people back and
settle down so that they can actually have
a calm business audience, crypto and
blockchain-based business audience that
are not gonna be scared of going to prison
to sandbox with. you know they're gonna
bring all the stuff back again like i said
you know it's it's it's the of course it's
like a slogan you know like yeah we want
american you know american crypto what's
american crypto but in the end is just he
just wanted back in the u.s. so they can
make proper regulations of the can make
sense out of it And I think that that's
smart if that's what's happening indeed,
in fact. Indeed, if that's what's
happening. Yeah, and again, going back to
what you said about things getting a
little archaic, well, then like I said,
that's what it gets like. It's like that
volatility. If there's not enough volume,
there's going to be crazy volatility. They
need more volume in there. They need more
stuff happening there for there to be less
volatility and more stability to create
proper regulation. That's my thought on
it.
I'm a little more skeptical than you
there, Dan. That's very positive thinking.
Yeah, but you're in New York and you work
in academia. Of course you are.
Well, my thought is, I mean, Occam's
Razor explains a lot of Trump's behavior,
I think, personally. And that is that the
simplest thing is at play here, and the
simplest thing is that he's Really looking
out for his own interests. So there's
always as you said, he always kind of
sometimes blurts out his plans beforehand,
right? I'm just saying I'm gonna let you
finish.
I'm gonna let you finish Thanks, Kanye
I think that Occam's razor only works
with what the quote is, right? With all
things considered, with all things being
equal, the simplest explanation tends to
be the most correct one. You not all
things are equal because there's too many
question marks here about exactly what is
on the table here. So it's not being
objective. It's kind of being subjective
to what you're and again, that's why I
said I am speculating as well.
Correct.
You can't use Occam's razor here. At
least to me can't use that because not all
is equal.
Fair enough.
Go ahead. You finish. You finish.
You finish. We'll go with the simplest
solution here is usually what I've seen
work with him. And this is, so my thought
is that most of the stuff that he does is
in line with some sort of idea that he has
to benefit himself. And most of the things
I've seen as well while they may appear to
benefit larger groups as a whole, are
still benefiting himself, and perhaps that
was the main reason to do it, or perhaps
the idea was presented to him and he goes
along with it because it would also
benefit himself. So, I mean, if that's his
personality or whatever, that he's a
businessman, of course, you're going to
want to do things to benefit yourself. I
don't know if that should be done from the
office of the presidency, but whatever. My
worry is that if you listen to him...
Your worry is that Doge is going to go
after your budget. That's your worry, OK,
qx()? I know, I know.
We're private. We're a land-grant
institution. We do have some funds, but
it's mainly a private institution. Anyway,
so if you remember when he was talking
about when people were asking him
questions about the Trump coin, right?
When it spiked to like $34 or $43 billion,
whatever the hell it was. Now, there are
two ways you can interpret what he said,
right? He looked at them, or he didn't
even look. I think he was signing stuff at
the desk at the Oval Office. And he said,
34 billion, 43 billion? Oh, that's nothing
compared to, I don't know if he stopped a
sentence or he made it indicate that
that's nothing yet kind of thing. Either
he's being, you know, being what he's been
before where he's, you know, pompous and
was like, Oh, that's nothing. That's
barely anything, you know, kind of thing.
Or he's, there's some serious plans in his
head to make a decent amount of money.
Right.
And why Greenland it's, I mean, it's,
it's how much is the GDP of Greenland?
I don't know. What is it? Let's look. 3.2
billion.
Exactly. Exactly. Listen, I think we're
running pretty short on time. Let's get
3.2 billion.
Yeah. Yeah.
But I didn't buy like 15 Greenlands.
Yeah. So all I'm all I'm saying, all I'm
saying is that something like something
like Ergo exists outside of these walls,
right? Something like Ergo. Well, Ergo
would benefit, of course, like all other
cryptos. If Trump had some deregulation or
even, you know, It'd be fantastic if at
least some more clarity and more defined
guidelines and boundaries and rules would
come out on the US for crypto instead of
what we've had for the last x years where
who knows if you're breaking the rules,
right? Who knows if you're doing this? So
that's a positive step, right? Let's get
some clear things in place of how things
are done and what we do. Ergo will benefit
from that stuff as well as even if Trump
starts a Bitcoin reserve and starts
pumping into that, Ergo is going to
benefit from that. All ships are going to
rise in crypto. Yeah, gotcha. But the
point I'm trying to make, Dan, is that
Ergo can survive without that, right? Ergo
can survive in a state of privacy because
it's optional. We're deregulated,
essentially decentralized, because anybody
can run a node in any country with just a
small computer. We have amazing open
source tooling that anybody can jump onto
and use. So when I see these storms out
there that are rip roaring and people like
Trump are ripping up, not ripping up, but
moving around and getting hyped up for the
crypto markets and that kind of thing,
Yeah, that's great, but I feel like here
we are in our Ergo Juggernaut and any of
these storms, while it may rock the boat a
little bit, it's, you know, it's just a
Thursday night storm for Ergo. You know,
no big deal. We can, you know, we'll
persevere through everything. That's what
it's built for, I guess is my ending point
there, Dan.
Well, and that's a good point And i'm
sorry that happened or i'm very happy for
you All right.
Let's get a question. What do we have?
And oh we got here we go. This is a good
one Mohammed esmer Our favorite
non-favorite person who likes to trash who
guys has gotten banned from main chat like
300 times He says qx() and daniel argue
alive about who is a better pronokia. So
he's calling us a liar So I don't know
about what maybe about the positivity i
go, but I want to take this chance to
remind people that while Ergo is an open
ecosystem and it's free to use anybody can
use it you know do what they want with it
take as much control as they want to
federated social platforms are not Discord
is not Telegram is not so if somebody like
Mohammed's going to come on there and not
provide proper discourse, not have
conversations, but have agendas to fud or
do anything like this, you bet your ass
the owner of those federated systems is
going to hold them accountable for the
guidelines of the chats and they're going
to be kicked out. be prepared for that
folks we had a prominent member of the
ecosystem that was kicked out for their
behavior a couple weeks ago and it still
does not ring well with them and they just
cannot understand the difference between
open systems and federated systems which
is really funny because of what they were
working on so if you if you don't like the
Ergo chats if you don't like You know,
being held to community rules, which I
will say are so much looser than any other
crypto chats I've been in ever. Ergo
allows so much fud as a form of discourse
going in there, right? I mean, you've been
in there, Dan, right? Like people are
allowed to speak their mind and we chat
about it and we like challenges. So you're
already at a very loose space in a
federated chat with community guidelines.
Just be aware of that, guys. Was that
prominent community member you, qx()?
No, I won't mention a name. The
Sigmanauts know we were discussing it the
other day.
Okay. Well, it's probably you. Yes. But
anyway, let's get to maybe one or two real
questions before we sign off for the
evening. Let's see. Oh, and sub-blocks,
you know?
Oh, is that Pulsar? Pulsar, it's so good
to see you. Pulsar's been busy in real
life, so it's nice to have him pop in
here. Soon, Pulsar. So the epics are out
of the way. The voting has been done, I
think, on testnet to get that node there.
So that was a holdup with what they're
testing on. So more testing there. I guess
we're at that stage from what we were
waiting on a while ago. So soon. It's
moving, Pulsar. It's moving. Maybe you
should help kushti Pulsar. Pulsar is an
expert in, I think it's C sharp, is it? I
can't remember, but he rewrote He rewrote
FleetSDK to FleetSharp so that there's
more options of programming against Ergo
libraries, which is fantastic. Pulsar,
you're my hero. All right, next question.
Okay, we got one from Wendy Moon. Do you
think it would make sense to promote Ergo
platforms to non-crypto folks using
terminology other than crypto? because
every person is losing trust in crypto
thanks to meme scams. So, okay, well, let
me just throw kind of like my 25 cents of
thing in here, and then you can follow up
on the qx(), because-
Oh, I will. I'll follow up, Dan.
Yeah, you just keep talking and talking.
Anyway, so my feeling and this is not just
for Ergo I think you know the same thing
comes up in Cardano as well and others
like when marketing when marketing when
you know when mainstream marketing and
it's like well okay okay so who and i
think i actually spoke about this before
who knows who underwriter laboratories are
you will Now, if you're an electronics
person, you know exactly what I'm talking
about, but the average consumer, you guys
who are the average consumer of
electronics, do you know who underwriter
laboratories are? You will.
Another global safety science company
with more than a century of expertise
innovating safety solutions.
They are, but that's the thing. The
average electronic consumer does not know
what UL is, but UL is like one of the
backbones of electronic safety in the US,
and possibly the world, and have been for
over a century. And why do you not hear
about the UL? Because the UL provides a
very, very needed and robust function that
other products can be built on or built
against or be benchmarked against. And so
while you don't, as a, I mean, they try to
like promote them like back in the day, I
think. And in fact, if you look on your
electronics somewhere, you're gonna see
the UL logo. But for the main part, you're
not gonna be buying like a Sony TV and
somebody's gonna say, oh, well, this is UL
approved. But Sony is not going to ask UL
to market their TV for them. They're going
to use UL technology to create a better TV
and then market it themselves. So that's
what I think personally and as a business
owner and as somebody who's building on
Ergo and Cardano, I think that it's
actually the project responsibility to
promote their product versus the ecosystem
kind of trying to push them as a project
in the ecosystem. Of course, The support
is greatly appreciated and is needed to
sometimes kind of invigorate the ecosystem
or prop it up. But I really think that...
it should be up to the project. You know,
the project, individual projects building
on Ergo should be out there promoting and
talking to the non-crypto people because
those are going to be their users. Just
like what we're doing with Palmyra, you
know, I mean, we don't really talk too
much about Winter Protocol, which runs on
Ergo. We talk about the utility, you know,
and when Theodore, our head of business
development went to Greece a couple of
months ago, He had zero conversations
about Ergo there. Zero. He had zero
conversations about technology there. He
just, well, I mean, he had, but I mean,
what's under the hood type of technology
conversations. What he spoke about is the
solution. You know, the solution that will
help these guys be able to export their
olive oil and get a better profit on their
olive oil. And yeah, under the hood, it
uses blockchain, it uses Ergo. But in the
end, the solution is what we offered them.
And nobody had any questions. Nobody was
asking. Oh, well, wait a second. How does
the blockchain do stuff here? It's like,
well, they don't care. They just know that
they can use this thing is going to make
their lives easier. They're going to make
more money. That's it. So, yes, I mean,
that's what I think. And like I said, I'm
not saying that the ecosystem should not
be doing some sort of a advertising type
of thing if there are funds and if that
ecosystem is actually designed for that
because some are not. Some are just
designed to be kind of like the tool chest
to build on. but, yeah, but I think, I
think if I think that like mainly it's
just basically, projects responsibility to
promote the solution that they created. So
that's, that's what I think. What do you,
what do you think qx()?
You are muted.
How did that happen?
That happened when you press the mute
button.
Oh, is that what that does? Oh my
goodness. So what I was lip syncing
earlier is that the Ergo Foundation has
been doing this for a long time, right?
They've been promoting a grassroots
approach of here's a tool, here's how it
works, here's what you can use it for,
here's how you can also build, here's some
code you can learn, all that kind of
stuff. So when I parse this out with
current times, I'm thinking that when a
lot of people say marketing and getting
Ergo out there, Who do they mean that
we're trying to get it to? Are we trying
to get it to people that are going to buy
and sell, buy low, sell high, and just
price speculate? Or are you talking about,
let's get it out there like things like
Dan's doing, things like I'm doing with my
students, things like other people are
doing where you're using utility to make
something and have people use that thing.
And yeah, they may know that it's Ergo,
they may not, but you're using the
product. We specifically went with
Tipperbot at Cornell because I'm not going
to sit there and try to explain to people
what a wallet is, how to use it. You know,
a thousand students, I'm not going to sit
there and say, here's how you do this,
here's how you do that. Instead, it's just
like, Here's what we're doing. If you want
a free plot then sign up for this and
you'll get tipped and you'll go from
there. So building systems around Ergo
that people don't necessarily have to
know. So I think Ergo Foundation's been
doing that and that's what a lot of people
don't like because they want the other
type of marketing which is let's get
people in here to just buy and not
utilize. So it's I don't know, Dan. It's
tough. You definitely need a... Those are
two different teams, right? There's a team
for that and then there's a team for what
the EF has been doing as far as promoting
utility and usage of the chain. So I don't
really have a better answer than what I
just spouted.
I think that's fair. That's a fair
answer. Like I said, some ecosystems are
not... They're not VC ecosystems where
it's just basically, it's really not about
the tooling as much as it is about pumping
the price and having the Silicon Valley
approach to marketing that we're trying to
get away in a way. And so yeah, so these
guys are gonna pump the price and they're
gonna they're gonna fill their ecosystem
with bullshit and but it's gonna be big,
you know Yeah, a lot of these guys are
pumping first utility later, right?
That's like let's let's get the money in
and we'll figure out how to fix issues
Ergo wasn't born like that.
Ergo was born with the utility, you know,
so we can't expect it to become that now,
like I said, I'm not diminishing the need
for exposure. Correct. But we have to
understand.
We just need to be conscious of what
we're looking for, how we go about it.
That's exactly it. Who are we advertising
it to? Now, Wendy Moon was talking about
not crypto people. Okay, that's good. But
like I said, that, I feel, is more of a
project responsibility than, say, the
foundation. but yeah, if you're talking
about tooling, then yeah, that's, that's
something that you want to market to maybe
developers, you know, obviously, or
somebody's, you know, somebody's designing
a project. And again, that's a different
type of marketing.
Well, my 17 year old child wrote me two
days ago when they were at school and
said, hey dad, thanks for being terrible.
Well, they didn't say that, just kidding.
They said, they've been speaking to me off
and on about their economics teacher who
is very anti-crypto, right? So the the
economics teacher is giving the same old
tired arguments of oh It's money from
nothing and there's no value and it's a
bunch of scams Okay, I get it. You know,
those are the things that we get from
those kind of uninformed people So they're
asking a question they send a bunch of
texts from an email right up that the
person economics professor did about their
latest chapter and about crypto, so I gave
it a nice rebuttal and just you know with
those kind of things it's simple it's like
you talk about what putting a value what
it means to create a financial system
right and how how's gold or dollar you
know any different in value putting in
besides it's propping up markets right now
right that's the only thing they have but
initially we people put value on objects
or things or or or monies right same with
crypto and then explaining to them that
The proof of work crypto actually takes a
conversion of energy to create a store of
value as well. And then I got into a brief
discussion with them about inflationary
measures, right? And how if there's an
issue in the US, we just turn on the
printing machine and print more dollars to
pay for it. thus increasing prices across
the board for everything. And not just
naturally increase. When large
corporations see inflation going right,
they jack their prices up before it even
happens. It's like this preemptive thing
of an excuse to jack up your prices. So
it's all like some snowball avalanche
effect. So spoke about that, and my child
was actually ill. That kind of makes
sense. So I forgot to write, but I was
going to say, hey, if you want somebody to
come in and and debate with him in class
about it and chat about what they might be
happy to. I think that'd be a lot of fun.
But so that brings me hope that the young
generation at least can be like, oh, you
know, that does kind of seem stupid that
we just continue to print our own money,
you know, out of thin air. And then people
say that crypto has no real value.
You're like, OK, you're well, it's
basically like you said, it's basically
people don't understand the core concept
of why money has value. You know why yeah,
I'd have value any kind of perceived value
So that's that's definitely You know,
that's definitely a big deal because it's
just not that's it comes from lack of
understanding of their own, you know field
of expertise but anyway, Speaking to Wendy
one last time then I I think with Ergo and
with any chain that has utility, you're
going to see adoption by everyday people,
by things like Dan. Maybe there are even
services that are centralized that are
using decentralized tools. You could
create a service that Is it like right we
have like last pass right it stores all of
your freaking passwords all in their
security enclave? And you just know your
one big password things like that could
exist for Ergo for multiple wallets and
exchanges and things like that or any
crypto You know nothing I would use the
hell that I'm gonna put my seed phrase on
some server the only place my seed phrase
is public is Luis Vatra's tipper bot right
that's the only place that my seed phrase
exists online for the Tipperbot wallet.
But other people may be comfortable doing
that. They might want that security. And
with that cost comes an extra cost,
perhaps. And then with that comes like
insurance for, you know, scams that they
go through. So all this kind of stuff can
be built on top of what we have already on
Ergo or any other chain that takes utility
and actually building seriously. So we'll
get there, Wendy. I think we'll get there.
Yeah.
We will we will all right well, I need to
wrap it up for today cuz actually I got
another it's only like 11 o'clock Dan
Yeah, but I got I get a I get a space
Coming up time how long?
Pretty soon and before that I have to do
stuff.
Oh Honey, do this all right. What else do
we have any other questions in here real
quick?
Let's see
Nothing that can't be asked in chat. Oh,
we got a brand new segment. Oh, here we
go. Hi, brand new segment out here.
Welcome Rich. What is my best way to, what
is my best bet? Present my ideas, but
protect my IP. I'm looking to meet and
safely give my team ideas slash work. Do
you mean an Ergo Rich? So it's,
Yeah, that's a tough question. So, you
know, Ergo embraces open source, but we
also have a mix of open source and closed
source. You'll find a lot like people will
write smart contracts that are open
source, right? So like Spectrum, like
MewFinance, like DuckPools, right?
Contracts are open source. But then they
closed source their UI, which is their
unique blend of that kind of thing. So I
would say if that's what you're asking,
you can do, and you still want to be as
open source as you can in the Ergo
ecosystem, You if you're closing anything
off you need to provide innovation in that
closeness, right? So let's say you create
a tool or tooling the open source of
contracts and you have some whiz bang UI
that you're hosting it costs resources to
host and You're doing that but then
perhaps you can also offer some you know
open source version of that earlier
version beta UI that can be on on GitHub
that somebody could download and run your
app themselves without having to rely on
your web server. So there's blends of that
kind of thing. But it is a tough question,
Dan, right? How do you protect your IP
when we're in a fully open source place
where anybody could take your stuff and
run with it and do better than you at it?
It's a tough one. Overall, it makes the
space better. It does. But there are ways,
Rich, that you can still, I mean, closed
stuff in Ergo isn't shunned. You know,
people, it's just about expectations. And
what's the word I'm looking for?
Trade-offs.
Trade-offs. It's all about trade-offs.
Yeah, trade-offs. But be transparent
about it, Rich. If you're building
something and you publish some of it and
you don't publish the other stuff, don't
hide it. Say this is what we're doing. We
feel this early on if we release our UI to
everybody, somebody can easily take over
and blow all the hard work we've done. So
we're going to keep our UI private until
version 3 then maybe open source version 1
UI on top of the open source smart
contracts that we've done in two years or
something like that so there's definitely
options out there and like I say before
With Ergo, at least, with things like
Nautilus, I can interact with closed
source systems like closed source UIs. And
I can still see everything that's going
on. I can look at that information in the
advanced mode in Nautilus. And I can see,
OK, here are all my outputs. Here are all
my inputs. And I'll see what's going on.
So even when interacting with those kind
of things, still as the user, I have other
tools that allow me to exactly see if I'm
going to be scammed or messed with or
anything like that. All right, Dan.
Agreed. All right. Well. Are we good?
We're good, Dan. We're good. I mean, you
came 15 minutes late, and we're leaving
five minutes early from that. So you owe
us five minutes in some other time. So you
got to make it up.
I'll do it in some other time. I'll do it
at IHOP.
That sounds good, Dan. I'll give you an
extra five minutes at IHOP.
Speaking of IHOP, their competitor,
Waffle House, is charging $0.30 extra an
egg. Or is it $0.50 extra an egg? Would
IHOP ever do that, Dan?
IHOP not.
That's clever. Good way to end it.
Everybody, have a great week. Thanks for
joining us.
Thanks a lot, everyone. See you next
week.