Hey.
Hello everyone.
My pleasure to be here again.
And today, well, there are three of us.
So we have mgPai again.
Hey, everyone.
Nice to be on again.
It's great to be here with you, mgPai.
I've missed you a lot.
Oh, is that the case?
All right.
Where's your TMG pie?
Oh, I mean, I just we all have nothing in
my hands.
You just woke up at nine o'clock, sir.
Are you OK?
I'm not OK. Nice.
All right.
So what's new, kushti?
You've been busy, real busy.
You know you will be safe let's say. All
right so yeah a lot of things going on so
well fixing some issues with 6.0 as yeah
Dusek is doing well quite awesome audit so
finally some good quality audit is coming.
So, yeah, well, fixing issues being
found.
Then, yeah, so for sub-blocks, yeah,
working on, well, prototype implementation
of, well, blocks generation, so, well,
spreading transactions.
Input blocks and so on.
So maybe next week even I will have some
demo for local DevNets, well local miner
based I mean because yes stratum is not
ready stratum proxy and so on.
So well that's just initial prototype
local miner based.
Then what else?
So, yeah, well, and gentlemen, as you are
probably both mining in the testnet and
only you, right, then, yeah, let's
consider a 6.0 activation date in the
testnet.
So, yeah, maybe by tomorrow so that there
is one issue how to be fixed and then yeah
we can do another release candidate 6.0
release candidate with public testnet
activation details and well yeah testnet
has some custom soft fork activation
parameters so that means we can have
activation quite soon then and then yeah
well audit to be continued so I've started
a raffle actually well to raise some funds
for rewarding Dusek and then yeah well
with audits done, and I also will recheck
everything a few more times, and then we
can think about watching mainnet
activation, maybe starting from March,
something like that.
So, yeah, a lot of things going on.
Also, well, Dexy Gold audit is done, so
all the 18 contracts reviewed.
And, yeah, so currently, well, the issue
is too, well, Polish backend.
And then, yeah, well, consider how
front-end would like and who will work on
that.
So, well, maybe and hopefully and already
pre-confirmed that C8 will do UI.
Yeah, well, other options are not so
viable at the moment.
I'm also pushing guys to start a new
SigmaUSD Oracle Pool version 2 based.
For Oracle Pool updates, I finished the
code to produce needed transactions.
I'm going to test in the testnet and then
we can consider how to update the mainnet
pool.
So yeah, a lot of things going on in
parallel.
Also, there are some talks going on
within I think to propose actually some
things in regards with reworking things
based on experience I've got from ErgoDevs
as well as other organizations we have in
the community such as Sigmanauts, Ergo
Foundation and so on.
And yeah, well, posted recently, well,
Core Track roadmap based on my own
observations and also feedback got from
other developers.
And yeah, thinking to do that for other
tracks, well, we need to consider what to
do with pools, so trying to get from
Palmyra what they're planning to do with
Lithos Protocol and so on.
Then yeah there is need to get well
information from Oracle Pools so I'm
pushing guys to do there so yeah well a
lot of mess there yeah big because it's
not so you know centralized shitcoin with
team I mean all that's bizarre.
Yeah, we have different scams basically.
But yeah, you know if you want to
coordinate and well, even get a picture
from what's going on, that's complicated.
And that should be complicated, I guess.
That's the point of having a normal
community, not stimulated one like
shitcoins are doing with, well, sponsoring
mercenaries and so on.
All right. What's on your end, guys?
I think mgPai should go next.
Yeah, sure.
So let's see.
So over the last, I think, few months or
so since I've been on here, I haven't had
too many updates.
But one thing I've been discussing with a
few members in the development community
is the standardization of off-chain bots
and framework.
I think that's quite important, because
for those of you who don't know, off-chain
bots are needed to process transactions
that go through more complex smart
contracts, such as your DEX transactions,
NFT marketplace transactions, or certain
ones, and then DuckPools.
They all use these off-chain bot
executors, and the problem with them and
they're more specific.
They're all specific to UTXO blockchains.
And the problem with them development
wise is that it takes a lot of time,
effort, research and work to actually have
one running.
That's why development on these chains
just takes so long compared to something
like EVM, where you don't need any of it.
Of course, the downsides of not having an
EVM, right?
It might make development experience
better, but it makes the blockchain much
heavier and have a lot of bloat and all,
and you can't run a node as easily.
So the problem on Ergo, and frankly on
Cardano as well, is that there's no
standardization of this.
As a developer, you just got to do
everything from scratch, build everything.
And everyone has their own way.
I looked at DuckPools' code.
It's in Python.
And they're using some node API to write
everything.
Then Spectrum is on the other end, where
it's a very complex and heavy code base.
Then my own framework is also different
compared to how both of them do it.
I would like to think it's in the middle
between the complexity of DuckPools and
Spectrum.
And then everyone just has their own way.
And we kind of got to fix this.
And recently, Fleet SDK, the JavaScript
framework for building Ergo, has been
getting really good.
It's supporting a lot of things that were
needed from the Java and the Ergo AppKit.
So recently I've been playing around with
that and experimenting with writing my own
off-chain in a different language, in
TypeScript, and it's going pretty well.
There's not many bottlenecks left.
So I think that's the next step for
developers or the DevDAO is to create a
standardized framework for off-chain,
maybe record a few videos and have some
good documentation on how to go about it.
Like maybe kushti was mentioning that
Dexy Gold is coming up, the audit is going
well, the UI is in progress by C8.
So maybe it'd be a good framework or a
good opportunity to demonstrate how
off-chain works by maybe writing it in
Fleet SDK using or to execute Dexy Gold
transactions.
And another thing is that I've been doing
over the past almost year is learning a
new language called Go.
And the benefits of this language is that
it's very good for concurrent
applications.
So it just processes things more
efficiently, or it's easier for developers
to process things more efficiently.
So, you know, we have another community
member, the guy who's doing the Keystone
integration, PG, and he's working on a Go
library for Ergo, right?
So the development and it's like almost
like it's almost good, you know, just a
few more issues.
But the development of this would be also
nice because Go is a really good language
to do this in, to do off-chain.
And so we're really looking forward to
that.
So, you know, as time goes on, the
development experience is looking really
good for Ergo.
We're getting more and more tools at hand
to attract a diverse set of skills.
So I think that's also the next frontier,
along with kushti doing his own updates on
the node.
That's just fantastic, mgPai.
I love your hat.
Where'd you get your hat from?
Yeah, this is actually some new merch I
got from Crypto Chips.
I was talking to the founder of Crypto
Chips.
I'm like, hey, we need some Ergo hats and
all going.
So he sent me a good nice prototype of
what he can achieve so the community might
see this drop in the future.
You're extorting free swag from
suppliers.
I'm prototyping here.
That's awesome.
Well, speaking of swag, I put up an
announcement last week.