Hey everyone, how's it going?
Hello, welcome everybody.
Hi kushti, how you doing?
Doing well, how about you?
I'm hanging in there, still nursing off
whatever I had a couple weeks ago, but
maybe someday it'll get rid of it.
Crazy. So it's lasted this long.
You managed to not get sick this winter?
Sorry?
You managed to keep from getting sick
this winter, kushti?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, so still, yeah. I'm
totally fine. And yeah, I even have a lot
of power during the winter.
So how's about your Sigmanauts power?
Sigmanauts power.
It's been slow burn this semester, I
guess, this start of the quarter. I've
been doing a lot of focusing outside of
that on my Cornell stuff.
What's today? Today's Thursday? So we
didn't have the show. Yeah, so we had the
show last week and I got some good ideas
on how to help that BRICK economy get
going.
And the idea was that people were seeing
our show and they're like, hey, why does
this blockchain recycling have to stop
after the show is over? And I was like,
well, it doesn't. I said we could set this
up upstairs in our IT place.
And then another idea came that what
could facilitate more value pointed
towards BRICKs, Cornell BRICK. And the
idea is, okay, we can blend the two.
So instead of students throwing out their
massive amounts of paper after they're
done critiquing, you know, we're talking
four or five huge, like 42 by 60 inch
print outs, we can have a large bin in our
area and every time a student brings one
of those plots to recycle after they're
done with it, we can hand them off like
ten BRICK or five BRICK or fifteen BRICK.
So this will not only encourage students
to bring their plots back and actually
recycle them instead of throwing them in
the garbage or letting them fall on the
floor and the custodial staff takes care
of them in the garbage. But it'll also put
an even bigger system of value in place
for the BRICK in that it's a reward token
for recycling your plot.
which you can then use after probably,
we're thinking maybe every six or seven
plots recycled, you'll generate enough
BRICK to print another plot for free. So
there's incentive for kids to actually
recycle them and get that BRICK in turn
for value to then put it back into the
system and plot with it.
So that's our next step in doing that.
I've been thoroughly testing my system set
up and it's been running well for me
printing from it with blockchain payments.
So that part's ready to go.
So once we get that bin set up, we'll
start that and get going. It's going to be
interesting. A lot of kids are excited. So
we'll see.
Yeah. That's actually quite amazing. So I
thought actually, well, I've been thinking
actually, well, for many years about, you
know, creating monetary systems where
money created, you know, when people,
well, recycling wastes, you know, doing,
well, positive things like trees planting,
reforestation, stuff like that.
Yeah, and well, it could be more useful
than those carbon credits, right? Yeah,
there are two tokens, so carbon credits
and there is also debit token, I believe,
carbon credits.
From what I know about that system, it's
usually not about carbon at all in the
real world. Usually those credits are
being used to cover many holes different
agencies like UN agencies have.
In general, from what I know, that system
is not working well. It's possible to
design high belief systems in bottom-up
fashion, which will work better. Well, a
way to emit new money, right, when
students are bringing plots to be reused.
So, yeah, it's quite exciting, actually,
experiment.
Exactly. Try to create some sort of local
incentive that really has a direct effect
on the students and I mean honestly these
students may somewhat care about recycling
but you know they don't have time for it
it's not at the top of their mind but if
you provide some sort of incentive
directly to them where the effort is low
too they simply have to just walk 50 feet
over to our office and dump a plot in a
bin and then we tip them the BRICK, I
mean, that's going to be some very simple
incentive to do this kind of stuff.
So yeah, super excited about that. We'll
see how they respond to that. My guess is,
you know, Cornell is like many Ivy
schools, there's a lot of cash tuition
students, I imagine. So you'll have a mix
of students who just don't give a crap.
And then you'll have a mix of students who
will be like, you don't care? Give me your
plot. I'll recycle it for you. And they
take the BRICK out of it.
So I think you'll see a lot of that. So
you'll get this active cleanup of people
who want free plots walking around the 350
student studio and being like, hey, are
you done with that? Can I recycle that?
You know, that kind of thing. So it'll be
an interesting economy there.
I'm really interested to see how it's
going to play out. And then they were also
talking about yeah, what if I leave or
what if I no longer have to do plots this
semester or, you know, what if there's no
value in the token that's valuable to me?
And then the kids were like, oh, you
know, I'll give you, you give me your
tokens and I'll buy you some coffee or
I'll buy you lunch at the restaurant
downstairs or that kind of thing. So those
are neat swaps that could be happening
too.
Yeah, that's quite amazing. Comparing
with other ways to emit new money we have
in the crypto space. For example,
airdrops. Usually airdrops is when you're
just rewarding people for creating
accounts, right?
And social media wealth and you are
basically basically incentivizing spam,
right? So creating spam accounts and
Facebook, social media to get more airdrop
tokens.
But here you have some real and positive
way, right? And while it's still based on
a trusted party like an airdrop, but yeah,
at least you know, well, distribution has
some antecedent mechanism and you also
will bring in a positive impact in return,
right, like waste recycling.
That's actually quite awesome. And have
you announced the community chats we will
have?
No, let me do that today. Why don't you
announce it in person right here and then
we'll announce it on Twitter later.
Yeah, but so what's the time? Is it 3 or
4 p.m.? I propose both times. Let's pick
one.
That's UTC proposed?
Yeah, yeah, so 4 p.m. UTC maybe.
Yeah, that's beautiful. Yeah, that works.
All right, so next Tuesday will be
February 4th. Yeah, so let's meet our
community town hall and discuss different
well, monetary innovation aspects we have
in the Ergo Core protocol and the
ecosystem.
And, well, not just dApps, but maybe
things like BRICKs would be good to get
more insights on that actually. But yeah,
we will also discuss storage rent for
sure, then algorithmic monetary policies,
well, emission reduction and possible
effects, right?
So if we are talking about the native
cryptocurrency, then yeah, we can discuss
custom emission contracts, FIMO, miners
rights protocol. So all those things.
We can talk a little bit about the
storage rent too. Let's bring that to the
front of the picture too. Cause I think as
of now, it's still just Sigmanauts pool
doing it and a few independent devs doing
some sniping as well So it'd be nice to
get that word spread out more I'll try to
maybe I'll invite the DX pool guys have
them announce it in their channel as well
as others
Recently, Sigmanauts collected some good
amounts of ERGs, like 14 ERGs.
I didn't see that one, but yeah, there's
been times where we've had two or three
ERGs in one shot in the storage rent pool.
It's pretty impressive. Five, I think, was
the one that I noticed a couple of weeks
ago.
Yeah, super cool, super impressive that
that happens. I don't think people
realize. Because we're on the Ergo how
amazing that is but if you get somebody on
another chain I bet, well that's tough too
because Bitcoin maxis are like, oh, it's
great that coins are lost, right? They're
like that's beneficial to the system So it
is a little tough sell to those guys, but
I think it's amazing
Yeah, but yeah, well, there are some
heated talks in the Bitcoin community as
well, right? So it would be good to get
Bitcoiners joining discussions as well.
Yeah, so some good tokens got storage
rented recently as well. I've seen that
one of the earliest Ergo Lore series NFTs
got collected and then burned something
like that.
So there was some interesting story. I
don't know, maybe accidentally burnt. So,
well, that's also interesting question,
right? So what are the burning practices
in storage rent? And yeah, actually, it's
quite interesting because, well, every
party which is collecting so Sigmanauts of
those individual snipers so that they can
use different strategies, right? That's
quite funny.
So briefly, chat on that, kushti. So
there was an early conception, an early
idea that miners were the only ones that
were allowed to recreate boxes, right? But
you had mentioned in an AMA at one point
that that's not entirely true at this
point anymore.
And now anybody can try to include the
transaction in a block. It's up to the
miners to include it or not, but anybody
can take any of the storage rent if they
get their transaction picked up in the
block. Is that true?
Oh, it's actually how it was designed
since day one, right? So, well, no need to
log to minerspubkey or whatever. Well,
miners always can reshuffle transactions,
right? So, well, if some sniper dev is
collecting storage rent. So, supposedly,
if miners are not lazy, they will just
throw away such transactions from the
block, right, and replace with own storage
rent.
It's in some theory, right, where miners
are well behaving rationally, right, so
maximizing their profits. And what we have
in practice, some miners are well a little
bit weird, right, mostly. So they're not
maximizing their profits even, which is
quite counterintuitive.
Right, right. So this storage rent was
kind of designed in mind that, yeah, once
it was able to be active, you'll get the
pools to pick it up. But we're kind of in
a limbo state right now where not all the
pools are picking it up yet.
And devs have the ability, or anybody
that can write that code has the ability
to snipe themselves the storage rent if
they want to. In an ideal scenario, and I
imagine how you designed it, was that once
every pool is on storage rent, the dev
snipers don't matter because the mining
pools will just replace those sniper TXs
with their own TXs to claim storage rent
in the blocks they find.
Right. And well, eventually we will get
to that stage, right?
Interesting transition stage, though.
Yeah, so when emission would be low, like
three ERGs per block, right, so there will
be a lot of incentive, right, to collect
storage rent. So not to be lazy about
additional source of income.
But speaking of storage rent.
Did you just say transaction?
Yeah, but you also said it's lazy. You
didn't say transaction. You said
transaction. What's a transaction QX?
That's a new term. It's a quantum based
transaction.
Yeah, no no kushti didn't say you said
it.
Oh, I said it. I can't speak I've got
like a pound of like whatever in my face I
can't speak at all.
I got a pound of New York.
Yeah, I got a pound of New York Well
speaking of storage rent kushti there's
$20,000 worth of liquidity in the ERG/PHP
token that was picked up by storage rent
the first Big big pull for the whole PHP
token so 20 grand of liquidity. I think
that's pretty damn amazing.
All right, so wait, so basically 20k USD
worth of value are now because of, well,
basically digital waste recycling, right?
Yeah, exactly, exactly.
That's quite fine. I mean, that's the
whole new dimension in the understanding
of blockchain economic protocols maybe,
right? So when you can get new value from
recycling digital waste basically on the
blockchain. That's very funny actually.
I mean, it's a narrative, right? Only on
the Ergo. Really cool.
Yeah, so, well, actually, it's quite
strange even, right? So, well, Ergo was
launched back in 2019 and still it's the
only blockchain with storage rent, right?
well, generic sigma protocols language,
right? So, the ability to create
cryptographic protocols as applications,
right? Variety of cryptographic protocols
and so on.
So, yeah, well, it's even strange that no
one is copying that, but maybe because the
time is a bit different now, it's not 2015
anymore, so people are just, well, those
days are doing somewhat, I don't know, new
BFT protocols and then trying to will
present them as proof of stake like I
don't know Cardano's you know proof of
stake so like no normal proof of stake but
yeah actually it's just BFT under the hood
so well more centralized consensus
protocol obviously and then yeah they just
have EVM on top of so well it's now about
like 100 chains which are pretty
indistinguishable to me.
So what's varying there is a set of
venture capital funds backing those
protocols. That's the most differentiating
part usually those days.
Talking about miners, Dan, how are
lithium miners doing? Different kind of
miners. Any news from your side, from
real-world mining?
Our partners, the ones that we're
building the lithium index with, one of
them is actually, I guess, in whatever
it's called, well, the circle, so the
circle to be picked as the mining
secretary for Argentina.
So just like with all appointments,
there's several leading candidates, and
then one of them gets appointed. So he's a
leading candidate to get appointed to the
mining secretary of Argentina. So we're
definitely going to be into mining big
time.
Yeah. And so, yeah, we're actually
connecting with other lithium pricing
source providers because we're trying to
build out an Oracle network to supply all
these different prices for the lithium
index. So, yeah, we're making connections
to other mining organizations and
companies and widening out our network.
So yeah, we're quite a lot of mining
happening in a literal sense. And yeah,
and actually, I was telling QX that our
Biz Dev lead in Buenos Aires is... My
Argentinian friends keep telling me how to
say it right now. I was Americanized it
too much.
So he is an Ergo fan and so our partner,
one of our partners from Buenos Aires,
they run an on-chain payment network, and
of course, you know, legacy and on-chain
payment network.
And these guys have, and I think I told
you, QX, about this. I'm pretty sure I
did. In fact, I'm positive I did. They got
a huge mining farm for Bitcoin.
And so they wanted to actually know what
can be done with Ergo if they were going
to turn that on to Ergo. But the problem
is that the bulk of it is ASIC.
Yeah, so that's the problem. They have
some video card, just strictly video
card-based miners, but the bulk of it is
ASICs. So we're trying to figure it out.
We're going to see what can be done with
the ones that are not ASICs, which could
still help, help secure the network. But
it would be really nice if we could turn
on the bulk of these things. But the bulk
of these things, yeah. Unfortunately
they're ASICs, but well, we'll see what we
can do so They're gonna sell them for GPUs
and I'll let him know that Just take like
a 30% hit no big deal They got like some
insane amount of hash like hash rate
happening with all those ASICs like it's
told me I was like, holy shit.
I mean it's It's one of the largest ones
in Argentina, I think.
Do they have hydro nearby?
Well, so even hydroelectric? Yes. Yeah,
actually, there's quite a bit of
hydroelectric in Argentina. In fact, I
think that there are, I've heard, I
haven't actually seen them, but I've heard
that there are hydro-powered miners in
Argentina for Bitcoin.
So I, you know, I'm also going to
research that, see what we can do for
Ergo. There's quite a bit, you know,
because Argentina is, is like very, like
adaptive now to try and get, try to get
into the opportunities that they have now,
because it just really opened up after you
know, decades of corruption, and then, you
know, just literally like I think Milei is
literally the first guy who really kind of
opened up Argentina.
And so now they're just opening up,
they're like, oh, wait, wait, we got all
this opportunity now. Okay, so what can we
do? And so of course, the first thing
they're doing is jumping into a bunch of
Bitcoin stuff. But we will, you know, I'll
see what I can do to guide them in the
right direction, so to speak.
Maybe we'll send QX out there in his
poncho and they'll think he's local.
No, that's perfect. Lucy and I can go
down and I'll wear my poncho. She can wear
her poncho.
You know the thing about Argentina, I
know it's kind of a duh, but like, you go
to Argentina, and you know it's big on the
map, but you don't realize how big it is.
It's freaking big, man. There's a lot of
Argentina.
I took so many plane rides, all these
different provinces. And actually, yeah, I
think actually in Cordoba, there could be
some hydroelectric opportunities. Also, I
think I might have something, so we do
have some connections there that I can tap
into if you have something in mind for
some hydro-powered mining stuff.
Well, for ASICs, we'd have to wait for
some sort of sidechain, right?
I'm not saying all of them are ASICs,
just this one partner of ours has a huge
amount of ASIC rigs. And so I was trying
to, because they were really interested in
mining Ergo, but then they gave me the
configurations and I'm like, oh, wait a
second, yeah, that's not going to work.
It's not going to work here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. So there's going to be
something, you know, I mean, like I said,
they're very, very open to opportunity
over there, so.
Dan, I saw you repping Ergo with your
Ergo sweatshirt on your talk with Charles
Hoskinson.
How'd that go?
Hoskinson? Who's that?
I don't even know his last name. I don't
pay attention to that crap.
What's his last name? Is it like
Rubenstein or something? What is it?
How'd you guess? How'd you guess?
Oh, Hoskinson?
There you go. How'd that go? You repped
Ergo? You had your shirt out that you
stole from us?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Some weirdo gave me
that t-shirt, or gave me that sweatshirt,
and I kind of like it. So yeah, I thought
I'd rep Ergo. I was kind of thinking. I'm
like, hmm, well, this is the Cardano
founder. But then I'm like, oh yeah, but
he's also an Ergo guy too, so it's cool.
And yeah, I just, you know.
It worked out but yeah Do I wear the
t-shirt with soy sauce stains on it or do
I wear the Ergo shirt?
It was a tough choice That is that is
pretty racist you think because I live in
Asia I'll have soy sauce stains on my
shirt That's just you've been canceled QX.
I just can't do it Andy Andy cut his feet
cut his feet Andy
So how was the, how was your presale? I
saw you announced round two.
Well, so, so like, you know, with
Charles, the talk with Charles is really
good. We actually mentioned, Oh, thank
you. Thank you. Oh, damn, he's back.
Anyway, yeah, so we actually did talk
about Ergo a bit. And so there's, you
know, it's just very interesting because,
you know, Charles is kind of into partner
change right now. So he's kind of, you
know, multi-chaining, multi-chain surfing
right now.
Yeah, yeah, the pre-sale is doing really
good. Yeah, we're in phase three now, so
phase one and two is done. Phase three is
going, and yeah, I mean, we got everything
lined up. We're going to go TGE next
month.
Got some RSV that came in through the
pre-sale. Because we, you know, like, are
basically, you can participate in the
pre-sale with RSV, ADA, USDM, and that's
it, I think. And maybe there's something,
one more.
But anyway, oh, and of course, you know,
we got Pyro on our team now. I don't know
if you know this or not, but Pyro has
joined our team a couple of months ago.
So, we are now, four, out of, well, five
actually, cause Sam was also an Ergonaut.
So, out of a team of 20 that are Ergo
peeps, we got Luca, we got Shashir, you
know, and we got, yeah.
Oh, oh, and, Rob just joined the team as
well.
Wait, Rob, Rob, Rob.
No rob, i'm gonna butcher them Luivatra
You stole Luivatra.
Yeah. Yeah, he's mine now gosh in the
back You done Luivatra there goes Paideia
Yeah, yeah, we're gonna have to hire
somebody for Paideia To the clutches of
Palmyra
Yeah. So yeah, yeah. He's working with us
now as well. So we got, yeah, we got
Luivatra. We got me, Sam, Shashir, Luca,
Pyro. So it's like the Ergo All-Stars. I
mean, Alex is advising us.
The only one that's left out with no
chair when the music stops is QX. What's
up there?
I figured that was intentional, Dan. I
figured it was intentional.
So I think that's a feature, not a bug.
I think it's great that you're, you know,
cause one of the things you notice in, at
least in the bear market, we noticed that,
you know, devs need to eat something,
right? It's people like mgPai going to
school, they need some sort of sustenance
to be able to survive.
And the fact that, at least Palmyra right
now can provide who's Ergo, who's part of
Ergo, part of Cardano. who can provide
these devs with some sort of sustenance so
that they can survive on chain and
continue to be here is fantastic.
I like to have a pool of talent I can
pull from. It's people that I know, people
that I can trust. For me, right now, it
would be a pain to go through the entire
process. I'd rather actually work with
somebody I know. Ergo's got oodles of
amazing devs and builders in the
ecosystem, so that's why we're working
with the ecosystem. It only makes sense.
Well, kushti, we didn't hear what's new
from you.
A lot of things. But yeah, there was
intense chats, the developers chat
yesterday, as usually. So yeah, well,
sub-blocks implementation is going well.
So yeah, I made some API methods even. So
now I'm checking how things are
progressing well with some API methods.
Then, yeah, well, all the issues found in
6.0 are fixed. So I'm going for public
testnet release. So, well, looking, trying
to find who is mining in the testnet. It
seems it is you, right? Only if it's you.
But yeah, I don't know. There is some
miner, but cannot really find it.
I think that's mgPai. My node is up to
date and my mining core is running fine on
my server, but I think when I tried to
remote into my basement miner, it was
choking.
There is no need to mine, right? There is
need to find the current miner. It's one
party at the moment, some party, but it's
not Michael, it's not mgPai.
Oh, it's not mgPai.
Yeah, it's not you then. I don't know. So
we need to update the public testnet. So
to make a warning and activation of 6.0, I
think it's quite ready. And then, yeah,
well, final audit and we are good for
mainnet warning and activation.
Then, Yeah, well, pushing DEX developers
also, well, it's a little bit hard
because, well, it seems that there is no
synchronization, basically. So trying to
get guys in sync, to get UI and main
deployments finally done. Well, it's a
long story, but Yeah, at this point, well,
the only thing I can do is just push the
front-end and back-end developers to get
in sync and deliver the back-end and UI.
Then what else? Also, participating in
some forum discussions in regards to
real-world assets and DAO. Actually, it's
interesting to have Luivatra in Palmyra
because there is a transmute DAO idea on
the forum by some guy.
Well, we're actually setting up a DAO for
Palmyra Economy. That's one of our pillars
for Palmyra Economy, is there's going to
be a DAO that is basically going to work
in a sense like one of the core entities
to drive decentralized business
development. So we'd use the DAO to vote
on proposals like in Catalyst, but
hopefully without all the drama, to
develop business in different regions.
Yeah, but then there could be also
smaller DAOs like, well, I proposed many
months before Paideia launch and we will
propose again when I will have some time
to have gold oracle pool operators DAO,
which is uniting gold oracle pool
operators with gold related products
developers such as Gluon and Dexy.
The idea is to have DAO with deciding
some things in regards with how to spread
reward tokens and so on. Currently it's
done just in the chat but it would be more
clear and more transparent to do with the
DAO. The same could be done with lithium
oracle operators and lithium product
developers as well.
It also would be an interesting option to
have some smaller DAOs for very concrete
and specific niches. Also writing some
forum posts with some things well, which
I'm talking about things like Cardano
Summit, so maybe the North, if we had such
discussions, right.
So, well, the idea is how to have a
unified vision, right, about what, well,
the ecosystem is and could be, right, in
the future. So, well, how to combine well
DeFi we have and the real world assets and
then well different peer-to-peer cache
constructions well things like ChainCash
and so on right to have some well
ecosystem which is which can be
well-transformative rights for large-scale
transformations and mass adoption.
We'll visit Hong Kong in February, so
we'll see then again.
So, actually, we've got to talk
potentially about maybe doing some Palmyra
Ergo thing over there. We've been talking
to a friend. You know bond villain looking
friend who who's been helping us set up
some stuff in Hong Kong. So yeah, we got
to talk about that off offline
potentially.
Well, we already talked about it, but we
got to see what we can do because there's
going to be quite a few people over there.
I think that if we do an event in a kind
of a nice place, not too huge, but
something where it's going to be just very
organic and interesting, I think, I think
we can attract some people there. There's
going to be, like I said, there's going to
be a lot of like, you know, usually, you
know, the Hong Kong events are pretty,
like there, there's a lot of people, so it
could potentially bring some, you know, a
lot of fresh meat over there.
There's an IHOP over there, isn't there
Dan?
In Hong Kong? I know there's Anytime
Fitness in Hong Kong. That's also how I
chart the world, because I got this gym
membership that actually works in several
countries, including the US. It's a US
company that actually operates a pretty
large gym network in Japan.
So they're really big in Japan, but
there's quite a few of them in the US,
plus some other countries. With Singapore,
there was Anytime Fitness in Singapore and
other Asian countries. And so I just kind
of always chart my travels. I don't feel
like looking for a hotel with a gym
because those are more expensive.
So I'll just get an Airbnb next at
Anytime Fitness. And yeah, the closest
IHOP I know is actually in Dubai, I think.
Yeah, Dubai, Dubai is the, yeah, whenever
I'm in Dubai, I always hit up the IHOP
over there. So I don't have to go down to
the US, but unfortunately they haven't
discovered the wonder of IHOP in Japan,
but yeah, QX.
So when we're there at Rare Evo, you're
gonna be at Rare Evo, right?
Next year? Is that this year?
This year. This is 2025, the beginning of
2025.
We'll see. We'll talk in the Sigmanauts
about it.
Let's not talk about it. Let's just
fricking go. Let's go. You owe me at least
like three trips to IHOP. I'm sure I do. I
did you one in a really nasty way one time
and that was the first time. That was the
first impression is the only impression.
That's true. That's true.
Oh, yeah, so you screwed up. But yeah,
Alex, let's see if we can do something in
Hong Kong. Let's get some new eyes and new
faces in the ecosystem.
Yeah, so actually we had a meet-up there
back in 2019, so we have some, well, old
Ergonauts in the town. well some were
active in the chats after so one guy Sam
was a video operator actually at the
meetup and yeah so some other guys and
well yeah there was one guy oh but yeah so
he's in the town but he didn't attend that
meetup but yeah he bought like two
Bitcoin's worth of ERG just a few days
after the mainnet launch.
One guy from one of the biggest VCs
actually in the cryptocurrency space. This
time I will meet a lot of guys from the
biggest Asian VCs to check the temperature
in the room. It's a quite interesting time
right now, so well at least it's worth to
check the temperature.
Are you going QX or are you going to stay
at home and not do anything again?
It's in Dubai or Hong Kong?
Hong Kong.
I'd love to. That'd be amazing.
So let's go. Happening next month.
It's tough.
That's not tough. You just buy a plane
ticket and go.
Talking about things, when you will be in
Argentina again, then? Maybe I will come.
Yeah, actually, that would be great if
you could come along late March, early
April.
Oh, let's see. But it's really tough.
Yeah, especially around that time. Let's
see.
Yeah, we're probably going to go right
after, so we're going to go to the US for
the World Tea Expo and just myself and
Theodore. Business development and then
we're going to go to Argentina from there.
Before that, I'm going to go to Sri Lanka
and lose some weight eating super hot
curry.
All right, but actually, so in April, I'm
planning to visit Japan, actually. But
it's closer to late April, and it will be
Miyako-jima Islands. And then, yeah, I can
visit also Tokyo or, well... You should go
Miyako-jima to Osaka.
Yeah, Osaka, sure, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, Miyako-jima.
Yeah, yeah, Miyako-jima is nice, yeah.
Yeah, so there will be a financial
cryptography conference there this year.
In Miyako-jima?
In Miyako-jima, yeah. So that's an island
conference, so you know, well, one year
they're organizing a conference somewhere
around the Caribbean, and the other year
they're organizing it's Well, it's some
islands in Asia or Europe. So yeah, it was
Malta before and Borneo and now...
Oh yeah, remember Malta, that was what,
2016, right?
17, it was April 2017, yeah, beginning of
April. And yeah, it was, there were a lot
of people there, right? So Charles, so the
whole IOHK, I believe. back then. Oh,
yeah, yeah. Wait, wait, wait. What I'm
talking about. I met you there. Yeah.
So are you talking about just Miyako-jima
in Okinawa? Or are you talking about the
main? Because there's a lot of
Miyako-jimas.
Oh, so some islands nearby Taiwan,
actually.
Oh, that's Okinawa, yeah. Okay, well,
that's about an hour by plane from me, an
hour and a half by plane from me, so. All
right, so you can... Can't drive to
Okinawa, unfortunately, but in April, it's
actually probably gonna be really nice.
April is already nice and warm over there,
so I might actually just gonna come and
hang out with you over there, and then we
can take a ride back to Osaka.
All right, all right.
We got 12 minutes for questions, but
before I started those, kushti, while you
guys were talking about Japan, I looked up
my testnet miner, and I am the single
miner, so good news. You want me to stop
it? What's the deal there? We'll connect
later.
No, no, no. So just mine and wait for
instructions.
Just keep on going. Okay. I'll hold
tight. That is me. Good. Okay.
Stop and wait for instructions, QX. Don't
be a hero.
Only on Ergo can you set something up and
forget about it and forget it was you. And
then months later, it's like, oh yeah,
that's me.
All right. So yeah, I will just provide
you a 6.0 jar. And yeah, you will need to
put, well, one value in a config file. And
then, yeah, the rest will be done
automatically, like voting and activation.
Perfect. And yeah, we will enjoy public
testing of 6.0 features in the testnet.
Nice.
All right, so let's jump on the
questions. Let's start. OK, so here's one.
What does Charles think about Rosen
Bridge?
So actually, we had quite a few
conversations about Rosen Bridge with
Charles in the past. He's very interested
in it. I mean, it's great tech. Now we
are, I mean, we haven't really kind of
carried those conversations over any
further beyond just the initials, but
yeah, he had nothing but good to say about
it.
And, you know, it says it's good tech and
it's good that it's an ecosystem. So
potentially down the road, we can
integrate it a little bit more with what
IOG is doing maybe do a, you know, Rosen
Bridge to midnight, something like that.
That would be interesting, I think.
Yeah. So recently I watched you guys'
video. So you and Charles talked about
Rosen Bridge and Charles mentioned that,
well, Hydra would be beneficial for Rosen.
And yeah, well, It's very true.
By its design, Hydra is most beneficial.
Hydra is a high-performance layer 2 on
Cardano, but it also could be ported to
Ergo without the hassle and yeah, it's
well, super beneficial for federated
protocols like Rosen and Oracle pools
actually, right?
So for Oracle pools, you may have just
one on-chain transaction in case of Gold
Oracle pool, for example, right? Instead
of 20 per epoch, right? So you can reduce
on-chain loads by 20x, right, basically.
Well, in an optimistic scenario. So, well,
most of the time, basically, like 99.99%
of the time, right.
And yeah, the same about Rosen. So you
can greatly reduce blockchain loads, so
reduce fees by using Hydra for Rosen. And
yeah, that's actually a super good point.
So well, federated protocols such as Rosen
and Oracle pools can get well, a lot of
boosts without any reduction in security
from Hydra.
Yeah, totally. Yeah, we had those good
conversations about Hydra. He's actually
been talking about Ergo spinning up a
Hydra head for quite a while now, so maybe
that's something we should look into.
Right, yeah. Sounds beneficial, right?
And yeah, especially for federated
protocols. And we have a few of them
already.
Yeah, let's see. Okay, so what do you
guys think about the Miners Rights
Protocol?
Oh, QX. Are you with us?
I'm here, I'm here, I'm awake, I'm alive,
I'm alive. So Miners Rights is a protocol
of something that was developed in the
Sigmanauts mining pool, spearheaded by
Mark the Shark, and it's like... Oh, I
see, he's like, hey guys, what do you
think about... The miners' rights
protocol.
No, no, no. I have been... So, Sigmanauts
mining pool has been running without me
for a long time now. Mark the Shark is in
full command of this. I don't even mine to
it because I'm using my RTX 3090 to mine
testnet, kushti. So, I can't even mine to
it anymore.
What the most? Actually I'm thinking
about rewarding testnet miners at some
point by building trustless, first
trustless pegging right between Ergo
mainnet and Ergo testnet and then you can
bring testnet ERGs to the mainnet and
Well, establish liquidity pool, and then
it could be like a sort of meme coin,
maybe, right?
Oh, that would be interesting. I could
also see Mark integrating testnet into the
Miners Rights Protocol rewards so that
somehow get just in some sort of public
database, perhaps, entering your mainnet
address into the chain so that it could be
read so that you could also be rewarded on
mainnet with the Miners Rights Protocol by
mining testnet.
So yeah, Miners Rights Protocol is like
Mark's original idea on steroids.
Essentially, it's minting a token to be
kind of to designate yourself to a pool,
the Sigmanauts pool at this point. And
then that gives you mining rights to the
pool, which also allows for rewards and
bonus tokens and distributions during that
mining process.
So it's essentially not a commitment
protocol, but he's calling it a Miners
Rights Protocol. But the PDF is right on
the Ergo main web page. I encourage you
guys to read it. It's essentially Mark's
imagination, Mark's dream child, and it's
going to be pretty damn cool.
Also, if you go into the weeds, imagine
Setting permissions and configs via NFTs
minting for your mining instead of going
to a website and logging your IP and
setting your configs there in case the
website goes down. I think about HiveOS.
How cool would HiveOS be if you could set
your configs for all your rigs in an NFT
that you hold in your mining wallet and
then that could read the mining wallet as
opposed to... Right. What happened to
HiveOS six months ago? They lost
everybody's configs and burn out some
people's cards almost
So, stuff like that would be really cool
and is possible with the Miners Rights
Protocol.
Yeah, that sounds interesting.
Yeah, yeah. So, check it out. It's way
more technical than I'm explaining. I'm
just giving a high overview. The PDF's
right on the website. Just type in Ergo
Miners Rights Protocol. It should be the
top result.
Yeah, actually good for miners' privacy,
right?
Exactly, 100%. Yep.
Many miners do care about privacy,
actually, and that's good.
Yeah Yeah, all right. All right. Let's
see. We've got a couple more questions
here. oh, has kushti ever tried to play
Cyberverse We talked about this.
It's a no-go. We want kushti to program.
We don't want him to sit and play
Cyberverse for 10 hours.
That's a no-go Mr QX the party pooper
says it's a no-go
All right, so maybe this weekend, yeah,
actually, I need to spend the weekend on
doing slides for Hong Kong and yeah, well,
doing some more writing. So hopefully,
well, I need to finish something and then
hopefully can open the draft of the Ergo
book, I mean the structure.
So it's just... You could be like Elon
Musk and you can pay me to run the kushti
Cyberverse account and I'll run it for you
and everybody can think it's you.
Don't pay QX for anything. It's going to
go out and buy weird ponchos and dogs.
What do we got?
Okay, is there a way to find out how many
participants are in the SigmaUSD Oracle
pool?
SigmaUSD Oracle pool, yeah. So currently
it's just about four or five Oracle pools
and yeah, you can find them on the
blockchain actually, right? So by just
tracking transaction and the maximum
amount possible now I believe is about
like year 12 but yeah only four or five
participating because of lack of
incentivization and that's why well there
is a community now well organized, about
launching, version two pool well with,
incentivization, right in the form of
token like, GARD, but now it would be, I
don't know, maybe dollar, oracle for
reward token, right.
And then, lithium, token would be Lord,
So it's lithium oracle reward token.
My reward for running SigmaUSD Oracle
pool is that kushti talks to me every two
weeks to remind me to consolidate my
wallet because my Oracle stopped
reporting. So that's my reward.
Yeah, so that's actually another problem
of version one, which is fixed in version
two. So there is no dust in version two,
right? So currently we are discussing how
to update the version one.
which is also a bit tricky it seems, but
previously we updated a few times version
2 and well, it went smoothly after all, I
believe. but it was before Gluon and Dexy,
so well, let's see, so now it will be a
bit more complicated, I believe.
But yeah, it's better to update because,
well, we cannot rely on goodwill in the
long-term, right, so there is need to have
more sound and incentive-compatible
protocol. So version 2, And yeah,
hopefully there will be more people there.
So well, if you are talking about gold
pools, so we have maximum number of
operators about 20. So yeah, exactly 20
right now, I believe. And yeah, well,
online we have currently from 14 to 18,
right? So well, good number actually.
Once again, Oracle version 2 is like
bulletproof, at least from tech running
it. I mean, I check on it every couple of
months, kushti, and I'm like, oh, yeah,
but still reporting, still good.
It's just like... Yeah, so... Actually,
my Oracle is getting issues, but yeah,
they are coming from CoinGecko, so it
seems my IP is blocked by CoinGecko. But
yeah, it's probably because, well, along
with Oracle, I'm running also some other
scripts, which are well, fetching data
from CoinGecko.
So probably, yeah, that's too much for
them. So my Oracle, yeah, often only
because of CoinGecko not providing data to
post on the chain. So, yeah, I need to do
something. Let's see.
We got a good question at the bottom,
Dan.
Is that because it's addressed to you,
QX?
no i think anybody can answer that
honestly i don't know why i think we can
all