Good day everyone, I am Alexander
Chepurnoy, also known as kushti,
co-developer of Ergo, proof-of-work
cryptocurrency, realizing the concept of
programmable money, and my talk would be
about property rights in the age of
programmable money.
And the talk will connect some dots.
In particular, it will connect previously
US-sanctioned smart contract, so
autonomous code on blockchain which got
sanctioned.
Money of the future, so programmable
money, tokenized real world and blockchain
assets such as art objects and property
rights.
And if you are talking about property
rights of the future, so programmable
property rights as well.
OK, so let's start.
So what could be a property when we are
talking about digital world, blockchain
world, where we can have autonomous code
while handling some money, some tokens?
So there was a very interesting case
recently, a case of Tornado Cash.
Tornado Cash is a service that is mixing
potentially identifiable cryptocurrency
funds with others to obscure the trail
back to the funds original source.
This is a privacy tool used in Ethereum
and
Ethereum-like networks where all the
transactions are public by default.
And at some point the US Department of
the Treasury blacklisted the protocol.
And then, very recently, on November 26,
2024, a U.S. federal appeals court
overturned an earlier ruling stating that
the law could not sanction a protocol.
Well, if we are talking about details, so
exact words are that Tornado Cash's
immutable smart contracts.
The lines of privacy enabling software
codes are not the property of a foreign
national entity, meaning that they cannot
be blocked under different regulations.
Alright, so here we have that if some
code is not associated, some code along
with its assets, right, such as assets
been mixed by Tornado Cash.
Autonomous smart contract so both the
code and the assets it's owning in the
process of mixing not recognized as
someone's - so individual or company
property.
At least according to current US laws,
but probably in other jurisdictions it
would be the same, but yeah, it's the very
new thing. It's just a few days basically,
like two weeks in just one jurisdiction.
And the same results we got.
The same results maybe in a bit more
technical form, because we are not
lawyers, we are developers.
Developing the concept of programmable
money.
So in our physical real world every bank
note is not protecting itself, right?
So it's passive.
And in the digital world, so in the
setting of programmable money, every
digital bank note is protected by a public
key or many keys and also potentially
programmable logic.
Every digital bank note is protecting
itself with some program and execution of
that program possibly with signature check
after decides whether a note may be spent
or not.
And this is actually already quite old
concepts going from Bitcoin, early days of
Bitcoin, even Bitcoin script, but
developed in the Ergo community.
And so in case of blockchain based
programmable money like Ergo or Bitcoin we
have programmable logic expressed against
the state of the blockchain right because
on the blockchain everything is just the
state of the blockchain. To be connected
to the external world you need for trusted
entities and the whole point of the
blockchain is to avoid trust.
But we can imagine non blockchain based
programmable money also where logic is
expressed against state.
Every user of a money system agreed or
enforced to be agreed on.
Example of that could be CBDC central
bank digital currency but I'm not aware of
any using such programmability at the
moment but in the future that would be the
case probably.
And then in the age of programmable money
the talk about ownership is becoming more
complex so we have individual
ownership when a digital banknote belongs
to just one key, always right, depends on
time and other things which are happening
on the blockchain.
We also may have cooperative property
when a node belongs to multiple keys, for
example, with quorum voting needed to
spend a node.
And also we may have contractual
property, right, so autonomous property,
property which belongs to autonomous
contracts such as Tornado Cash in
the example I've provided before.
So we can define contractual ownership
when an owner could not be defined, right?
When there is no owner, for example,
right?
So owner could be pseudo randomly chosen.
Maybe in future or maybe we have rotating
right to do some things based on
randomness pseudo randomness if we are
talking about blockchain or maybe an owner
will be decided based on
the state of blockchain right in future.
So maybe it will go to a miner of
particular block on the blockchain or
whatever.
There could be very different options
here.
And yeah in this case when we cannot
identify owner because it will be decided
by a program at certain point there is no
any owner at all.
Then we are talking about contractual
property.
Right those things maybe a bit abstract
for you guys so let's talk about art now
let's talk about things which are closer
to you guys let's talk about tokenized art
so what's people are now doing
with art and blockchain so there are two
options so first you may tokenize physical
art ownership usually by dividing
ownership rights and pieces right and
issuing tokens where one token is
corresponding to one piece
of an art object and then we have
tokenized ownership with for example 1000
tokens representing the full ownership of
our art object.
Another option is to create digital art
and put it on the blockchain.
You can
break it into pieces as well, but in this
case it's more popular to make an NFT, so
a single token which is associated with,
for example, this black swan picture.
All right.
And this is just one dimension of
ownership, right?
Let's call it quantization dimension.
So you can have a single token
representing the whole art object, or you
may have multiple tokens each representing
part of a digital or physical art object.
OK, but then, going back to programmable
money,
there is another dimension, so every
token, whether it's NFT or one token out
of 1000, can be protected by a public key
or many keys or even programmable logic.
Right and similar to programmable money
program execution with possible signature
check after decides whether a token may be
transferred from existing owner to a new
one or not.
And
here we have options we already defined,
so individual, collective and contractual
ownership.
But in case of multiple tokens
representing an art object, for example,
there could be different options for
different pieces, right?
Of an art object means different tokens.
For example, we can imagine 200 tokens
out of 1,000 to be owned by an art
gallery, 100 tokens by a painter's
cooperative, for example, with 9 out of 15
signatures needed for transfer rights, or
we have 15
signatories in the cooperative and then
nine is enough for transfer, nine
signatures.
And then we can lock 700 remaining tokens
to a contract which puts one token every
week, for example, on a decentralized
blockchain-based auction, right?
And for those 700 tokens at the beginning
we have contractual ownership, right?
But then, yeah, after auctions those 700
tokens would be possessed by other
entities, right, and they could be
individual, collective or contractual
again.
Right, so this world is going to be quite
complicated, right, and also exciting
because with contractual ownership we also
have contractual possibilities.
We may do a lot of experiments around
sales of art objects, right?
I think even from this simple example
this is becoming quite obvious.
And so we may discover a lot of new sales
models.
We can have trading boosting by liquidity
provision.
Right, which can be made a part of
emission contract, for example.
So in this example where we are selling
700 tokens one by one, every week on a
decentralized blockchain based auction.
We may require proceedings from auction
to be going to liquidity pool.
Right, so then those tokens would have
good liquidity.
Right, in a liquidity pool where we have
tokens representing art objects along with
tokens representing Euro, for example,
right, or USD or gold or cryptocurrency
tokens such as ERG or whatever.
OK, then we can have time logs, for
example, to prevent immediate sales where
it's needed, where it makes sense
contractually and so on.
And by
doing all those new things and by
combining them differently.
We are bringing our financialization of
art to completely new level, making
financial schemes around such
financialization also a kind of art.
All right.
And there are a lot of tools already
available in the Ergo ecosystem, such as
airdrop tools to reward some community
with tokens.
Auction coin framework to emit tokens via
auctions periodically.
As in our example, and possibly inject
funds raised into liquidity pools.
Then there are a lot of fundraising tools
such as MewFinance where you can
fundraise.
You can raise funds to do a new art
object, right, and after tokenizing it you
can reward
contributors with tokens.
There are auctions where you can put
NFTs.
There are already a lot of NFTs there.
There is some tooling - decentralized
autonomous organization it's called, but
we can call it just digital cooperatives.
And this tooling is for token based
decision making.
There is such tool Paideia on Ergo and
you can use it, for example, to have some
kind of cooperative rights associated with
some art object, for example.
Or you can tokenize maybe some collection
or even some movement art movement and so
on.
You may have liquidity pools, order book
based decentralized exchanges and so on,
so on.
You may have NFT collections, so combine
different
unique pieces like this black swan along
with white swan for example and maybe pink
flamingo and so on into a single
collection with some common properties.
And so on, so on, so on.
So there are a lot of tools already and a
lot of possibilities outlined in this talk
and not only.
So let's discover the new age of finance
together.
And I hope, with all those new schemes
there would be a lot of experiments on how
to tokenize or to build also sustainable
finance right for artists at least, but
not only.
OK, so please check the links where you
can find tooling mentioned.
And here is Ergo's Telegram group and my
personal Twitter.
Thank you for your attention.
Have a great event.
Bye.