Welcome to the live Ergo developer update
with me tonight.
I have the amazing, the elusive, the very
busy Joseph Armeanio.
How are you doing, John?
I'm doing all right. Busy week.
What is it today? Tuesday?
You know, I've lost track, honestly.
Feels a little deeper in the week than
Tuesday, but that's how life goes
sometimes.
It does. I like to say what a week it's
been today.
You say that on Monday. That's half my
life usually.
Let me stick the link in chat so people
can join us. There we go. Live link is in
chat.
All right, guys, we're live with the Ergo
update. Joe managed to find some colored
beverage in his closet.
I am also cheersing to Ergo and its
success.
And we're going to bring you all the news
of the ecosystem from last week and maybe
some bullshit along the way. We'll see.
Joe, what do you want to talk about
tonight?
I don't know. I haven't been paying that
much attention to be honest with the
latest bullshit in the crypto space.
There's always something going on.
Well, I think we got some more official
pumping of the Trump token from Trump's
truth social account. I saw that this
week.
I don't know where to start with that
stuff, Joe. When are the people that are
using blockchain for its intended purpose
going to outnumber the people that are
just using it to get rich quick or steal
money from other people? When's that going
to happen, Joe?
It's hard to say. I think we're going to
see a split in the crypto space at some
point, right? Because if you look at
what's trending in popular at this point,
it's institutional adoption, using stable
coins to absorb treasuries, creating the
regulatory beginning of stable coins.
I think that generally once something is
under the purview of regulators that tends
to move more in a ratchet, like one
direction, rather than it starts and then
that's it forever, right?
So I think we're probably gonna see some
kind of public-private partnership digital
money that may not have the greatest
assumptions in terms of surveillance.
We're gonna see a lot of that stuff,
yeah.
The ability to seize it. With stable
coins more, we're probably going to be
moving in the direction where there's just
a lot more financial surveillance that's
possible on public blockchain.
And then the question is, how do we get
to privacy? Right? Because that's
something that I think in some sense, the
market will demand it, right? And that's
kind of an open question.
We have this idea of confidentiality
where you're kind of trusting someone
won't reveal your information rather than
true privacy assumption, which is where
you're trusting the cryptography that's
actually concealing your information.
It's interesting. From my personal
perspective, and it could be wrong and I
hope I'm wrong, is that generally in the
Western consciousness, you have a public
private partnership and you have powers on
the back end and people can invest in the
prison that they live in. They're happy.
Because then you have the profit
incentive, right? We've seen this already
with a lot of - you can look at Gmail, you
could look at Facebook, you can look at a
lot of these public private partnerships
that have in the back end that end up
giving way too much data information that
doesn't really benefit users other than
the user experience of it, which even then
is somewhat hard to argue.
I think there's always an equal opposite
polarity, right? It's like thermodynamics
when it comes to energy and probably also
culture too. Where if we do see more
institutional adoption and we do see more
surveillance and tracking compliance based
tooling that's forced on people, I do
think that that is the best narrative
privacy projects and resilient neutral
money has ever seen.
So mainstream blockchain adoption, right?
I think we're gonna - I think it's so vast
and so different. DJ, if you have a
question, pop it in there. No problem.
It's so vast and different that it's going
to be such a myriad of things out there. I
think we're going to see a ton of
centralization, a ton of controlled
assets. As you said, that you can mock
down and you don't really have control of
it.
But we're going to see blockchain
adoption to where you don't even have an
idea that the blockchain is happening in
the background. Like you're interacting
with something and boom like I was
thinking the other day like with all these
AI fakes out there, right? And you can't
trust videos or pictures anymore. If Joe's
gonna publish a video, what better way to
signify that Joe is the owner of that
video and actually publish it by putting
the checksum of the video in a transaction
on chain signed with Joe's wallet then we
know right off the bat that it's Joe's
kind of thing. So those kind of things can
be in the background people won't even
know that it's a case, but it's easily
look up, and it's resilient cause it's on
tons of different nodes and that kind of
thing to the point where we also have peer
to peer finance institutions where you
have the bank of Joe, the bank of QX and
all that kind of stuff.
I don't think it's going to be one thing
and that's it. We have to be ready for the
fact that peer to peer be a big chunk, but
it might be an outlier as well at some
point.
Yeah, to some degree, I think we need to
take a step back and realize what is a
blockchain? It's a ledger. From a close-up
perspective, it's a ledger that's just
replicated around the world, hopefully.
If you have a single signer ledger, I
don't know why blockchain is really the
way. A lot of the best properties of
something like Bitcoin itself had to do
with the fact that it's distributed enough
that it's kind of unstoppable, right?
That's really where I started to gain
interest in this space is this idea of
saying, if we can create neutral money and
it's the system out there that anybody
with an internet connection can
potentially connect with or interact with,
you just remove so many barriers of trade
and commerce and expression and exchange
between people.
And so when you get into it's a
centralized system, I don't see why it's
even worth mentioning to be honest. I
mean, there are other database structures
that are probably more performant, right?
Yeah. And that plays into the part where
I don't think the centralized - I don't
think at least a peer to peer
decentralized - let's take the US, right.
And some of the major players, right. I
think that's going to be an obvious
adoption of centralized structures that
they have control over. I don't think that
peer-to-peer decentralized networks are
going to be widely embraced by governments
per se, right? They're built for the
individual so that they're on the same
footing as the person with insider
information or the person with more money
or that kind of thing.
So I think we'll see that kind of
peer-to-peer adoption on a broader scale
across the world as opposed to let's hope
that the U.S. government picks up Ergo or
something. It's not going to happen,
right?
Yeah, I think it's interesting to see how
any type of internet technology can
potentially remove boundaries, right?
We're in a Discord channel or a Telegram
or Signal and we're talking to kind of a
global audience in a frictionless way.
We're communicating, exchanging ideas.
And so this idea where if you do have
these internet protocols, you can open
markets, which is powerful, right? I think
that's ultimately the main interesting use
case for stable coins in a way, is you
have this ability to expand the dollar's
reach into a cross border environment
without having to deal with exchange
markets, right? You use Internet
technology to bypass a lot of the physical
infrastructure that you'd normally have to
deal with.
And so we probably will see a lot of
adoption of dollars we already have with
USDT. That's one of its more interesting
aspects has always been these local money
exchanges that will kind of create their
own conversion and kind of ramp people to
the dollar or dollar exposure and
circumvent whatever system they're in. So
I do think there's value there. It's just
a question of data availability for the
user and control functions in the backend
that I'm just not a fan of.
Yeah, I can see tiered blockchain ledger
tiers essentially with centralized
blockchains will only expose this part of
the transaction or the chain to you at
this tier or always ways to sell the data
that you're collecting. Absolutely crazy.
But you're talking about stable, right? I
briefly read an article that things like
gold, silver are becoming more attractive,
stable options, as opposed to the US
dollar, right?
Well, I think that many people have
called the dollar the cleanest dirty shirt
in terms of currencies. There's a lot of
debt backing the dollar. We're in a weird
position in a lot of different ways with
humanity. It's just honest. The debt
burden globally is huge. We've gone
through this rapid acceleration of
technology to where we went through the
mechanical age and then the electronic age
and then the internet age. Now we're
entering into the machine mind age.
Yep. Absolutely crazy. We're live at this
time. It's like somebody's great
grandfather had an outhouse in the field,
right?
Yeah, exactly.
Now we're moving into the age of
artificial intelligence emerging and all
kinds of - you can synthesize a dead
parent's voice, like I can synthesize my
mother's voice and feed her all the emails
she's ever sent me ever and then have a
chat with her. It's insane. Absolutely.
So I mean, technology is accelerating.
Social consciousness hasn't really caught
up with where the edge of that is - it's
kind of a wake effect where it takes a
while to bleed through to the masses but
the tip of the spear there is moving
faster and faster and faster.
So it's going to be disruptive, right? I
would say that when you look at technology
as it develops, it's a force multiplier.
And so we are moving again through
probably a decade of disruption where
everybody that has a shovel is going to
get displaced by somebody that has a
backhoe. And I think people have a certain
awareness of that, in my opinion.
Yeah, it'll be interesting. How do we get
to a point where people start? I mean,
American stuff, right. In America, you sit
back and you say, I don't agree with this
administration, but I'm not going to do
anything about it. So you have this kind
of - I'll just focus on me and my local
network. And I'll be good to the people
that are in my local network.
Yeah, that's true. Local networks
important, but I'm thinking about not just
the US outside of the US at one point. At
one point, if the knowledge is given,
these people start saying, you know what,
I'm going to take control of my own
assets, my own ability to make sure that
somebody's not screwing me over. These
tooling that can guarantee kind of a
predictable manner in how it's being
executed, right?
At what point does an average person that
is being affected, like Joe, we got it
easy, right? I mean, we got it really
easy, right? We have jobs, we have house,
we have those kinds of things. So we can
go to the bank, get a loan, we can take
money out of the bank, but that's not the
majority of the world, right? So my
question is, how do we - I guess it's a
slow burn, right? Eventually it's a slow
burn. How do we get that information in
the people's hands that it really does
matter for their livelihood about these
kinds of changes that'll make a big
difference in their lives?
I tend to think that the best way to do
something like that is teach by example.
If you're talking about more mature
financial tools, the crypto space is a bit
immature. We have to be honest.
I'm going to have to edit that one out,
Joe.
Oh, yeah, shoot. We're live.
Sorry. No. I mean, listen, a lot of the
times if somebody that's not familiar with
crypto asked me what I do, I say I try to
work with open source financial software.
Versus crypto. And then it's an
interesting conversation. Well, what is
that? I say, well, it's this ability to
see and understand the system that you
interact with.
How do you argue against that? That
doesn't - that's got to sound attractive
to almost anybody.
Yeah. Then people are genuinely
interested because it's like, well, I've
never thought that - I go to the bank and
I have no idea what their balance sheet is
or no idea who's holding the mortgage to
my house because it's been auctioned off X
amount of times or titles.
Your student loans go through like 10
different fricking people.
If you get into this idea of having
different assumptions in the system, the
financial system, people are interested in
that, right? Because many people are,
they've either thought about it and it's
kind of a wild thing or they haven't
thought about it. You pay off your house.
Who owns the title to your house? Yeah, it
usually gets passed packaged and passed
around. Who owns the title to your car?
Who owns your student loan?
The type of inability to see into our
financial system is fascinating, yet the
mirror is put on the user where they're
constantly wanting to know who are you,
how much do you have and where did it come
from. Which in some sense is a very weird
relationship.
If I just met you and I'm saying, hey,
QX, can you look after my money? And
you're saying, well, who are you? And
where'd you get this? And me as the person
who actually has the money that's handing
it to you, what do I get in terms of
transparency from that side? It's
interesting.
It's so normal that nobody questions it,
but there's a lot of things in this world
that are so normal that nobody really
questions it. And I think that money is
one of the things that when you really
start to question what's happening in
terms of the system itself, it's a deep
and weird hole.
It is. And you're talking about are the
money makers that made me think like on
chain, right? I can - even the layman
essentially can see a transaction in your
wallet and see where it's going, see what
it's like. They might want to be able to
read a smart contract, but at least they
can go to GitHub in just the whole thing
into an AI and maybe ask it what it's
doing so they may have an idea when you
sign off for a mortgage like - you sign,
you're not reading those 800 pages that
you're signing, right? You have no clue,
just kind of the general ideas of what's
happening with that paper that you're
signing.
One of the more interesting aspects of
learning machine models really is this
idea of being able to digest large amounts
of information and spit something out to
the user like something is off here.
Right? Because it takes a lot of time and
energy to dive through that. Can you hear
the dog?
I love it. It's fine. It's a good
background. Guys, don't worry about it,
Joe.
All right. There's probably like an eight
foot bear out back trying to swat him or
something.
Yeah, I know.
All right, let's see. We got a question
here really quick. Karim says, Spectrum
Finance needs to come back strong. You
know, I get it, but they don't necessarily
need to. We've got all the contracts
online. We've got the that are open
source. We've got the UI that's open
source. Anybody can pick it up and start
cranking out more features. MewFinance did
it. They took the front end and did a ton
of optimization tweaks to it and using the
smart contracts for the pools. So anybody
can do it. That's the beauty of it. I
don't think - we gotta try to stop
creating idols, right? We gotta stop
creating like, oh, this is a thing that's
gonna save us or that kind of thing.
Yeah, I think that's the better option is
just ideate and push for ideas. Yeah,
there are some interesting options for
decentralized exchange that haven't been
explored on Ergo. It'd be really cool to
see.
Joe, I'm just waiting for you to build a
DEX into Rosen Bridge.
To build a DEX into Rosen Bridge? Well, I
think it's better to build around Rosen
Bridge. And the reason why is because you
have a system that doesn't rehypothecate
assets, holds collateral one-to-one. And
when you start to seek yield or swaps
internally, you create a much messier
situation in terms of being able to audit
the fact that there's no rehypothecation.
So you could get into cross-chain swaps,
it's doable, but it's not necessarily
changing the protocol of the bridge
itself. I think sometimes there's a way to
make Rosen faster that's relatively
straightforward, basically.
Right. Rosen fastening.
Right. What you would do is you would
require a premium fee on the person that's
bridging, and you would use the bridge
protocol in the background, and you would
simply have liquidity providers that front
an element of weaker assumptions, release
funds, and then get paid as the original
transaction goes through.
Yeah, you want fast pay a premium, right?
That's kind of how the banking system
works, right? You can send something
faster and add a little bit of -
Speaking of speaking of Rosen and
Fastlane and that kind of stuff, I was
speaking to - I was helping out a guy
who's spinning up a watcher on Aragore, I
believe, first, and he's looking at
Cardano. And he is one of his questions
was - Do you, can I use the same
collateral? The 30,000 Rosen and the 800
ERG. Can I use the same collateral for
Cardano and Ergo? And I was like, no, I
said it's a completely separate set of
collateral. You have to actually run a
separate watcher. You can't just put both
in the same file. And that sounds like a
bummer to the person running it.
But that's the beauty of ROSIN is that
you're forcing a distributed method, even
if I'm the same person running three
watchers, right? I'm running it on
probably three different computers. Yeah,
I'm running it on three different
computers on two different networks. So
you're forcing kind of this distribution,
right? Of course, some people are going to
run onto the same machine. But still, the
smart thing is, I'm going to run my
watches on three different machines
because I have them. Because if one
machine goes down, I don't lose out on all
three profits, I only lose out on one
profit until I fix it. And then the other
two machines are still picking up profits
for the chains that I'm on. So with that
model that you're doing, you're kind of
forcing this spread out decentralization,
even among individuals who are doing more
than one watcher set. So I think it's a
brilliant idea that you're requiring
liquidity for both staking liquidity for
both for any chain that you go on for each
watcher, essentially.
So that was just an economic friction to
create.
Yep.
That's why it's there.
Awesome. All right, we've got another
question. Dejan wants to know if Ergo is
kushti's main thing or he's got a side
hustle. Also, same question for
developers. Where is money coming from to
finance Ergo development? Good question.
Oh, that's a good question. Let's see,
I've worked with kushti for quite a while.
I don't think he's actually been paid by
anybody since about 2021.
I know, I don't think so.
So it's a question of saying, why? Why
would somebody put years of their life
into building something that is subject to
hyper volatility and is subject to people
that are constantly aggressive and people
that are constantly quite pushy? And you
have no direct financial incentive to do
that in terms of salary. It's because he,
number one, he enjoys developing.
What gets him excited is to read research
papers and think, what is possible? But
actually, the thing that probably
interests him the most is kind of the idea
of free banking. And I think that just
comes from his perspective of the world,
seeing kind of the state of the world,
seeing technology, seeing what's
potentially possible and how that could
benefit and change systems and improve
people's lives. A lot of crazy shit
happens on planet Earth because of our
money systems.
Greed, money, yep.
Yeah, well, I mean, it's like the ability
to print money is the ability to fund
wars. You usually have hyper
centralization and Cantillon effects and
the downstream effects of that warp.
Not just like, you have the power, you
have the money printing, look at the US
right now, right? They're prolific money
printers, we are. And not only that, but
we have the power to actually hurt other
economies, right? So we can not only print
our own money, but we can then hurt other
economies strategically during that
process, to even bolster a dollar even
more. So it's frickin insane.
I mean, it's a tool of power and control.
It's a weird system, right? So I guess
from some high level, the question is if
you can change the emission consensus
around money and you can change the
distribution mechanics around money. And
you can build systems that are more
transparent. That also offer the potential
to be more private, that also offer all of
these - I think that as systems advance, a
lot of exotic financial instruments that
were at one point only reserved for the
select few will become common. And then
things will get interesting, right?
So, yeah, I don't know. I think his
motivation is just simply based on where
his passion is and where his understanding
of how technology could potentially change
things. One of the things that tends to
get Alex the most excited is the idea of
free banking, which is in a way very, very
different than the layer one blockchain
attitude, right?
The commercial attitude. Yeah, yeah,
yeah, 100%. And it doesn't take much to
learn that about kushti, right? Read his
forum post, check him out on Twitter. And
it's very - It's very apparent early on
that if that's his attitude and that's his
core principle of supporting that kind of
self sovereignty of your own right.
There's a lot of people that don't want
to touch the money systems in the world.
They want to enhance it. And we're seeing
that with stable coin adoption. Well, I
think the funnier thing to do is touch the
money. Touch the money, change the system.
And crypto has kind of gone full circle to
where we started. It's kind of like fuck
the central banks. And now it's literally
let them power the central banks and take
bonds and mint dollars, which is a wild
turn of events. But I don't know.
Different time, different era, I guess.
Yeah, my second part of that question is
where is money coming from to finance Ergo
development? And that's a great answer on
that. It speaks to the resiliency of Ergo,
right? There's money coming from all
right. So there's money from the EF for
bounties, right? And then there's project
money, right? There's those projects that
have posted or have started projects and
gotten support funding. Look at Palmyra.
Look at Crux Finance. Look at MewFinance.
Look at all those kind of things on Ergo
so far. But the crux of the matter is that
the idea is that - And that makes us
resilient, right? Is there's no funding to
dry up. kushti's developing as he is.
I said we're poor.
So people are developing because they
believe in the cause of there should be
some fair system that's out there for
anybody to use. Right. And you can't dry
that up. Right. That's a cause that people
are willing to pick up and fight for.
So I think it simply goes to this idea of
adding value to a system. If you add value
to a system, you enhance it, right? And so
a lot of the developers that I know that
work on Ergo, they're adding value to the
system to enhance the value of the system.
That's why they develop.
Right, and that's the beauty of Ergo,
right? Because the Ergo community and Ergo
itself, that's literally on the Ergo
Manifesto about what its purpose is for.
So go to another chain such as Ethereum.
You'll be drowned out, right? You start
speaking like this. Well, let's make a
fair mining. Well, let's say back when
Ethereum was proof of work, right? You do
a fair mining initiative where you have
something like Lithos with distributed
miners collectively coming together,
right? That possibly could be drowned out
because that's not of interest to people
trying to make buck or make millions of
dollars off that kind of thing. So on
Ergo, it's the interesting value of the
chain is that we're building for something
better, right?
Yeah, that's the goal. Of course, there
are people in there that want to double or
triple or 10 times or 100 times their
investment on that. OK, you deserve it.
Actually, if you're investing in a project
like Ergo early on, sure, whatever. You
deserve that kind of thing. But I'd say
the meat of the people that are here in
Ergo, the developers that are working on
it are working on it for that cause.
Right. They're here for a reason because
they believe in what Ergo is and what it
represents. They believe in the mission
statement. And that's why they're here, I
think. So these bull markets, these bear
markets, it doesn't matter. There's always
somebody that believes in Ergo that's
still building and continuing really cool
stuff.
That's where Bitcoin came from, in a way.
There was no direct funding sources from
the chain. It was just proof of work. And
you can look at Litecoin, proof of work.
That's changed a lot, right? The incentive
structure in crypto has gotten a lot
different over time. Or I would say just
things are way more centralized. But yeah,
I think that if you're going to raise
funds, I've always been an advocate for
build a product that's public facing and
open source. Right. And which is
interesting because that's probably
backwards for how most people fundraise
today.
No, you know, I said that to the
blockchain group that I speak that I gave
a lecture to. I said, the scary thing
about open source is that anybody can take
your stuff and spin it up and try it
themselves. I said so. So the issue, the
challenge that our developers face, the
community developers on Ergo when they
open source their projects are that they
now need to think that, code's all open
source, anybody can take out of the spin.
So I need to come up with some unique
property that makes me better than anybody
else that would be trying to run my code,
right? And that could be customer service,
that could be the interface that they're
pumping from. So it opens up a whole new
world of competition with this open source
stuff that doesn't exist with closed
source stuff, right? It's absolutely
amazing to watch.
I tend to think of that from a totally
different angle.
All right, let's see.
So if somebody rebuilds a Rosen bridge,
that's better. And it leads to more
adoption. Fuck yeah, do it.
You may lose half your team to that new
company, right?
Fuck it.
It's a matter of progress. I don't know,
look at Bitcoin or any type of science -
you build on the shoulders of those before
you. That is progress. That is how
progress is made. So if I come up with an
open source idea that I pursue and it's
retooled in a way that is better, that's
awesome, right? Because what am I trying
to get rid of - Rosen is trying to disrupt
middlemen, right? If we can get around the
friction of that in terms of listing
access and access to liquidity, amazing,
do it.
If we look at Lithos. If we look at
Lithos, it's a matter of putting the best
assumptions to miners, right? If somebody
else can do that, I think that the idea
itself is beneficial because of what it
provides. So if somebody can rebuild it in
a way that's better, I'm happy.
Right. That's scary. And I agree that
that's one point of it, right? That's one
way to look at it. But it's tough to
attract a lot of develop. You got to be
kind of a developer with big balls, I
guess. And I hate to see I hate to use big
balls. Elon Musk has ruined the big balls
thing.
Give me one second.
Yeah, I'll keep talking. So I feel it's
tough to you have to get a really strong
developer that's really confident with
those kind of things and recognize that I
need to kick ass and Oh, hey, puppy. Hey,
buddy, that's a puppy. with little needle
teeth. I really need to kick butt and give
something that somebody else isn't going
to give if I want to stay ahead of the
curve. And that drives progress for both
sides, right? So I think it's great in
that matter.
Let's see, what else? What else are there
questions? Is this guy going to bite you?
Well, what a cutie, what a cutie.
Let's see. Any other questions? Smart AI
Learning says currently AI can generate
and play 3D games within a model as seen
in Google projects. If AI generated mining
becomes possible, how might it impact
other algorithms? I don't think there - I
mean, mining is still going to create,
still going to be requiring of power,
right? You're still going to need
something to actually compute the problem
that the blockchain is presenting you
with. So I'm not sure what you're asking
that Smart AI, but perhaps you're speaking
about generated mining. That doesn't make
sense to me.
I have no idea.
Yeah, so as far as mining goes, there's
no way around solving the problem, right?
Even if you use AI to try to solve the
problem, you're still using a crap ton of
video cards to do it, right? So the power
consumption might equal out the same
there, if that's what you're asking for.
If you're asking for other things about if
AI or quantum computers essentially can
figure out that kind of thing, well,
Ergo's kind of got that figured out
already in that Joe's idea on sigma chains
or side chains can create quantum
resistant chains that you can move your
store value over to, to protect it. Things
like that can always be made. Ergo can
kind of stay on the head of the curve like
that. So that's what I love about Ergo
too, Joe, is that the ability to pivot is
freaking insane with a project like Ergo,
right? When you have open source, you can
always tweak it, always modify it, you can
always extend it. So it gives you a lot of
flexibility.
Yeah, I see the same thing at our
college. We have - we're one of the
smaller colleges inside Cornell
University, the architecture department.
And I will say to my counterparts, they're
like, what are you doing? And what are you
doing? I'm like, I just spun this up the
other day. And I threw it at the students.
They're like, What? And I'm like, Yeah,
who cares? This is a cool thing that we're
trying to do. And the students can test it
out for us. They like it. They like it. If
they don't, they don't. And people in
bigger entities just can't do that, and
especially when things are closed source.
So yeah, I think Ergo really champions at
that where they have the ability to just
pivot on a dime. kushti can say hey, let's
try to think of this or a community dev
can come on and do that. But yeah, that's
what I love about Ergo the ability to
pivot on a freaking time about that kind
of stuff. Your dog's adorable Joe.
I look at it as a success, honestly, that
there's not a lot of demand for a token
launch platform. Now, you may say, there's
not many projects starting in Ergo, blah,
blah, blah. That's why it's not needed.
The way I look at it is that there's so
much tooling involved in Ergo with
airdrops tools, with token distribution
tools. Sigma Lock should be coming out any
time now. We're waiting for kushti when he
gets a free second to review the
contracts. That's all. There's so many
things and toolings on Ergo that things
like Bulbar, things like GreasyCex, things
like - What else? All these other projects
can launch and do token distribution
without even using a platform like that.
So I see that as not only, hey, it sucks
that Ergopad can't sustain their model on
Ergo, but the decks are kind of stacked
against them with that kind of open source
tooling that anybody can use and jump
onto. Did you send your puppy away, Joe?
You have little Ergo bird things for your
puppies.
Oh, Joe hit the wrong button.
All right. Let's see. We can jump into
the... Let's see if he's still here,
actually. What did he mute? One moment.
There's he just muted his video. That's
all. No biggie. He's probably spanking his
puppies.
All right. So back to let's see if we
have any questions we can answer while
he's gone.
New world disorder says you can't change
the world, but you can change your world.
Yeah, exactly.
You can change your network, too.
Right, right. That was back when we were
talking about outside of the US
recognizing that these toolings are great
for them. Yeah, I agree. Yeah. I mean, the
centralized systems are louder, much
louder much more appealing to people but I
think slowly by slowly we'll get more and
more people over to the side of where you
feel like there's a benefit to being in
control of your own bank of your own
resources. Yeah I think we're in the
infancy stages of it that's for sure that
is for sure I think we're pretty early in
what these protocols will be capable of.
Did you beat your dog Joe? No just
outside.
You got a bone you can throw him?
Yeah, just throw a ball.
So I used to live in. Before I live in
town here where I am now, I used to live
in the in the boonies. We had 35 acres,
not much the Colorado standards, Joe, but
it was pretty good for New York standards.
So we have 35 acres and our dogs used to
love to run outside, right? You just let
him outside it, whatever time they'd come
back when they were ready kind of thing.
But those puppies would bring back like
deer ribs or like a whole leg of a deer.
Your dogs do that to you. Sometimes it's
just a huge bone in the yard. You're like,
okay, where the hell did that come from?
That happens. And you get the dewormer
out, then you get the shots out.
All right. Mark the shark. Mark the
shark, everybody. Mark the shark's got a
question, but Mark the shark is in Florida
right now. He's going to the Mining
Disrupt Conference. He's going to spread
the glory of GPU mining and peer-to-peer
networks. So that's going to be - Awesome
that Mark's there. We've never been to
district before, it's mainly a Bitcoin
focused I imagine Joe right Bitcoin
probably So, it's gonna be nice to have
him there putting the GPU mining in
people's ears the word of Ergo and all
that kind of stuff.
Don't worry about your dog Joe. We can
hear you. It's no big deal. Just shake it
off. Really don't worry about it.
Alright, Mark the shark says with
sub-blocks could make a tool to compete
with Zelle - seems it runs similar to a
blockchain. Zelle is what Zelle's a cash
transaction app, right? Transferring money
to each other peer to peer, right? That's
so that's what I feel the attractiveness
of sub-blocks will be, right? One thing
people need to remember is that finality
is key, right? Finality is the security
that dApp providers and central exchanges
are going to rely on. So whether if Ergo
settles in two minutes and they say 10
blocks is what we trust that is not going
to be rolled back on the chain. I don't
think it's ever been a rollback on Ergo,
but whatever. Sub-blocks doesn't really
change that from a dApp or a central
exchange point of view, right? Because as
kushti said, these are kind of weak
blocks, right? So they're still going to
want some sort of confirmation in there
that gives them the finality and the trust
that they can say, yeah, OK, you've
transferred us $10,000. Go ahead and take
it out of your bank.
What sub-blocks is going to be a boon for
is for peer-to-peer transactions, right?
It's going to allow me to transfer ones to
Joe within a few seconds, then hop off
that with chain transactions, all of that
kind of thing. So yes, Mark's totally
right. Mark, that sub-blocks will be a
great addition for these kind of really
fast peer-to-peer transactions that you
can kind of have a soft finality for. So
yeah, looking forward to that.
I think kushti just released RC3 for
Mining Testnet. I'm still on RC2 for
Mining Testnet. So there's no real need to
upgrade. But yeah, excited to see the
progress on that.
Your dog's all right, Joe. Joe, it's like
babysitting three-year-olds. You're
babysitting your nieces, your nephews,
dogs. It might be easier with
three-year-olds, Joe. I'd tell you, they'd
be asleep by now, I think.
No, there's a lot of potential
applications that that opens up. The big
question is just going to be the
assumptions of settlement, right?
Exactly. Yep. So I think, yeah, honestly,
I think it's going to be a big plus to
peer to peer kind of things. You walk up
to a friend, you send them money, boom,
it's done. It's there with sub-blocks. You
want to withdraw $30,000 from exchange.
You send $30,000 worth of ERGs to the
exchange. Yeah. They're going to probably
still wait for 10, 20 main blocks for that
kind of transaction to finalize. So don't
think that that's going to make it any
faster there, but yeah.
What else, Joe?
I don't know. Any other questions?
My sister got me this candle for a white
elephant gift at Christmas. I haven't
burnt it yet. No other questions. We can
keep going. Let's talk about, why don't we
talk about the dev updates and then we can
come back to shooting the shit if we get
there and we're still awake. Sound good?
All right. Let's see. I'm going to hit
the dev update button. It's going to
switch scenes. Oh, beautiful. Perfect. All
right. Do you have the dev update in front
of you, Joe?
All right. Perfect. The first one, this
is from 319. This is an NBR with Nautilus.
They released version 1.1.0. And since we
haven't done an update yet, since 1.0,
everybody should make sure to upgrade to
1.0. Absolutely beautiful, very beautiful
wallet for the Chrome plugin extension.
Takes dark mode. It looks fantastic. Love
it. So he released version 1.10, polished
SigmaUSD dApp implementation, fixed a
ledger connection bug, fixed Firefox
compatibility issues. Added semi-automatic
release CI, which has built the different
targets and release happens in the CI
workflow. Publishing in stores is done
manually after functional and security
tests. Minor UI tweaks. Next up, add
internationalization support. That's a big
word to save for three cups of peach
schnapps.
All right. Looks like next we have
kushti. He's been working on the Ergo
protocol and reference client doing some
research and development. With Scripto
3.1.0, with Scala 3 support released,
along with new version for Scorix, Utils,
and D-Box. So Josnia has been on that for
PRs working towards that end. So that'd be
nice to see Scala 3. Ergo 6.0.0 RC3 has
been released. A couple of fixed PRs for
6.0 has merged into the 6.0 branch. He's
working on polishing to propose for
review. So everybody out there, please
take a look. It looks like polishing 6.0.0
PR for the node. It's a proposal for
review as well. For sub-blocks, Forks
resolution is done and covered with tests,
planning the peer-to-peer layer for
sub-blocks propagation. So that's another
step.
And also, people who are running nodes,
please, if you're starting up a new node,
don't take 6.0, right? Drop down. Those
are pre-releases. It's not going to work
on the normal node. You have to drop down
to 5.2.1 or whatever the latest 5 is kind
of thing. So make sure you do that. And
also FYI, our community note update. The
RocksDB database loves SSDs. Man, that
thing is fast, Joe.
For some reason, my node on my
aero.aep.cornell.edu explorer just chunked
out. It toasted. I can't remember why.
It's been too long. So I had to rebuild it
from scratch and I use the latest RocksDB
and holy cow. Nothing is fast. If I go to
my SigmaUSD oracle wallet, you know,
usually on the old node that took about 15
seconds 20 seconds to load that things
loaded in five seconds, because that thing
has like 30 40 50 thousand transactions
from SigmaUSD oracle but yeah RocksDB if
anybody has the time to and they want to
redo it to RocksDB. It loves SSDs super
fast. It's fantastic.
All right, let's see what else we have.
kushti says, ChainCash. He's got a paper
out. It's done. Will appear on preprint
server shortly. Awesome. I'm really
excited for ChainCash. ChainCash is like
the thing that, no, it feels like - It
feels like we're taking power away from
the government with this kind of thing. If
it goes on, if people actually use it and
use it for what it's made, it means that
entities and groups can actually mint
notes based on their reserves and people
can pass them out and actually use them as
forms of payment for things that represent
the reserve. Like, how cool is that? How
cool is that for an entity to be able to
mint their own currency? Right. That's
flipping awesome. And you may say, well,
why don't they just mint a token and sell
their token and that kind of thing? This
is totally different. This is literally a
note that is backed up by a reserve from a
treasury of an entity that does it or
backed up by anything else. It could be
backed up by physical goods at some point,
depending if they can figure out a best
way to rationalize that on chain. But
yeah, super cool, super excited for
ChainCash. That's going to be really cool.
Joe, your dogs are fine. Don't stress
out, buddy. All right, what else we got?
I'll go with Dexy since it's still
kushti. Dexy, he says deployed UI for
Testnet. They've got the XYZ link right
there for Ergo-Fi. Please give it a try.
On Sigma Rust, Python binding is done by
disk and pushed to PyPI. PyPI. I've
reviewed and approved another couple of
6.0 PRS by do sec. Great. It looks like
you got Kobe Selardoor.
All right. So it looks good to be back.
Good to have you back. Kobe. The Ergo node
open API fixed, issue 2199. It's worked on
open CI issue 2202, with sigma state
getting to know the Merkle trees for sigma
script. Like he reviewed one of Joe's next
PR node reviews for sigma state and
script.
Oh, all right. Let's see what else we
have.
Oh, holy cow, Joe, we've got a Paideia
update from Luivatra. I need a sip of
peach schnapps after this.
All right, Luivatra, we got Paideia fix
an issue, breaking display of token amount
for some tokens and send funds proposals
resulted in and. Man tracking down a bug
that happens around start of new staking
cycle, causing the stake to be corrupted.
A reset of the off chain bot fixes this,
but not ideal. So trying to make permanent
fix. If anybody has Paideia sitting on the
wallet, please, please join the General's
Paideia DAO, right? Stake that Paideia,
get more Paideia and participate in voting
on changes on the overall Paideia DAO. So
you're missing an opportunity there if
you're sitting on Paideia in your wallet
or the crux. Added better error handling
on some of the endpoints inspired by
tokens being minted with funky registers.
I wonder what Luivatra's funky definition
is.
All right, you got Joseph Mice there.
All right. All in Beene. I've been
putting the final touches to finally close
the first version. I've done a great job
to significantly improve the front end.
Once we have everything tied up, we'll
proceed to implement support for other
tokens besides the ERG. With Celaut.
I'm still working on refining and
maturing what I have to take confidence
steps forward, although I'm happy with how
things are going.
Joe, I think we need some meme coins with
your dogs. I think we need some dog meme
coins.
Do your dogs ever sleep, Joe? Do your
dogs ever sleep?
All right, what else we have here? Let's
see. Anything else?
We've got some debugging going on, some
cross help here. Issues requested for
Sigma Rust. We're going to contribute to
it and they're prepping for the developer
chat tomorrow. Yeah. Cool, that's it for
that chat there. You switch back to our
double window here. OK, we're switched
back.
Let's see what else we have for question
here we have. No more questions we have.
Would be sick to see a Stripe type app for
Natalie to plug into this AI-generated
games, Mark says. By the way, Mark's
developed, for those of you who don't
know, Mark's fine-tuned a LLM to, what did
he do? He fine-tuned an LLM to respond
back with node queries or something like
that. I've had too much peach schnapps to
really center on exactly what he did. It's
been too long, but something like that. So
Mark does LLM tuning in his IRL life, in
real life life stuff. So he's really
diving into that for Ergo.
For those who don't know, Mark runs the
Sigmanauts mining pool. If you guys are
mining and you're mining to anything other
than the Sigmanauts pool, consider
pointing to the Sigmanauts pool because
there's bonus tokens that are there. We
also are the only pool that collects
storage rent. So there's a lot of extra
ERGs in there that come out each week as
well as bonus tokens. And there's a really
we're on Telegram, big chat in there,
super fun to hang out there and chat. So
there's no reason why you shouldn't join
the Sigmanauts pool there as my plug for
the Sigmanauts pool.
What did you do with your dogs? Did you
strangle them, Joe?
No, I put the puppy in the box. It's got
the little cage, the quiet box, the wire
box.
Oh, that's funny. It doesn't try to bite
the wire.
No, no, no. It's just like a state of
depression.
It's like crap. I screwed up.
Yeah, probably should have started there,
to be honest.
No, it was cute hearing your pups, Joe.
All right, what else? Anything else to
chat about? It's 11:05. I'm sure my wife's
in bed, so it doesn't matter what time I
go to bed at this point.
What's new for Rosen Joe? What's on the
roadmap after Doge?
Oh, after Doge. I definitely like to get
more focused on the Nervos bridge. I think
that if we're going to talk about EVM
environments, there's definitely the
possibility to go to something like base
or ink, get into the exchange sphere, just
because there's liquidity there. If we're
talking Bitcoin forks, probably Bitcoin
Cash. It's a big community and I don't
know, generally is a little bit more, I
would say aligned with UTXO. That's some
good development happening there through
time. So let's see.
All right. I know there's some, when the
Sigmanauts was an ask to use some EF funds
to help bolster, there was the Binance
pool. Or the I think it was PancakeSwap. I
think it was a Binance pull on Pancake or
something like that. So I think that I
think the EF was like, yeah, we'll put up
for a vote and it probably will pass. So
expect to possibly see some more liquidity
in that pool. So that's super sweet.
Oh, Byron asks when the US Ergo meetup
Joe, you've got a building.
I have a place in Colorado Springs. If
the community ever wants to have a U.S.
meetup. Yeah, I've got keys to.
That's pretty central, too. I think
that's a good spot for it.
Yeah, I've got keys to a place in
Colorado Springs.
We have like a we got to have activity
lists of like an Ergo hike where we hike
to the summit of some mountain.
And I mean, it depends on the time of
year. There's always stuff to do around
Colorado, but it's pretty much downtown,
downtown. So it's a good spot.
All right. I wonder how many people get
out there.
I don't know. I've always said I have
keys. I don't really want to do anything
more than that. And I think that's a
pretty good contribution. So community
gets building.
You figure it out.
Yeah, exactly. I mean, yeah, I got a
pretty busy life. I can't really I don't
have the bandwidth for that, but I do have
a place. So if people want to make that
happen, we could definitely do it.
Maybe we should talk about it more in the
next couple of weeks or months to try to
get more people interested.
I've done my part.
You've done your part. You've offered
Joe. Yeah, perfect. Well, what else do you
have on the back burner besides Rosen?
Anything else kicking around?
Working through the rollup contracts, a
lot of potential edge cases to be aware
of. So that's something just go slow, do
it right. And everything will go kind of
downhill from that point in terms of
coast. It's like the hardest part of
Lithos, probably the humming.
I think we can get qx() to come out to
Colorado.
I don't know, maybe if you ask him.
So talk more about Lithos. What step are
you at? I saw an update the other day.
At this point, basically refactoring the
rollup contracts. At that point,
everything from there is kind of downhill.
It's just like, let's tweak it. Let's see
how it performs. Play around with the LETS
token. So we'll actually have kind of a
public test net after this next milestone,
which would be real cool to see.
And there's no, this is not, you know
how, well, let's take Rosen for example,
right? Everything's written back to the
Ergo chain, right? Lithos. So if another
chain wants to adopt it, there's no write
back to Ergo chain for any of the
settlements, right? It'll be purely on
their chain if they rewrite it for their
chain.
Yeah, we have the potential to take
Lithos across Bitcoin, just proof of work
in general. So it is designed to be pretty
modular.
So for those people watching that aren't
familiar with Lithos, in short, it's an
ability to kind of solo mine but still
pool mine based on chain. So you don't
have to join something like Herominers, a
single mining pool. You're essentially
solo mining, but still collectively you
can join a decentralized pool,
essentially.
Yeah, you'll be able to join kind of a
special type of mining pool that will
allow you as the miner to build blocks and
you'll still have the potential to get
shares. It's just how that's calculated
and done is not a secret.
Awesome. Awesome.
I think somebody's happy. I put the puppy
in the box.
I think that's a thing. A big thank you.
What's this one's name?
This is Bella.
Oh, Bella. Italian. Very nice. What kind
of dog?
Shepherd mix, I guess.
Oh, very nice. Would she be able to take
your no, your child could take everybody,
right? There's no question about that.
No, she and the shower friends.
Oh, that's sweet. That's very sweet. Do
they does your child sleep on your bed
with you?
No, usually close up in front of the
doors to the house.
Really like guard dog?
Yeah, he's that's kind of their nature.
That's amazing.
Yeah, so he's got the house on lock 24/7.
All right, I think let's see how long
we've been going on for we've been going
for oh an hour and four minutes Joe And
rusting just said good night. So if
rusting says good night, and we don't have
anything else to talk about let me finish
this up here
All right, everybody, thank you for
coming. Sorry if the dogs were crazy. I'm
watching an 18-month-old puppy, and it's
kind of half velociraptor and half
crackhead. So I'm doing my best.
Productivity has declined for the last
day, but I can eat it.
I got to make it back to the liquor shelf
to put this away, and then got to stumble
upstairs. I don't know if I'll make it. My
wife might find me on the landing in the
morning, Joe.
Well, Taylor, I said I'm sorry.
Thanks, everybody, for watching. It's fun
to do these live Dev updates. We'll do
them as often as we can get Joe to
function at this hour.
All right. Have a good one, everybody.
Ciao.