Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, and a
hey, hey ho. And yeah, this, you know, do
not adjust your television. We are
controlling the transmission on this
YouTube channel, because that's how
YouTube works. But anyway, yeah, so this
is your weekly AMA with me and, wait a
second. OK, so we got kushti here. We all
know him. And so the other guy without the
hat kind of looks like the guy with the
hat they usually hear. But anyway, say hi
to everybody. Guys with and without hats.
Good morning, everybody.
Hi, everyone. My pleasure to be here
again.
Morning? It's not morning, it's evening.
What the hell, what are you talking about?
Quality extreme, yeah yeah. So there's a
lot of exciting stuff happening in the
Ergoverse. I'm actually pretty excited
about the Disco Solaris crossover. That's
really cool. I always really like the art
and Disco Solaris. That's kind of like my
cup of tea, you know, that kind of stuff
like new futuristic stuff or whatever you
call it. I always liked it so I'm glad
that they bridged over to ERG and looks
like they're actually already moving some
NFTs. Do you have, do you guys have a
Disco Solaris Ergo NFT yet? I don't, not
yet but yeah I'll try to buy some.
Yeah, that's MewFinance is doing it
automated, right? So they'll read the
metadata on Cardano and dump it into
register over on Ergo and remint a token.
And they don't burn it all the way back.
They throw it in a lock contract. Yeah.
What's that? The Dark Lord or Dark Knight.
Darko, Danny Darko, he told me that
they're mewing it over there. Like I said,
I'm just happy to see that because I've
always been an admirer of Disco Solaris
when it was even just on Cardano. The
community has always been really cool. I
know the people that made that project.
You know, they always kind of try to just
kind of be really community focused. So,
yeah, I'm glad that they're on Ergo,
because I know they've always actually
been fans. So I'm glad that they finally
kind of decided to move to Ergo. So what
else do we have? Some emission reduction?
We emit less now?
We do. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, that happened the other day. We're
down to, what is it, 15, kushti?
Yeah, so 15 now. And yeah, it's quite an
amazing house. Well, somewhat it was.
I think it's a good opportunity to
mention that Sigmanauts Mining Pool remind
people that they're collecting storage
rent and that hopefully at this point can
do a little bit of offsetting compared to,
you know, taking into account the emission
reduction. So for those of you not in a
pool or in a pool and want bonus tokens
and storage rent, join up with the
Sigmanauts Pool, please.
Wow, you sound really excited about that
QX.
Was that too formulaic? That was too,
like, monotone, wasn't it? Yeah, that was
a little bit like... Hey guys, join up
with the Sigmanauts pool. Is that better?
Now you're getting all choppy and
robotic. I mean, you know, you kind of
are, but still, though, you shouldn't be
as choppy and robotic as usual. Yeah,
yeah, so that's cool. What else has been
going on?
Well, we're talking about an Ergo meetup
in Colorado Springs this September, early
October.
I saw Joe talk about that. That would be
really cool. Yeah, actually, what did he
say that he was going to, he's thinking of
doing it?
It's either the first weekend in
September, which is like the third, or
else like the 10th, whatever the first two
weekends are. We're going to put out a
vote to see which one is more attractive
to the most people.
Well, you know what would actually be
really cool would actually be to make it
around the time where Evo is happening in
Vegas, because you're going to have a
bunch of people like, I mean, Vegas is not
super close, but it's not super far either
from Colorado. I'll be there, so I'd love
to make it out. I don't know if I'll be
able to come out to the US just for that,
but if I'm already in the US, I could make
an effort to come out, and I'm sure others
would as well, since they're all in the
same. But anyway, that's something to talk
to Joe about, I think. But I think that
might make sense. I don't know.
So Rare Evo 2025 is when?
It's the beginning of August, I think.
Oh, that's pretty close.
Pretty close. It's April.
I know, but planning, Dan, planning,
organizing. We got to get the band. We got
to get the strippers, that kind of stuff,
you know.
Well, I already got those tokenized, so
it's good to go.
I will put out a community vote and see
what people want to do.
This is not a democracy. This is like a
little bit of a democracy. It's controlled
by a select group of secret individuals.
Joe's got a location that he's got to
check dates on that's not always
available, so we've got to work around
that. Hotel prices weren't terrible in the
area. I think around September it was like
120 bucks a night or something like that.
Or you just pitch a tent on one of Joe's
2000 acres kind of thing. Doesn't Joe like
own a mountain or something or parts of
mountains?
Yeah, just there's caves we can we can
you know, we can just go in a cave or
something and just you know Airbnb that.
Yeah, 100.
What else is happening? Was it last week
or this week? We had some GraphQL issues
if people were noticing. Two of the three
load balancers went down. Load balance
machines were not performing well, I
guess. So they just needed to bounce with
NGINX and they worked fine after that. But
that brought us to how Nautilus works.
Right now Nautilus defaults to Sigma space
GraphQL. But hidden there's a hidden list
of rollover servers for GraphQL and right
now in the Ergo ecosystem we have at least
four or five maybe six public ones so
we're getting Captain Nemo a list just to
make sure he's got them all so that if
something like this happens again then
it'll keep rolling over to all the
available GraphQL servers kind of thing so
that was interesting to see those. It's
good to see where the choke points are
that we've overlooked before before things
go crazy, right? So that was good and bad
at the same time to see, I think. Dan,
what about, we get a lot of questions
about Palmyra and all that kind of stuff
lately, how's Palmyra going?
Who?
Palm Myra.
Who's that? Do I know her? Oh, yeah,
yeah, yeah. So, you know, we got the
launch on the 14th of August. And this is
going to be the very, very first
cross-chain launch using Rosen Bridge. So
we're going to be utilizing Rosen Bridge
to launch on both Cardano and Binance on
BNB. So that's going to be really cool. So
we're using DEXs on both Cardano and
Binance. We're going to be launching on
MintSwap on the Cardano side and on
PancakeSwap on the EVM side. We're already
talking to Mo and Joe and making sure that
everything is kosher. We have staking on
both. The thing about it is, I was talking
to Mew about potentially doing something
over there. The problem is that so one of
the things that we ran into when we were
finalizing everything for TGE is we had to
get approval from the Seychelles FSA. So
the company that actually is minting the
tokens is a Seychelles company. It's not
from Palmyra. It's from a partner company.
And that company had to get a license from
the Seychelles FSA, which was the first
actually ever utility token license issued
over there, which is pretty cool, I think,
and that was issued for Palm. And that
took quite a bit of time, well, not quite,
but more time than we thought it was going
to take or hoped that it was going to take
because it was literally, we're literally
the first ones to go through the
regulatory process. And so we finally did
get it. The thing about it is that to keep
it classified as a utility token and not a
security, there has to be clear utility in
every chain. And so essentially what we
need to have is staking support for every
chain. So right now we have Cardano, we
have EVM because that's where our main
token supply is on. We still haven't built
it out for Ergo. So once we build it out
for Ergo, which is obviously in the
pipeline, then we're also going to be able
to start a liquidity pool on Ergo, as in
us doing it. Without that, we can't
officially do it because then that would
violate regulations and basically screw up
the utility token classification. But
that's obviously doable. You can bridge
the tokens through Rosen Bridge and use
them on Ergo as well. So if you want
RS-POM on Ergo, you have the ability to do
that. All right, but so what do you need
sort of like staking context? So for
basically we need to have staking support,
so we have dynamic staking. MGPi and Luca
developed it for Cardano and for EVM
because that's our two main token holder
groups are mostly Cardano and some EVM on
BNB. And so, like I said, that's what
we're using Rosen Bridge for is to be able
to move back and forth between these two
ecosystems. Like I said, for us to be able
to support Ergo officially, we would need
to have staking on Ergo or else it could
actually be classified as security on
Ergo. So that's what we need. We need to
have staking support for staking on Ergo
before we can spin up any kind of
liquidity pools on Ergo. I was researching
this today because like I said, Mew, I was
talking to Mew about this and I talked to
Sam about this. And yeah, that looks like
for us to be able to do that, that's what
we need to do. And like I said, it's in a
pipeline, but it's not gonna be available
at launch on the 14th, unfortunately, but
we'll get it going. Oh, I see.
But staking, so before Ergopad guys and
Paideia, well, did staking contracts, so
maybe you can talk with Louis about it.
There is something that we can
potentially do. I'm not sure because also,
yeah, we, Louis Wattray is also working
with us. You know, we're kind of like the,
we take all your best Ergo peeps and get
them to work for us. Haha. So Louis
Wattray is also working on smart contracts
with us. So maybe potentially it's
something that he can look into because he
also worked on Paideia, right? He, or he
still is working on Paideia. I know that
qx() knows all about that. Is he working
on Paideia QX? What happened to you? You
sound really distant.
Louie.
Louie, yeah, yeah. We need Marty to work
on the front end of Paideia as well.
Marty, if you're watching this at some
point, fix the front end of Paideia,
please. Thank you.
Well, okay. But I'm saying, you know,
just right now, thinking about my own
project, I need to have staking support on
Ergo for me to do that.
Yeah, you got it. You got it with
Paideia. You've got the tech there with
the Ergopad. It's all there. You just got
to put it together, Dan.
Yeah, so yes, it's not, like I said, it's
on the roadmap. It's just like I said,
it's not going to be available on the
14th. So you would have to, if you want to
be able to do stuff with Palm, if you want
to stake with Palm, use Rosen to either go
to Cardano or to EVM depending on what you
want to play with. If you want to play
with both, play with both. I'm actually
really excited about this because I think
this is going to be... Well, I know it is
going to be the first official launch, a
multi-chain launch using Rosen, and I
would really like to see what it looks
like in action because that's actually
going to bring... We are lining everything
up to make sure that there is going to be
a bunch of trading arbitrage between the
two chains. And so it would be really
interesting to see how Rosen stands up to
real-time arbitrage. I think it'll do
well. we're betting on it. We're invested
in that decision, but I think it'll
actually do well, and I think that'll
actually kind of give other projects a
nice preview, I don't know why I said it
weird, preview of how you can do a
cross-chain launch using Ergo tech. It's
pretty exciting to me. And like I said, I
would really like to see how it all works
out next week.
Yeah. Well, we've seen in practice or in
examples, arbitrage happening between
Cardano and Ergo simply with, Rosen, Rosen
ERG. So, and, and, and Rosen Bridge. So
yeah, it seems to work well, at least, you
know, you'll, you'll notice that during
times of pumps, a lot of arbitrage is
happening back and forth between the two.
So yeah, cool. That'll be neat.
Yeah. Oh, actually I got a, I got a
question, from, Luke, a Gray Smith. So
then if you buy a bunch of Palm tokens on
Cardano using Ada, do you lose my, do I
lose my Cardano voting power? I mean,
yeah, because I think Cardano, you can
only vote with, with, with Cardano. I
don't think they have like, what, what is
it? I mean, actually, I talked to Charles
about this a while back, but I don't think
there's anything like Babel voting support
or anything on Cardano just yet. It would
be interesting if there was. It would be
pretty cool if there was. But I don't
think there is Babel. I guess that what
you would call it, what would you call
something like that if you're voting with
native assets? Proxy tokens, I guess.
Proxy, OK, yeah. I don't think they have
anything like that on Cardano yet, but
hopefully that's something that's going to
be in the pipeline. And like I said,
actually, I talked to Charles about this.
Couple of years ago, I think. It's been a
few years since I talked to him, and he
did think that that's actually something
that's been really interesting, but I
think it's just a matter of priorities of
what they want to deploy now versus down
the line. Yeah, so the answer is yes, you
would. I would imagine lose voting power,
but you would gain voting power and
participation power in the Palm economy in
a Palmyra ecosystem where you can actually
use those tokens for the Palm DAO, which
is going to be its own ecosystem. And
that's also something that we're going to
be launching. And actually, potentially,
once we bridge it, we'll also bridge it
over to Ergo. We're most likely going to
be using the Paideia infrastructure for
that for the DAO.
The ADA that you sell Palm for, it goes
into some sort of treasury, regardless of
whether you spend it or save it. You could
do some sort of percentage voting power
there because if, let's say, you poll
daily the amount of Palm holders on
Cardano that have purchased with ADA and
directly into the treasury or the
liquidity pool. You could then, use that
ADA. Oh, well, this is, I guess this is
only for ICOs, right? If you actually hold
the ADA anymore, but if you hold the ADA,
you could offer a percentage of voting to
Rosen Palm holders and Palm holders and
you guys vote yourselves according to
their plans, depending if you have that
DAO infrastructure.
Now we kind of make us see, I mean, that
essentially would make a DRAP on us.
Yeah, exactly. Yep. I mean, that's, yeah,
but the thing is, DRAPs are delegating
their ADA. So, like, I don't actually, you
know, the DRAP, or people are delegating
their ADA to DRAPs like they do with
staking. So, you don't actually let the
DRAP custody the ADA. But if we're
custodying the ADA, then we, like, I mean,
theoretically, we can be our own DRAP, but
that's kind of, you know, well, first of
all, it's a bit moot because you know, you
got de-reps with that, you know, have way,
way more voting power than, you know, than
we would if we custody or if we did
de-repping with the ADA that we hold. And
also, you know, that ADA is being used for
other things. So it's like, you know, it's
kind of a...
Yeah, I'm just saying it could be an
attractive alternative to saying, hey, you
buy Palm, you can still vote. You can
still have some voting power on the
Cardano ecosystem.
It is possible, but I would actually
would like to see some sort of like proxy
token support for that, because I think
that would actually make it a lot more
interesting for people who are investing
in native assets in both Cardano and Ergo,
because with Ergo, if you have native
asset support for voting, then you could
potentially use Rosen to bridge some
assets back and forth between Cardano and
Ergo. So you can use like Ergo tokens and
make them into RS whatever on the other
side. You can use RS ERG on the Cardano
side for voting. That would be kind of
cool, I think.
Yeah. I mean, the tricky part is locking
up the ADA that you purchase that proxy
token with, right? Otherwise, it's double
voting rights at some point and you're
diluting the voting pool.
Yeah, yeah. And, and, and, and you may,
it tells me to, whatever that means.
I think you, I think you know what it
means then.
I, well, that that's actually, you know,
our head of business development in
Argentina, his name is Facundo Ramirez,
and his nickname is Kufa, but sometimes
it's FAKU. So he might be talking about
Facundo. I don't know. That's a
possibility. So maybe he's just saying
shout out to Kufa. So yeah, Jume, if it is
a shout out to Kufa, then shout out to
Kufa. If not, then I'm going to talk to
the CIA about this and you know what I
mean.
Oh, he knows what you mean. kushti, you
got node 6.0 RC4 out successfully on
mainnet, no errors, fully synced. And you
were saying something like, you had a
tweet the other day that said that you
know of none of these infrastructure
upgrades have ever broken the chain,
unlike other.
Yeah, but for RC4, you need to understand
that probably this version would be broken
after RC5, and RC5 would be identical to
the final release. There are some fixes
still needed to be included. So two pull
requests now under review, so once
approved and merged, RC5 will be released
and yeah, that's basically the final
version of 6.0. So, yeah, RC4 is not
stable release, still, right, but you can
sync the mainnet with it, at least. And,
yeah, well... To the best of my knowledge,
no any applications were broken due to
protocol upgrades. That's kind of
philosophy here, I guess, the non-breaking
development process. Application
developers may be confident that what
they're building will stay. The ecosystem
could be built as a kind of I don't know,
like a medieval cathedral, right? So
people built them for centuries and well,
still they're around us and yeah, well,
very solid constructions after all. So,
yeah, well, the idea here is to have a
good foundation for building digital
financial cathedrals, like solid
constructions. And non-breaking protocol,
core protocol development is absolutely
crucial here.
Yeah, I'm looking at the node list,
kushti, and I still see there's nodes on
stuff as old as 5.0.9, for goodness sake,
back there in the active node list, 5.0.8.
And they're still trucking along, no
problem.
Oh, that's okay. So you can use even
4.0.100, right? Something like that. But
what I was talking about is applications,
so if you have some application done in
ErgoScript back in 2019, right deployed on
the blockchain around that time you can
use well it's right now so all the boxes
are spendable and exactly in the same way
as six years ago. And yeah, well, there
are more exciting things. So now we have
finally, Merkleized Sub-Syntax trees and
Merkleized Finite State Machines, examples
done in ErgoScript. And they're allowing
for a lot of cool things, like you may
have a wallet which is controlled by one
of, let's say, 100 policies, right? So you
may specify well, 10 or 100 different
spending conditions and instead of some
huge script, so you are just including
hash, Merkle tree root hash, right, and
well, policies are written under this tree
and then you present script, you're
executing during spending and while
proving execution of it so yeah that would
be helpful for some complex wallet
scenarios like Bybit, for example, right,
that's a recent scenario when hackers are
able to drain the wallets, right, so you
may have like different spending policies
protecting a big wallet like Bybit, right,
and well, to avoid, well, big scripts and
to avoid showing all the logic actually
also, so to have somewhat privacy, you may
use this Merkleized solution for storing a
lot of policies in a compact way. Well,
with Merkleized Finite State Machine, you
may have multi-stage contract execution
with states, well, been progressing right
from one state to another and when the
contract is reaching final state, well,
the UTXO is becoming spendable so yeah
it's even more powerful construction so
yeah may be useful in different contexts
and also to have some privacy so for
example if you have some disputes in your
contract some dispute path then yeah you
need to show it only during the dispute
right otherwise if some escrow for example
is used in a dispute process so well the
identity of an escrow agent is hidden
right before the dispute starts and so on
so yeah a lot of possibilities and well
contracts were done back in 2018 but yeah
now are they available in ErgoScript form
so yeah you may check so a lot so of new
possibilities for ErgoScript developers,
which were available on a low level
before. And also for sub-blocks, so I'm
already doing initial tests of multi-peer
network. Well, actually I have two peers,
one on my laptop, another is on server.
So, well, I'm also doing debugging of
both.
Is this what you called for the other day
where you want somebody to help you run a
DevNet, kushti?
Yeah, so for now, well, it's better for
me to have, well, just two nodes of mine,
both in debug session, right? So I'm doing
debugging of both nodes in parallel to see
how the peer layer is working. And then,
yeah, well, after some time it would be
good to have more peers with mining. So,
well, I'm doing CPU mining on both peers.
So, yeah, well, CPU mining is enough.
Well, also for Dexy we have found people
willing to hold update keys for the
initial periods and also we considered
bootstrapping. So, yeah, well, everything
is set for launch. May not launch. Then we
may proceed.
Dan, can you click on Ursa Miner's
question? It's a good segue into this.
Let's see.
Ursa Miner says, please explain how
oracles are safe from hacks or gaming of
price feeds like LBMA or Shanghai index.
Do you want to take that one or you want
me to take it or what do you want to do?
Well, I'm sorry, kushti can take it or I
can take it. That's fine. Either one.
Well, I mean, I can talk about this
because actually this is something also
that we're going to be building out for
Lithos. I can chime in on this because
Ursa Miner is talking about LBMA. LBMA is
a commodities gold standard. LBMA gold is
the standard for commodity trading for
gold. It has specific purity. It's 99.8, I
think. That's basically what makes it
uniform. If you have LBMA gold, then it
doesn't matter where the gold comes from.
Now, the problem here is that with gold,
it happens with, you know, with others
like lithium, it also happens where there
is price manipulation happening, right?
And so you have, well, so with gold, you
actually have more even price reporting
because there's a lot of places that
report the price. But with something like
lithium, you don't have enough places that
you have a uniform reporting standard.
What you have is you have these
disparities in price, which can then be
manipulated by producers that want to make
the price go up. Say there's some
producers in some Latam countries that
will stop producing lithium to make the
price go up. Even though they can't
produce it, they feel like they want to
make more money, so they just stop
producing it and increase demand. It's not
easy to do that with gold because there
are just too many, right? But essentially
what happens is even if you have a bunch
of reporting places, most of the time it's
actually, it's not a lot of small
companies that are doing it, right? It's a
lot, you know, most of it is just like a
handful of large companies and large
producers that are doing the reporting and
that are setting the prices. And even if
you have smaller producers for gold, like
for example in Thailand, they have their
own standard. But in Thailand, even though
you have a bunch of small producers, they
all are part of this like gold consortium
that will then set the price for that day.
And so again, even though you have, you
know, not decentralization, but
distribution, like a distributed consensus
for price discovery, you essentially only
have one central entity that will decide
what the price is, and then it will report
it up to the oracle or report it up to the
index. So that can be manipulated, because
even though you have distribution, you
always have the centralized points that
end up reporting, because not everybody
can report it. With the decentralized
oracle ecosystem, basically the more
oracles you spin up, number one, oracles
can be run without specific vetted
interests in keeping the price up or down.
Because if it's an effective oracle
system, it'll have its own incentive
structure that will incentivize the oracle
to produce proper data, right? So you
don't have data manipulation. That's
number one. So it's not reliant on the
incentive of the price going up or down.
It's reliant on doing your job because
there's an incentive structure built into
the oracle network of rewards and slashing
or whatever, however your network is
built. That's number one. Number two,
anybody can spin it up if it is
decentralized oracle network. So you don't
have to be like a gold consortium to spin
up a gold oracle, a gold price oracle. You
just have to have the hardware, and you
have to be able to participate within the
financial structure that extrudes these
rewards. And so that's a lot harder to
manipulate, just like any decentralized
consensus is, because it's a decentralized
consensus, right? So you always will have
a minimum, like a minimum consensus for
something, you know, for price or
whatever, right? So even if like, say, I
wanna manipulate it and I start up my own
oracle and I start giving out shit data,
it's still, you know, you still can't
convince everybody to give out shit data.
It's really difficult. Like it is with
these distributed consensus, with the
centralized consensus or, you know, public
ledgers. So, I mean, that's essentially
like, that's what the I think that's what
makes it makes it different, right?
Because even with the big indexes, the
information still comes from centralized
sources that have a vetted interest in the
price doing whatever it's doing versus an
oracle network as interest in channeling
proper data because their incentive is to
get rewards and not get slashed by the
oracle incentives. And if you do have some
adversarial players in the network,
chances are really good that you can get
enough non-adversarial players in the
network that would just want to
participate in the network and not try to
manipulate the price. And so that you can
then mitigate price manipulation or data
manipulation from adversarial parties. So
I mean, that's how I see it working. I
don't know what you guys think about that.
Yeah, not bad, Dan. I'm impressed. Good
job. Yeah, so like you said, it's only, I
mean, the data we're bringing on chain
with oracles is only as good as the data
that's out there, right? So there could be
manipulation probably sooner on the
outside world than there is coming into
the chain. With Dexy, we have, what is it,
15 kushti right now with gold oracle.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Something like that.
Yeah, hotline.
Yeah, so right now, the only thing you
can slash on that is your participation
token. There's not a vested interest in
that, not a vested amount of money that
can slash, kind of like the Rosen guards
would be. But there is the incentive that
if I screw up or start reporting falsely
or get a bribe from somebody on the
outside, I'm going to cut off any sort of
income that I'd be getting from the gold
oracle token for the forever, you know
what I mean? It'd be done. I'd be an
untouchable, don't touch, blacklisted kind
of thing. So yeah, there's that incentive
to be a good actor there. And I do think
you're right, Dan. I think in these
circumstances, especially in the Ergo
ecosystem, you're going to have a larger
group of actors naturally that want to do
well and do good and continue a good
service. Yeah.
Well, in oracle pools, if you're
providing outlier data, then your data
point is just excluded, right? And for the
rest, which is calculated, posted on the
chain. Then you need to convince the
majority of oracles, right? to post some
invalid data but yeah well as HQ said and
some other comment about that so yeah well
after all oracles well just passing data,
right? Pulling data right from outside and
yeah, there is not much you can do with
outside. Well, so you may pull from
different source and do everything.
Average it out, yeah. Yeah, you can do
your own data provider. So for USD, well,
it's CoinGecko by default. And here, well,
I made my own provider once and here
posted data from a different source and so
on but yeah after all so well in most
cases oracles are well not not forming
data right so they're just pulling the
data from some source. And then, yeah,
well, it's interesting in regards with
lithium to use actual producers or market
participants as data providers. That would
be quite interesting.
Yeah, that's actually something that I
started working with my business
development team on right now is actually
contacting market participants and
producers to work with us in delivering
this data so that there could actually be
arbitrage opportunities for different
regions for lithium, because right now a
lot of it is actually kind of fragmented,
right? So you've got different prices
coming out of different regions. You also
have another problem, which is logistics,
right? This is actually not just for
lithium. One of the biggest issues
commodities face is a problem with
logistics. For example, in the case of
Argentinian lithium, one of the main
problems that Argentinian companies have
right now that have access to the lithium.
Even if they have land that has lithium
deposits and they want to spin up an
operation, it's not just about spinning up
an operation that will then process the
lithium brine and then extract lithium out
of it, but it's also about getting it out
of there. The customer's not going to come
to you. You have to ship it to them. What
you have to remember is that most of this
stuff happens in high elevations. Some of
you saw the, yeah, a lot higher than that
QX. Yeah, way higher than that, way
higher. If maybe some of you saw that the
documentary we came up with, The Lithium
Must Flow, we're at, I forgot what it was,
but it was like 10,000 or 15,000 meters up
or something. It was basically where if
you are not a fit person, don't run,
because your lungs will burn. And I mean,
I am semi-fit-ish. I do exercise. And even
I made the mistake of thinking that I was
more fit than I am. And I forgot that I'm
middle-aged. And I try to climb up a dune.
And then my lungs said, no, fuck off. and
then just burned a long time. So don't do
that. So point is that when you get up to
these elevations, you get logistics
problems. So just in the case of lithium,
lithium deposits are at high elevations
and they're in these remote areas. And so
you have to be able to get it out of
there. And so what happens is some
companies, like say the Chinese companies,
they'll come in there and actually ship
all of their logistics providers as well.
They'll take all their trucks over there.
They'll take all the drivers and
everybody. So they'll ship the entire kit,
not just start the facility in the higher
locally, but ship everything over there.
Everybody's gonna be Chinese, right?
Everybody down to the drivers is gonna be
Chinese. The trucks are gonna be Chinese,
like all this stuff. And so, yeah, so
basically what you get is a problem in
logistics, which then has a, which then
creates a problem for delivery, which then
creates a problem for equal price
sustainability. And so, and so that's what
happens, you know, with, and then it can
also happen with gold as well. You know,
there's some areas, say like in Africa,
for example, that are gold rich, but you
can actually cannot get the gold out
easily. And that is why, you know, they'll
be sitting on gold deposits, but like
getting those gold deposits out of there
might be a problem. And therefore they
can't really do much with it. And they
have to, you know, have to rely on outside
means or lowering the price or whatever
else. So, yes, so basically, actually, to
get back to the original question here,
right, so the question here is the
question that was asked here is, are we
relying on centralized sources like
CoinGecko? Yeah, and in the case of
commodities, a lot of times you have to do
the same thing because there are just not
enough sources out there that, I mean,
like, say, for example, what Alex said,
you have to create his own pricing index
to be able to pull data so you wouldn't
have to use CoinGecko. So most of these
oracles will just pull stuff out of
CoinGecko, they'll pull stuff out of
CoinMarketCap or a couple of other ones.
So it kind of defeats the purpose. Well,
it's like, well, yes, basically just kind
of like a proxy for an API at that point.
You're not really a pricing oracle. But in
a real pricing oracle scenario, what you
actually want to have is that variety. And
it could also be part of the protocol.
Like, for example, only a certain amount
of oracles can report prices from these
particular places. You know, there should
be, there should be oracles that report
prices from like, you should see, you can
set your, your, your minimum threshold
for, oracles reporting prices outside of
these, you know, the CoinGeckos and the
more CoinMarketCaps, you know, just all
depends on that. But, but really, yeah,
just all about kind of getting a variety
of data and in commodities as well. You
want to have producers reporting because
you will get a variety of data out. And of
course, there's going to be some data
bullshit going on there, but you can have
number one, an incentive structure to
mitigate that, and number two, a
mitigation protocol to an algorithm that
will counteract that kind of behavior. So
there's several different things you can
do if you get enough data. Because if you
don't have enough data variety, then
there's only so much you can do.
Yeah, that's going to be interesting,
Dan, because people need to remember that
these oracles don't just exist for Palmyra
or Palmyra, right? These are going to be
on chain in public to everybody. So there
could be competing oracles, right? Your
oracles, Dan, that you've helped perhaps
set up with lithium could be more of an
average pricing than somebody setting up
oracles pulling on-chain data from other
lithium price providers that maybe is a
little faster to adjust price or rides a
little higher. So then it's up to the
dApps to decide which oracles they're
going to price from from there. So there's
actually a competition among oracle
providers, even though they're
decentralized and open source at that
point, which is interesting thought. Cool.
We got another question here before we go.
Yeah, sorry, go for it.
Yeah, so there is more here. So for USD,
for example, well, if you are not using
CoinGecko or CoinMarketCap, then you are
using some exchange probably directly,
right? And then you need for enough
volume. So what CoinGecko is doing, for
example, already is averaging data, doing
weighted average from different exchanges,
it's already improving quality of data,
three to five at least. And then yeah well
for the lithium use case well if producers
are going to put data on chain it would be
quite interesting actually case where we
can create some alternative price index
right maybe also secured with some
on-chain protocols and so well
transparency which would be quite
interesting because well for existing
price it's not quite clear right well how
they formed and what manipulations there
probably it's not even possible to
Well, there is manipulation. It mostly
comes from certain Asian countries. And
it's a problem because it literally...
First of all, it creates an opportunity
for more manipulation. It basically feeds
itself. It also stifles real business
because some of these guys just can't
really do honest business because there's
manipulation. Yeah, it's a problem.
Yeah, looking at CoinGecko, guys, there's
at least a top 15 are considered somewhat
trustworthy of their combined score or
their combined price for Ergo. Spectrum
Finance or ErgoDEX is 16, and it looks
like they're getting prices from that as
well. Yeah, so it's getting from DEX, it's
getting from CEXs for the CoinGecko price.
But yeah, I would say that is an issue
that for the oracle 2 is not going to do
is that we're getting it from one source
that aggregates other sources. It'd be
nice to aggregate the sources ourselves
inside the oracle protocol so that if one
thing goes down, it doesn't matter. We
still have 16 other sources that we're
pulling an average again and weighting and
kind of thing. So yeah. Cool. Well, it's
10 o'clock, boys. I've got in real life
meetings. I got a hit.
You don't have any meetings. You just
have to... I'm not important. I'm not
important at all. You have to go and stare
at the wall again. Come on, you're working
for them. What do you guys do there
anyway?
All right. All right. And Sigmanauts, I
will be around, I don't know, on Saturday
or Sunday, my evening. So let's have some
community chats over the Telegram, just
text chat maybe about high-performance
proof-of-work protocols, sub-blocks, all
that stuff. So yeah, I'll see you around.
Awesome. Yeah, bye.
All right, everybody. Thanks for tuning
in. And yeah, next week, same time, same
place, same channel on YouTube. And until
then, this is Dan coming to you live from
Japan. Still have a bunch of work to do,
by the way. It's only 11 p.m. All right.
And to the sides here, I got, well, I got
QX and I got kushti. It looks all just all
wrong. Anyway, thanks. Thanks for leaving
us off on that QX. All right, we're gonna
sign off. See everybody. See you later
buddy.