Welcome, everybody. We wanted to put
together a 2025 video. We've done that in
previous years, so I thought it'd be good
to spend some time with Alex and catch up
with Ergo, how things are going and where
we're going, I guess, most importantly. So
how are you doing today, Alex?
Hello everyone, yeah, doing well. So it's
weekend but busy with Ergo development, so
just published sub-blocks, so inputs and
ordering blocks. EAP draft initial one,
but yeah, we'll improve it in the coming
days. And yeah, we're also working on
prototyping codes. There is some already
done, but more will be done. And yeah,
well, a lot of other things going on at
the same time. So with 6.0 development,
6.0 audits, and so on. So yeah, well, it's
a busy, busy time.
So why don't we start with the
sub-blocks, since that's kind of in your
mind already. Where do you see kind of the
use of sub-blocks. Those of you that don't
know, it's been inspired by Prism and as
well as Parallel Proof of Work, which I
believe Agolos came out with that paper.
So what do you see that doing to the
network and how do you see that changing
not only transactions and user experience,
but mining in general?
Yeah, also bottlenecks. So currently,
well, it's, you know, well, on average,
every two minutes on average. Yeah, a new
block is being generated, propagated over
the network, right, and well, the network
has a big load, right, every two minutes,
but other than that, well, the load is
minimal, right, so the network is idle.
The sub-blocks, well, the loads will
become spread, right? So, well, the
network would be busy all the time and
yes, well, the bottleneck is moving to
network bandwidth, right? And well, this
resource network bandwidth is hopefully
will become more and more available with
time, right? So even with well flat
peer-to-peer network, we will get better
performance every year basically.
Awesome. So how do you see that differing
from how many other cryptocurrencies are
attempting to kind of scale their
bandwidth?
Yeah, but most are not even trying,
right? So, well, the general approach
unfortunately seen now is just to make
networks less peer-to-peer, more
centralized, right? So, well, to rely on
just, well, powerful validators in data
centers, so powerful machines with a lot
of well, memory and bandwidth. But then,
yeah, well, it's also about, well,
increasing centralization, right, in
regards to many aspects like validation.
So most of our network clients just have
to trust those powerful validators. And
yeah, well, it's also about centralization
of power, decision-making in the community
to some degree, and also centralization of
assets ownership, because usually those
validators also have big stake, right? And
they are going to have a bigger stake.
That's why they are willing to block,
right? So, well, it's kind of a digital
oligarchy, right? After all.
Yeah, there's a lot of systems where you
have stake dominance and then you have
order flow dominance. And then, you know,
you kind of just have these kings in the
system, right?
Right, but also they're becoming more and
more powerful, right? And, well, with that
validation, centralization, there are also
ones which don't know what's going on in
the network even, right? Yeah, the massive
gap, it seems. Yeah, but then also, well,
a lot of blockchains just doing something,
just one specific step, right? And not
always correct. So many are switching to
proof of stake with claim that it is
improving network performance, which is
not the case already quite seen from my
Ethereum experience, for example, right?
Many are introducing very weird concepts
such as sharding, so fragmenting liquidity
in DeFi. This also having quite weird and
inconvenient consequences in the real
world. So even sharding author Vitalik is
now not talking about this anymore. And so
on and so on. Many just changing constants
that was popular in Bitcoin forks. just
well-increasing block size, for example,
and claiming that this is somehow related
to scaling, right, and so on. So, well, in
Ergo, well, it was multi-level approach
since day one, right, so it was the first
network implementing stateless clients, as
well as so-called lock-space mining.
Right, and now bandwidth utilization,
right. And well, doing all this preserving
peer-to-peer nature of the network. which
is always sometimes tricky, but yeah,
well, it's the goal after to have a real
peer-to-peer network.
Yeah, it's foundational. I think that
ultimately without that foundation
everything else you build, you know, just
as a different animal. And it's
interesting to see how, I don't know, it's
like everything is being abstracted
further and further and further away from
the notion of a peer-to-peer network,
right?
Right, and also, yeah, peer-to-peer
exchange after all, right? So, well, with
peer-to-peer network, naturally, you have
also peer-to-peer exchange, right? So,
well, even if we are doing some smart
contract, right, it's just between you and
me, right? It should be. We shouldn't have
some contracts backed by VCs with, I don't
know, admin keys belong to developers and
VCs and, I don't know, them deciding to
follow some regulations, I don't know.
Which probably, well, you don't care
about, right? Because, well, it's not even
about your jurisdiction, maybe, right? But
still it's enforced. Yeah, and also there
could be, I don't know, different
adversarial actions, right, from those
owners and also hackers and so on and the
question is why do we need to accept all
these rights when it's about peer-to-peer
interaction.
I think that's mostly lost, sadly, in the
crypto space, right? Where, you know, it's
no longer about like my ability to I don't
know, interact directly with you with no
intermediary or no point of control in the
middle. Right. And things have been, I
don't know, shifting for a long time in
the crypto industry space to where now
it's quote unquote web three, whatever
that means. versus peer-to-peer.
Yeah, and so yeah, this web3 usually
means nothing, right? So there was a
foundational article by Gavin Wood but
yeah well initially the term was used for
actually very different things right so
initially it was introduced by Tim
Berners-Lee and Web3 by Tim Berners-Lee
was about making a web machine-friendly,
right, by using semantic web tools and so
on. But then, yeah, well... Gavin Wood
maybe because of not being very literate
about, I don't know, works of other
people, foundational works, by the way,
and well, already quite established. So
well, I visited Web3 conferences back in
2008, 2009, right? So before all those
blockchains and yeah, I mean, people
discussed all that stuff by Tim
Berners-Lee. But okay, so yeah, we heard
maybe not very literate guy from Ethereum
will reintroduce the term, but what we
have now is not corresponding even to
that, right? And currently Web3 is mostly
just some web term used to introduce
tokens mostly, right? And yeah, the token
game with VCs, right? Backing your
tokenomics, let's say. So yeah, well,
aside of that, well, most of Web3 projects
don't make any sense, to be honest.
No, I think 2025 is definitely going to
be an interesting year to watch like
general mission drift in the
cryptocurrency space where it started with
this idea of peer to peer networks and
censorship resistant exchange between
anyone anywhere in the world to, yeah,
more. I don't know. I think as you see
regulation and friendlier potential,
there's going to be a lot of honeypotting
where people try to position for control
in essence, right? Like the magic of
Bitcoin initially was like if under these
certain set of assumptions, you can assume
that the network is honest and operating
trustlessly, right? And things have kind
of been re-engineered to where there's all
these different layers or wrappers of
trust, you know, up and down different
stacks to where it's hard to call certain
things like DeFi when, you know, at the
end of the day, you're talking about
things with potentially a lot of legal
entanglement and backing by government
bonds and, you know, all kinds of strange
beasts coming into the space. So I don't
know. I think that long term, that's going
to be an interesting differentiator is the
idea of like compliance and the potential
reward trade off on that side versus
trying to remain open and neutral and
censorship resistant. You know, in a world
where I think that schism is going to just
increase from where we are today.
Interesting. Yeah.
Yeah. So, well, going back to sub-blocks.
So, oh, yeah, well, that would bring
network performance to theoretical
maximum, right? It's possible for
peer-to-peer network. But then, yeah,
well, always possible to make
optimizations, right? For, well, message
exchange and peer-to-peer networks. And
also networking is making progress from
year to year and well with that there will
be a natural performance increase and well
in Ergo well it's. It was chosen to have
flexible approach, right? So to avoid any
magic constants here like block size and
so on. So to give miners possibility to
readjust parameters because well, we have
progress in the hardware, right? And not
just hardware with time.
Yeah, yeah, I do hope that, you know, we
see a lot more miner involvement. Seeing
the Sigmanauts pool starting to implement
demurrage is pretty awesome. I saw that
they had thrown up a mining and ecosystem
development grant from the EF, which I
know that you and I are no longer directly
a part of, but I certainly I hope that
those that are looking at the EF take a
long look and see kind of the value of
mining because that's, you know, proof of
work is, I don't know, becoming less
common, I guess, in terms of how people
are thinking. But I don't know, maybe that
has to do with like just education, right?
So having some initiative to demonstrate
the value of mining and decentralization
and, you know, kind of what Ergo is
working towards with GPU mining, I think
would be really valuable. especially
given, I don't know, crypto is a crazy
space, my friend. I read things all the
time where I just kind of scratch my head.
Yeah, I actually think proof-of-work
assets are getting appreciation and the
more proof-of-stake assets we have, the
more valuable perspective proof-of-work
assets may become. Because well,
proof-of-stake is giving holders free
money basically, right? We are staking.
And well, with those free money, people
are often buying hard money, right? So
proof of work currencies. So I think this
is one of the reasons why Ethereum is
doing poorly after the merge, right? So
well, now, well, Ethereum stakeholders are
getting free money via staking, right? And
well, what I'm thinking about, probably
they are buying Bitcoin mostly, right,
with those staking. And that's also
probably happening with Ergo and Cardano
maybe, right? And well, I think with time,
so with more and more proof of stake
assets, right? Means more and more free
money have been distributed. So well,
money you can get for nothing just for
having proof of stake assets, right? And
well, holding them. Basically, so people
would put those assets, proof-of-stake
free assets into proof-of-work, right?
This would make proof-of-work assets more
valuable with time. I don't see well
recognition of this pattern, but yeah, I
think it's emerging actually.
It could be. It could be. I think, like,
with Ethereum, there was a period of time
where they had this, you know, distributed
proof of work security wall that was
pretty amazing. And in my opinion, they
actually had the right incentives in terms
of MEV distribution, where because, you
know, MEV itself was kind of being
democratized through mining pools and
adding to mining rewards, it created the
right incentive for mining growth, right?
Meaning it's like that value is being
distributed to support the security
budget. And it's shifted a lot in a lot of
proof of stake systems to where that value
is, it goes to internal entities, it goes
to, you know, like, you know, entrenched
parties, which doesn't create an economic
incentive, you know, for people to join
versus having fee distribution. So I think
that's a powerful vertical that, you know,
hopefully, you know, I know, qx() has been
looking at MEV and various potential cases
for Lithos, which I guess we'll get to
later. But I really believe that, you
know, demurrage and MEV distribution, it's
creating the right incentives for a
growing act set of security actors, I
guess.
Yeah, but also with proof of work, well,
new Ethereum tokens were not for free,
right? So, well, miners actually put a lot
of work into the mining distributed
supercomputer to get them, right? via work
lottery. But now, yeah, well, new, well,
Ethereum tokens are basically for free,
right? So you just need to hold assets,
right? And well, then, yeah, well, you,
you can basically, well, exchange them to
Bitcoin, right, depending on pricing,
because you don't value, right, those free
assets. Because the intrinsic value for
those tokens is well about zero. Just a
little bit of computational efforts to
validate and propagate blocks around the
network.
So speaking of kind of financial
products, you know, sometimes I get a lot
of questions, you know, why Ergo is
focusing on introducing, you know,
different stable coins, stable coins
design, different backings or pegs to
algorithmic stable coins. So, you know,
what in your mind kind of drew you to
explore the Dexy implementation? versus, I
guess, their traditional mindset is just
going to be, let's, you know, deal with
these freezancies, assets, you know, USDC,
whatever, you know, fill in the letter.
What made you more attracted to something
like Dexy versus, I guess, the traditional
stablecoin?
Oh, but traditional are trusted, right?
So, well, you trust Tether team. I don't
know. I mean, I don't know who's there and
why should they be trusted and probably
they shouldn't, right? And even more, I
don't know, probably no one really has
trust, right? Tether folks, but still
people are using tether, which is quite
absurd. So yeah, well, then there are
different options, right? So you may have
I don't know, like peer-to-peer trusted
currencies. So well, maybe you can try to
recreate a web of trust, right? So like
traditional solutions from public key
infrastructure, traditional decentralized
approaches. But yeah, I mean, you still
need for some buffer at least, right, for
some least common denominator, which is
about algorithmic stablecoins, I believe.
Right, so even if you, for example,
issuing your own dollars, I don't know, or
gold-backed tokens like Harmony or gold,
for example, right, and I'm accepting
them, but then I'm trying to pay with
them, right? So, well, who will trust,
right? And why people should trust? But
if, well, your tokens are backed at least
partially, right? Or maybe fully with
algorithmic stablecoin at the moment. I
mean, if there is backing at the moment,
right? Then, yeah, it's more or less
trustless, right? So trust issues are
solved here. If there is, well,
unconditional redemption possible, right?
Well, redemption without your control at
least. So then, yeah, well, even if there
is, you know, these trusted issuance, like
if you're issuing your Armeanio tokens,
then yeah, it's better to back them with
algorithmic stable coins, right? And maybe
then work on eliminating or reducing need
for algorithmic stablecoin liquidity with
clearing, and so on. Or maybe have
fractional reserve, maybe like free
banking system, so eventually they went
into fractional reserve state anyway. But
yeah, well, for starters, you need for
backing, right? To get trust and so on.
And well, it would be much better than,
well, having a trust to Tether team and
well, government bonds they could have,
but I mean, that's also a question of
trust, right? Whether such an issue to
have, right? So they're trying to do
audits and so on, but yes, still, you
know, it's always a question of trust to
some degree, at least. What do you think?
But then, yeah, you also have trust in
government bonds, right? Transitional
trust and yeah, there are a lot of new
issues arising.
No, I think it breaks down to this idea
that as kind of, I don't know, you started
with Bitcoin, it was more or less a kind
of simple straightforward system. And as
things have become more complicated, you
know, you get new layers, new layers of
trust to where I think that in many cases
that's not a concern anymore for people.
Ultimately, what leads the general person
to reevaluate trust is when it's misused
or abused against them, right? And, you
know, that's never an optimal way to learn
but I guess in a way that is going to kind
of be the path where let's see what the
friction points are. I don't know. It's
gonna be an interesting year. There's I
think there's gonna be a lot of like
entanglements as some systems push for
broader adoption and whatever compliance
or schism away from this idea of open and
censorship resistant trustless networks is
going to be. That's going to be the most
fascinating, let's say, vertical to watch
in probably the next couple of years in
the crypto space, I believe. But I agree.
I think that having algorithmic
stablecoins or some notion of an asset
that addresses volatility. You know,
because again, if somebody is going to use
cryptocurrencies as a form of payment, you
know, when you get in line at the store,
you want the same purchasing power when
you, you know, finish checking out as when
you got in line and sometimes like the
volatile nature of these assets doesn't
really do many favors in terms of kind of
creating the adoption for kind of stable
goods and services and exchange, et
cetera. So I really do believe that stable
coins in some sense have been and will be
kind of like the first killer use case for
programmable money where, you know, people
are experiencing inflation or simply want
to be more free from control systems and
you know it's a nice option to have.
Right and yeah so well algorithmic stable
coins do have own cons right but still you
know well it's useful building block for
well more complex systems. So yeah, I
mean, even for, as I explained, trusted,
right? Stable coins like Armeanio gold in
my example. So, well, it makes sense to
have some trustless backing, right? So
yeah, algorithmic stable coins
essentially.
So another big vertical I think that's
quite interesting for the Ergo ecosystem
is cross-chaining, merge mining, just
interoperability in general. So with 6.0,
what are we opening the door to support in
terms of cross-chain interoperability on
Ergo or side chains, double-merge mined
side chains, all of that kind of space
that we're growing into?
Right, so it would be possible to have,
well, Bitcoin relays, right? Well, already
there is a prototype and then, well,
two-way relays with Autolykos or maybe
SHA-256 or whatever. Sigma side chains,
right? So you may have a relay on Ergo
chain and a relay on side chain. So
sidechain relay on Ergo mainchain and
mainchain relay on Sigma sidechain. And
with that, you may have even trustless
bridge, right, and other cross-chain
trustless applications. But yeah, there
are more options, right? Like we have
Rosen Bridge, right? To connect with,
well, chains which are not so easy to
connect in a trustless way, fully
trustless, such as Bitcoin, well, Ethereum
and so on, right? Most of popular chains.
Yeah, I'm hoping that with Rosen, we
continue to expand across the various
ecosystems and points out there. And I
think 2025 is going to be interesting in
terms of plugging in market making bots on
top. Right. I really do believe that a
bridge has a just base transfer protocol
is well, interesting. It allows you to
create markets and open the door to
arbitrage across different environments
based on demand. But having the ability to
manage liquidity more seamlessly and
accelerate that, I really think is one of
the keys to growth long term you know as
well as potential solutions to kind of
intermix faster bridging and DeFi which
you know again accelerates kind of the
arbitrage potential but you know even
right Even beyond, I think, having kind of
relays and greater interoperability
between ecosystems is certainly something
I'm always going to encourage us to
support and grow into. I think there's a
lot of opportunity in that space that is
still mostly unrealized.
Yeah, so I think applications are needed,
right? Well, in addition to bridges such
as, well, onramp, right? And DEX access
and so on. So, well, it would be good
maybe for a Bitcoiner, right? Somewhere to
use escrow contracts for, well, better
onramp, right? So to get from fiat to
Bitcoin. And then, yeah, maybe even to use
Spectrum DEX to exchange a bit of Bitcoin
immediately to gold, for example, to have
exposure to both Bitcoin and gold.
Spending fiat on that and using Ergo
blockchain, right?
Yeah, I think it's going to be an
interesting year for metal stable coins.
You know, if I put on my tinfoil hat and
say, OK, well, like if I could change the
trajectory of the crypto industry in one
way for me, I think that like I don't
know, we have these peer-to-peer networks
that are kind of, they're a wrapper of the
internet, right? And the internet itself
is its own kind of animal that's
decentralized. You have, you know,
endpoints all over the world. And I don't
know, I think that using fiat as like the
primary peg or wrapper for cryptocurrency
is just the wrong choice because it's
centralized. If the internet itself was
centralized and we tried to build
cryptocurrencies on top of a centralized
network, it would be doomed to fail. And I
think everyone can say like, yeah, that's
a terrible idea. We need like a
decentralized foundation to build off if
we want resilience. And the same thing is
true in terms of like the base monetary
network that we build off. We chose the
wrong one as an industry, in my opinion.
Like, you know, gold and silver is every
country you can pretty much find some
fungibility dealer you know it's pretty
universally accepted there's friction
there but it is a decentralized base
monetary network versus fiat is its own
walled garden and so whenever you're going
to deal with like these walled
environments there's going to be a lot of
entanglements it's going to inevitably,
like control is going to creep up from
that foundation. So I think that at least
having, you know, algorithmic, you know,
gold and silver pegged assets, hopefully
open the doors to where we can start
building that foundation where metal
becomes a I don't know, potential rail in
certain areas. And in a way that's
backwards, right? It should, probably
should have been built the other way, but
it wasn't. And I think a lot of the
conflicts we're gonna run into as an
industry is because we built off the wrong
network. Like we didn't, again, go back to
the internet. If we use some central
system, how could we expect to be
resilient through time?
Yeah, so I agree. So yeah, gold, silver,
maybe lithium even, right? So those assets
actually do have very impressive
decentralized mining networks, right? Much
more decentralized than Ergo or Bitcoin,
to be honest, right? So well, you can mine
gold with variety of tools right starting
with pretty medieval ones still used in
many areas around the globe to very
sophisticated chemistry based right more
modern chemistry based tech well and There
are players of very different scale,
right, from individuals and families in
Africa, for example, to huge corporations,
right, big nationwide corporations. So
yeah, well, players of very different
scale with very different tooling. And
yeah, to be honest, unlike proof of work
mining, so yeah, tooling is more
decentralized. Yeah, right. So well, let's
be clear because there is no Well, economy
of scale we do have in hardware and well,
yeah, many attempts to... have more
decentralized production of hardware
actually failed, right? Because, well,
it's a hard field for competition. It's
very, very hard to compete with hardware
manufacturers, existing ones, right? If
you are starting to produce tools for
mining, digital mining. But yes, digital
mining is better than other ways to
produce digital assets.
I think GPU mining is in a very
interesting place, to be honest. You know,
in some sense, it's like Bitcoin has
created this market where, I don't know,
it's mostly about energy arbitrage, right?
Like, miners are naturally, like, going to
go to where there's excess energy and then
try to, you know, plug in and profit from
excess capacity, right? And it seems as
though, at least on the GPU side, we're
seeing massive scaling of infrastructure
around AI and, you know, LLMs. And it's
going to be interesting to see if long
term there's excess compute that then
becomes like this driver for where it's,
you know, most profitable to mine. It does
kind of make sense. If you look at like
proof of work is this mechanism of seeking
over capacity, right? And that's always
where it's more profitable is when you
have over capacity, cheaper energy,
cheaper, you know, hardware, et cetera. So
I think GPU mining is an interesting place
to be long-term actually.
Right. But yeah, going back to physical
assets, so yeah, well, they have very well
established mining networks, right? And
well, pretty understandable distribution,
right? Made over centuries, if you're
talking about gold and silver, especially.
And so, yeah, well, also, well, you cannot
create gold or silver out of thin air,
right, unlike fiat currencies. So, well,
it's, yeah, I mean, it should be naturally
the basis, right, for stable coins or
peer-to-peer networks.
Well, originally, you know, metal was the
peg for fiat, you know.
Right, yeah.
Like fiat was just a wrapper for, you
know, metal itself. So I guess in some
sense, having metal is like the base and
some digital wrapper of metal. This is an
interesting concept. Speaking of mining,
are you tracking the Lithos development at
all in terms of how that could potentially
shift the centralized or decentralized
nature of proof of work mining?
So, yeah, trying to get details, but
yeah, fairly general picture still, to be
honest. Well, trying to get details from
qx(), but yeah, well, it seems that there
will be a lot of interesting things there,
right? Even some, well, specific
applications, specific rollups. which is
quite interesting. And well, yeah, it's
quite ambitious, right? And yeah, well,
quite exciting, well, approach to
reworking mining. What do you think about
Lithos? Maybe you have more talks with
qx().
Well, I think that ultimately if we can
get block production back towards the
individual miner away from pools, you
know, the network resilience of proof of
work and kind of like this ability to, I
don't know, censor validators is going to
make it a lot more resilient, right? You
know, we saw that in Bitcoin already. You
know, that's kind of been an ongoing
struggle with Ethereum as soon as they
went to proof of stake, where it's like,
you no longer have a fair network, in my
opinion, like, okay, in Bitcoin, Because
Bitcoin is a bit dumb by nature it's more
of like you get your payment later right
now and that's not so terrible I guess
depending on market conditions maybe at
that at the wrong time some you know if
you have block producers that are saying
hey you're not gonna be in our block and
you get kicked down the chain enough you
know you could definitely encounter some
like severe price impacts or something but
it'll get there eventually right when you
talk about like a network like Ethereum
where race conditions are a lot more
complicated because you have other assets.
Then things get really sketchy, right?
Like you have DeFi and you have collateral
that you're trying to like cover based on
market conditions or you have an
opportunity that's based on race
conditions. You simply broke the network.
You have you can't have like multi-tier
user base where you know one person can
come into a block half the time and
economically compete with somebody that
can always be included in a block like
that's that's a breaking assumption and in
my opinion for any like, yeah, neutral
economy. So I think if we like,
ultimately, the way around that has to be
like become uncensorable. And it makes
sense in my framework that the only way to
do that is to empower the individual
miners. So there's not some like pool
that, you know, inherits that liability.
Does that make sense? Right, right. Which
I guess gets you back to non-outsourceable
puzzles. Why was that valuable when Ergo
first launched? Kind of the same concept,
right? Right. So I do think that long term
that's still probably going like from an
outside attack perspective. I think going
after how blocks are built and like the
choke points around fiat rails are the two
primary like regulatory vectors. So
hopefully, you know, we can be a bit
hardened.
Yeah, so I think, yeah, well, talking
about non-outsourceable puzzles and
Lithos. So I think for, well, every proof
of work currency, it should be in
desiderata rights to, well, have
protection against pooling, right? But
then, yeah, yeah, you have a lot of real
world rights.
Forces yeah you have you have incentives
and I think that if you could create the
right incentives to encourage local block
production, then it's feasible. Because
that's ultimately why people pool their
hashrate anyway, is more predictable
revenue flows or mining flows. There's an
incentive to do so, and it's hard to say,
okay, we're going to operate on principle
and not incentives. That's a failed...
that's gonna be a failed system real
quick. Altruism is a terrible security
assumption in the wild, I guess. So yeah,
I think we're in for an interesting time.
Why don't we get into ChainCash? I know
that's kind of been something that's been
of in and out of your mind for years, you
know, building free banking or alternative
economies on top of Ergo.
Oh, actually, yeah, I mean, initial
thoughts appeared before the mainnet
launch even, so back in 2018 probably.
Right, something like that, but yeah, so
the original idea was, so it had a
different name even. Yeah, and the idea
was to have a circle of circles, basically
to have different local exchange trading
systems, right, because that was
primitive, known to me back then. So I
started with that so that the idea was to
have well collateralized local exchange
trading systems and non-collateralized and
then to have some exchange right between
different circles between different LETS
systems and having gateways some economy,
right, well for actors willing to project
liquidity from one kind of financial
system to another, right, and so on. But
yeah, then, yeah, so somehow I realized
that, well, ChainCash so well spender
signed currency based system could be
actually a more general right so with that
you may include local exchange trading
systems as well as I don't know very
different systems right you know in a
single financial system global one and
having basically the same right and well
anyway you would have conditional
acceptance right like in LETS of LETS
circle of circles right but yeah also more
flexibility and so on so that was quite
evolutionary process But yeah, so I think,
well, it's the natural next step talking
about ChainCash. So well, you have
blockchain assets, right? So talking about
proof of work assets or proof of work
derived assets like ones with emission
contracts tied to proof of work. blocks
production such as I don't know auction
coin maybe even rights or well maybe
currencies with emission contracts with
the emission going to miners, right, like
some projects did, but only for part of
tokens. But if we are talking about whole
supply going to miners, then yeah, it's
not that different from ERG, even maybe
from native token, right, in regards with
money production. So yeah, we have those
hard assets, Ergo, other proof of work
cryptocurrencies. Well, if they do have
good distribution like Bitcoin. Right,
then, yeah, maybe we have assets of, I
don't know, the different quality, let's
say, right? But then, yeah, still for the
real world, you need for some expansion,
right? You need to introduce trust
sometimes. You need to combine trust and
collateral and so on. So a variety of
options to expand trust. monetary base or
blockchain assets to, well, money being
used in the real world. So that's more or
less like monetary systems are working in
the real world, right? Where you have
some, well, monetary base, like M0
aggregates, right? And well, on top of
that, you are creating more and more
derivative layers but here yeah it's still
peer-to-peer right so well it's based on
individual choice of security parameters
and so on and yeah so it's it's it's a non
It's non-enforceable, right? Also, no
actor should force you to accept assets
you don't like, right? Like happening with
fiat currency, for example, which you have
to accept if you run a business in some
jurisdiction, for example, right? Yeah,
you almost always saw in almost all the
jurisdictions, you have to accept fiat
currency rights of all that jurisdiction.
And yeah, in ChainCash, so yeah, it's kind
of free. And yeah, free banking system
basically, right? So the different agents
are free to issue their money, but then
yeah, it's up to you which money to
accept. So it's more or less like, well,
free banking systems existed in many
countries before central banks, well, to
power our money issues.
It's going to be interesting to see.
ChainCash, I don't know, could grow a lot
of different ways. Like the circle within
circles idea is interesting. Looking at
how like the shadow banking system will
have to retool itself based on like
potential changes. And, you know, let's
say we do get central bank digital
currencies, that's going to be interesting
to see how like, you know, shadow banking
sides of economy and gray markets, black
markets coexist. within the centralized
beast that's coming. It's gonna be an
interesting world, my friend. I think you
and I will be alive the day that cash
disappears, right? And it's quite
interesting to game theory out. What comes
next? Right. And I think that at some
point, like a reversion back to metals
makes sense, because what else are you
going to have that you can have custody of
and you have strong trust assumptions
with? I don't know. We're in for an
interesting time, I guess.
Right, but you can combine blockchains
with metals, right? So you may have, I
don't know, physical gold, which is
secured with algorithmic rights, like what
Palmyra is planning to do with lithium
rights or to secure lithium which is not
produced yet with algorithmic stable coins
and similarly you can secure brick of gold
which is not delivered yet to your control
party with algorithmic stable coin rights
and then yeah you use also some escrow
contract for security right for for kind
of insurance And then, yeah, so this way
you can use metals, right, but with also
some additional security provided by
blockchain, but also well in a
capital-efficient way, right. And then you
also can actually issue I don't know, more
relaxed money like ChainCash, right? On
top of metals secured by stable coins, for
example, and so on. You can just issue
ChainCash notes on top of algorithmic
stable coins and so on. So yeah, a variety
of options. And yeah, you can have things
done in a pretty capital-efficient way
here, right, using clearing, mutual credit
clearing and so on. So not so much backing
would be needed even because that's also,
well, a hard problem, right? So you may
have trustless assets like over
collateralized algorithmic stable coins,
but they're not capital efficient, right?
So you need to do something right to not
to use so much of those assets. So to use
clearing as much as possible, right? So to
minimize amount of stable coins, used
over-collateralized stable coins.
That's an interesting, interesting
thought. Going back to the future of Ergo,
what would you say is the long-term vision
goal plan for the ecosystem community,
development community, and how best to
engage users and developers to get
involved in the vision and the future of
building Ergo?
Yeah, so I think we actually have
discussed, right, different aspects of
future of Ergo, such as well, more stable
coins, well, tools for monetary expansion,
then cross-chaining to bring more assets
and also to bring applications to other
blockchains. Decentralized onramp, which
is getting more and more critically
needed, right? Especially, well, with
degradation of centralized exchanges we
are witnessing. And then, yeah, well,
decentralized marketplaces. What else?
There would be needs probably in many
areas for off-chain solutions, layer-2
networks, right, for, well, cheap. maybe
almost free transactions here also, maybe,
well, very fast, right? Well, maybe even
sub-blocks would be not fast enough. You
may use Lithos and so on. And yeah, so I
think, well, all those things combined and
those things are not imaginary, right?
prototypes at least for almost all of
them. Sometimes we have tooling already
available, but just maybe not tested and
used much. With all those things we may
say that Ergo is actually a kind of end
game for crypto. envisioned by godfathers
of Bitcoin. Maybe not in detailed way
because they were not capable to figure
out details back in 2009, 2008, 2009.
Sometimes it's quite funny actually to
read the writings as well as, I don't
know, even earlier writings from 2000s
like different Cypherpunk writings on
future of peer-to-peer digital cash. But
yeah, now I think we have a pretty
well-established and detailed approach,
which is finally allowing to achieve
dreams from 2000s. And yeah, that's what
we need for more developers, enthusiasts,
monetary hackers, jazz hackers. So well,
enthusiasts, running experience and so on.
No, I think at some point, you know, life
is a circle. Right. So I think at some
point, you know, this idea of like, I
don't know, wrappers with a lot of
different control points on top of
wrappers with a lot of different control
points will be problematic. Right. And
when it becomes problematic, then this
idea of, you know, peer to peer finance
between you and me with nobody else in the
middle will become more attractive. I
guess, I don't know, there's always a lot
of hype and marketing and I don't know,
salesmanship, guruing in the crypto space.
But I think at the end of the day, that's
ultimately the kind of first principles
approach is to stay low and peer to peer.
system. And, you know, I do hope that, you
know, perhaps 2025, perhaps 2026, we start
to explore, you know, perhaps enhancements
in privacy, new Sigma protocols being
supported, etc. I don't know for there
yet. But, you know, it seems like we have
a foundation where, you know, that very
well could be 7.0 or 8.0 or whatever.
Let's see.
Yeah, so I guess sigma chains or layer 2s
could be useful for privacy, right?
Especially if it's possible to break link
between well, entering and exiting layer
2, which should be possible in Ergo, by
the way. For example, you may enter layer
2. with the condition to exit to stealth
address, which is what I'm thinking about
a little bit. But yeah, I need to write
down all those things. But yeah, well, it
would be good to get more researchers'
rights, also hacking around all that
stuff. Absolutely. So yeah, well, going
back. So yeah, I think in 2025 it is
critically needed to get more actors, more
organizations, maybe even in the Ergo
ecosystem. And it is critically needed to
get some more researchers and yeah, more
developers, core developers, application
developers. and, yeah, well, more users,
right, more, well, enthusiasts, more
teachers, right, explaining, well,
technology, right, to the masses.
I think ultimately that might be the
starting point, right? If I look back at
the history of Ergo so far, it seems as
though DECO was actually one of the
biggest like aggravators and motivators
for growth and development expansion. Just
kind of that free YouTube course where,
you know, covered the like base
foundations of Ergo UTXO building on Ergo
sigma etc so i i think that's always going
to be something we should be really
mindful of is kind of that intro ramp and
education for people out there that you
know are interested because i don't know
it's I don't want to say crypto has a lot
of foolish teachers around but it's a
crazy goddamn space my friend.
So I think there should be focus in 2025
on, well, growing a new generation of
Sigmanauts, right? So it's always needed.
And yeah, well, I think that's, yes,
sometimes it's missed, right? So that's,
yeah, well, for a Sigmanaut, yeah, the
first goal should be to I don't know, grow
replacements, right? Well, expand the
movement.
Yeah, I really hope that through time we
become less important. That would be
awesome to see.
All right, so yeah, well, let's have
exciting 2025. I'm pretty sure it will be
pretty crazy, but hopefully exciting here.
Buckle up, wear a helmet, let's have some
fun.
All right, bye everybody.