Hello everyone.
Hi everybody. Welcome to the, what do we
call it, kushti, we're calling it the Ergo
ecosystem weekly AMA?
Yeah, so I had some discussions with
folks, well, Sigmanauts we had in Hong
Kong, our consensus Hong Kong event, and
yeah, well, it seems, you know, like Ergo
AMA does sound quite strange, I mean,
considering that I mean, it's a protocol,
right, and the assets are not controlled.
And, well, there is no any party, right,
which can represent itself as Ergo, then
the question is what does Ergo mean. So,
well, Ergo ecosystem is then quite better,
right, in this regard. Just a word game,
maybe. But yeah, well, there is such
feedback.
All right. That sounds good to me. We put
it on the poster this week. We'll see how
it flies. But it does make sense. There's
no. Right. I mean, we have the EF as the
official Ergo Foundation entity, but from
there it's all ecosystem people that
broadcast here and do this. You're not
part of the EF. I'm not part of the EF.
Dan, I think still an advisor, but yeah.
And also it's not official entities. So,
I mean, it was established not to control
the protocol, right? So, well, it's vision
document which I composed with the help of
MX, I believe, and some other folks back
in 2019. So, yeah, it's not saying that
this entity is, well, controlling the
protocol and this entity is official. I
mean, there is no such word everywhere. At
least we didn't make it because, I mean,
it's also quite confusing. I mean, what
does it mean, official?
So, what's... I mean, when you're talking
about something official, that does mean
some compliance and, well, responsibility,
right, and then control, but, yeah, well,
I don't think Ergo Foundation has control
to start with, and then, yeah, it doesn't
make sense to tell about other things such
as responsibility and compliance and so
on. It was designed this way. It was never
considered as official, at least when it
was established.
At some point I also removed the words
official repository, because it's the same
problem. What does it mean, official code
repository? The term is not quite clear.
And also, you know, the problem is that in
Git, you can fork the code. And there are
like tens, maybe hundreds of forks of Ergo
repository over GitHub. And you can find
words official repository in those 100
repositories around GitHub. And that
doesn't make any sense. So, well, this
should be attributed outside, but then,
yeah, it's the same question. I mean, what
makes this repository official? What does
the term mean even?
What'd you rename the GitHub to? Did you
have DAO in there at all? Like the
ergo-dev-dao-github repository for that
stuff?
No, no, so it's ergo-platform, but yeah,
well, the repository is just... So it
wasn't the node code repository, so it's
now just saying what it is, right? So,
well, it's the node code, well, yeah, so,
well, it's the initial implementation,
right, so, well, to be considered as a
reference for further implementations,
like Sigma Rust, for example, is
following, well, the Sigma SDK
implementation, right, of ErgoTree and
ErgoScript, but well, this reference
nature is not making anything official. I
mean, I don't even understand such term
here to start with. Or does it mean
official? And who can give such status to
some codes? Right, well, no any
jurisdiction or whatever considered right.
So it's misleading. It's confusing and
does not make any sense.
No, and it also doesn't lend a hand to
resilience necessarily. If you have
official things, official things can be
taken down and pulled away, and that
doesn't look good for a project
necessarily. So if it's not representing
an open source peer-to-peer project like
Ergo properly, then there's no reason to
have it there, especially because of that
kind of exposure. So without those kind of
self-proclaimed official entities, you
have a bit more resilience to the
protocol, I think.
Yeah and so what's also discussed in Hong
Kong and tell us about Hong Kong kushti
tell us about Hong Kong yeah so we heard
well like hundreds of conversations with
different entities and people around. And,
well, also talks with Sigmanauts. Well,
what we have currently in the ecosystem,
right, is, well, a variety of players or
commercial players established such as
Zengate right we had a lot of
conversations with Sam Zengate still then
yeah not legally established anywhere to
the best of my knowledge but still doing
some commercial activity such as Rosen for
example right so.
Then, yes, some non-profit organizations,
community organizations, established
nodes, such as Sigmanauts, Ergo
Foundation, Ergo Devs DAO, and so on,
right? So, well, it's now maybe... Well,
the best representation of this core,
right, could be some kind of informal
alliance, right, and then there is
actually some marketing group, well,
existing, just to think, such as
Sigmanauts, right, some private groups,
but it actually has a lot of people from
community, like 60 or 70.
So then, yeah, well, the idea, which I
still need to write down there, actually,
because, well, spending a lot of times
after the trip, well, finishing
conversations, resolving different issues
and so on. So, well, the idea is to get us
in sync right there. And then, yeah, well,
try to represent Ergo collectively, right?
Well, there are different representations
of protocols we have. Well, the core
protocol, right? And then, yeah, well,
some protocols on top of such as oracles
and so on right and infrastructure and
yeah that's totally perfect right to have
different views but then yeah well the
idea is to get in sync and represent Ergo
well as somewhat well some common grounds
which is shared, right, for different
builders of peer-to-peer everything kind
of future.
And then, yeah, well, there are different
users, right, for those entities. So for
Zengate, it's, well, mostly about B2B,
probably, right, relationships. For
MewFinance, it's, yeah, very informal kind
of relationship right and the same for
Rosen and so on but to say that it is B2C
even right if it's about again some
protocol as in case of Rosen run by like
hundreds of people right so then yeah it's
it's kind of I don't know like mostly like
digital corporation which is run by well
broad base of shareholders something like
that right.
How did that work for Bitcoin back in the
day, kushti, since you were around? How
did some kind of... Yeah, I guess so.
There were different efforts, right? So
initially it was like Bitcoin talk, right?
And well, I haven't been around back in
2010. But, yeah, from reading the forum
after, it seems it was like, I don't know,
just a bunch of enthusiasts trying to push
Bitcoin as unstoppable money, well,
launching different initiatives,
initiatives such as, well, helping
WikiLeaks, for example, right, when it was
cut by established financial institutions.
So, well, it was maybe the first, well,
marketing campaign, big marketing campaign
for Bitcoin back in 2010, right? And,
well, there are opinions that, yes,
Satoshi disappeared after, probably,
because he thinks started to be quite
serious, right? It was not just a small
peer-to-peer effort, a peer-to-peer system
from enthusiasts, right? Well, starting
with Wikileaks campaign.
But then, yeah, there was attempt to do a
Bitcoin foundation, right well with
basically the same mission I believe right
as Ergo Foundation so yeah well I guess
Ergo Foundation is kind of like third or
fourth iteration of the Bitcoin foundation
but then yeah well the foundation seems to
exist and then well what we had after and
what do we have now? Well, it was
established especially clear during the
block-sized civil war, right? So, well,
there are some commercial organizations
starting with Blockstream. So Blockstream
was a commercial company established back
in 2015 by like eight co-developers of
Bitcoin with the idea to develop
sidechains and then Lightning network as
well. So it's still doing more or less the
same, right? Not quite successful, but
Blockstream got successful in mining at
least.
mining Bitcoin, right, so it's also quite
a big miner. I don't know about these
days, but it used to be quite big. A few
years ago when I checked, it had like, I
don't know, 16% of total mining hash rate.
So yeah, Blockstream and then some other
commercial companies which are, well,
basically sponsoring co-development,
right? There are some grants, some
salaries for co-developers, but yeah, by
commercial companies. Then there are
miners for sure, big pools and hardware
manufacturers right so they're just one
company basically now but yeah back then
back in 2010 so back in block size civil
war times there were more right and so
well yeah in regards with protocol they
came into some agreements, right? Like
Hong Kong agreements.
Do you think they had not an easier time
per se, you know, because they're forging
the way with Bitcoin? Definitely a
different time, right? Because at no point
did people compare Bitcoin in the early
days to other... There were no other
market cap coins to compare it to and say,
why isn't Bitcoin rising as much or why is
Bitcoin falling more than this project
over here? So I feel like while it was
difficult for them to pave that initial
way into cryptocurrency, they didn't have
the same, you know, it's a totally
different world now than it was back then
with other VCs pumps to compare it to and
those kind I mean the number one thing we
see in chats when people try to FUD us is
right. How come this isn't performing like
this or how come this isn't performing
like this? Meanwhile you look in Ergo's
fairly well following Bitcoin or
following, you know other chains as well,
but Bitcoin didn't necessarily have that
in the beginning. There wasn't that kind
of FUD, I'd say, that most chains nowadays
are exposed to.
Well, there were no talks about pricing
at all back in 2010, right? Because there
were no exchanges. So, I mean, those
talks, yeah, well, certainly did not take
place at all about pricing. Yeah, about
competition, I don't know. So, well, I
think the biggest competition, the biggest
fear was, you know, the fear of total
crackdown and, well, the biggest fear was
and still is fear to go to real world,
right? So, and then, yeah, so Bitcoin find
itself in a little bit gray areas, right,
and still, well, the whole space is there,
and then, yeah, there is competition,
somewhat competition there, but, yeah,
well, competition for liquidity, right,
and going into this a little bit gray
zones, but, well, it's still, I think,
more or less the same challenges overall,
right.
I mean even, well, if you see like, I
don't know, 1,000 different assets on some
centralized exchanges, some centralized
exchange, right, CoinMarketCap, whatever,
the question is, well, what's the real
world impact from like, well, any of them
right beyond like a few like I don't know
Monero Bitcoin so yeah I think the answer
is zero real world impact to those
projects. Yeah, so well, it's just about
games in sandbox, but then I mean, it's
quite strange. I mean, discourse, right? I
mean, how successful Ergo is in, well,
games in a sandbox. I think it's one of
the things I see. It's strange optics,
right?
Yeah. But the global idea of
cryptocurrencies and blockchains, I still
see the narrative is still even from
people like Michael Saylor, right? Who's a
big Bitcoin proponent, right? All I see in
the tidbits of him. I'm sure maybe deep
down if I watch a video of him explaining
things are going through it There might be
more but the bottom line is the only
tidbits I see from him on Twitter or the
news sites or other big influences like
that are that you know, specifically with
Bitcoin, that Bitcoin is digital gold and
Bitcoin is the investment. At no point do
I hear the narrative ever shifted to, you
know, this is a utility and here's how we
can layer onto this and build more
utility. And here's what we can
potentially do in the future. So you have
all these voices with pushing this big
narrative of, here's this investment tool,
here's this digital gold that's
non-inflationary, that your dollar will be
worth more if you invest in it. So that
trickles down to everybody. And I'm sure
that's what's contributing to the massive
speculation on all these pump and dump and
VC investments. I think it's going to be
hard, but I think the narrative needs to
change to not just here's some
deflationary currency that you can use.
It's internet magic money, but here's what
we can do with it. And here's how it can
help people in other countries. Here's
where it can help local shop owners.
Here's where it can help people sick of
things like eBay or other things. Here's
where we have a digital stable that you
can put your money into and fight
inflation there. So yeah, I think until
the, the main narrative changes to
utility, and what it can do, we're still
going to see a massive, you know, thought
process that cryptocurrencies for
speculation and for, and for pumping and
earning.
Right. Well, actually, digital gold use
case is not that bad, right? Because,
well, it's, well, people need to store
value, right? Especially during turbulent
times. Fiat is totally unacceptable for
that. Basically, there is no stable fiat
currency. Yeah. So you can buy gold,
right? But it's quite inconvenient, right?
In many aspects then. Well, digital gold
is better, right? In many aspects. You can
send it.
Easier accessible, easier to store.
Outside, yeah, easily. You can accumulate
it easily. There is no need to, I don't
know, build storage, right? Some
underground storage in your backyard,
right? And then, I don't know, expand it
when you have more gold and so on. So,
yeah, well, it's more convenient, right?
But then, yeah, so if we are talking
about, well, not VCs, but even commercial
companies and then central banks and so
on, right? They have access to gold,
right? Well, especially central banks.
Well, in some, in actually many
jurisdictions, they monopolized access to
gold, even so, gold producers have to sell
gold to central banks in the first place,
right?
But, well, if they have digital gold,
then, yeah, I think it's quite natural,
maybe for commercial companies, actually,
in the first place, to build money on top
of rights or to have trustless
derivatives. And here Bitcoin is quite
failing and Ergo could be superior, I
believe because you can have trustless
derivatives right you can combine
collateral with trustless like ChainCash
is doing right so you can have well many
issues for real world needs on top of
programmable digital gold which is quite a
different story well especially
considering that even if you have Bitcoin
right but well, it's just an asset on your
asset sheet, right? The question is how do
you produce derivatives? Derivative
instruments to be used in international
trade, for example, right? Who will trust
your asset sheet, right, in like thousands
of kilometers away? in some remote
country. So, and well, here is trustless
derivative instruments, quite superior,
right?
So, yeah, well, had a lot of talks about
that, and yeah, it seems that there is
huge demand for that, right? So, and well,
it's it's developing in different ways
around the globe, right? So, well, in the
US, for example, as far as I know, well,
there is prohibition for CBDC now, right?
But then there are commercial companies
like Tether basically doing free banking,
so issuing dollar, right? minting USD
rights according to some corporate
procedures basically. I don't know what
kind of oversight they have now but
initially I hate it was there was no
oversight, right? Well, it's hard to say
what's going on now, but yeah, probably
with relocation to Salvador, right? There
wouldn't be much oversight also, right? So
this is basically about going to free
banking, right? The system where, well,
money created without oversight from
central bank by private banks, right, so
currently money created by private banks
as well, but a tight oversight from
central banks talking about reserve system
assets control.
Free banking, there is need for
transparency, right? Especially talking
about international trade, right? Global
setting, like this operating case. Yeah,
well, I think programmable gold, again, is
a bit misjudged, right? It's not allowing
for derivatives. Yeah, well, at the end of
the day, there were a lot of Bitcoin
events about Lightning network and so on.
Well, it's still basically early stage and
what's Lightning guys, TAPS companies are
to do now is to get away the initial
peer-to-peer, totally peer-to-peer
Lightning design, right? So basically
compromising the initial design in the
name of convenience and so on and well the
whole Bitcoin DeFi movement I believe is
about getting trustless derivatives but
it's going slowly there are certain issues
on the way and so yeah.
How do we wedge in there? How do we you
know, it's got to be from what I my
posture on Bitcoin users, maybe just an
axis that I'm exposed to is that you know,
if it's not Bitcoin, it's nothing right?
So how do we that's that's a hard hard
market to bust into and especially say
look, you know your protocol is amazing.
It's Bitcoin. It's digital gold It's been
around forever, right? It's the first one
Well, not first one, but you know first
big one But here's a layer with Ergo that
can turn your Bitcoin into you know
lending platform peer-to-peer swaps all
that kind of stuff. So how do we I mean,
that's a market we have to break into, I
think, right? So I think that should be a
lot of our focus as well, is not only
preaching that to those people, but
showing by example, as well as marketing
to them.
Right, so then maybe it's better to start
with, well, entities which do need for
monetary expansion, right, so which are
using Bitcoin for reserves, right, on
other levels, so it could be some small
community, right, or a big corporation.
Because if there is some guy which just
bought Bitcoin and then claiming
superiority of Bitcoin, I mean, that's
understandable story, but I mean, what can
you do with that? It's just a guy who
bought, I mean, like brick of digital
gold. And that's it, right? So it's not
about need for derivatives, right, or
whatever. So then I think it's better to
find some partners in the real world. And
here we also had a lot of conversations
and, well, it's too early to announce
anything but yeah well actually Ergo is
now well I think since second half of 2024
so well it's now under radar of many
entities so from even Bitcoin OG whales I
know about some to some big Middle East
funds and so on. Now it's also known that
it's under the radar of some Chinese funds
and so on so yeah well I think I think
well well, the recognition is coming,
right? Because, well, it's kind of an
interesting time, right?
So, well, again, back to consensus Hong
Kong. So, well, partly it was like meme
coins funeral, right? So, it was quite
clear to most people that after this scam
space, well, this scam space is going to
be, recognized, right? I mean, it was
quite clear, since like early days.
Are very clear than what it is. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it was quite clear
that it's about scams, but you know, I
mean, when you have like billions at
stake, so you have, you know, like, CEOs
of centralized exchanges talking complete
nonsense like meme coins will be the next
cycle, which is completely insane. I mean,
it's like, I don't know.
But it's like, it's like, it's like
burning. It's burning paper to keep warm
instead of wood, you know, or coal.
But when you have stake, when you have
stake in it, then you can tell even such
nonsensical things, right? Like scams will
be the next big thing. Yeah, I mean, scams
are always making crypto, unfortunately,
right? But I mean, making a trend out of
scams. So yeah, even biggest centralized
exchanges, which tried to push such absurd
nonsense back in 2024, now stepped down,
you know, because, well, it's way too
much, right? So retail cannot consume this
anymore, right? Because, well, I don't
know, it's too scammy to start with. I
mean, it's a much bigger scam than all
those previous scams, centralized
exchanges supported.
Yeah, I hear that. That's the noisiest
part, right? I mean, those people as well,
unfortunately, once those things dry up,
they're looking for the next thing. And I
think we just have to keep shouting
utility and usefulness and that kind of
stuff to perhaps be picked up in whatever
cycle is coming next, but yeah, it's
really tough to you know, go somewhere and
talk about it and the number one thought
on people's mind is a crypto scam. Isn't
that the Trump coin isn't that the meme
coin, you know kind of thing so it's a
hard battle of fight against but I think
Sigmanauts are positioned in a good way at
least because we have the we have the beef
right we have the stuff to back it up and
say look, you know, whenever that happens
and somebody says it's a scam I say hey
look, here's what we have on Ergo. Here's
what we're doing. You know, that's totally
wind going by us that we don't technically
listen to too often except when people
come in and FUD so in those conversations
I say we have this we have something like
SigmaFi where if you want to buy a car and
you have crypto that you don't want to
cash out necessarily you can You know
speculate a little bit and lend it, swap
it for SigmaUSD, cash out and then pay
yourself back slowly to repay the loan or
DuckPools or those kinds of financial
tools. So there's so much stuff on Ergo
that I can point to to these people to
make them think oh really? You know, that
can be done. That's not just a magic money
kind of thing. So I definitely think we're
well positioned more than anybody else in
that matter.
Right. And yeah, also more interesting
tooling is coming. So index funds, for
example, right. Well, another iteration of
ErgoRaffle, I think it would be much more
useful for just ordinary folks, right,
which are willing to collect ERGs for
their project, for example, but USD,
right, or maybe even gold-denominated
assets such as Gluon or Dexy Gold. And,
yeah, so for Dexy Gold, well, as UI, well,
the second attempt to UI is quite near.
Hopefully we can launch well in coming
days, weeks. Let's see.
You see the beautiful, yeah, you see the
pictures from C8?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. So then, yeah, so well,
the plan, you know, is to, well, resolve
storage rent issue for SigmaUSD bank box
and then yeah well I can issue take last
look and generate with AI some more tests
for Dexy Gold but yeah that's just I don't
know like one day one and a half and then
yeah we can go live. So, yeah, the Dexy
Gluon, but then, yeah, index funds. Index
funds, I see them as, well, brick also for
building financial infrastructure. So, for
example, for ChainCash, right, well, if
you are willing to put, like, multiple
assets in reserve, then you can do your
index funds, right, put assets there and
then use index funds tokens as a ChainCash
reserve basically right and by that you
may have like multi-asset reserve and so
on and yeah well another thing which could
be quite interesting and yeah I'm
currently checking is to have
collateralized off-chain cash right with
well clearing off-chain clearing, and then
redemption to layer 2, but then most of
transactions in small communities, for
example, would be cleared before
redemption, so you can use it for charity,
instead of providing loans, you can just
who provides donations to some African
village for example so you can put
collateral and issue payment notes and
then most of them would be cleared on the
way so you have like 20x of economic
activity versus your collateral which is
much improvements right in comparison with
donation.
Is this like an offshoot of ChainCash,
kushti, using kind of the same idea?
It's just off-chain collateralized cash.
But yeah, also you can go further, right?
So for example, you can put your funds,
not in like on-chain contracts, bound
collateral, but to DAO treasury, right?
For example. And then, yeah, these DAO may
vote which are not created within
community to redeem, right, which are not.
So when there is need to go outside, for
example, for some community, right, they
can vote on redemption, right, but
otherwise you can have money circulation
within community just like an LETS system,
right? So without any collateral, without
anything, just IOU community notes, right?
And then in case of international, well,
inter-community trading, so you can go to
treasury. Actually, that's quite used in
some parts of Mexico, even. There are some
communities in Chiapas, for example, which
are quite autonomous, but they need some
money sometimes, and to make this money
they are selling coffee some premium
coffee actually, but they're selling just
a little bit to cover expenses needed when
they're interacting with outer world and
so on.
Yeah, so, well, it's just like tools,
right, what we do have in DeFi, I believe.
And, well, it's now time, as there are
enough tools, to go outside and, well, to
become a reserve asset for different
calibers from small communities to, well,
as it's permissionless, right, and then
you can expect big players, well, even
maybe state level actors at some point
like happened with Bitcoin right no nobody
predicted that by the way back in 2010 it
wasn't it was it was quite anti-state
right back in 2010 but yeah it's happening
so and well you cannot prevent right this
and permissionless system but what's what
should be in focus for builders, I
believe, is how to serve, well, real
needs, right? And, well, communities
people in need. And then, I don't know,
big players will come, I think, because,
well, everyone will realize what's real,
what's not here after all.
I mean, that's a hope, right? Yeah. Let
me just give two quick updates before we
jump into questions. Maybe one, we've got
to vote up on Sigmanauts at least from the
Sigmanauts side. We've got to vote up on
Sigmanauts to send neuro yogi Mark the
Shark to Disrupt, which is a big mining
conference in Miami. So I think it's very
important that we Ergo as a proof of work
chain, even though you know, it's, there's
a lot of ASICs and those kinds of things
at this conference. That's the center of
it that we send somebody down there to
mill around say the word Ergo get people
out there and let them know that GPU
mining is there and benefits of it and the
peer-to-peer kind of resilience of it. So
that vote is a couple days in a couple
days more left. Hopefully it's looking
positive and we'll be able to fund them to
get out there. We'll make them a bunch of
business cards big ones with like a wallet
on the front and in the back things like
the Sigmanauts mining DAO or Rosen Bridge
or those kind of things where yeah you
know if you're mining Bitcoin over there
with your ASIC and you have a large store
of them why not put them to use why not
bring them over to Ergo and use our
learning systems, use our DAOs to help run
those things. So that's a message there
that we're hoping to do. And I think Mark
will be very successful at it.
We also have a vote up. We've revamped
our SigShop. So you might see some new
postings on MewFinance. HQx is going to
handle all that front end stuff. And then
we've got myself to ship them out to you
once they come in. So we've kind of
divided up the work as opposed to all
being on one person. So those are up.
We've got all the inventory matched with
his site. So please order away, order your
stuff. We've got hats, sweatshirts, and
t-shirts. Once those run out, we'll talk
about doing different stuff and maybe take
votes on what you want to see next for
swag. So those are the two things out of
the Sigmanauts. Anything out of the
developers DAO question specifically
before we go to questions?
Yeah, so we're also having first voting.
So yeah, the key is distributed. And yeah,
well, I'm having some issues with my
voting to try to understand. But yeah,
it's quite exciting to see it's in action
in the form of DAO. So yeah, well, and
well, it's also good to see more
contributors. So well, we have some guys
back now, like Corbey Chalador, and some
new guys. So there was quite intense
developers chat yesterday. And yeah,
that's just the beginning, I believe.
Nice, yeah, I'm looking at Paideia now.
You guys have your first vote up that's
active. 100% yes, it looks like it's going
to pass.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. So we'll do more. And
yeah, so there is also a fundraising I'm
doing for DevsDAO basically. So for
security audit of 6.0 to be made by Dusek.
Actually, he already found quite a lot of
issues, right? Especially around
versioning. It would be good to do more
audit. We continue to check all the
things. But yeah, well, he found even some
non-trivial DOS possibilities. So yeah,
that's quite amazing. I think should be
rewarded. So please check raffles on
ergoraffle.com.
All right, very cool. All right, let's
dive in. We've got... Let's see. I had to
mute the Big 3D. He was being a little
special there, but let's see if he has any
good questions in the beginning. Well
we'll take this from him. It won't let me
show it actually. Let me see. All right.
All right. Let me show it. It won't let me
show this question, but I'll read it. He
says, the Big 3D says what's happening
with Kraken is Ergo. Will it be listed in
the future? So you don't know there was a
there was a comment by Dave I believe it
said his name Peter maybe I can't keep
track of the Dave and Peters on the on
there, let me look it up. It is Peter that
said that you know, it were there was some
misunderstandings in his his response
there but we as Sigmanauts are thrifty,
right and useful of our resources, so we
are currently trying to go through another
method to get our voices heard behind the
Kraken lines. So keep you updated as it
can go, but we'll see what happens, right?
And furthermore, we always have Rosen-ERG
to back up on. That application is in.
Peter's aware of it. You know, we got the
classic DM response of, you know, we have
a lot of things in our backlog, but we're
hoping our new countermeasure to penetrate
their defenses will go off smoothly. So
we'll see how that goes.
All right, all right. But yeah, well, as
I have some experience of talking with
centralized exchanges. Talks with MEXC
started, for example, back in 2019. I had
some calls and a lot of talks with one of
the top managers, actually. I don't know,
maybe because it was a small exchange
maybe back then. Quite small.
Well, a lot of these things happen,
kushti, with personal relationships,
right? So, I mean, that's technically the
avenue we're attempting here. So, yeah.
Right. So, yeah. Well, relationships and
also a lot of, but again, always
happening, right? With MEXC, it started
with like 5 Bitcoin, right? But finally,
well, it was community fundraiser. For how
much in total, like 60k? I don't know, for
40k, 60k, something like that. Yeah, and
well, yeah, and it was much better than
five Bitcoin, right? And well, it was also
about much bigger exchange in 2024 than
back in 2019. Right, so, well, you know,
if you are not listed, then you can always
be in talks, right, so they are not
finishing, so, well, there is no point
here, right, so, period, I mean, here,
well, until it's listed. Right. So well,
we have another rounds and, let's see,
well, whether, we will be successful in
these rounds or another one.
Yeah. But yeah, I mean, that's just game
rights. Quite strange, but, well, yeah, I
think actually, well, it should be in
focus maybe at this point. Well, there is
need for some U.S. exchange, right, for
sure. Critical needs maybe depending on
community feedback but other than that so
it's always better to spread vision right
and well to take care about recognition
and getting more Sigmanauts on board and
we'll get more builders, right? And yeah,
well, to build liquidity around and so on.
And then yes, centralized exchanges will
come, right? Naturally. But yeah, well, at
the same time, it's good to continue to
talk, at least to get temperature right in
the room.
No, right. Yeah. I mean, brigading, too,
is also fun online, right? I love seeing
the Sigmanauts bomb, Twitter bomb Kraken,
and Dave and Peter. It's always fun to
see. That's, I think, that's a good
indicator of a live community, and that
shouldn't be stopped. That's great.
We have a comment for the website. I
think you need to update their website
team Some links are broken some CEXes that
listed Ergo, but not linked on Ergo
website. That's I believe you can suggest
changes to that or maybe that's dev docs
on the Ergo website, but that's Glasgow,
ping Glasgow. That man's happy to fix
everything and he will be surprised if
there are things like that so please ping
Glasgow directly to make him aware of that
kind of stuff for the website.
Let's see. Here's a question from Bobcat.
He's wondering, are there any plans to do
joint eUTXO hackathons with either Cardano
or Bitcoin ecosystems to increase
visibility?
Yeah that'd be nice with Rosen right with
Rosen it's interoperable right you can
have a joint hackathon and have a common
token between them so yeah it's possible
but the question is would would others be
willing to do that right we're part of
somewhat part of the UTXO alliance so I
guess we could start it there yeah there
but you know actually it's interesting
idea so well I can I can bring awareness
to UTXO alliance calls and maybe it's what
to discuss with Cardano peers as well.
So in the last week we spoke about, we
spoke about a mini hackathon for,
sponsored by the Sigmanauts and it jumps
off of Mark's idea to specifically train
an AI model to not only write ErgoScript
and smart contracts, but to check it too.
So you have one that does both, or you
have a specially trained model to write it
in a special chain model to check it. So
those kinds of things could also be, you
know, that could be across many chain
collaboration with Cardano to get it to
write smart contracts and Cardano as well
as Ergo. So maybe we can see if Mark knows
anybody over in Cardano land or any
Sigmanauts do to see if anybody's
interested that that may be something
coming down the pipe.
No, let's see. Well, it would be funny
even to have maybe Bitcoin and
ErgoHackathon. But we need to do some
counterpart. Because we can do stuff like
DLC contracts and the different atomic
swaps and so on. So, well, things which
are quite quite common for both
blockchains, right? So I don't know. Let's
see. Let me also answer from FC Alex
thoughts. So if any on recent discussions,
that's Jack Dorsey, Satoshi, no comment.
Yeah. So, you know, Satoshi is not some I
don't know, philosopher, like writer, or
the internet, right, like fiction writer.
But yeah, so he is a developer, C++
developer, and he is using, he used I
mean, quite unique style of coding, right?
So then she show me Jack Dorsey C++ code
and I can tell her. But yeah, I'm pretty
sure he's not because I'm not quite sure,
Jack Dorsey used C++ ever in his life. And
you know, Satoshi's C++, I mean, it's
quite unique, as I said, so it's not like
professional corporate developers C++,
more like hacker or InfoSec, maybe
developer C++. Right, so well, it's quite
unique and it's a thing which you cannot
really fake, I believe, especially back
then, right, without AI and whatever.
Because, yeah, well, there are some things
like how you work with stack and so on,
which are showing what you are usually
doing. And so, yeah, well, based on that,
Satoshi was quite like a hacker, an
InfoSec developer, maybe. Not a professor
in cryptography, for example, definitely
not a corporate developer. not Jack
Dorsey, not Nick Szabo and so on, right?
Well, in regards with other candidates,
the first question is, show me the code,
right? Well, especially around that time.
So, for example, I found some Adam Back's
code from 2007 on the Internet, and yeah,
I can say that Adam Back is not Satoshi as
well right because well it's it's quite
different so and you cannot really change
style in like months you know right okay
let's see we've yeah sorry gone we've got
let's answer this really quickly for
people wondering.
Why did Joe leave the foundation? I think
from my understanding Joe leaving the
foundation gave him more flexibility to
run his own projects, right? So now he
could focus more on Rosen Bridge which
needs a ton of focus, right? They're not
only dealing with you know, it's not like
they're dealing with one chain here
They're dealing with Cardano Bitcoin
Ethereum Binance and he's got a fairly
large team to run as well. So so all that
kind of stuff, as well as all of Joe's
musings, I believe led Joe to want more
flexibility in that kind of project
running. So that's why he took the leap
there. That's my understanding.
Yeah. And Joe's around. Yeah. Well, we
have talks like daily, maybe. Well,
almost. And yeah. So, he's also publishing
quite nice articles, these days. Right.
He's got like four or five that he sent
me.
Yeah. Very nice. Yeah. What's, what are
they? The, the internet?
Yeah. Yeah, but also a new proof-of-work
scheme, tailored for high-performance
AI-oriented GPUs like H100. Yeah, that's
quite interesting.
Those 85 gig memory GPUs, what to do with
them after they get dueled for AI. He's
got a nice write-up on that. Pretty cool.
Yeah.
Yeah. Well, and also some modification to
the Bitcoin runes protocol to have
metadata which can be used then maybe for
Ergo applications.
All right. Let's see here. We have Bobcat
wants to know if there's any follow-up to
Navjit the CEO at Iagon Yeah, Bobcat.
That's we spoken with him that's part of
the path that we're looking forward to
build a real relationship with somebody
behind the lines of Kraken so thankfully
Navjit has some connections and we're
moving forward with that the best we can
so very grateful for Navjit to reach out
to us on Twitter very thankful let's see
we've got you want to talk about.
All right. Let's see. Misfit toy has two
questions. They're centered around
sub-blocks, but he's saying, Mr. McCracken
from ADA, from Cardano says the biggest
hurdle for Ergo getting adopted more and
it's the slowness. Do you agree? Then the
follow up question is how fast will
sub-blocks make Ergo fast in Solana? He
says it'll be one of the fastest period to
peak, but not AWS. What's the difference
kind of thing. So I guess a general
question about, in summary, kushti, are
two-minute block times causing a slowness
and adoption of Ergo and will sub-blocks
appease those people who want fast
confirmation times?
Yeah, I don't know. So, well, I never
heard, for example, that's, you know, like
10 minutes blocks. Well, it's a problem
for Bitcoin adoption.
Right. What is it? 10 minute blocks on
Bitcoin? Bitcoin is 10. I can't remember.
So it's 10 on average, but yeah, there
was the case once when, you know, like
many years ago, I met one guy to cash out.
And yeah, we did wait for block, well,
some space for like, one hour and a half.
Yes. So sometimes you can wait like two
hours for Bitcoin block. And, yeah, well,
I, I never heard that this is a problem
for adoption. I mean, it, it depends on
what, what, what, what adoption looks
like. Right. So, well, it's, if adoption
is about, well, games and sandbox again,
like, well uh having a meme coin casino
right like pump.fun then yeah maybe yeah i
mean it's but i mean it's not some some
kind of adoption which is expected, right?
And Ergo protocol could not be good here.
Well, not because of block time, but
because of peer-to-peer nature, right? So
when you have like hundreds of laptops,
ordinary laptops, like you're using some
laptop, right? qx(). for running an Ergo
node and so probably you wouldn't be happy
to see it's been overloaded because of
some casino, right?
Yeah, so then there are some specialized
networks which are not peer-to-peer
actually like Solana and so on and so on,
right, which are well suited for meme
casinos or tap games or all that stuff.
So, well, it's quite pointless to talk
about competition with them, because it's
different classes, right? I mean, you
cannot compare peer-to-peer network with
data center-based BFT, somewhat. But block
time, it's the same. I mean, if it's
peer-to-peer, it's it would be like Ergo
in a way right and then yeah if it's data
center based and yeah you can have a meme
coin casino right talking about adoption
right no not not just confirmation time so
that the question is what adoption is
right and so if we are talking about
things like, I don't know, programmable,
digital, gold-like assets for a resource
of any caliber, right? Then, yeah, well,
it's two minutes block is okay. And there
is no issue here.
Yeah, that's something that's
Yeah, then if we are talking about
payments, right, like the very natural
thing you can do with money, then yeah, I
mean, it's then sub-blocks would make a
difference. But yeah, I believe after all,
with adoption, so most of transactions
even in regards with payments would be
off-chain, right? Because well, it's
whether you have sub-blocks or whatever
the question is. Can your laptop do that,
right? Also being connected with hundreds,
thousands of laptops around the globe. And
if it's about some crazy meme coins
casino, then yeah, there is no technology,
right, which can do magic here, right? I
mean, there is no magic. We have just a
data center based systems which are doing
great finance like meme coins casino but
then it's I mean it's simply dangerous for
the founders maybe even right to some
point because it's it's pretty much like
having PayPal right but also without any
licenses and yeah, also with a crazy
casino on top of with a lot of crazy
events happening like daily from
presidential rugpulls to now also
suicides, right, and live streams.
Absolutely insane, yeah.
And so, yeah, and if it's run on top of
centralized system like Solana, right, and
so on, then at some point there would be
question of responsibility, right, of
organizers of all such systems.
Yeah, I think I think that'll come with
education custody I think I think you know
people just touching systems based on meme
tokens. That's all they see right They see
why isn't Ergo able to support this or why
aren't people flocking to Ergo for this
kind of craze and I think it's a matter of
time in the ecosystem and a realization of
what blockchain the sustainability of
blockchains actually is in the future and
that's what Ergo is, in my opinion,
peer-to-peer networks, finance, tooling,
that kind of thing.
So it's just an education thing, I think,
when people make that distinction of...
Yeah, going back to Satoshi, so he also
stated pretty clear why peer-to-peer
structure of network was chosen, right,
and why Bitcoin is following certain
paradigms and Bitcoin not appeared out of
something, right. So there were more
centralized payment systems which were
shut down before, right? And so Bitcoin
was actually quite a counter reaction to
those shutdowns, right? So yeah, I mean,
and well, it seems it's all it's all
silenced these days right so well for some
reason we need to to have something with
totally idiotic discourse rights, which is
completely ignoring the history of
cryptocurrencies, of Bitcoin, of payment
systems, after all, pre-Bitcoin payment
systems. Then the next question, how fast
will sub-blocks make Ergo faster than
Solana? Yeah, so it could be maybe faster
for some notion of confirmation, right?
But yeah, still still, it, it, it wouldn't
be about, you know, like, bringing, I
don't know, millions of transactions, to,
to, to hopefully laptops.
Hopefully we can program in some failed
transactions to them, given that same
experience.
Sorry.
Hopefully we can program in some failed
transactions just to give them the same
experience.
A lot of system messages to be counted as
transactions and so on. Yeah. So actually
a performance wise proof of work protocols
like Ergo are the best, but then yeah, you
need to consider that there is peer to
peer network after all. Right. And there
is commodity here. Well, because there is
need to have secure network, not data
center-based network with not so efficient
even BFT protocol, consensus protocol, but
also with very centralized approach to
everything.
We've got a good question from CLS90ZZZ
on Rosen. What happens if Rosen guards do
a mistake like Bybit multi-sign instead
once the Rosen-ERG price crash versus ERG
on Bybit? If you've got your funds out,
you're fine. But with Rosen, you look
exposed forever. So I can give a stab at
that question. You can correct me. If I'm
if I'm wrong. So Rosen has right so in
order to fake out Rosen you need to
socially attack the watchers and I guess
hack the guards, right? So you have to
socially engineer the guards or else find
out their locations and their IPs and what
machines are running them on and try to
hack that so remember, the Bybit Multi-Sig
error was going from a cold wallet to
another wallet, redoing the contract for
that. So if you're talking about watchers
and guards, first of all, you'd have to
get a majority of the watchers fake an
actual transaction right and then the
guards would find that transaction and
most likely they'd catch it and see that
it was a fake transaction right somehow so
you have that double layer there let's say
you compromise the guards on top of that
right the guards would have the guards
still need to look on the chain so you'd
have to essentially compromise both the
watcher system and the guard systems to
get a fake transaction through that way
right so let's go to the cold wallet side.
The way that we work from cold wallet on
the guards is we literally have cold
devices that we initiate transactions on.
So in order to fake us out there, you
would then have to compromise one of the
guards and initiate a cold signing
transaction that we see that. It's not
broadcast anywhere. We do it with our
local communications group. So in the
beauty about Ergo, the beauty about
pulling things from cold storage, even in
Cardano, is that we can see exactly what
address it's going to, right? There's no
complexity as there would be in something
like the Bybit attack where they can
change the multi-sig contract without you
even really knowing, right? They can mask
it. So on Ergo, everything's perfectly
viewable before we sign cold transactions
to get them into the hot wallet. We can
say, okay, here's the originating wallet.
Yep, here are the boxes in the originating
wallet. Here are the funds that are
transferring, and here's the wallet it's
going to, and it's visible every step of
the way. So that kind of Bybit attack
would be extremely hard or near impossible
on Rosen Bridge or Ergo. kushti, you want
to correct or fix?
kushti, you want to correct or fix?
I can add that Multisig is also done very
differently from Ethereum and Solana,
right? Well, in Ethereum and Solana, for
example, it's about some predefined
contracts SDK contracts and well there was
issue with re-entrancy for example there
which resulted into wormhole hack of 120
million USD so in Ethereum that's about
well again some contracts not even
standard to the best of my knowledge then
yeah there were different contracts so for
example parity which also lost like
hundreds of millions back then probably in
current prices much more like I don't know
billions maybe because of yeah well
contracts had possibility for everyone to
nuke it and then yeah some schoolboy nuked
it and then, yeah, so he wrote on Reddit
or some forum, I've forgotten, like, oh,
yeah, yeah, your contract is allowing for
call suicide. And yeah, I just made
suicide call and it seems instead. So, you
know, for a lot of funds, so Parity funds
got from Polkadot ICO and also funds of
users of that library, multi-sig library,
but Parity were lost. Other contracts also
not immutable. I still need to check
details, but it seems it was the case. Not
an immutable multi-sig. So in case of
Ergo, Multisig is immutable, right? So
it's natively supported. There are no
re-entrancy calls and so on because, well,
no re-entrancy here. And yeah, well, it's
also truly ZK, right? So from, if ZK is
used, ZK signature is used by guards. But
probably it's right, because it's about
some custom software, so then it's
possible. So then, yeah, well, it's very
different, actually, implementation of
Multisig. Well, on Ergo, blockchain versus
Ethereum and so on. Well, it's much
simpler and immutable, so safer in general
for users, I believe.
Yeah. Yeah. They'd have to literally
change sources from that. So we'd see that
in the transaction, that it was actually
going to another wallet. So that would be
very hard to pull the wool over the eyes
of the guards in that matter. So yeah. All
right. Let's see. We've got, let's see,
one more question. I think this is a good
question. We have many whales in Ergo.
What advice would you give to them to
utilize a margin investment to maybe get
some type of return? or to help with
adoption with a large investment. kushti,
the amount of times I see arbitrage
opportunities on the chains that Ergo is
linking to, whether it was Rosen Bridge,
there's many arbitrage opportunities for
whales to utilize that. There's lending on
DuckPools, there's lending on SigmaFi,
they're supporting projects as well that
come up as well support early and and work
with them for your investment there, too
so that would be my spit out of what
whales can do to help bolster the
ecosystem as well as their own their own
bags to help them work for them. We do
have we do currently have whales doing
some arbitrage across but not as much as
could be done. That's for sure We had a
whale try to tank DuckPools the other day,
right they they changed the, what's it
called? They tried to lower the price,
with lowering the price of ERG and the
demand on the SigmaUSD pool, it liquidated
a lot of users. So that's a not very good
way to make use your bags. So that's for
sure. I'm kind of dishonest, but it's
financial, you know, it's permissionless.
That's financial linked to tooling. So, I
mean, you got to watch out for that stuff.
But yeah, in the short arbitrage, SigmaFi
DuckPools, supporting projects are great
ways to make use your bags work for you.
Yeah well and getting providing more
liquidity right so getting better
liquidity everywhere so it's quite
profitable for whales so well Cardano
whales it seems I know most of folks
provided liquidity on Cardano DEXes and
yeah it seems they're quite happy about,
well, APY, all that stuff, you know, and,
well, it's, it seems so liquidity
provision is also good for a price, right?
Because, well, people need to buy ERG then
there is need for liquidity, right? And...
Not just ERG, right? Not just ERG, there
are many opportunities on Spectrum, on
Ergo DEXes, as well where you can create
yield farms, right? Yeah, so if you want
to invest your Rosen-ERG bag, your ERG bag
into projects, and then provide liquidity
for those projects on DEXes, you could
also yield farm. So you'll be getting
extra token bonuses from those yield farms
too. So keep an eye out for those kinds of
things too, and snap those up when you
can.
Right, but then, yeah, so Spectrum,
Uniswap, PancakeSwap, then there is
Spectrum DEX, right, and here is also...
MewDex, MewDex, kushti.
MewDex, yeah, so there is also, well,
need for liquidity, so... there are many
pairs which can be created in order to get
from arbitrage just for example Gluon Gold
to SigmaUSD right pool it's probably not
there right but then you can naturally
earn through arbitrage with ERG pool and
the same for many assets actually so I
haven't seen even ADA to ERG and then
again, you can earn from arbitrage. So
bots will do arbitrage automatically.
If you guys watch the Rosen Bridge
website, you'll see 40,000 ERGs going back
and forth, 50,000 ERGs going back and
forth, hitting these arbitrage
opportunities. So it's being done, but it
needs some more competition, I think.
Yeah, but then there is need for more
thick Bitcoin liquidity, Bitcoin, and so
on, right? So, well, I think whales have
not just ERGs, probably also Bitcoin,
USDT, and so on, right? So then, yeah, a
lot of liquidity provision which would be
good for Ergo, right? After all, because
well, the deeper liquidity is yeah, about
more possibilities everywhere. All right,
so yeah, it seems, yeah, it's time to end
the AMA, right?
We've gone, I've got to get back to real
work, kushti. All right, everybody, thanks
so much for joining. It's been a pleasure.
Thanks for all the questions. That was
great.
Alright, alright. Yeah, thank you
everyone. Thank you, bye.