Hey, everybody.
My name is qx().
I'm a Sigmanauts.
And with me, I have Dan Friedman and he's
a Sigma.
It is.
Oh, Dan Friedman.
Oh, he switched us.
That was really trippy.
That was super trippy.
Wow.
You missed that one to be Dan Friedman
for a minute.
Darn it.
Yeah, sorry, you're not handsome enough
to be, I'm not. I had a good, I had a
couple good lines too I was gonna spout
out that like I am Dan Friedman and I'm
here to bring you just an amazing, amazing
AMA of stuff for Ergo. So with me I got,
well, I got qx() and his three favorite
boxes to his right.
Oh, yeah, those are great. That's a
classic example of project managers being
awful.
Yeah, it's a classic example of you not
putting your shit away.
No, no, no. That's out on purpose to
remind me to take it to New York City when
I go there. Huge project that we did. A
lot of stuff. And whoever was... I don't
want to blame the architect designer.
Maybe the builders. I don't know.
Yeah, you blame the architect designer.
Whoever was putting the floor box plates
into the boxes that are showing behind the
stage didn't make sure they were going to
fit. So it's easier for me to just buy
them and install them myself. But classic
kind of little punchlist stuff that is
$3,000 a fix or $200 for me to buy it and
take it down there and fix it kind of
thing.
I have no idea what you're talking about,
but... Well, it's okay.
How's your week been, Dan? You had a
successful Zengate liquidity launch,
right?
We did a thing. Yeah, we did a thing. We
launched a token for those of you who have
been living under a rock. Yeah, Palm is
out and it is live. And yes, sir, it used
none other than Rosen Bridge to go
multi-chain at launch. That's amazing,
sir. Which was really cool. It worked
fantastically.
So the thing that I was wondering about
is how would arbitrage work between the
two chains. And it actually worked really
well. The price is pretty much the same on
both sides, on the Binance side as well as
the Cardano side. Staking is working
really well on both sides. Yeah, just
everything really worked out well. I mean,
Rosen worked fantastically. And so like I
said, I'm very happy to be the first
official multi-chain token launch using
Rosen. So kudos to the Rosen team. And
yeah, it was no complaints yet.
Give it time, right?
Yeah. Give it time. We'll find something.
So it currently, can you do more stuff?
Like let's say people only really... Let's
say people enter from the Binance side. Is
there a benefit for them to move over to
the Cardano side to have more utility with
your token at this point or vice versa?
At this point, well, first of all,
there's more support on the Cardano side.
So we just have more support for more
wallets. So on the Binance side, I think
we got Metamask support. But, you know, it
works weird because you would think that
Binance works with Binance, but it
actually works with Ethereum. And it
always confused the shit out of me, like,
why is that? You know, I mean, I know why
that is, but I'm just saying it's kind of
like a really, really weird UX, qx().
I thought Binance Chain was based off
Ethereum, no?
It's based off Ethereum, but for example,
if you're using a ledger with Binance, you
have to turn on the Ethereum app. Yeah.
Not the Binance app, although they have a
Binance app, but that's just for holding
tokens. For you to do any kind of smart
contract stuff, you have to turn on the
Ethereum app.
Oh, interesting.
It's just weird UX. It's just really
weird UX. So yeah, so on the Cardano side,
you have a lot more... Well, we also have
the community that's mostly on the Cardano
side. So there's that. But, but really we
try to kind of, you know, spread utility
evenly. So you do, you can, and you're
supposed to be able to do the same stuff
on both chains.
And so this is what I was talking about
in the previous AMA, which, why we can't
just kind of like, you know, flip a switch
and get Ergo support is because it has to
be the exact same stuff on Ergo. And we
will eventually, we'll put assets on Ergo,
but we can't just, you know, we can't just
like move it over. It's not as simple as
that. If we move it over and it doesn't
have the same support, the same utility,
then it's a problem. It's a problem for
regulators.
But on the Cardano side, you've got more
wallet support. You have more community
support.
Are you still giving it away for a stake
pool rewards as well?
Yeah. Yeah. And, and, and exactly. Yeah.
So, so on the Cardano side, you still have
the ISPO, which is still happening. Right.
So, we don't have that on the Binance
side, because there's no stake pools in
them. Well, there are stake pools, but
they don't work the same way as, as they
do on the Cardano side. So, yeah.
On the Ergo side, would you use the code
from ErgoPad eventually and refactor that
or start from scratch for staking?
I mean, the thing is that I actually
talked to Luca about that and I've talked
to Luca about the smart contracts on
Paideia or Paideia or whatever but do we
however you say it in a really weird you
know upstate New York accent Paideia yeah
Paideia whatever papa papa papa deal
papaya. Their smart contracts for staking
don't do the same stuff. So it's different
type of staking. We have liquid staking,
which works differently, or I'm sorry, not
liquid, dynamic staking, which works
differently. And so for us to actually
utilize those contracts, I mean, it was
really, we'd probably just have to do our
own thing over.
So explain the dynamic staking. I miss
that.
Yeah, so basically, it's dynamic. It's
unlocked staking, but it is divided by, I
think, what is it, every seven days. And
so it's not delegated staking. where your
tokens are locked into staking, but it can
be unlocked at any time. So there is no
wait like you would on an exchange or
something. Sometimes if you stake on, say,
Coinbase, they call it staking, but they
actually lock your tokens up if you stake
Cardano tokens. With our staking, although
the tokens are locked up for staking, you
can unlock them at any time instantly. And
the only thing is, if you are before the
end of that epoch, or the staking epoch,
you just don't get those rewards. You have
to stay to the end of the epoch. But other
than that, it's dynamic staking.
So it's like ErgoPad, but you'd have to
refactor in the epoch.
There's actually more to it. That's a
super simple way of explaining it, but
there's more to it. Actually, you can
check it out. If you go on the Palm
Economy socials, there are links and also
the Discord as well. Actually, Discord is
probably better because I think Palm
Economy would have to find the tweets
where we put in the links for the portals.
But on the Discord, you have links readily
available, and you can check it out.
We have a staking calculator tool that
shows you APY and APR with a little
sliding tool to show you if you stake this
much, how much it would come out as, and
so on and so forth. And so we already have
something like, I think, like 250 million
palms staked. So at current prices, that's
about a quarter of a million dollars
already staked in the first couple of
days. A little more, more like $300,000
worth of palms staked. And more and more
is growing.
What actually I spoke to one of our in
fact our first. Token holder from way
back. You know, and he came in at the
angel round. So these guys are, you know,
like these guys are the whales that came
in at the angel round. And he's basically
saying that I'm not touching this stuff.
Well, he's got really long vesting, but
also the stuff that he does have right
now, it's still, you know, the stuff that
unlocked on TGE is also, you know,
considering what they got into, at what
price point they get into is pretty
considerable. But he says he's not
touching it. You know, he's just staking
it. And everybody just loves it. Everybody
loves the staking. And it's really good.
It's a great design. The UI is really
good. UX is great. We're supporting, I
think, all the major wallets right now.
They just enabled support for Eternal. So,
yeah, the rollout has been actually pretty
smooth.
It's considering what we had to do. Yeah,
I'm really happy with everything. And of
course, it wasn't just like a flip of a
switch type of thing. We had to make sure
that market making is done properly. we
have to make sure that liquidity is
supplied properly, just to make sure that
everything is stable, because a lot of
times Cardano projects, as well as Ergo
projects, they'll launch a token, which is
fine, and they just launch it into the
wild, and bam, there you go, and they
don't really do anything to it.
And of course, on the Ergo side, it's not
as crucial, I guess, to have a market
maker because you just don't have that
huge amount of volume that they can do
anything with. On Cardano, you still don't
have volumes like you would on the
Ethereum's of the world when you're
launching an asset. But it's still,
obviously, I think we're getting something
like about $150,000 worth of volume a day.
There is probably about $350,000 worth of
liquidity backing the token on the Cardano
side, I think maybe like 150 on the
Binance side.
You have to make sure that all these
things are really worked out to make sure
that nothing crazy happens to it. like,
you know, that there's support for people
that, you know, they want to do what they
want to do. You know, they get your token,
you do what you want to do with it, but it
doesn't, you know, it doesn't like,
doesn't beat the system up too much. You
don't have too much, too many huge swings
that really kind of freak people out.
So yeah, it's, it's, it's been, I mean,
we're still in the middle of it. You know,
everybody's probably had like four hours
of sleep at the most. the past few days,
including me. And you see I am wearing my
Palm T-shirt today. And yeah, I actually,
I was so tired today that, and pretending
that I'm not, that when I was at the
office, I was wearing this T-shirt. And so
I have two types of these T-shirts. One is
just got the Palm logo right here. And the
other one's got the Palm logo and it's got
a thing on the back says, keep Palm and
tokenize RWAs.
And so Maureen and Luca were at a dev
meeting today. They have these daily dev
stand-ups. And so we have this, we have a
conference room at the office, which is,
it's like a big glass wall, but it's its
own room. And so they're in the room and
I'm about to leave the office to go and
take care of some errands. And I'm just
walking out and they're all at the at the
big TV talking to our head of development
and I'm just, I'm kind of standing there
and I'm saying bye to everybody and I
pointed the back of the shirt and I'm
like, check it out, check it out.
Yeah, see? Everybody's looking at me
weird and then I want to walk outside, I
realized that I wasn't wearing the shirt
with the stuff on the back. So I was just
basically pointing at the blank blackness
of my t-shirt. And people thinking like,
what the fuck is the deal with this guy?
And of course he played it off like, oh,
it's okay, Dan, it's okay. And I'm like,
aw. Like here you are 11 o'clock at night
Japan time Coming out for the video Dan
for the AMA look at you Sacrificing I'm
not probably gonna sleep till about 2 a.m.
Because there's a million million other
things to do but yes That was fun pointing
at a blank t-shirt And yeah, the That's
you know That's that that's the kitten
caboodle right there
Well, that sounds like I'm excited for
the opportunity to see Palm come to Ergo
and utilize Paideia. That's, you know, I
think that's going to be really cool. Are
there any other? What's it called? What's
governance look like on the other chains?
With Paideia, you can essentially do
things with the treasury collectively as
you stake. Is that something that is
beneficial to Palm in the future?
Yeah, absolutely, because what we have is
called the Palm DAO that we're actually
going to be rolling out really soon. And
yeah, I mean, we'd like to utilize tooling
for that on all chains on Ergo as well.
But we still need to kind of work it out.
We haven't really done tooling for it on
the Cardano side either. We have kind of,
we have things standing by, so it's not
going to be a big, like a big lift, a
heavy lift to get this thing going. And,
but really it's not just about the
tooling, it's about setting up the
ecosystem that supports this, you know,
and, and, and really setting up the
processes that, that, for, for proposals
and for voting and for, you know, all the
different iterations of it.
So, yes, so that's going to take a bit of
time. So first of all, the Palm DAO is
going to have the funding rounds. It's
sort of like catalyst, but it's going to
be a little bit more spontaneous.
Basically, people are going to be able to
submit a proposal eventually from the Ergo
side as well, right now from the Cardano
side and from the Binance side when we
build it out on there as well, and then
get it voted on by palm holders that are
part of the DAO. Just to that that if they
feel that this proposal is in line with
expanding of the ecosystem because
basically what it is is decentralized
business development. Right So that's what
it's saying for So how are you gonna
manage?
I mean, how many how are you gonna manage
three different governance or how many
ever chains you expand to? How are you
gonna manage those kind of? governance
stroll ups from different things.
It's the same as it is with staking.
We're just going to have to build it out
the same on all the chains. You know, it's
going to have to be able to do the same
exact thing on all the chains. It's, it's,
it's not easy, but I mean that that's what
it is going multi-chain, you know? I mean,
you have to go multi-chain. If you want to
reach a wider audience, you have to be
able to do all this stuff.
You feel it's too, the UX would be too
difficult or not too difficult,
undesirable if you just force them to one
set of governance on a chain using Rosen.
Like if you want to participate in
governance for Palm, then hop on Rosen and
stake in Paideia or something like that.
That'd be too much of a UX hassle for some
of these people.
I think that we can actually do it the
other way. They can do it natively on the
chains that they're on and then we can use
a Rosen to kind of put it all into one
place when the time comes to utilize
things. You know, so maybe like the heart
of it can be on one chain. It could, for
example, be on Ergo and then all the all
the votes. They can come from all the
different chains, but they go through
Rosen and they end up on Ergo. It doesn't
have to be, I mean, what I mean is the UX
has to be the same, right? But the
technology, I don't, well, at that point,
I don't know because it's gonna be, yeah,
we have to kind of flesh that out a little
bit better because the DAO would actually
have to be incorporated, right? It would
have to actually be like an entity.
For it to work properly for it to work
properly on, you know, in, in, in, in real
life as well. So like these things that
are, like the contracts that are, that go
through the DAO were actually enforceable
by law, you know, because, you can't, you
know, you can't just like, trust me, bro,
this kind of stuff.
Yeah.
Classic. Trust me. I mean, yeah, these
are on-chain contracts, right? But you
have to be able to actually have a tool in
the real world to say that the on-chain
contract is enforceable, legally
enforceable. And actually, interestingly
enough, in Japan, they've developed
regulatory tooling like this. So we're
actually thinking about establishing the
DAO in Japan.
And so like I said, what we need to do is
we need to understand, it's not really
centralizing it, but keeping the heart of
the DAO on one chain, but then having
people from other chains coming in and
voting on the DAO through the bridge, what
do we have to have on other chains for it
to actually be compliant with regulations?
I don't think we're going to have to build
it out on every single chain fully, but
there's going to be a minimum requirement
of what needs to happen in each chain for
it to work in a legal manner.
I could see you using ROSEN somewhat
transparently in the background so that
the user interacts with some sort of
contract on the chain and their token is
transferred to a lock in ROSEN and
actually staked in. And then send back
with a batch of bots eventually Yeah, you
could yeah do that fairly transparently
not gonna be fast fast, but it would have
to be fast fast, you know, right?
Right with Rosen right now, you know like
arbitrage takes like what did we do? We we
sent through the first batch of liquidity
going to pancake swap and That took a
couple of hours. It took a couple of hours
to go through, and so what if it did? For
the applications that we're utilizing them
for, that's fine. Finality, in this
particular case, is not that big of a
deal. For example, if you're using a DAO,
and say we build the DAO on Ergo, And then
you have Cardano, Ergo, and Binance and
whatever other chains we decided to add
support for vote in the DAO, right? I
mean, that vote doesn't have to happen
like this, right? It could take a little
bit of time for this whole thing to
propagate through Rosen. end up on Ergo
and then execute the smart contract on
Ergo, which will then basically tally up
and fix the votes and then execute
whatever conditions that contract has.
Yeah, so it should be fine. I mean, as far
as tech goes, it's just all about
compliance-wise, like I said. It's a real
thing, right? It's not just like, well,
it's kind of cool. It's not just cool
tech. It's actually like a real entity.
It's going to be a real DAO. It's going to
be an incorporated entity. that is
compliant with regulation, that creates
contracts, on-chain contracts, that are
illegally enforceable. It's the big-pants
DAO of the deal right here.
All right. Well, that's exciting. Very
exciting, Dan, for so late at night.
You look really excited right now, qx().
I am. It's my early morning, so I'm still
waking up. The crack of noon.
Yeah. I know.
Well, we got some big announcements so
far. We got... For the Sigmanauts mining
pool mark developed a really sexy
dashboard. It's called ergo miners.com And
it's very newish kind of looking so it it
really blends in even above and beyond
some of the other major players out there
with dashboards so if you're a miner or if
you're you know, somebody that just wants
to dabble in it, even if you're just a
gamer and you want to tune your computer
over at night time while you're not
playing a game or during the day while
you're working, check out the Dash. It's
pretty damn cool. It's quite the upgrade
from the old Dash and a huge upgrade from
the simple Dash that we started out with.
So yeah, bravo to Kudos to Mark for doing
that.
The other big news Dan is we have
launched the official date for the 2025
Colorado Springs.
Oh, yeah, I saw that I saw it.
Yeah October 10th 11th and 12th. So the
main thing is the 11th people get there
the 10th We'll do something and then maybe
breakfast on the 12th when everybody goes
home but we crowds we're open sourcing it
just like the rest of Ergo so if you are
in the Ergo chats head to look for I guess
I'll pin it in a second but look for the
pin and there's a GitHub where the
information is for now and anybody can
fork and do pull requests on that sign up
page as well as the MD file explaining
everything to offer suggestions about what
to do, help with planning, all that kind
of stuff. So I encourage you to go over to
that on the GitHub and participate, sign
up, throw in some suggestions of what to
do if you know the area and that kind of
stuff. So I thought that was, Jemai had
the actual idea to put it on GitHub. So
that's what I did. I don't think there's
any other event or community that works
like that, so it's really fun to see.
Let me see what we have already. We
have... Do I have any pull and over pull
requests yet? We have Just one pull
request I did last night for some
suggestions as well as a sign-up So head
over there and do it if you don't know how
to do a pull request You're welcome to
send me the data and I'll put it up there
for you to sign yourself up To pull up
your pants qx() that I'm not where I'm not
wearing any pants.
Well, exactly. So just you know, like fix
that I
Yeah, yeah. Oh, and by the way, by the
way, I mean, the, I see the question up
there from- What do we see?
From, where is it? High quality Ergo.
Uncle Dan, when six 50k worth of
Palmarinos. We still haven't forgotten
about that. That is gonna come. What soon,
like I said, as soon as the Ergo support
is added- Checks in the mail.
Yeah, the check's in the mail, except
it's like Pony Express. No, but seriously,
we're doing that. It has not been
forgotten.
We've talked about doing a roundtable on
Cardano, Dan, so we may come to you
knocking.
yeah well yeah make sure it's like really
a round table because people say it's a
round table but sometimes they're
triangular and it just really really fucks
with me it screws with my OCD so just make
sure it's like round round table
Cute Dan cute.
I know it's adorable adorable.
All right, what else we have for
questions? Actually, we have let me see. I
think kushti had a sub-blocks update Let's
see
He's got some rough protocol working,
tested with two peers, still out of work
towards improving efficiency. So he's
still cranking away on sub-blocks, which
is great. And he's working on node 6.0. I
think he said last week, I don't know if I
made the AMA, that we have a full sync of
node 6 RC3, I believe, with mainnet. and I
think some others are starting to hop on
and test it. So that's looking great.
For anybody who's running a node right
now and you're running it on an SSD and
not some old platter drive or a small like
Raspberry Pi with an SSD, I encourage you
to go to 5.125 I think it is, the RocksDB
version. It's going to require a full node
resync but Wow, it's quite a bit faster. I
updated the secondary Ergo Explorer that I
run to that, and it's a big difference in
fetch times for mining wallets for smart
contracts and that kind of thing. They
usually take a second to load. So I
encourage you node runners, if you're
doing that, hop over to that. I don't know
if Satergo switched to rocks as a default,
but if he didn't, maybe it'd be great to
encourage him to give that option when you
spin up a database to see which one you
can use the same to. So yeah, that's
really cool.
What else? What do we got for questions,
Dan, the man?
all right what do we got for questions we
got we got we got we got we got a lot of
shit we got a lot of shit given us in the
channel so maybe yeah but i think it's i
think it's the same is the same guy you
know you are it's a big 3d yeah yeah
because he wants some attention here's
here's one maybe Sigmanauts will help with
the LP on the Ergo side just saying so
They wanted to make it clear that, you
know, it's really not that we are trying
to neglect Ergo. It's really not at all. I
mean, obviously we are bullish on Ergo,
but we build a bunch of the stuff on Ergo.
You know, it's still on Ergo. When the
protocol is on Ergo.
That's what you say, Dan.
We launched Ergo technology. So the only
thing, like I said, is we need to add
staking support, the same type of staking
support, on Ergo before we can actually
bridge the tokens and bring them to Ergo
through Rosen so that's the only thing and
at this point we just have quite a bit of
stuff that is being built out we're
actually expanding our our dev team to to
give us more support
Oh, who are you stealing now? You already
have Louis Vatra. You stole the Louis
Vatra.
We're done poaching. We're done poaching
you guys. Maybe. Maybe. I mean, if
somebody else comes around, we'll poach
them too. And they're going to be, you
know.
And now Crux is never going to get
finished, Louis Vatra.
Yeah. Oh, wait.
I got to do my weekly shout out. Hey,
Marty, please fix the UI on the front of
Paideia. You got some updates to do,
buddy. Hopefully he watches this week and
not last week. I don't know.
But already wherever you are, you know,
it's like an anchorman, you know, when he
like blows the horn and it just like, it's
hurt across the mountains. And then his
little dog is like bathing in like runs
out of the little, little creek in the
woods. Well, Marty is somewhere in like
in, in, in Canada bathing, you know, steam
hot ice bath. Yeah. Yeah. It's an ice
bath. And he, and he hears,
Paideia Crew, assemble! Assemble! You
know, qx() saying that, you know, and he's
like, what? Oh my God, I have to fix the
tooling. Darn it. Eh? Because he's
Canadian. Eh. A.
Anyway, so they just, I know it's a bit
of a tangent, but yeah, that's how I saw
it in my mind when you gave the shout out.
Yeah, so to get back to high quality
Ergo, yeah, like I said, we fully intend
to add, it's not a problem of the actual
liquidity being added to Ergo, right? It's
not a problem. It's like, oh, we just
don't have the money to put there. It's
really all about making sure that it's
compliant with regulation. That's all.
It's just for the protection of the
ecosystem.
Well, maybe you can publish the
requirements, Dan, and then maybe some
developer would give a basic.
I'll have that conversation with Sam and
with Luca, well, Luca at the office
tomorrow. He's in Japan right now, hanging
out. Did you know that?
Luca's in Japan?
Yeah, Luca's been in Japan for weeks now.
He's going to be here for quite a while.
He's staying at the Zengate corporate
apartment right near the office and having
a time of his life. Very nice.
Nice.
Is mgPai joining you this summer as well?
So, yeah, we're going to try to get him
out as well. We're going to see. But yeah,
mgPai, well, he was out here for a couple
of months last year. Or I don't know.
Well, it was quite a quite a while. I
forgot if it was a couple of months, but
it was quite a while.
It's probably got to come back and see
his kids. I mean, I'm sure they should be
born by now, right?
mgPai.
Yeah.
All right. Well, some more questions,
Dan. It was a failed joke. It was a failed
joke that mgPai is living it up when he's
in Japan and then he's got to come back
and face his consequences.
Oh,
All right.
Let's, let's answer some of these
insults. I feel like I get an insult. So
this is great. We've got, all right, you
go first. I'll go the one after you. Palm
was promised four CEXes and a few days
later can't even get listed on coin gecko.
You take that. I'll take the next one.
Yeah. So you know, it's like when, when
girls, you go out with girls and then, no,
you can't make that enough.
You can't make that analogy to the big
3d. He has no idea.
Oh yeah. He does. I forgot. He, he, he
doesn't. Yeah. He, he, he, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I forgot. Okay.
We already did, but it's a secret and it
is a game like Magic the Gathering and
then you have to find the four CEXes and
collect them like the four rings of power
in Lord of the Rings. That might do it
down. Okay. Okay. There we go. There we
go. On a serious note, coin gecko should
be up any day now. We actually submitted
the application a couple of weeks ago, but
it takes a couple of weeks for them to get
it going. So that should be like,
literally I'm checking coin gecko to see
if they, you know, and I can't stay on
those listings just because
As soon as it happens, the bots come into
all the chats, they look for all the
admins, and you get about 50,000 DMs
saying, hey, I'm Billy Bob, but yes, let
me help you out.
Let me help you. I am professional
administrator. I like administrating. I am
very impressed with your project.
I'm impressed with your project. They
don't even name the project.
They can't even get their bot to scrape
the name of the chat. I do get the bots on
Telegram sometimes. They're like, wow,
Dan, I'm really impressed with the
performance on Ergo. I would like to help
you. I'm like, oh, thanks. That's really,
really nice of you, whoever you are.
And then sometimes they'll be like,
because I'm in Japan, so they'll just send
the Japan bots to me. But they're going to
be like really crappy Japan bots that
speak Japanese, not like the Japanese.
It's like broken shitty Japanese, but they
have a Japanese name. Like, yeah, yeah,
you're real, sure. Like, you know, the
first thing they always do is like, I am
blah, blah, blah, right? But in Japanese,
you hardly ever say like, I am blah, blah,
blah, because it's actually rude to keep
saying I am, right? Well, it's rude, but
it's also just like colloquially
incorrect. So the way you speak, you
don't, you seldom say I. I am, right? Like
that's actually, it's kind of like a joke
with the Japanese because like foreigners,
when they start just speaking Japanese, I
am in Japanese, watashiwa, you know, and
then like, like they always make like
behind, you know, like in, if you get
them, like in the right moment, they'll
make fun of foreigners speaking Japanese,
like watashiwa American desu, because
that's how the, that's how the foreigners,
you know, like Americans, American sound
to them.
But, Yeah, so they always come in and
they they start with watashi wa i'm like,
yep, you're Japanese definitely That's why
you start with I am which the Japanese
hardly ever start with or even ever start
with in that kind of conversation But
anyway, all right that fun fact for you
qx() next time you want to speak Japanese
I will do that.
All right next question big 3d qx() where
when Kraken wear Kraken cracking We're
Kraken. All right, here we go. You ready?
Hopefully nobody from Kraken is watching
this. I'll give it to you guys straight.
All right. We have two pathways into
Kraken.
potentially. The first pathway was a chat
joined by myself, Armeanio, kushti, I
think Cannon was there, with Dave. I think
it's Dave. Yeah, Dave Brumfield from
Kraken. All right. It took a while to get
Dave to recognize that we didn't have a
Ethereum contract ID, that we wanted token
on Ethereum, essentially. And once that
was established, there was some back and
forth about what would be best to list.
And that would be Rosen-ERG on Ethereum,
Rosen-ERG on Cardano, or ERG layer one.
It's obvious ERG layer one is a long ways
out because it's a lot of work for them
and there's not a lot of monetary reward
for them to do that work. So that is on
the very low end of the totem pole for
layer one. Rosen token though, Rosen ERG
on Cardano Ethereum is going to be much
much easier to list. Rosen-ERG on Cardano
is probably the best option because we
have quite a bit of liquidity on the
Cardano side and we have, what's it
called, more wallets. And compared to some
tokens they've listed recently, they
listed a wrap token, the flux wrap token,
we have more volume than they do on the
Cardano. Our Cardano volume on Rosen-ERG
is more than the Ethereum volume of Flux.
So we match that. But the thing that we
don't match is we don't match wallet
holders. And that's it, I guess. We don't
match wallet holders. Flux has 10,000
wallet holders on Ethereum. We have about
500 on Cardano.
The Sigmanauts are working on a
promotion, a faucet, and things like that
to get our wallet count up. Once we get
our wallet count way up, we will develop a
market-making plan and then approach Dan
again in that same chat, not Dan, Dave,
and let them know that we're here at what
they suggested our requirements should be.
And by then, too, they should be done
refactoring the Cardano update that
happened a couple weeks ago, or maybe a
month ago, Dan, whatever that big update
was that they were fumbling around with on
the Kraken side to get native tokens
ready. So that's one pathway.
The second pathway, and I have no NDA
signed, so I don't give a shit right now,
is a bribe. Literally, literally somebody
on the outside that has a connection with
the inside that would like a finder's fee
for getting us into a suggestion. And that
is around $50,000. And that doesn't
guarantee that we get in. We could be
exactly at the same place we are in the
chat with Dave and kushti where they're
saying, oh, we need your wallet count up
to this and that kind of thing. So that's
something that I'm not even looking to
pursue at this time because it could be a
huge waste of money at that point. And
it's so shitty too.
So there you go, there you have it. Those
are the plans. Sigmanauts are going to
come up with a way to engage the Cardano
community to get our wallet count up,
whether it means a lot of Ergonauts
porting over some ERGs to Cardano with us
helping pay fees maybe or some incentive
for that, as well as some other things
that I won't say on the recording. So
there you go, big 3D. All right, what else
we got, Dan?
Oh, this is actually interesting. We were
just talking about this. Can Palm overtake
Ergo in market cap soon? I think I was
talking to Luca about that today, maybe. I
don't know how I'd feel about that. I'm so
conflicted. I mean, yeah, it would be
great if Palm has the market cap or the
size, the ecosystem size that Ergo has.
but I want Ergo to be bigger. I don't know
which one is, which one like, you know
what I mean? Like there is no, they just
both feel kind of like I, yeah, I want it
to be as big as Ergo, or it would be
really cool if it was actually bigger than
Ergo, but it wouldn't be also at the same
time. Because then why is Ergo not, you
know, like why?
It's like that scene in Total Recall, and
you're missing a third hand, Dan.
I totally get what you mean.
Yeah, exactly. Exactly. Yeah. Anyway,
that's actually a trend on TikTok right
now.
Wait, really? What's the total recall?
Third hand? Like the three-breasted woman.
Stop. It totally is. My wife would show
me, she's like, is this real? I'm like,
there's zero chance it's real. It's AI.
But I think it's on TikTok or Instagram or
something where they got these like three
breasted models that are just popping up
everywhere. And it's just odd. And
actually, a lot of people don't know where
that's from because they're not old
enough. Yeah, so some because I told my
told my wife she's like look at this like
oh You mean like like what is that? What
are they trying to like make it look at
the girl from total recall? He's like
she's like what? Oh my god.
Did they not put that on the new the
re-release the new version?
Yeah, but they didn't though, because
that's not the new version, right? Okay.
The new version doesn't, I don't think,
no, actually, no, they do have one. I
think they, I think they do. I think they
have one. Yeah. I think they do have it,
but you know, Colin Farrell, right? Yeah.
Yeah. But, the new total recall doesn't go
to Mars, you know, get you asked the Mars,
like, Oh, right.
It's all like through the center of the
planet or something to the other side of
the planet.
At first, I actually didn't like that
movie, but it grew on me. Like, cause I'm
a huge fan of the original. of Paul
Verhoeven, original. But when I saw the
new Total Recall, I'm like, what is this
shit? This is bullshit. He doesn't even go
to Mars. But then it just grew on me. It's
actually a pretty OK movie. It's
interesting. Yeah, but anyway.
So right now, Palm is at what? We haven't
calculated the market cap yet, actually.
FDV right now is at about 80 million. So I
think that makes Palm Like, maybe 10
something like that like 10 millions. I I
I honestly I I would have to calculate it
But I think it's like 10 maybe a little
bit more. So you got six times to get the
Ergo That's 62k right 62 million right now
six and Ergo doesn't do anything then
yeah, It could do that. But like I said, I
don't know how I'd feel about that like on
one side would be like, oh, yeah this is
great on the other side of like Damn it,
like, why, come on, Ergo. You know, do
something, do something. Move it, man,
come on, come on. The Palm is catching up
to you, come on, man. Anyway, yeah, so,
like, that's, that's, that's, that's
something, like, literally a conversation
that I had today.
We got another question from Matus Bor.
Yeah, you got it. Hello fellow Ergonauts.
I was wondering if anyone is actively
targeting the gaming community. It would
be interesting to onboard people who can
mine while they are not playing games.
Yeah, Mark the shark. I think that's a
good approach to target those gamers. I'm
looking at Mark's dashboard and he's got a
nice little bar graph. a progress bar that
essentially says, hey, in order to get
bonus tokens, you need to mine for four
out of seven days or something like that
of the epoch of the week. So that's
something that can easily be done by a
gamer who, when they go to bed, they just
double click on the executable and walk
away. And when they come back to the
machine to game, they stop the executable,
they game, they do what they need to do,
and then they double click on them. so
those mining doesn't have to be persistent
right it can be done just on the spare
time so yeah mark the shark i think that's
a i think that's a great idea that
actually you know i actually saw something
that could be really interesting for for
this and i don't think
I don't know if this game is still around
or has been developed or whatever, and if
it's actually worldwide or maybe it's just
in Japan. But there was a game that they
kept advertising on the phone when you use
the free apps that have the commercials in
them. And it was called, I think, Idle
Heroes. something like that. And basically
the thing about it was, was that it didn't
have any like, like active gameplay. A lot
of the gameplay was passive gameplay. So
you would set it up, right? And then it
would actually like, when you turn off
your phone, the gameplay would happen and
like the battles would happen and stuff
like that. And then like you'd have to
turn off your phone and turn the game off
for the, for your characters to, to, to
evolve. right because they have these like
characters that would evolve when when
your phone it's like sort of like pokemon
you know like pokemons when they like
evolve to become like i don't know more
scary pokemons right right it was kind of
the same concept i actually always thought
that that would be really interesting for
for gamifying mining
No, I think you're right. So you'd feed
your characters with hash points that
you've earned, essentially, or shares that
you've collected.
You basically, you tell them what to do,
and then you put it into some passive mode
where it still mines. And you just kind
of, whatever you do, you can, you know,
through gamification, you can select the
type of mining or the Yeah, the rate of
whatever right and then it'll grow the
character and then you get rewards through
the game I always thought that that was
actually a really interesting way to to
gamify and incentivize Mining through
different devices to game through like
through game through through gameplay So
it might be a best idea yet dan better
than palm
Then nothing is better than Palm.
No, so that's like the games I used to
play, the tech space web games I used to
play in the early 90s where you just go to
a website and you'd build up your army
slowly and then you'd choose to attack
somebody. And then when you came back,
you'd learn the results of the battle or
else while you were away from the
computer, somebody attacked you kind of
thing. It's all just database stats
hitting against stats like that. Yeah,
that's a really cool idea. Feed them with
your bonus points or the shares that you
pull from your mining pools and that kind
of thing. I mean, the big farms would be
able to murder you, so you'd have to have
some sort of equalizer out there or some
sort of diminishing return for the huge,
huge farms that are playing. But yeah,
that's a really cool idea. Mark can
probably vibe code that in a couple days,
so maybe he'll do it.
I think it's actually not that hard to
code. It's just the actual graphics. It
just has to be aesthetically pleasing. It
just has to look cool, right? But that's
just art, and we've got artists in the
community, so they could actually do that.
It shouldn't be a difficult thing to do.
But yeah, I just always thought that that
would actually be a really good way to
incentivize mining, and especially with
Ergo, where you can actually use all these
different devices for mining. You know,
you could do that. I think actually they
used to do something similar with Bitcoin
way back in the day, where there's like an
app that I forgot exactly what it did, but
it was basically like an app where you
would watch advertisements and the more
advertisements you'd watch, they'd pay you
in Bitcoin for watching advertisements.
Awesome. Oh, I got five, I got six more
minutes before I have to go. Let's bang
these questions out, Dan. Mark says that
that's what he's kind of working on with
HashMons and CA has the art ready to go,
go, go. So it'll be more of a tech space
stat kind of. initial thing, which I think
is a great way to start it. Awesome. All
right. Wendy moon says, do you think Ergo
will get more attention when the emission
reaching almost zero as the only proof of
work change to not rely on emission? You
said it in the end, Wendy, you said it on
the last part of your sentence. I think
Ergo was going to get even more attention.
When people realize that Ergo is actually
thought of the end game, they thought of
sustaining a chain after emission, tails,
you know, so I think that's a big, a big
plus for Ergo. And you see it now, if you
hide over the Sigmanauts mining pool,
you'll see, I think Mark said he
distributed 98 ERGs or this, close to that
in the wallet, the other week, from
storage rent alone plus bonus tokens as
well and things like hopefully in the
future where you'll be able to do token
releases through minor protocols right so
somebody like Dan could give you know a
couple hundred thousand tokens to to Mark
and people that would be mining would then
be released those tokens to it so yeah
ICOs via mining. I mean, what more fair
ways are coin releases and offerings
initially for people actually putting in
the raw labor to keep the chain secure? So
I don't know why there's not more of that.
Honestly, I don't know why token launches
are at least on proof of work chains. Why
token launches are done through these
token launching platforms as opposed to,
you know, feeding it out to the miners and
then the miners are welcome to sell it.
And then the community can buy it from the
DEXes kind of thing. So yeah, but yeah,
Wendy, I think, I think that's a huge
thing that's going to put Ergo above
everybody else eventually when they look
at it.
All right, we got a bunch of things. You
see anything else?
Yeah. Okay. I mean, there's a couple of
Palm questions, I don't know. But let's
say, do we have any Ergo questions? I
mean, I'd be more than happy to answer
Palm questions, but I want to answer Ergo
questions.
Luke Grasmith says, will we protect
foreigners and Canadian people from ICE if
they attend Colorado meetings? And Mark
says, at best, Colorado is open carry.
Perfect.
Yep. There you go. So yeah, don't, don't,
don't fuck with Colorado, Colorado.
Let's see. Oh, here we go. A personal
question. BodyMax Fitness, who I think is
a big 3D, maybe. qx(), would you ever
leave Ergo? At what point do you say
enough? I'm moving on. There's nothing to
move on to, guys. There's nothing else in
the ecosystem or in the space that does
what Ergo does. I see Ergo in my own use
as a utility here on campus. Right now,
it's integrated into our charging system
for plot billing. And I just saw two
students pay for plots with ERG while we
were in this meeting. You can see it on
the chain if you're looking. It's going to
be integrated into a DAO eventually as
well. I can't do that with anything else,
I don't feel. No, I don't think there's a
point in my immediate future where I think
of Ergo as a failure ever.
Let's take a hypothetical. Let's say the
crypto market goes through a really cold
winter, a lot of things disappear, Ergo
goes down to an all-time low like
everything else. I'm still going to be
using Ergo to do my stuff here. I'm still
going to be building on it. So that's the
resilience of Ergo compared to other
chains where you have somebody with a big
fat wallet holding a lot of tokens that
all of a sudden decides it's not worth it
and move on. So no. The answer is no.
There's nothing in my immediate there or
my future that says I'm done. All right,
we got one minute.
One minute and then ignition. All right,
let's see. All right, so what should we
answer here, the last thing that we should
answer?
Lord Black gave a shout out to ERGs
awesome anybody else mining with AI cards
no i think from what i heard lord black i
think mark was mark and Cannon were
talking to somebody about it i can't
remember but the problem with the ai farms
right now because i thought was right hey
let's Let's advertise to these AI farms
that they can also mine cryptocurrency on
their downtime when they're not being
fully utilized. But as of yet, from what I
understand, the AI farms are getting
pounded just relentlessly. There's no
space that they can actually do that yet.
So maybe in the future, when AI gets more
optimized, I think OpenAI just came out
with something that said that was the case
with one of the new models. You'll have
some space that maybe we can start pinging
these guys and saying, hey, you guys
should mine some cryptocurrency while
you're not doing AI.
What is it? Armeanio is working on some
idea where he's got something on the back,
back, back burner in his head about
utilizing AI and a side chain specifically
for that kind of thing. For all these
cards that are no longer useful for AI,
might still be useful for mining, and are
still very, very much powerful, can mine a
side chain. Yeah. And Lord Black, yeah,
I'm running like 20 nodes. No, more like
probably 10, but yeah. And just a shout
out again to Satergo for anybody who wants
to get into the node market. Super easy
desktop wallet. One click node install.
Really, really nice and easy.
All right. Well, I think we heard enough
about your node there, qx().
Yes.
Well, where do you got to go? I got to
go. I got to go, guys. Alright, well, I
guess great to see everybody qx() needs to
run Probably to the boys room No meeting.
Yeah, so I guess we'll wrap it up from
here for now All right. Well, so next next
week same time same place same channel and
until then this is Dan Barely alive, but
still kicking from Japan With qx(), who
you can almost call a man. Forget that.
When you can. Signing off. Ciao,
everybody.