Hey.
Good morning, kushti.
How are you doing?
Doing well, doing well.
How about you?
Good, good, good.
A little sleepy, a little sleepy, but
hanging in there.
How's your week been?
So it's busy, super busy.
So yeah, just today had a call actually
with some guys from African government
about tokenizing real world assets like
minerals they're producing with the main
idea to find also funding model for local
small and medium-sized cooperatives, well
entities doing mining right. So well it's
a huge problem it seems so yeah well let's
see how it goes but having a lot of talks
these days about well possibility to build
this and that.
So a lot of folks are currently in Dubai.
It's Token 2049, but yeah, I have enough
connections. So there is no need to waste
time on those big events. So yeah, busy
with, well, talking a lot despite skipping
those events.
So, yeah, well, maybe we'll provide more
details, but then you need to finalize
some talks and well also started talking
developers community. We had quite good
developers chat yesterday so the talk is
about what to do after sub-blocks right.
So well what do we have currently right so
we have five - no five - oh 5.0.26 which
is under review and well it will be
released first I believe and it will help
with user experience little bit by
supporting block candidate regeneration
finally.
Then yeah well 6.0 is finalized, well
it's quite huge update so it's about 16-17
thousand lines of code. Yeah so well it's
under review right for some time and yet
it is still under review right so that
there were some issues found, fixed, so
now it's hopefully finalized but yeah well
still hope that there is some audit going
on.
But, yeah, well, we can start reaching
pool, mining pools anyways, and fix voting
height, right, to start voting. And then,
well, in case of successful voting, in
case of super majority, 90% actually
support, well, we will have activation in
three months.
Right, and then for sub-blocks, well,
I've done recently peer-to-peer layer, so
new peer-to-peer layer messages. Well,
proper validation of sub-blocks, right,
because, well, certain transactions cannot
be included in sub-blocks, for example,
emission, right, transaction and other
transactions which depend on block
timestamp and miners public key.
Right because well they are changing from
one sub-block to another so then yeah well
if for soft fork, right, then such
transactions cannot be included into a
sub-block because, well, all the clients
would receive just full blocks, so they
are doing now, right, and, well, the
transaction could become invalid, right,
in well-filled clients, but being valid
for new clients. Otherwise, I mean, if
we're allowed for inclusion of such
transactions.
So, well, this is fixed now, right? So
there is proper validation of sub-block
transactions. And well, like 99.9%
transactions can be included and will be
included in sub-blocks. Right, so well,
now I'm...
I believe block candidate generation is
also done, so what's needed now is to
rework peer-to-peer layer a little bit to
send full blocks to old clients on
generating a block. Not a sub-block,
right. And, well, to send only, well,
basically difference to new clients,
right? Supporting sub-blocks to avoid
setting, well, full blocks on their mind.
How old can you go there, kushti? How old
can a client be?
So all the clients before sub-blocks
would be supported, right? Everything.
Yeah, so after sub-blocks deployment,
yeah, even 4.0 would be supported.
Wow, that's impressive.
We are quite extreme here, right, about
support. So, well, in next version 7.0
right if it will be released there will be
probably some breaking changes for clients
before 5.0.23 or 24 so it's documented in
the release notes so but this is about the
next update right so 7.0 so it will be I
don't know in one or two years if it would
be needed at all in the first place.
Currently, what was the point of the
developer's chat in particular, I started
with that, is to discuss what would be in
focus in regards with core development
after sub-blocks, right? But yeah, well if
there is no any concrete needs then maybe
in the first place and it seems well for
developers, ecosystem developers it's the
same based on feedback so it seems the
main thing needed is well improving
developing experience right and targeting
well real world needs I believe right
because well it's the time we are living
in when it's not a toy in a sandbox right
anymore so well it should be time right
now for beginning of transformation of
financial tooling well on scale right.
We've got MGPai joining us. He'll be
patched in in one minute. There he is.
Welcome MGPai.
Hey guys.
Good to see you sir.
Nice to be here.
So it's the moment when we have
cryptocurrencies going into corporate and
national reserves. At the same time,
tokenization of real-world assets. Well, I
see a new wave of demands for privacy, all
right and so on so and well that there is
even a particular interest in proof of
work again I believe right well in certain
circles it's a little bit strange because
yeah it's not about retail even often,
right? Well, it's the strange time where
most of retail is simply retarded, right?
Well, an interesting proof of work, for
example, is coming from corporate
entities. Right, it's quite of reverse
what we had a few years ago, but well,
well, depending on the environment, our
principles are still the same, right?
Yeah. Okay, so, and yeah, talking about
real-world adoption, so what's on your
side, what's new with the BRIC experiment?
Also, it's really funny to watch people
are, as they recognize the way these kids
work is they always put, I don't want to
say they put everything off for the last
minute, but they prioritize, right? And
their priority is usually their work. So
if they don't have time to read
instructions or do anything, that's
usually the last minute. But the incentive
has been there long enough now for
students to recognize that their peers are
getting free things from handing and
recycle plots.
So if you do the equivalence, we've had a
ton of recycling and we've saved students
about $1,000 so far with utilizing Ergo
and the BRIC token. So the way it works is
students will bring in their plots after
they're done with them, stuff them in a
basket, and we say, OK, that's worth 40
BRIC or 50 BRIC or 60 BRIC. And we tip it
to them with Luivatra TipperBot.
And then the way my system works, I've
explained it before. When you send through
the interface to plot, it triggers a
pop-up in Discord channel that they just
copy the code to tip. They tip it. The
off-chain bot reads the wallet and then
marks the plot to be plotted kind of
thing. So it's a really simple setup using
the TipperBot and Ergo. And it's working
fantastically well. I don't think I've had
to bounce anything in the last four or
five months that I've been running it.
So it's been fantastic, except when
Luivatra's plot went down once. So
students now, some of the students are
trying to circumvent the rules a little
bit. Initially, I was like, okay, one plot
you bring back, it's 40 brick. But these
plots vary from 32 inches long to 160
inches wide. So what these kids, some of
these kids are doing is they're slicing
the plots into short pieces and rolling
them up and taping them to bring them to
recycle. So it looks like they have 10
plots, but in reality it's like three or
four.
So I've switched to the method of just
saying, yeah, the mass of that paper looks
like X amount of plots. So here's X amount
of bricks. So it's really funny how
they're trying to squeeze as much as they
can out of this kind of stuff. So the next
step as this gets more and more popular is
I'm going to approach the departments
themselves the architecture department and
say hey you know to show the students that
you're serious about recycling and reusing
why don't you sponsor some brick and give
us an injection of five thousand or ten
thousand dollars worth of brick and then
we will inject that into the students and
they will have free plotting from the
architecture department to encourage
recycling.
Or it's a bonus thing. You bring your
plot back this week and then the
architecture department tacks on double
the amount of brick that you get for your
plots that you're bringing back this week.
So not only we're giving the word that the
architecture department is serious about
students recycling and reusing, but
they're also injecting funds in to help
out with this kind of thing. So it's
really fun. It's looking good.
And the students, we've got about 60, 70,
I believe, students that have set up
wallets and have been currently doing
those transactions. So that's about, what
do we have, about 350 architecture
students. So as I said, it's a slow burn,
but it rolls. And then it catches up and
it explodes. So it's cool. And especially
next semester, when we get more funds in
there, it'll be really fun.
But it's so cool to watch. I'm asking
kids like, some kids just show up with
like, I know they haven't recycled as much
and they're plotting like bam, bam, bam.
And I'm like, they must be trading in the
back. I didn't look, but they must be
trading in the background, something. So I
need to study the chain to see how that's
happening and how some people are ending
up with more brick than the other people.
Cause they're not getting it from me.
That's for sure. So.
Yeah, so maybe they're using brick as a
kind of currency.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, but that's when the real fun
starts, right? When people are starting to
use it to trade. And I think that that's
natural, especially when you are dealing
with students, right? So well, you, then,
may naturally expect attempts to cheat,
right?
And also, test the cage, you know, test
the wires if they're going to zap them or
not.
Yeah. But also a lot of unplanned
activities, right? Including exciting
ones.
Yeah. And it's nice to also use as, so we
hire about 20 student workers here to run
the center over there. And brick is really
like, typically at Cornell, you can't be
like, hey, good job. Here's 50 bucks extra
for your student work. That never happens.
But with Brick, we can say, hey, that was
awesome. Thanks for doing that. Here's 50
bricks towards your plotting. So it's this
bonus incentive structure that not only we
give to students, but we can give to our
student workers as a bonus for work well
done or extra things that they've done or
that kind of stuff. So that's a really,
really good tool to have in the tool chest
when you're doing that.
All right, and yeah, it would be
interesting to get information, right?
And, well, trading, I mean, if it happens,
but probably it does, right? If you see,
well, some secondary transactions, so not
generating from you. Then, yeah, it means
that there is some, well, economic
activity, right, exchange in this brick.
And well in regards with all those things
currently well I had a talk with HQx just
yesterday, so he was hit by this incident
in Spain, blackout, right? when there was
no electricity. So, yeah, well, the idea
he has is to do something with mesh
networks like, well, at least some catalog
of services, right, which you can access
when you don't have electricity for some
time.
But, yeah, well, then it's also possible,
so what I'm thinking about now is some
sort of off-chain currency, right, and we
also discussed that, backed by on-chain
reserves, right, so it's like ChainCash,
but with notes being created and
transferred our off-chain networks, such
as mesh networks or just, I don't know,
maybe the trusted server may track.
But then you have reserves on blockchain
and the same reserve could be reused in
multiple networks. So it's kind of like
BitTorrent but for payments. So you have
some global layer with reserves which
serve the blockchain right and then yeah
very different currency systems off-chain
on top of it such as community currencies
well those mesh networks. Well, temporary
or not so payment solutions, maybe some
social media means of payments, right?
So, well, I'm also thinking about such
possibilities. So it's basically like a
tipper bot, right? We have a telegram. But
you can tip for content and not
necessarily with, well, money which do
exist, right, so you can first, I don't
know, give a star, right, to some content
or the internet and then pay, well, enough
debt to others collected, right, once a
month, maybe even, and then, yeah, well,
it's a good selfless payment to some
degree.
kushti, what about... What's the
possibility of... You're talking about
ChainCash and mesh networks with low
bandwidth. What's the possibility... I
know it's risky, right? What's the
possibility of integrating into a wallet
some sort of offline exchange so that if I
come to you and we meet up someplace
without any kind of internet wireless
signal, but you transfer me from wallet to
wallet and you sign a transaction
essentially to my wallet, I guess you
could spend it beforehand from another
wallet.
The thought is, if you can pre-sign
something and transfer it to my wallet,
then when I get internet, I can send it
out. But with UTXO, I guess you could
spend it from another wallet before that
transaction hits the pool. I guess there's
no way to do that without protecting the
asset offline?
So, if there is some trust, right? It had
to be trust, yeah, right. Yeah, you can do
some on-ramp. So, for example, you can get
state of on-chain reserve without even
having a network, well, without having it
right at the moment of a deal by just
checking NIPoPoWs proof corresponding to
the latest time of synchronization with
the network.
And then, yeah, well, you can see reserve
rights of a seller and during exchange you
are getting assigned notes and then, yeah,
you can present this note to a smart
contract when going online, right? But
then, yeah, well, if the seller is going,
so if you're buying, well, on-chain assets
this way, right? So then the seller may
appear before you on the chain and redeem,
right? So the reserve, so yeah, but then,
yeah, well, you may have some trust.
That's when you bring out the wrench
remedy on the seller.
Right. So, well, if there is some, even a
low bandwidth access, right, then you can
have... Right. It doesn't take much. Yeah,
true. ...transactions. So, yeah, there are
lots of possibilities here. I mean, even
if there is some super limited access to
mobile network, like SMS access, right,
then yeah, it's possible to do a service
which is not relying on trust to the
seller, right? So you may have a trust
infrastructure provider, right? Which is,
well, providing SMS service basically, but
no more than that. Something like that.
If we need to have devices like really
real Ergo gold bricks where you put
stablecoin onto a ledger device that never
reveals its seed phrase to anybody, right?
So there's no way to extract the seed
phrase. So when you deliver these physical
devices, they know that there's no
extraction that could have been done to
it, and it can be redeemed without
somebody coming in behind you to the
internet first. I guess that'd be a little
risky, right, though, if it broke or
anything like that?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. And it's also quite
experimental. It's called, in
cryptography, PUF, so physically
unclonable function. But yeah, so a device
which cannot be cloned. But yeah, I
actually don't know the current state of
this field. We need to check even.
Cool. All right. Well, MGPai, how's,
how's your neck of the woods?
Hey guys. I just been really busy on the
Cardano side of things, building over
there or, I'm sorry.
You're cutting out. We can't hear you at
all.
I'm just kidding. MGPai. He said Cardano.
So I said you were cutting out.
Yeah, it's been very busy. We have
implemented staking for Zengi. I mean,
it's not just staking, it's very dynamic,
right? Because the rewards need to adjust
due to real world factors. So there's
several contracts working in conjunction
with each other to determine how much
rewards and how they get changed weekly.
So I've been working on that for a while.
So it's done. It's deployed to Cardano
and yet it's going quite well and a lot of
I think the contract hit like 1300
transactions and there's like 600 million
Palm tokens which are like our Palm's Palm
economies tokens right it's locked so I
think that's worth like almost close to a
million dollars I don't know what the math
is but you know it's going quite well.
And I think it really showed me doing the
development on how things are in the state
of Cardano. And I frankly think it's not
that good compared to Ergo. The
development is just too over complicated.
It's UTXO already, right? So that of
course adds some layer of complexity that
most of Ergo developers are familiar with.
But then Cardano just goes the extra mile
to make it more difficult for you.
So the tooling is not really there. I
constantly need to go into libraries.
Libraries are basically you borrow code
from other developers because you don't
want to reinvent the wheel. On Cardano, so
the assumption is, right, whatever you
borrow works when you use a library, when
you're coding. So on Cardano, you've got
to throw that assumption out of the
window.
And I constantly find issues in
libraries, and I have to go in them, and I
have to understand the library and fix
them. And whereas Ergo, you know, being
like what, like almost 100 times smaller,
or maybe like 10, 20 times smaller than
Cardano has much better libraries. I don't
have to do that too often. I might need to
look into a library due to a lack of
documentation. But there's no really big
issue.
with the library and if there is an issue
it's quite easy to get the contact of the
contributors right on the developer
discord because you know everyone's just
so like close together right easy to reach
and you know they'll fix it like I think
Anon_BR or yeah yeah he wrote the FleetSDK
library for Ergo. It's really, really well
done. He's an amazing, talented developer.
He's basically a solo developer who worked
on FleetSDK entirely.
and then Morphic who worked on AppKit.
They're really really robust libraries and
it's quite impressive what Ergo has
managed to do while being a fraction of
the size of Cardano. It's honestly quite
ridiculous Cardano being a multi-billion
dollar blockchain and then tooling just
you know being all over the place. Like
everyone has their own thing. Like there's
no unified Cardano entity.
There's no like a large library bank from
the Cardano foundation or IOHK or anything
like that that you have full access to,
kind of thing like that.
Yeah, nothing like quite robust. I think
now Cardano, I'm not too sure, but Cardano
has like a serialization library that's
written, but you're written in Rust and C
and or C, I don't remember. I mean, you
don't use this because this is a really
low level tooling. So it's kind of like
SigmaRust on Ergo or how SigmaRust should
be on Ergo in the sense that it's a
library that other libraries use rather
than developers using it directly because
it's really low-level primitives.
But yeah, it's quite bad, but hopefully
they fix it. But I think the biggest thing
anyway for Ergo and Cardano both is to
improve this developer experience because
I also had to do stuff for EVM on Binance
Smart Chain. I implemented the same
staking stuff and it took me a fraction of
the day. It literally took me like six
times less time and work doing Binance
because, you know, I mean, of course, this
account model makes things easier, but the
tooling is just, you know, all there. It's
just everything works. Everything's fast.
Yeah, but the EVM is disaster, right? So
it's happening every day and it's shit.
And yeah, I mean, it's because of it's
well, a broken model, right? So I mean,
definitely, I mean, we should stay away
from that because I mean, it's complete
nonsense. Even those guys, well, thinking,
understanding that it's broken, right?
Even Vitalik is now proposing some new
nonsense, like replacing EVM with RISC-V,
but it's basically the same mistake,
right?
Because, I mean, those guys are hopeless
in the first place. They don't understand
that the what they are doing in the first
place, right? So, well, it started as
programmable money, but then those guys
started to do decentralized computer for
something, but still no one has clear
idea, no one can explain why do you need
decentralized computer even, right? I
mean, it's nonsensical idea, also, well,
non-scalable by definition, done very
badly in EVM with all those hacks.
Well, including DAO hack when Vitalik and
friends rolled back the chain and so on.
So, yeah, it's a complete disaster. And
it's, I mean, talking about billions,
well, billions are even making things
worse, right, for all those chains. I
mean, it's not just nonsensical disaster,
but also involving big money in the
process of those disastrous effects of
building a replicated programmable
calculator for unknown purposes.
I think big money, at least in my
experience, can help with innovation, but
it also can stifle it. Years ago, I was at
a conference at Stanford for the stuff
that I do here. And the director of the
group, the director of IT there at the
time, said, or the CIO, I guess, whatever
the hell CI is called, CTO, Chief
Technical Officer.
Said, one of Stanford's biggest problem
with innovation is that we have too much
money. If there's a problem, we just throw
money at it. So where's the pain and
growth of innovation when you can just
say, let's just buy. Let's just pay for it
kind of thing. So that does have quite of
an effect on that. When you're backed in a
corner and you can just pay your way out,
that's definitely stifling for any sort of
innovation that would have come for that.
So yeah.
That's quite an interesting point, but I
think, you know, of course there's good
and bad things from anything, right? So we
should take the good from EVM in terms of
like, you know, developer experience.
Yeah, but the problem is that there is no
good things anywhere. So it's developer
experiences about doing broken contracts
which has re-entrancy and all that stuff
and then spends months on auditing things
right, properly. I mean, spend also a lot
of money because there are just few
entities in the world able to do proper
audits of this mess. Right. So, I mean,
it's, it's, well, honestly, I mean, I, I'm
looking, at, this EVM, from, 2014, right.
When, we, we had, well competing approach,
NXT 2.0 in, in the NXT community, which
was rejected and then was implemented in a
quarter. And, yeah, I mean, it, it, from
the start, it was quite clear that it's
not a good approach, but I mean, well,
fake simplicity, right, of development
also will edit issues like this DAO hack,
for example, and hundreds of hacks after.
Like, do you feel, MGPai, I think when I
was talking to you before, you were happy
with the short amount of time it took you
to build contracts over in Binance when
you were doing the staking, right? So my
question to you is, do you feel as secure
about the contracts you've written over on
Binance in the amount of time it took
compared to if you were able to write
those same contracts over here on Ergo?
What do you feel more secure about? I
think my security, so I am quite secure
about the, I mean, all contracts, of
course, but I'm secure about the Binance
contracts because it comes from an open
source, well, it comes from PancakeSwap,
right? Which is the leading DEX on
Binance, right? So it's time tested, it's
a time tested contract, right? It's been
around for like, I think three, four years
now with no issues and it's open source,
right? So I think that also contributes a
lot to something right you know if it's
been tested if others have used it and if
it's open source you know and people can
already attack it and if there's no
attacks done like you know there's pretty
good chance of it being secure.
I think a good really good thing about
EVM is about the contracts is that a lot
of their things are open source contracts
and you know and that's missing in Cardano
actually a lot of things are closed source
and it's really weird I don't like it like
all their off-chain and all it's all
closed source on Ergo at least Ergo is
much better in that sense where the
contracts are open source for the most
part so is off-chain and generally the UIs
are closed source on Ergo but I don't
really find that to be much of an issue.
I mean, it was lovable. You can write a
UI in a couple of minutes, right? So
that's not really, yeah. I think the
community pushes for that too. I think
it's good to still see, not violently
though. Sometimes community gets a little
rabid, but it's good that the community
still considers the default. Are you going
to open source the contracts? Are you
going to at least open source the UI or
whatnot kind of thing?
Because that boils down to, it is hard to
run a business on open source things. You
have to pivot to the point of providing
something more than, you know, if you and
I are going to run the same thing, MGPai,
you would have to provide something better
than I could do it. So that would result
in your skill of running the business, of
the offerings that you do, the connections
that you do. So it's a whole different
facet of business running when you're
trying to compete like that.
But if it's not open source, I mean, who
will use it? In this DeFi space, it's not
quite clear. I mean, how can it be called
DeFi if it's not open sourced? I mean, how
can you claim that it's DeFi
decentralized?
That doesn't stop Solana or any of those
companies or Avalanche or whoever those
guys are. Yeah, I'm claiming that. While
we're talking about other chains, guys,
can I ask a quick question? Bitcoin,
trying to squeeze a ton of things into
blocks, right? So they can essentially
become a cloud storage at this point. What
would that look like on Ergo? Didn't we
not have a block limit at one point and it
just clogged the shit out of people's
nodes and you had to crank down the block
limit, size limit?
Yeah, so we have a block size limit, but
it can be repurposed by miners, right? So
they can lift the limits and already did
that, actually. So the current limit is
like 2x of initial. And well, miners can
always raise for more. In Ergo we have a
storage rent which is providing business
from collecting the garbage data after
four years. Here I don't see a big
problem. It's much more flexible, right?
Compared to at least Bitcoin for that
kind of...
Comparing with everything. So to the best
of my knowledge, there is no storage rent
anywhere, right? So Ethereum community
tried to do that tried to push for that.
Vitalik, even I believe back in 2015-16,
but yeah, well, now it's forgotten. But
there is some EIP about that Ethereum. To
the best of my knowledge, that's quite
natural, I believe. Incentive model and
anti-garbage measurement is done in the
Ergo only.
All right, we got 13 minutes. Let's hit
some questions. All right, all right.
Matta says, kushti doing tremendous work.
I thought we'd put that kudos up there.
White Cat wants to know, nice to see
everybody back. Question for today, what
have you guys done for Ergo in the last
seven days? I think we just went on for
that for 47 minutes. But White Cat has not
sold, so. All right.
Let's see. We just commented on the
Bitcoin OP_RETURNs controversy, I guess,
right? From Luke. I already had that
question. Let's see. Oh. Anything you guys
see you want to answer? Shout it out while
I look.
I don't see a chat. Where is that? So on
mobile, I don't see it even.
Well, here we go.
Please comment on the Bitcoin OP_RETURNs.
But it's all this hell, actually. I spent
a lot of time around Bitcoin developers
back in 2015, beginning of 2015 when I
visited different events around San
Francisco and there were a lot of Bitcoin
developers around as well and well one of
the most topics was yeah OP_RETURNs so
there were some hot debates about making
it 40 bytes or 80 bytes or something like
that.
But yeah, I mean, it's always possible to
encode data, right? It seems well in
different ways. So, well, instead of
preventing that, it's better to provide
some simple way, I believe, to write data.
And then, yeah, some simple mechanisms for
preventing spam attacks and dust, garbage
in the UTXO set.
Yeah, well, I believe Ergo is doing quite
well here, right? Well, OP_RETURNs is also
quite a simple mechanism. There is need
for some anti-dust measurements and it's
missing Bitcoin and there is a lot of dust
in the UTXO set which is slowing down
transaction validation and so on.
But yeah, well, we have what we have. So
Bitcoin protocol is quite stable now,
right? So we cannot expect any big
changes. Only some, well, some soft
fork-ish, right? Like taproot and before
segwit. But well, there are some talks
actually about demurrage in the Bitcoin
community as well. Right? So well, I see a
lot of talks about telemission or
demurrage. But yeah, well, I can't imagine
a deployment of that. But let's see. Let's
see.
All right, let's see what else we have.
We have, I think it's for MGPai. Let me
find it. Where'd it go? It is from
UrsaMina. MGPai, here you go. MGPai,
please comment on Ergo utilization in
Palmyra. Could it be done without Ergo?
And if it could, why Ergo?
Yeah, I think one place where Ergo shines
compared to Cardano is with our
transaction fees. It's much more
affordable to do bulk tokenization on Ergo
compared to Cardano because the MinUTXO
for creating a token is like 1.2 ADA. So
this means that you basically got to pay
like a dollar, a dollar 50, depending on
the price, just to make like one token,
right?
And that of course, you know, is not
affordable if you have like something in
large quantities you want to tokenize or
like, for example, like beehives from
various farmers, it'll all be a unique,
unique asset. So, you know, if you want to
do like a thousand, you'll need thousand
unique mints on Cardano, which gets really
expensive. It's not scalable, but compared
to Ergo, you can do it for a fraction of
the cost because the main UTXO on Ergo is
like worth a fraction of a penny. And even
if Ergo does like a 10X or a 100X, it's
still going to be much cheaper than
Cardano.
So are you, are you worried, do you have
plans in place for demurrage? I mean, if
these RWAs sit in a box, or are you going
to have like requirements where when an
RWA is put inside some sort of box and
it's going to sit there for a while, you
always, you always have to include with
some ERGs or something like that. Yeah.
The last thing you want is like something
pulled from the chain that's supposed to
be tracked forever, right?
Yeah, the idea is that you have a bunch
of tokens in a contract, right? Or if
there is a contract, you let the contract
be recreated on its own without doing
anything extra. So we would have that
along with an off-chain bot seeing if it's
close to expiry, it can just recreate that
and prevent the need for demurrage being
collected at all, right? But adding ERG to
an asset itself is a form of deferring the
demurrage if you don't do anything about
it. But if you do something about it, you
don't really need to worry. So you could
have some ERG as a buffer. Then on top of
that, you can have an off-chain that
constantly recreates the UTXO so demurrage
doesn't need to be collected.
Cool, cool.
Let's see what else we have here.
What is the state of your platform of
tokenization?
So yesterday I was on a call with some
African government, as I told in the
beginning. So the interest in having some
platform for real-world test tokenization,
right? And then, yeah, with Ergo to build
some, well, financial to link around for
funding small and medium scale miners. So
what's the current status of tokenization
platform? What's doable there? Is it open
sourced and available to test?
Yeah, so we have the Palmyra protocol as
an original prototype. But personally, I
don't have any involvement at the moment.
But I have Luca, LDG, who's been on Ergo
the last month or two, working on updating
the Palmyra contracts beyond MVP. He's
working on implementation of that and I'll
probably be on it in the next month or two
While I wrap up some Cardano things And
you wrap up SigmaLock front end bots.
Yeah Don't forget about that MGPai All
right, we've got the cook reminded
everybody that the NH roads and he's very
correct and
And maybe MGPai can speak to this since
he is an EF member, right, MGPai? He said,
they were talking about marketing. And
Ayanesh says, to me, it seems like EF
wants marketing to come from users and the
ecosystem. It's not bad, necessarily. But
most users, myself included, just want the
number to go up and don't want to have to
work for it. I mean, that is what it is.
Some people join the ecosystem and you'll
see, I mean, look at a lot of us up here
at front of the camera, people in the
Sigmanauts, they join the ecosystem and
they recognize that Ergo's focused on kind
of a grassroots movement as far as
marketing goes. That was the original
intent of mine.
My understanding of the intent of the EF
was that. And we're doing our parts, not
being paid just for the good of what Ergo
is and what it represents compared to all
the other projects out there. But that
being said, the EF has given out grants,
guys. So I know that it's work sometimes,
but if somebody has an idea that says,
hey, we want to do this kind of outreach,
like take Mark the Shark. He wrote a
proposal that said, look, we want to do
outreach via mining. We're going to
develop a mining tool that's easy and plug
and play kind of thing with a dashboard
and these kind of NFTs to get people
excited about it.
And he got a grant for it, and he's
working on it as we speak. So that stuff
is possible. Write up a nice proposal,
send it to the EF. And if you don't want
to do the work, maybe you'd like to write
the proposal and then find other people to
do the work. But here, at least, the
people I'm looking at right now all pick
up pick up a wrench and start tightening
stuff and loosening stuff and playing with
stuff with no idea of being rewarded other
than the fact that we're creating
something unlike anything else.
Yeah. Yeah. I also don't understand what
users mean here. So how are they using?
Because, well, I'm here currently in Ergo
because I'm also a user, right? Otherwise,
what's the reason I'm not getting paid by,
well, EF or, well, users or any other
entity, right? So, well, the interest is
to use the Ergo, right? And, well, the
reason why I'm using it because, well,
for, well, things I'm interested in simply
there is no alternative, right?
So, well, still there are a lot of pros
of UTXO. Well, I think from what I'm doing
as a user, the guy who is also doing
contracts on Ergo and so on, and I hope to
see that being used in the real world,
right, because, well, I'm a little bit
tired, to be honest, to be in the space
for like 15 years to the moment, and,
well, here, well, on this, nonsense about,
I don't know, it's always in the different
form, but about the same after all, right?
So, I mean, some projects are claiming
something, some hype, a number go up,
number go down, then yeah, I mean, it
repeats with some new narrative. It's a
little bit insane, to be honest, right?
Well, to continue to be saying in this
space, you need for some hope to see that
being used in the real world. what I feel
right by developing contracts and well now
now thinking about off-chain systems and
so on well and well reviewing contracts
right in peer-to-peer finance and so on so
well I think it's very natural.
Well, and now, well, in this space, there
are a lot of strange talks about products
market fit, right? I mean, even for
blockchains, right? Good occurrence. So
it's, it's hard to say what, what, what,
what, what, what is a product here, right?
I mean, naturally, if there is product,
then what's the decentralization here? I
mean, the blockchain. So it's hard to
understand all the stalls but yeah I think
that Ergo is pretty good and well
fulfilling all the requirements when you
are building tools for our grassroots
finance right for well sovereign finance
peer-to-peer economic interactions.
And, yeah, it has perfect lifestyle,
market fit, right, so, well, if you are,
well, thinking about, well, building
stronger communities and, well,
sovereignty of those communities and
self-individual sovereignty, then, yeah,
well, it's probably the best toolset I'm
personally having now, right? So, well, as
a user, well, I don't see a real
alternative.
No, I agree. I think it's the best tool
set that I've experienced. I can't imagine
building what I built here in this system
for students with Ethereum or even
Cardano. It would be impossible. I can do
an initial airdrop of brick to students
and give them 0.1 ERG, and they're set for
10, 15 transactions done each. What's done
and done is forgotten. The code out there,
I know the tool set, it wouldn't work
anywhere else.
So that's testament to me that as more
and more people start recognizing this and
building things on their own for their own
use cases and recycling code using other
people's, it's going to become very
apparent that when it comes to real-world
use cases, Ergo is really above everybody
else in that sense.
It's 10.02, guys. MGPai, you're going to
turn into a pumpkin. Are you skipping
class for this?
No, no, I have a later class today, so.
When's your first final?
It's in a week and a half.
Oh, not bad. Oh, one last question, guys.
This is from UrsaMina. This is a neat
question. Small amount of data, but they
want to know if they can use blocks to
store an encrypted password list,
immutable storage. Like how secure would
you trust encrypting your passwords into a
file and dumping it on chain?
I mean, just the encryption algorithm,
right? That you've got to trust. Yeah,
right. Exactly. Not really the blockchain.
How many bytes is it that you can store
in the register?
There is only a box limit, which is about
4 kilobytes. But you can spread our many
UTXOs from it.
All right, that's a good point. You
could. So just develop an app that breaks
it in half, breaks it in parts.
Yeah, that's a great point. Yes, so you
can save in chunks. And yeah, well, four
years after, you will pay for storage
rent. Then for four kilobytes, it would be
about like five ERG even, right? Something
like that, four or five ERG. So a few
dollars, which is quite reasonable, I
believe, amount considering that you're
storing your four kilobytes of data on
hundreds of machines, right?
That'd be interesting to set up a
password vault system on the blockchain,
right? Where everything's put there and
you're just... Right? I mean, but what's
the risk, right? You have LastPass just
had a huge nuke thing a year or two ago
right I think they had a big scare where
the keys were in charge of one person
essentially whereas you know something
like this each person would have access to
their own keys only I mean LastPass
probably had some bullshit about like
recovering if you forgot your password or
something like that right that's probably
how right exactly yeah safety net yep yep
yep so there's a master key but
Yeah, that'd be interesting. Yeah, that
would make me nervous, MGPai, because
you're really trusting whatever encryption
algorithm that you're using at the time.
I mean, I would trust them, right?
Because it's been time tested, right?
Like, no one's been breaking RSA
encryption. But it's like you kind of lose
a layer of protection, right? Because if
you have something, I know, like encrypted
in your own machine, like someone has to
get to your own machine to get that
encrypted. Yeah. You're taking that gate
away from them. Exactly. You take that
layer of protection away by directly
putting it on the blockchain. But after
that data is taken, then it's just
figuring out the password or brute forcing
it.
In that sense, those layers are the same,
just attacking something that's already...
UrsaMina wrote again, and he's saying,
how would anyone know its passwords? And
he's right. I mean, you can, like,
protection through obscurity, right, kind
of thing. But I guess if it got to follow
certain patterns, and UTXOs were created
around a certain amount of times, like if
it always spanned through UTXOs, and it
always was made at the same time, and it
was always made by certain wallets, you
could probably do some lookups and figure
it out.
If you break it into like chunks though,
I'm sure like, no, like how would someone
even know that there's encrypted data on
chain?
Send it through the mixer.
Yeah, that won't work. If the data is
like in multiple like chunks UTXO, it's
kind of messed up.
Yeah, but you also can store data in UTXO
protected with a stealth address, right?
So then recipient is not known. Right.
Right. Right. I mean, it's, it's, non,
only that's, yeah, well, it's, it's a
stealth.
You could store usernames and passwords
and separate UTXOs as well. Right. And
somehow find a way to link them just known
to the user based on some sort of hash or
something that they would do. So if
somebody, if somebody got a hold of the
usernames, that wouldn't matter. Somebody
got a hold of the passwords alone, that
wouldn't matter. But only the user knows
how to bring them back together.
Well, the next step in those off-chain
systems I'm thinking about, like off-chain
cash would be adding some privacy, right?
So, well, when you may have a private
transfer before on-chain redemption then
yeah it would be quite cool right so then
you have some private half-chain cash with
yeah well transparent on-chain reserves
right and redemption against them but yeah
that's quite different topic all right
boys let's wrap it up but yeah so what we
are doing next week ma spaces what
AMAs are easier, that's for sure. Yeah,
by the way, I will do spaces next
Wednesday with some media. So some
industry media. So I will share an
announcement in coming days.
Is it in English, kushti?
Yeah, yeah. So yeah, it's quite known
industry media. So there will be a Twitter
spaces event on Wednesday. So yeah, then
next Thursday, let's have AMA maybe.
All right. Sounds good. Send us a link so
we can push it.
Yeah, maybe we can have some occasional
community chats on Friday, Saturday,
Sunday, because, well, still there are
some topics to discuss, especially, well,
in regards what to do after sub-blocks,
right, and, well, how to get to the, well,
adoption.
All righty. Well, thanks for joining us
MGPai. kushti, it's been fun.
Yeah. Thank you guys.
Thank you.
Bye guys.
Thank you everyone.
Thank you for your questions.
Bye.