Hello and welcome to the Weekly Ergo
Proof of Work AMA.
With me today, we have the infamous, the
famous, the desirable, kushti.
How you doing, kushti?
I don't know about you.
Hang in there.
We've just been critiqued here at work.
So there's like no students around.
Final reviews are pretty much done.
We had to turn people away yesterday for
a recycling plot and getting bricks
because it was too busy.
We said, come back some other time.
We don't have time to deal with this
right now.
So I expect some people coming in around
noon today to swap some plots for bricks.
But yeah, everything is going pretty
well.
How was your week?
Quite busy.
There were a couple of releases, 5.0.26
and 5.1.3, so reviewing again 6.0, doing
some cleanup and so on, so hopefully we'll
be done by the end of the week.
And then, yeah, we can propose watching
to the polls, maybe from, I don't know,
like end of May, June 1st, then, yeah,
well, in three months we will. Whether I
have 6.0 activated or not.
kushti, how does that work?
How does that voting work for the miners?
The miner pools have to change a config
upgrade to that node and then that's it?
Yeah, so they need to specify the words,
yeah, we have a special parameter in
config.
So for some soft fork, well, miners asked
for some simplified versions, so we
delivered like two versions during
release, one with the option is set to on
and another is set to off.
But I don't really know.
So that was around 5.0 voting probably.
So we had that.
And then, yeah, well, most of miners
indicated the vote for 5.0 soft fork.
It was made a default option in some
release because, yeah, well, the voting is
going on for three months.
But, yeah, well, currently it would be
quite messy, so probably there will be
just one version.
Well, anyway, there will be two versions,
right, so with the level DB and the
RocksDB.
So 6.0, 6.0.
one and then yeah well at some point
there will be a version with sub-block
support six points I don't know maybe five
but yeah I mean it's a lot of things in
the pipeline so about sub-blocks well
working on efficient propagation of a new
block
because currently peer-to-peer logic is
about using the same mechanism so well
input blocks sub-blocks are propagated
when found but when a full block is
generated found then yeah it's propagated
fully like it's the case now right with
the current client so well
There is need to switch to announcing
just transactions not broadcasted before,
just few transactions usually.
Two in most cases transactions along with
header and that will be like super
efficient announcement of a new block.
Then we can start testing maybe even in
the public testnet at some point.
So first probably some devnet, maybe
public devnet.
Are you still looking for people to run
public devnet?
Let's see, so there is need ideally for a
few miners, right, to see competition
between miners.
But even in the public test, we have one
miner, right?
Who could be that guy?
Yeah, it would be good to have a few
miners in the public testnet around the
rollout.
Maybe even trying a mixed option when
some miners are on a sub-block.
Well, also sub-blocks supporting clients
and other miners.
It would be good to test that mixed
option because probably, well, it would be
quite realistic for the mainnet
deployment, quite realistic scenario.
Then, yeah, so for Dexy here, well, I'm
rechecking contracts and deploying one by
one in the mainnet.
Then what do we have else?
Also, a lot of talks are continuing,
well, different talks with entities
interested in tokenization for real-world
assets, right, and building, then
insurance schemes,
And like one design forum and I'm a
monitor the tools rights.
Well, I'm not even some governance in
Africa with the idea to provide funding
for small and medium sized cooperatives
because well in many cases.
So the land is owned by some family,
right, or small cooperatives.
Well, they simply don't have funding for
many corporations.
So, yeah, well, it would be interesting
to apply, well, the tool we have for such
setting.
Also, well, talking about, well, mesh
networks, right, and well, having digital
cash available right even when there is no
internet let's say for some time right so
when you may have some local payment group
and then yeah well those settlements if
needed using the blockchain
Maybe something like that would be useful
for the brick, right?
But, I mean, some time is needed for,
well, implementation and even considering
the proper architecture.
Then, yeah, well, also, so we published a
contract for on-chain reserves supporting
a lot of off-chain options.
on the forum, and well, one friend of
mine is interested in using that to
develop a system rewarding developers,
right?
So the developing communities, well, in
open source setting.
So you first may contribute, right, to
get maybe some just, I don't know, reward
points, right, but then, yeah, this
community may find some sponsor to do
settlements to contributors or just
choosing contributors or, well, et cetera,
using, well, the blockchain.
So something like that.
So yeah, it's quite interesting to find,
well, the use cases for blockchain.
So I believe it should be about Web3, but
not that Web3, which is considered now in
the blockchain industry.
When some use case and then issue token
and then hype and then run.
Yeah.
And yeah, claim that it's web three and
it's revolutionary because, I don't know.
So I spoke to many people asking what
does that mean of Web3.
So even the initial article by Gavin Wood
was quite fuzzy, right?
And well, what people have in mind now is
totally incomprehensible.
Then, yes, to me, proper web3 is about, I
believe, 99% of use cases.
There is no need for tokens, right, in
the first place, also well.
Mostly, there is no need for blockchain,
so it should be about mesh networks, Nostr
services, IPFS services, distributed
decentralized peer-to-peer systems.
Well, mostly off-chain payment systems.
Well, using blockchain is just a global
settlement layer, which is quite close to
the original ideas, I believe, of Hal
Finny, for example, from 2010.
But yeah, I mean, these days, it's mostly
something different and it's hard to
understand what the people are doing most
of the time.
All right.
So, but yeah, so I think, well, where
tokens are needed is, well, real-world
assets tokenization, right?
And, well, algorithmic stable coins, for
example, for insurance schemes and so on,
right?
And so on.
So, yeah, well, busy, as you know, and
yeah, so.
Hal Finny's birthday was on the fourth, I
think, kushti?
We just had Hal Finny's birthday on the
fourth, it would have turned. How old
would he have been? 60 something.
Let's see.
He's 59.
Hal Finny's birthday was on May 4th.
60.
You mentioned health, and I just
remembered that it's his birthday.
We just passed his birthday.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
I didn't know even, to be honest.
Yeah, then some talks are going on in
regards with blockchain development after
6.0, right?
One week ago, we started discussions
about Sigma chains and so on.
So yeah, we'll discuss these things.
kushti, I'm wondering about the nodes,
right?
Should we start, at least on GitHub,
should we start referencing the rock
database and what's the other database
that the original node used?
Level, levelDB.
So should we start at least naming the
files for the node so that people know
that the level DB is more compatible with
like maybe older devices or Raspberry Pis
and the rock database should be the node
of choice considering it's love of SSDs
and it's a bit snappier kind of thing?
Is that a possible thing we can do?
It would be good to compile a table.
Maybe we did that even at some point,
like which platform supported.
So for RocksDB, the issue is that less
platforms supported.
But yeah, the overall stability is
better, it seems right.
Yeah, I was running RocksDB on a side
project that I'm doing.
And it's crashed.
The computer has crashed on me many, many
times over the past couple of weeks as I
increased the RAM load on it.
And zero issues with RocksDB.
The database comes right back up,
continues finding blocks and good.
If this were LevelDB, it probably would
have required a resync of the node
already.
but it's been fantastic with RocksDB and
getting this machine stable.
Yeah so it's more stable and yeah I think
it's also generally much better probably
for SSD.
storage and so if you're using HDD maybe
level DB is more efficient even right so
well level DB is quite popular database
and yeah it's used in Bitcoin core right
and well the funny story is that we even
tried to do our own database
We did one back in IOG, so it was called
IODB.
So it was a quite specialized database
for blockchains.
So after that, there were several other
efforts, but that was the first one.
Why build from scratch, kushti?
Why not just optimize and fork something
already out there that's open source?
Yeah, but the guy who worked on that, he
built some quite well-known databases in
the Java world, right, so first he worked
for H2 and yeah, they also have some key
value database and then yeah, he worked on
some kind of low-level database, MapDB.
Jan Kotik was the guy and so yeah, well,
it was his own choice, right?
Because he is very proficient in that
database engines and so on.
But yeah, it wasn't quite finished,
right?
And yeah, unfortunately, the guy wasn't
stable also.
He didn't deliver major MapDB releases.
He didn't finish IODB as well.
So at some point we switched to... Did he
go on to work at Ethereum or Solana,
kushti?
I don't know what he's doing.
But yeah, so he's a highly professional
guy.
working on database engines, so I'm not
sure about Solana or whatever.
That was a joke, kushti.
All right.
Then we switched to LevelDB, which is
used in Bitcoin Core.
And RocksDB is basically some fork of
LevelDB, which was quite abandoned at some
point.
It'd be nice if there was some sort of
conversion tool, kushti, that somebody
wanting to switch over to RocksDB wouldn't
have to resync an entire node.
Granted, it doesn't take too long, a day
or so, depending on your connection, I
guess.
But still, it'd be nice to push a button,
do a conversion, and be up and running on
rocks from level database.
But I understand it's probably not a
high-trafficked request.
Yeah, I mean, would be good, but yeah,
well, there is no bandwidth for that for
developers.
And yeah, well, we need, for all more
developers, well, in regards with sigma
chains and so on right well even for
sub-blocks related development and well
other things so after 6.0 I think well
there is value in extending
capabilities of contractual layer to
support different execution environments.
Currently the Ergo chain is supported so
that would be good to make possibility to
extend easily to other blockchains as well
as off-chain execution environments.
So that was an idea which we discussed a
lot back in smartcontract.com days along
with Sergey Nazarov and Steve Ellis right
so to do some well tooling to execute
off-chain contracts right well
maybe in some case it makes sense.
And well, with the ErgoTree, it's even
possible to do contracts which can be
executed off-chain only at a certain point
and then, yeah, they can be submitted to
blockchain as well.
Probably, well, it would be quite
interesting, right?
It's not possible with EVM and other...
So in the UTXO set, kushti, those kind of
things would work where the collateral
would be essentially, or the value would
be locked into a contract that could not
be removed until you brought forward
whatever happened off-chain essentially so
right before or year participants satisfy
some condition in off-chain environments
right so the collateral can't go anywhere
until the off-chain code is brought back
on and checked and signed online
essentially to show proof that either it
transferred or some was taken from it or
that kind of thing so that's pretty damn
cool but then so then the question kushti
is how do
So you need some sort of trusted
application, right?
Offline.
So that if you and I are exchanging some
sort of offline contract, how do I know?
How do I verify that it's happening and
I'm really getting what I'm getting.
Yeah.
So, but what do you need to... In a
minimal case, it's a trusted context to do
execution again.
So you can do execution in peer-to-peer
setting even, but you need for some
trusted context, which is actually not
different from using oracles on chain.
Just more efficient and private probably.
more efficient private so on on
blockchain you are just finalizing right
financial agreements for financial
outcomes right you fix them and yeah
off-chain you need for some trusted
context provider basically right but
that's not different from oracle
So something like that, but yeah, well,
there is need to find time and finalize
all those thoughts.
And yeah, well, currently quite busy with
other things.
But yeah, well, I think it would be quite
interesting.
And by the way, well, chain link 2.0
papers.
Quite about that, right.
Actually, it's mostly about, well, ideas
we discussed back in smartcontract.com
days back in 2014, 2015.
So, yeah, because there was no factors,
right, unfortunate factors like Ethereum
network.
So, well, there was possibility to be
concentrated on some real things.
and demands, but yeah, well, it's
probably oriented towards the needs of big
corporations and so on.
And well, I think, well, you can find
well source of trusted context in much
smaller environments, right?
Right, so you could see community
organizations offering a bank of trusted
authorizations of these contracts or
holders of this, correct?
Right, yeah, so it could be a small-scale
environment.
Well, trust maybe is not so big question,
right?
Because, well, in small community, well,
big trust is usually not an issue, right?
And in opposite, so when it's some big
system, well, it's hard to get trust,
right, to anybody.
All right.
Speaking of devs, kushti, are you going
to join on the AI, ErgoHack 10?
I need to check, actually.
It depends on, yeah, sub-blocks,
developments, and 6.0.
So, well, if certain milestones will be
met, then probably, yeah.
Let's see.
So it's starting on the May 20th, right?
I believe so. Yep. You got it.
Yep, they've got the Ergo, just go to
ErgoHack.io for people watching and
interested and they've got the apply here
button as well as an explanation of AI on
the Ergo blockchain.
So yeah, I don't know, I don't know if I
have time to join, but it's definitely
ways that I've seen, what's it called?
There's some stuff in the background
happening that one of the developers is
working on that you guys haven't seen in a
while that uses AI, and I think they're
going to join.
But there's so much opportunity even for
simple stuff, like using AI for
auto-generation of artwork.
and things like that as simple as that,
baking that into some sort of front-end
NFT development that I've seen being
worked on.
That's pretty cool.
So I'm looking forward to what's coming
up with here.
I know Mark the Shark does a lot with
MCPs and AI to help you do coding as well
as ping things on the blockchain.
So hopefully we'll see some of that stuff
show up in ErgoHack.
Because I mean, one of the big pain
points that I run into here for casual
developers, or not even developers,
project leaders, right?
People running things like Bulvar,
GreasyCex, they need ways of airdropping
and pulling the chain that, sure, airdrop
tools are helpful, but what if they want
to know exactly who's holding what and how
long they've been holding it for and those
kind of things.
So there's a lot of opportunity for those
kind of AI toolings that can query the
blockchain with zero dev knowledge and
really give you back what you want.
So yeah, looking forward to that.
But kushti, I wanted to talk about
Rosen's treasury proposals.
Have you seen those come across the line?
Yeah, but yeah, so what's...
So Joe snuck out four treasury proposals.
Yeah, so what are you finding interesting
here?
Yeah, so I was looking at treasury
proposal three.
So one of the things I talked about a
couple of weeks ago was, what's it called?
getting listed on Kraken right we were
dealing with talking directly to Dave then
there was an opportunity I spoke about of
a kind of a back door entrance I'll let
Mark I'll let Glasgow talk more on the
back door entrance as he's gotten some
more info on that I'm not very
I don't think it's a great option, but
we'll see what he says on that.
But anyway, Rosen Proposal 3 deals with
this kind of thing by supporting SPOs.
A lot of funds came from, what's it
called, catalysts on Cardano.
And the idea is that let's, Rosen can
kind of give it back, but at the same
time, and more importantly, really bolster
ERG, Rosen ERG adoption on Cardano.
So what that does is twofold, right?
If Rosen is allowing some sort of HODL
game or SPO rewards in Rosen ERG based on
transactions in Rosen,
as well as Rosen proposal one which
bolsters liquidity quite a bit in all the
pools to encourage what's it called
arbitrage across and moving across a
bridge.
So think of proposal one, we're going to
bolster liquidity so that we encourage
swapping and nobody experiences losses or
very much when they do that.
Proposal number three, we skip to where
that actually rewards people for holding
that Rosen ERG.
And what that does is if you remember
from a couple of weeks ago, one of the
requirements, soft requirements that
Kraken was giving us was thousands of
holders, 10,000 holders to be exact around
that target, as well as a decent amount of
volume on the chain, which I think we
already have on Cardano.
So what Rosen Treasury Proposal 3 does
essentially is gets Rosen ERG into a lot
of people's wallets, so that'll take care
of the first issue there, as well as
encourages swapping across the bridge.
So I think they're really cool proposals.
They're out on, again, they're the GARD
proposals.
But I know a lot of you are Sigmanauts.
And since Sigmanauts own one of the
guards, it'll be a Sigmanaut votes first
to see what the Sigmanaut guard will
actually vote for.
So a lot of you are involved in
Sigmanauts and have that power to make
that decision on what the Sigmanaut guard
does.
I encourage you to read proposals one
through four.
I think they're all pretty good proposals
brought forth by Armeanio.
And think of it, don't think of it as in
a way as, oh, you know, we're giving away,
you know, treasury money that the
Sigmanauts earned essentially, or any of
the guards earned.
Think of it as we're utilizing funds we
didn't have before.
essentially given to us by running a
guard service which which i've been
running so no skin off your backs guys and
then we can take these funds and actually
do something good to either give us help
us get us listed on kraken
get adoption of Rosen ERG, bolster the
liquidity pool so we can see more larger
$50,000, $60,000 transfers between pools
without the worry of slippage.
And that, in fact, will eventually
bolster the watcher.
payouts.
So then we'll get more watchers and we'll
get more interest.
We'll get more people holding Rosen.
We'll get more people locking up ERGs,
locking up Rosen.
It all is a well-thought-out strategic
cascading effect to get funds locked, to
get funds to create more wallets for
people in other ecosystems.
So read them carefully with that lens on
and I think you might be swayed by Joe's
writings and musings and proposals.
That's the short of that, kushti.
All right, yeah, so I've checked the
proposals for all of them.
You read them right now in three minutes.
Perfect, kushti.
No, no, no.
So yeah, read the first three on the
second day probably, and yeah, the fourth
one just immediately.
So yeah, I think it's much needed.
Right, right.
Develop liquidity around rights.
Not only, but the fourth one, kushti, is
specifically injecting funds for
development, right?
Sigma Chains, Rosen Bridge, and contract
enhancements for Ergo Dex.
So, I mean, they're literally diverting
right back into the development of Ergo
for that.
So, it's like a win-win across the entire
ecosystem, I feel.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, it's, it's needed to increase
liquidity rights.
Yeah.
Yep.
A hundred percent.
The question is how to do that.
Right.
And in the environments where, well, no
one is controlling, the, the ecosystem,
right.
It's.
But then, yeah, well, it's, I think,
quite reasonable step forward.
All right.
Let's do some questions, kushti.
Sound all right.
Yeah.
All right.
Let's see.
All right, we've got a question from Ursa
Minor, kushti.
Is BASIS an extension of ChainCash to
encourage centralized systems to provide
standard notes, blockchain banking?
Is this the beginning of double entry
accounting methods using blockchain?
Yeah, so it's similar to ChainCash.
And basically, the contract is a
modification of ChainCash reserve
contracts.
Maybe, yeah, that could be done more in
future, right?
So, for example, to have on-chain cash
node, which is backed by a few parties and
then, well, also used as a reserve even
for off-chain payments, right?
But yeah, currently, well, the approach
is to use modified reserve contract
support of chain notes with no any
requirements basically to the notes aside
of being assigned.
by a reserve provider as well as some
entity also, which is tracking of chain
payments, to simplify the issues of
tracking.
Even that part could be missed, so maybe
in some environments there is no need for
this tracker.
Signature, but yeah, I think in most
cases it would be needed, right?
Yeah, well, it's true, it's a similar
approach to ChainCash, but yeah, well, now
just one reserve provider, but then yeah,
well, off-chain, you can build maybe a
system with, well, backing from multiple
reserves, right?
For example, having some trusted tracker.
which is collecting signatures from
multiple reserves, but provides only a
single signature during redemption, then
discarding other requests.
And so on.
So, yeah, well, the main idea is to use
it in environments where there are some
trust rights off-chain, like community
currencies.
Yeah, maybe these developer communities,
right, and so on.
So, well, it's still to be analyzed,
right, for different security threats,
attacks, and so on.
But, well, with some trust in off-chain,
I think it could be used right now.
What happens if I guess with a ChainCash,
let's say, you know, cause you can stack
collateral into ChainCash, right?
As it moves along, you can add and
subtract different collaterals into
ChainCash.
So what happens if, you know, there's...
What happens in the market if you find out
that one of these trusted entities is not
trusted anymore?
These ChainCash notes all of a sudden
lose quite a bit of value in collateral,
no?
Almost like a subprime mortgage backing
crash?
where all of a sudden all these ChainCash
notes that have been at least touched or
tainted or included with perhaps a bad, a
malicious actor, a backer, would lose
value pretty quickly, right?
Yes.
So, you know, in ChainCash, you can issue
notes without any backing, right?
So then it's...
Right, right.
purely trust-based.
And then, yeah, well, it's up to you
whether to accept such notes or not.
But yeah, if you accept them, then yeah,
well, you are getting all the trust
issues.
Right, right, right.
Well, it's just your responsibility.
But what's good here, I think, is that no
one is enforced to trust.
So there are very simple protocol rules
and that's the only thing you have to
trust.
Well, unlike, for example, complex stable
coins, algorithmic stable coins protocols,
to the best of my observations, people
just trust, right?
That's, I mean, they are safe, but they
have no idea how it works either.
So yeah, no, I, no idea.
How does it work actually?
So, here, rules are simple and, then,
yeah, it's up to you, but you are not
enforced, right?
Unlike, the stable coin protocols.
Yeah, well, every participant has freedom
to accept or not.
And then, yeah, well, certain... issues
are possible and maybe even collapse of
certain contours rights and ChainCash
powered economies.
But the whole economy I believe still
would be okay, right?
So in some sense, it's fragile.
Designs, well, unlike, you know, well,
economies where it isn't forced to accept,
well, instruments.
You may not like, well, for example,
government issued debt instruments such as
fiat currency rights.
So for conservative players it's always
possible to stay on the ground to avoid
failures.
kushti, I wonder if there's a subversion
of collateral you could enter into the
ChainCash contract that would act as an
insurance, essentially.
So I know all collateral is an insurance,
right, in this instance.
But specifically, an entity that could be
tracked as a single entity that would be
providing insurance to ChainCash notes
that would also include liquidity or,
sorry, collateral.
And then you essentially could track
defaults on chain.
So you could track every time that this
insurance policy was actually spent.
And then you could track and judge and
have a metric for trust of collateralizing
institutions that were defaulting or
failing to provide the trusted
collateralization.
So let's say you and I enter a contract
and there's no collateral, right?
So I trust that you're giving me a note
and I trust the value that you've verbally
or contractually attached to it, but
there's no collateral.
We could insert some collateral from an
insurance company, per se, and then If you
failed to deliver, if I wanted to cash
out, you failed to deliver, that insurance
company would pay that.
And then on Shane, it would be shown that
you were in default, essentially.
So now we know that the trusted bank of
kushti has defaulted X amount of times and
insurance collateral has been redeemed
this many of times.
So there would be a metric online to be
able to measure that kind of thing.
I think that's possible.
The issue is that, you know, what
constitutes default, right?
So, well, the default is when, so your
default, for example, right, is when all
the notes issued by you are not accepted
by all the, well, agents, right, in the
economy.
But you cannot probably say with
confidence that notes are not acceptable
because, well, historically, there were
examples when currencies of failed central
banks continued to be used.
For example, even 30 years after failure
of central bank of Somali.
So the notes of non-existing central bank
still being used, right?
Because, well, it's still the best
option, right?
So yeah, I mean, it's hard to say what
does default mean.
I gotcha.
Especially if there are no reserves,
right?
So if it's truly...
Right, right.
So, and, well, even in the world of DeFi
and so on, so, some people are still
trading, these, classic, Terra Luna,
right?
So they rename the original coins to
classic.
You know, I love that.
I love that mentality.
They're like, they're like, it's only a
hundred bucks.
I'll just throw a hundred bucks in and it
might make me a millionaire.
It's like,
Right.
So do we have defaults there or not?
Really?
So it's hard to say, right?
Yeah, that's a good point.
People are still trading failed stable
coins, right?
Buying and selling them like one dollar
for two cents.
Oh, boy.
All right.
We got another question.
It looks like the big 3D is in a good
mood today because the markets are green,
I guess.
So he's got a question, kushti.
It says, can you please provide a
breakdown of next steps for sub-blocks?
I guess you already kind of answered
that.
Is there an ETA when they can expect
two-second transactions to go live?
Maybe on testnet.
When on testnet, you think we can start
seeing two-second transactions?
oh so i don't know maybe next week even
so it's just like some some changes right
which are not quite predictable i mean
what's ETA there but yeah they're not
They should be so big, right?
So, well, let's try to roll out something
maybe next week.
So, yeah, it was possible to roll out
things even a few days before, but, you
know, the point is when you're deploying
peer to peer protocol, which is a subject
to change.
So those changes would be painful, right?
So it's, it's better to deliver some
finalized more or less version.
But, yeah, I don't know.
So if, that's not a big issue.
So for example, if we are going to launch
some public devnet with an agreement that
it could be shut down, like in two, three
weeks, then yeah, I mean, we can do that
today even.
Why not?
So that depends on deployment scenario.
All right.
So yes, still a lot of changes are
possible.
And well, those which are planned for
peer-to-peer layer, so it's better to
finalize things before deployment.
If we are talking about backwards
compatibility, So some need for it, but if
there is no any need for backwards
compatibility, we can do deployments.
Well, it's a little bit about the fast
and loose or, or slower and correct
essentially method.
So that's understood.
Yeah.
But, so usually, it's, somewhere in
between, right?
So it's about testnet.
So yeah, we, we, had 6.0 deployments when
it was more or less finalized, but well,
Even after the initial deployment, there
were some breaking changes, actually.
And, well, it was okay for the network
just because, well, it's not trivial to
break the network, right, but still
possible with the changes done.
And yeah, so in regards with peer-to-peer
layer, it's quite complicated, but yeah,
well, if it's about some public devnet to
be alive for two or three weeks,
Then, yeah, we can do deployment just
today.
So let's see.
We can set some day, right, and deploy
whatever possible by the day.
So it would be whether devnet for two
weeks or maybe something more stable.
That also could be an option if people
are willing to test something.
We can just CPU mine this public devnet
anyway, right?
No need to point GPUs to it.
Keep the difficulty low.
Yeah.
Anyone can do that actually right now,
probably using the branch.
So I didn't test the latest commits, but
should be okay.
So can test today.
I can roll out maybe, so I can use some
server of mine to deploy.
That's OK.
I've got plenty, kushti.
Don't waste any of your machines.
OK, we've got another.
Let's keep going, kushti.
Let's see, where is it?
Here we go.
Another one for the big 3D.
qx(), when can we expect push for more
holders of Rosen ERG on Cardano?
We need that Kraken listing.
So, big 3D, if you rewind a little bit, I
talked about proposal number three from
Rosen Bridge.
That's exactly what this is.
So, right.
If I told you guys a couple weeks ago, I
can't remember, the little secret was we
were going to develop a bot that does
airdrops to Cardano to get the token
holders up because it's crypto baby it's
just a bunch of bullshit you know Kraken's
looking to push a box on his little sheet
that says yeah they have 10,000 holders
it's just a line of bullshit but anyway so
Armeanio has proposed a really nice legit
version of that with SPO and HODL-Rosen
techniques across chains.
So please read those proposals, big 3D,
and hound the Sigmanauts.
Look up the Sigmanauts member and say,
hey, I like this proposal.
You guys should vote for this.
Or become a Sigmanaut and push it.
That's how it works.
Let's see.
This is always a tough one.
This is from a buddy, Aco.
By the way, Aco has a direct access to
Postgres database now.
So let's get on Aco for doing some cool
stuff with ErgoExplorer so that we can see
a lot of different things, kind of like
Cardano scan, where you can see the amount
of transactions, the amount of not
holders, but the amount of lots.
Direct access gives you much more
flexibility when looking up things.
We expect to see great things from Aco.
Anyway, it says, continue on kushti's
call for action regarding marketing.
Can you talk about any plans for
marketing from the EF or anyone?
Sub-blocks should have a big spotlight.
Unfortunately, neither kushti nor I are
members of the EF.
So we can't really comment on what the EF
is planning to do from there.
I know that I am always looking for help
on Ergo Twitter, the main Ergo Twitter
account.
So Rustin helps out a lot, but Rustin has
real life things to get in the way
sometimes, so he'll be gone for a few
weeks at a time.
So we definitely need coverage.
So any of you who are in love with Ergo
and know enough about Ergo to put some
posts out, I will make you a delegate on
the main Ergo Twitter account and you can
help out, right?
So please help out with that effort, at
least on Twitter.
Advertise things like Mark and Tim, Tim
Erg's broadcast for the peer-to-peer
podcast, those kind of things.
Create your own podcast about that kind
of stuff.
Put them out there.
All those things that you see that
community members make, it makes a huge
difference when you guys rebroadcast, when
you watch them, when you talk about them,
and put them out there.
That's the kind of marketing we can do as
community members.
But yeah, and don't be shy to talk to
Mark and ask him, sorry, Glasgow.
or AMG or anybody else on the EF.
mgPai, right?
He's probably done with finals this
Friday.
So feel free to hound mgPai about what
the EF is looking for for marketing.
So I encourage you guys to talk about
that.
Yeah.
Right.
So, yeah, well, I have some ideas about
marketing of sub-blocks, right, in regards
with high performance proof of work.
And, yeah, even, getting, some funding
for that, but, it's, quite early, turn
ons.
Let's see.
So we will have, Twitter spaces with, the
coin Republic and, crypto reach on
Saturday now.
Right.
What happened that, that just had to be
postponed for a little bit.
Yeah, so yesterday there were some issues
on the coin republic sites.
All right, so well, crypto reach had to
cancel.
So we considered different options like
moving to his channel.
or well, just postponing kids while
recording zoom.
like we did a couple of times back in
2020.
So yeah, yeah, finally, we've decided to
move it to Saturday and well, but maybe
it's still quite an announcement, I think.
So yeah, let's see.
But, well, anyway, I think, well, it will
be quite modern and still quite unique
results, right?
And, well, high performance network
networks.
And, well, there is needs definitely to
promote it and get attention from, yeah.
people interested in consensus and well,
proof of work rights along with sigma
chains and so on and so on, a lot of
things.
We are discussing how to organize wealth
efforts within that space.
All right, we've got one.
Actually, I've got a question onto this,
too.
We've got Bobcat here.
What are your thoughts on Rosen using
Snarks to strengthen the watcher guard
model?
So that also brings me to the question of
we see the recent release of Bitcoin OS
for Cardano, right?
And they're using fully non-custodial.
They're using contracts to lock up stuff
as opposed to kind of a watcher guard set.
What's the advantage of that, kushti?
You see something like Bitcoin OS using
Snarks fully without a watcher guard set
compared to something like Rosen Bridge.
And is it fair to not call Bitcoin OS a
bridge?
I mean, they're technically bridging.
They're just doing it differently.
Plus, I hate the burn and mint method.
I think that's the dumbest thing ever.
Maybe that's just me.
I think it's much more realistic that
Rosen is creating and locking all tokens
all at once.
And there's no burn.
There's no mint.
It's all done right off the bat.
But anyway, what are your thoughts,
kushti?
Oh, you know, so there are many
dimensions here, right?
So well, Rosen approach also probably
simpler, right?
hard to say in in regards with all all
those recent things like bit vm bitcoin os
and so on so there are certain scenarios
which are not considered like mass exit
right and in all those protocols so the
same is true for ark
And then BitVM, I believe all those BitVM
protocols.
So what happens in a mass exit on
something like Bitcoin OS with Snarks?
So just the main network would be
congested because exit transactions.
So mints and burns can happen kind of
thing and it just pile up?
Yeah.
So in case of multiple fraud proofs
posted on the blockchain, it would be
quite congested.
Right.
And with the, with the Rosen Bridge, at
least the watchers would probably pick up
the fraud before.
And if they didn't pick it up, then the
guard would pick it up.
So they wouldn't even get past that
point.
Right.
And, yeah.
So.
hard to say I mean so technically you
know well yeah it's it's trustless but
yeah well there are some new vectors which
are not even considered so I have attended
some Bitcoin lightning events back in
February
around Hong Kong and it was some panel
with Blockstream CEO and other folks, some
developers of Lightning Network.
So some BitVM solutions were discussed as
well.
And so, and so, and yeah, you even asked
directly questions about mass exit
scenarios, right?
In some Bitcoin power protocols, I even
forgotten which ones actually.
And yeah, well, it seems that there is no
clear answer.
I mean, it's just not considered.
But then, yeah, well, there are also more
trivial issues, well, tied with
complexity, right?
So if it's complex, then it's better to
wait for some time before using it, right,
usually?
Because, well, usually the problems are
in implementations, like Zcash, for
example.
had some issue in its circuits, right?
Unnoticed.
So it was a typo even in the paper.
So developers just implemented paper as
is.
Oh, with the typo?
Oh, shit.
That's rough.
Yeah, and because of that, even a hidden
emission of Zcash was possible if my
memory serves me well.
It was possible to mint Zcash.
It was a second problem.
So, yeah, I mean, it's often, you know, I
mean, quite good, but you have details.
So, yeah, well, let's see.
So I'm watching a little bit all those
things in the Bitcoin space, like Bitcoin,
Bitcoin OS, ARK, Cashew, Fedemint, and so
on.
And yeah, I mean, it's quite exciting,
especially considering that you can
replicate it in simpler ways on Ergo
right.
because ergo is kind of hyper bitcoin but
yeah well also new trade-offs and issues
so yeah it's not quite clear what's worth
to replicate right as soon as possible
probably maybe not
Anything, nothing at the moment, right?
Because, like, every, every tech has,
it's, uncertainty at the moment.
All right.
Let's see.
We've got a quick thing from Bevis.
Is there anything we can do to increase
volume in Ergo?
They want to sink some of their meme
profits into Ergo, but CEX volumes are
super low.
Yeah.
So read those proposals that I was
talking about.
There's some good proposals in Joe's
Treasury proposals that instead of into
CEXes, but it pumps it into DEXes, which
offsets that kind of thing.
So read those up, push people to pass
them, push the guards to pass them.
If you know the guards, you do know the
guards because they're posted on the Rosen
website.
And push those that you'd like to see
those kind of adoptions if that's what
you're thinking.
Let's see.
Why isn't Joe attending AMAs?
He will.
He does.
It's early for him.
Remember, he's in the Midwest.
So it's very early for him and he's got a
bunch of family things he's working on
right now.
So yeah, he'll be around.
He's not going anywhere.
Maybe we can do a later one later time.
So when it was once I made later time, it
was quite great.
Yeah.
Let's see.
Are you going to token 2049 in Singapore?
kushti?
Not sure.
So I'm thinking actually about attending
Korea, Korean Blockchain Week in
September.
Yeah, about token, I'm not sure.
It's, it's, quite big conference and so
on, but yeah, I don't know.
Probably, the, the, the right connections
already to, work with.
And, yeah, that does a big conference,
usually good, about side events to get
connections and, that's it.
Right.
So the conference itself is quite useless
usually.
Yeah.
Agreed.
I don't know much about the Korean
blockchain world.
I've been twice to Seoul.
The first time it was Songdo back in 2018
it was some academic conference and then
yeah we made ergo presentation in seoul
gangnam around september late september
2019 so yeah well after six years it's
definitely worth to visit again and now to
well get deeper
into what's going on there.
So, well, it seems Korea is always hot
about blockchain.
All right, we're eight minutes over, but
let's see if we have a killer question
coming in here.
This is actually a good question because
I think a lot of people, this is on their
minds.
What happens if Ergo hash rate stays low
while rewards decrease?
Is Ergo under threat as a blockchain not
being secured?
Didn't we have a decent hash back when
Ergo was 5 cents, 3 cents, 2 cents back in
the start?
It's always going to have an equilibrium
of what the profit is and how many people
are mining it.
Yeah, but it was Autolykos version 1,
right?
So you cannot really compare hashes
because well, then there was switch to
version 2, and yeah, well, I don't quite
know even how to compare hashes.
But even after the switch, so with
Autolykos version 2, well, as Well,
demands to RAM is growing with time.
**kushti**: