Hello and welcome to the Ergo Developer
Update.
A lot of things happening out there this
week.
I know we're a little late today by one
day, but the impact should be just as
much.
I'm not going to go into those current
events about the $1.4 billion hack.
We covered some of that in the spaces
that we did with the Rosen Bridge team,
Joe and one of his developers that joined.
So if you want to hear about that kind of
stuff, then tune into that.
It's still on our Twitter main Twitter
account.
It's about an hour listen, but always
good talks when you're talking to Joe.
Oh, it's good stuff to talk about.
So quickly, not a big dev update today.
But one thing I want to stress very hard
to you is that these events that happen,
these hacks, these things that could be
prevented, right? If there was due
diligence, if there was forethought and
actual research done before implementing
these fast and loose things or these fast
and loose protocols that, you know, you
surprise Pikachu look when something gets
hacked, right?
I think this is a good case to add some,
not hope, but add some justification to
why you're in Ergo, why you're actually
sticking around with Ergo, and why
something that's built for resilience,
it's built for mindfulness, it's built
from the beginning with things like
storage rent, demurrage, and other things
are, you know, these things are resilient.
These things are going to last through
these crazy hacks where a smart contract
can be changed, you know, just by the
multi-sig signatures.
It's like kind of stuff that you hear
outside of the ecosystem and you're like,
wow, you know, how was it this many funds
put into something like that when
something like that could have happened?
So moments like that make me very happy
that we're in Ergo and we're in it for the
long haul, you know, especially through
these turbulent times of, you know, VC
value extraction and all that, we can sit
back and think, you know, we're building
something that's resilient, we're building
P2P finance for essentially anyone.
So moments like that is, while they're
awful and you feel terrible for the people
that suffer those losses, it does
hopefully make you recognize why we're in
this space and why we're doing what we're
doing and why we're not catering to this
kind of pump and dump kind of stuff.
All right, that being said, let's switch
over to a quick little topic I want to
cover before we dive into the dev update.
OK, if you don't notice, I have Telegram
up to my, there we go, right there to my
right.
It looks like on the screen.
The Telegram channel I have open is
something very unique that I don't think
you find anywhere else in any mining
community out there, right?
In any major mining community.
Miners are unique, right?
Miners will point their rigs to something
and, you know, it's a business.
They'll point their rigs.
They'll cash out their token or they'll
speculate and hold that token and cash it
out another time.
That's a business.
That's great.
Nothing wrong with that.
But there's more that can be done with
this, right?
There's more involvement.
There's more control that these miners
have over especially our ecosystem.
You know, they're maybe used to pointing
towards a chain to mine where they have no
control, right?
We saw in the news the other day that a
chain was threatening Herominers, right?
Saying that you have too much of the hash.
If you don't back down or warn your users
or put a limit on there, we're going to
stop you from mining it.
Now, that should come in your mind as
like absolutely bonkers, right?
So props to Herominers for being like,
you know, screw you, you know, this is
permissionless.
This is supposed to be permissionless.
You know, we the miners should self
regulate here.
Right.
And that's our thought on that.
Miners should in their best interest be
self regulating.
Right.
It is not in their interest to get to a
point where the chain could be attacked
and the value that they've accumulated is
completely toast, right?
So in theory, miners should be able to
self-regulate.
And this is exactly what Sigmanauts'
mining DAO does.
Now, if you haven't heard about
Sigmanauts' mining DAO, or maybe you have,
so far that we know is the only pool
essentially that is collecting storage
rent, right?
It's a DAO-based mining pool.
That means once you come in, you get a
token that lets you use Paideia and create
votes that maybe change miner payout
methods for bonus tokens.
They have a ton of bonus tokens that
projects have donated to them.
So those go out every so often.
They have an amazing telegram here with
tons of chats, a general chat, a hash bot
that tells you the connected miners and
the current hash of the pool, block
notification bots.
Oh, you see how I haven't kept up with
that.
A storage rent monitor, it shows you how
much storage rent we're actually
collecting.
Announcements, payments blocks, the PHP
meme token that was started from one of
the first full package meme tokens that we
pulled from the chain with storage rent.
I think the entire circulation was
pulled, it was all in one box with not
enough ERGs, so really got lucky there.
And then they turned it around and added
quite a bit of liquidity to the PHP pool.
a fun show off your rigs pool
overclocking help bonus token distribution
so it shows every time that bonus tokens
go out and it looks like let's see 17th
and then before that was the 10th so it
looks like every week all these bonus
tokens are dropped to these wallets the
PHP, RSV, Dis, Ergonaut, little Puppy
token, GIF Fox, Ergo One, Wooden Nickels,
Clown, Sigma that's mining pool token,
Dark Erdoge
Terahertz, EGO, Bunz, CRPX, Troll, RSV
Hoskey, is that a Melty Smiley? I can't
see.
Comet, MiGoreng, Alien Rocket, Bulls,
Alien, Love, and GreasyCex.
So tons of bonus tokens that are there
for fun and also for speculation and for
cashing out.
A lot of these tokens have liquidity
pools.
Mining with the Sigmanauts gets you
several things.
One, it gets you voting power on how to
run the mining pool, right?
Because on Ergo, people seem to forget
that miners have control to change some
parameters in the entire chain, right?
That's often forgotten.
So Sigmanauts mining now takes that to
heart and says if you can change the
chain, miners should be able to manage
their DAO themselves.
All that kind of stuff is votable.
People put up proposals on Paideia, vote
on them.
I think the latest one was probably with
a PHP token distribution, or Mark actually
may have put one up today, I can't
remember.
But fantastic place to be, fantastic
place to take ownership and take control
of the ecosystem as kushti says.
I cannot, until hash gets too high on
this pool, I cannot stress to use this
pool.
They're the only ones doing that stuff
that I know of.
And, you know, why not get a little extra
bang for your buck when you mine into it?
All right?
Fantastic.
Let's jump into, oh, and you can get
there from sigmanauts.com slash mining.
You can see how to join the pool, how to
join the telegram and get started there.
Great, let's dive right into the
developer update.
All right, we have AnonBR with Nautilus.
The entire main interface is ported to
the new design system.
Now there are only four medium complexity
components on the dApp connector left to
be ported.
If all goes well, we can have a beta
release next week.
Refracted and merge add read-only
WalletView and restore WalletView and to
import WalletView.
Added recovery phrase backup verification
flow and create wallet view.
Added support for view storing wallets
from 10, 15, 18, 21, and 24 word recovery
phrase.
That's great.
Added several minor UI fixes and code
quality improvements.
All right, kushti with Ergo Protocol and
Reference Client R&D doing final audit and
code cleaning for 6.0 codebase for input
blocks working on input blocks coming out
to border and forks resolution.
Somebody put fast, very clever there.
SigmaUSD Oracle pool has been updated,
FII now update script is allowing to
update the pool to version 2.
And I think I said last week that won't
be GORT as in Gold Oracle Reward Tokens,
it's going to be Dollar Oracle Reward
Tokens, which is DORT.
So if you're privileged enough to run the
Oracle version 2 of SigmaUSD, it will be
DORT tokens as a reward.
OK, Celaut project, implementing simple
services to try to have some examples of
potentially interesting architectures.
At the same time, I'm fixing bugs I find
in the node and improving the usability of
the terminal.
Awesome.
C8 was talking about ZeroConf.
Let's see.
We have C8 here with Ergify.
ETA Dexy Gold alpha UI end of next week.
That's awesome.
Swap UI done.
History work in progress.
Mempool server integration work in
progress.
Design work in progress.
ErgoPay work in progress.
And you can see his work right there.
Did I forget the thumbs up now?
Good.
All right, we have Anand Bihar here
again.
I think he's just answering somebody.
Yeah, he's answering C8.
Is that it?
That may be a short one.
We have NoRoYogi.
This is Mark the Shark, the leader of the
Sigmanauts mining DAO, who we were just
speaking about.
Sigmanauts mining pool, ergo-miners.com
is back online.
Reviving miner, do you work specifically
for miners, changing payout for miner?
Reworked UI and embedded into dash, just
need to glance over database code for this
and should be there soon.
qx() deleted some massive files on the
server, and we added another volume to our
server, 100 gigabytes.
Yeah, we've had a few, in the beginning,
we had a few hangups of the logs just
going crazy and bringing the server down
for a few minutes.
So we turned off logging on one of the
apps, which made a big difference, deleted
some weird caching that was happening in
Docker for the database, and it freed up
like 20, 30 gigs.
So we don't even need to migrate to the
new drive yet, but super cool.
Pool hash at 103.
I think we saw it was 105 in the thing I
just had up at the time.
Distributed largest weekly collection of
ERG from Demurrage Storage Rent.
29.7 ERG.
So this is like, come on guys, like, look
at these other pools.
I get it.
You know, a lot of other major pools,
they're running ERG, they're running tons
of other chains, right?
So it's not on their main list to
implement Storage Rent.
It's going to be soon though, I guarantee
it.
But for now, Sigmanauts, hit it up guys.
Sharknet, funded 190 ERGs from community
and refinance for paying auditors for the
LLM generated smart contracts,
successfully built and trained LLM using
DR Pro on a small set of data provided by
Lotto, created simple UI for users to load
model to run locally.
So guys, this is very cool.
Let me explain where this is going,
right?
So imagine either going to a site, paying
a few tokens, or else, of course, the
ability to pull it down from GitHub
yourself if you have that ability.
Those options can always be available and
are encouraged in Ergo, right?
But let's say Sigmanauts are hosting an
LLM for a smart contract building.
Go there, put in a few tokens worth of
whatever your prompt is.
You're looking for a simple locking smart
contract.
You're looking for, I don't know, some
sort of time release or some other thing,
even more complex things.
That's the goal is you type in your
prompt, tell it what you want, and boom,
it outputs a smart contract that has gone
through numerous amounts of training
times.
to give you a smart contract that's
pretty good.
And then, of course, perhaps another very
specifically fine-tuned LLM to
double-check that smart contract for you.
Maybe they're built together, maybe
they're not.
Who knows?
We're not at quite at that stage yet, but
that's what this, that's what NoRoYogi is
working towards.
So super, super cool sharknet.
Okay, what else do we have node view x,
y, z, added pop-ups for Spectrum DEX
swaps, SigmaUSD swaps, bitcoin, Rosen
Bridge, sorry, SigmaUSD swaps and Rosen
Bridge events, decreased number of
requested boxes for index page price
chart, added timeout for node change
dialogue when loading node connections.
That's super neat.
Can we see it here?
Nice.
All right, we've got Rosen Bridge.
We are in step-by-step testing of Wallace
before opening the website.
Reform manual transaction, create four to
five test events between Binance and other
networks.
Once everything is verified, open the
website publicly.
They did.
It's open as of maybe last night or this
morning, or maybe it was yesterday.
Time kind of blends together, right?
Rosen Bridge Watcher version 2 completed
the observation status service to update
and change the status of operations.
Added the permit check service, which
registers as a permit check into the
health check service.
The Rosen Bridge app.
They've implemented a disconnect feature
to properly disconnect wallets.
Oh, good.
Ensure responsive design for tablet-sized
screens.
Apply the new design for monetary values.
The Watcher app.
Guard app.
Apply the same thing.
Add a TX status to public event status.
So Rosen Bridge is alive, guys, if you're
running a watcher, please let me take a
minute to tell you, please do this update.
Right.
That's very important.
I know some of you may be a little
nervous about the update from two or three
weeks ago where there's a database
migration.
Right.
Docker had pulled a version of the
Postgres database that was being used as
the in the pull commands to populate that.
So it had to be changed.
You were probably getting a permission
denied error when you tried to run it for
an update if you didn't follow the
instructions.
So please follow that.
It's 10 minutes max.
It does not take long to copy the
database, back it up, make your little
switches, and then push the old database
to restore to the new database container.
I did it on my watchers, didn't take too
much time at all, and I spun back up.
So if you're worried about that, give
that a try.
Feel free to reach out in a DM if you
like if you're running into trouble.
We can certainly help you and walk you
through that because it's very important
to have all those watchers up and updated.
Otherwise, you're just burning
electricity and it's not going to watch
any events, right?
Okay, what else do we have here?
Okay.
That is it, folks.
All right.
Thanks for joining us.
Make sure, again, watchers, update your
watchers.
Guards are all updated.
See if you can provide some liquidity.
I know MewFinance just created a fund to
provide some liquidity for Rosen BNB and
ERG on this side.
I think it's only 500 or so ERGs.
in total maybe a thousand so we can
capture the BNB.
I need to look at that but check out
MewFinance, check out that page where you
can contribute to that kind of stuff and
you'll automatically get those liquidity
tokens having a share in the liquidity of
that.
And don't forget to check out Sigmanauts'
mining pool.
Again, only pool that I know of that's
collecting storage rent for the time
being.
And you get all those bonus tokens and a
very cool, very unique community that's
always open to helping.
And you get to essentially run it as well
as part of the DAO.
All right.
Thanks, everybody.
Enjoy your week, I guess.
It's early.
Ciao.