I guess, the payment structure. I think
we're going to have a free tier. But of
course, the rest of the code is free. So
if you want to set up your own Open Web
UI, you're more than welcome to do so.
All right, and so what are the main use
cases for the current indexes? So is it
for like intelligence? Like analyzing the
blockchain?
Yeah, I'm hoping to create sort of agents
that were able to maybe say, hey, set up a
grid trading bot for me and then analyze
the data for like the last couple of days,
look at the grid trading bots and say,
hey, okay, we're doing pretty well. Maybe
let's update it, put more money into the
grid trading bot for a specific pair or be
able to spend the boxes itself on say the
Spectrum Finance. So be able to say, hey,
go ahead and buy a specific pair. Maybe
some sort of update recursively, like
every hour it checks, hey, should I buy,
sell, hold, and sort of do that sort of
mechanism. So allow the agents to be able
to operate on chain per the prompt.
That's interesting. It would be good to
get some applications generated by just
prompting the LLM.
Absolutely. That's the next step, but we
need to consider some initial
applications.
But, yeah, it would be good to get, I
don't know, like a new oracle pool, for
example, config for it with just one or
two prompts. So, to get data, some API
client or scraper for some data, that's
usually about just a few lines of code.
And getting Oracle Pool config done, so
we'll set the number of participants and
so on. That's what we are discussing for
the upcoming version 2 of USD Oracle Pool.
What should be number of participants and
so on? But then, in this case, we have
quite complicated update procedure from
version one to version two. And in case of
generating a new pool, it would be good to
have LLM generating a config. And then we
can do more like generate stable coins,
because it's mostly about using a new
Oracle and maybe tweaking parameters.
Then, yeah, people may do some stable
coins.
More stable and then some tooling like
options which could be nice because
originally options were created for
raising funds for agriculture industry,
for farmers. But, it's quite complicated
instrument it was. It used to be so only
banksters can do options, and you need to
have some big experience and so on to
write down a first option. But then, with
LLM, maybe it would be possible to avoid
intermediaries. So, a farmer can just
generate an option and launch it
immediately on chain instead of dealing
with banksters and paying a lot of money
for that.
What's the resource requirements for
setting up something like that?
So, I think there is some that the base
with scenarios. So, what's our parameters?
But here, maybe, in case if it's possible
to fit a quite big database to a LLM, it
could be better than a human in writing
options, because after all it's not
that... there is nothing magic here, it's
not that complicated task for LLM.
Shouldn't be complicated, shouldn't be
doable.
And they have an MCP. So an MCP server
for databases already. So like, for
example, there's one for Postgres. And so
you'll be able to facilitate, you know,
say, hey, what's in this data? Let's just
generally analyze it and then just give it
sort of those, with the database name, all
the APIs keys and things like that, and
should be able to kind of parse that out
in a lot easier fashion. I'm not sure what
database you mentioned, but I would
imagine they probably have one for that.
All right. How's the mining pool doing?
Sigmanauts mining pool.
Yeah, we're doing good. Let's see, I
think we're right about 90 GHz at the
moment. I'm currently working on updating
the web page for us. So kind of, we kind
of were thinking, you know, this is sort
of like the first sort of look for new
miners. And so we really need to have
something a little bit more polished for
our website. And so I'm working on
updating it. We have like the prototype in
terms of UI and UX done. So now it's just
working on the backend. And so I used
lovable.dev to generate the front end and
then from there working with Cursor to
facilitate the backend integration with
the APIs from our mining pool that we
have. So hopefully within a couple weeks
we'll have that up and running and ready
to go.
Yeah, we're just mining away. Going to
reach out to a couple other YouTube
miners, see if we can get them on the
peer-to-peer podcast and talk about
mining, because it seems a lot of talk
lately. Ergo is the last refuge for GPU
miners, and so I'd like to capitalize on
that sort of idea. You know, it's a great
place to be, great place to mine,
especially with demurrage. We handed out
over 150 ERGs this last week with
demurrage rewards. Then of course, we've
got the bonus rewards coming through as
well. So definitely we have the incentive
there to mine to our pool compared to any
other pool on Ergo, just because of the
fact, let alone we have demurrage as well
as the bonus tokens.
All right nice nice so from my side so
preparing 6.0 release now syncing with the
mainnet and fixing some issues on the way
so hard to predict when mainnet ready, 6.0
would be released, so now we're messing
with a little bit obscure issue. A bit
hard to predict, but anyway, it's close
and then we will start working with the
mining pools on getting activation,
setting activation date and informing
mining pools about the upcoming votes for
protocol update, soft fork, 6.0 soft fork.
Then, yeah, so for sub-blocks,
peer-to-peer logic initial version is
done, so in a few days we'll invite maybe
one or two folks to participate testing
devnet now with some peer-to-peer layer so
there is need for just like two or three
people there to update the nodes
constantly because it's still super raw
and so on but yeah there is progress there
aside of that there is upcoming 5026 not
released now with long-awaited feature of
Candidate Regeneration so it would allow
for faster confirmation of transactions.
So with Hardchains transaction we'll get
into the next block. And then, a lot of
other fixes and small improvements there.
So hopefully it will be released next
week.
Then, yeah, a good report from MewFinance
and there are a lot of updates in the
ecosystem towards unrolling new releases
and so on. Then yeah I personally
published a couple of new schemes on the
forum. Maybe LLM would be quite useful
there as well for launching, for example,
off-chain monetary systems for
communities. But yeah, we need first to
find how to do that manually.
Yeah, it should be standardized in some
way and how you set up off-chain bots.
Then, yeah, a lot of updates in regards
with development and a lot of talks, so a
lot of new contributors recently, so a lot
of talks about what's that doing so yeah a
lot of interesting things check developers
chats and so on if you're interested.
So I have a question for you about
sub-blocks. How would the mempool work
with sub-blocks being really quick
confirmation times? Would there be sort of
this new idea with the mempool where, you
know, because obviously they wouldn't be
there that long for the confirmation. So
is there going to be like a need to enter
mediary between like the mempool and like
confirmed or how does that work?
So in some regard, yeah, so sub-blocks
providing confirmations but with a higher
rate of orphans, much higher rate,
obviously. You may expect more rollbacks,
so mempool would kind of buffer anyway
when you are doing from one sub-block to
another transactions are getting back to
pool when you're applying new transactions
but new from a better chain but a
sub-block chain but it could be that some
transaction old fork would sit in the
mempool waiting for newer blocks. So,
yeah, it's more the same mechanics but
yeah, now, higher speed. So, there would
be a need to have bigger memory usage
sub-blocks memory on mempool because they
are in some sense about more same after
blocks so you are putting with a mempool
sub-blocks. And yeah, mempool would be
smaller now.
Right. Yeah, that's kind of what I was
thinking.
Because some algorithms are deficient in
the mempool, so it would be good for a
smaller pool. So I think it could be not
that efficient in comparison with having
transactions in sub-block.
All right, gotcha. But I would imagine so
with sub-blocks, we're probably going to
get new APIs to be able to call or are we
going to have the same APIs from the node
in the index nodes?
There will be new APIs and some methods
already implemented, but yeah just two or
three. So it's a very initial API. So in
the first place, the fault would be on
peer-to-peer and then on API for extra
indices that's still open.
So yeah, let me open the questions also.
Do we have anything there? Oh, second.
It looks like we have some in the chat.
With the global economy looking like it
is looking like it's in for a tough time
do you think this will hurt or help
crypto? I have no idea what do you think?
Yeah so about crypto should help Ergo it's
contra cyclical. The problem is that
currently the Ergo in my opinion kind of
trapped so it's considered crypto and
crypto is 99 percent useless. It has some
pro-cyclical value but yeah mostly more
for buying bitcoin and monero using to
bypass using bitcoin for him or holding
and I think now also monero maybe some
there is even Proof-of-Work will tell
about some foreign fans now looking for
work beyond Bitcoin and so on.
Kind of activity with that exact so in
TTC so our crypto cards should be in and
should help better money in turbulent
times so we have only kind of passive
digital gold. So Bitcoin and Ergo, was
positioned initially as presentations back
in September, October 2019 as digital gold
with contracts. So digital gold with an
ability to create trust. derivative
instruments on top of it, then it's
possible to do expansion to produce better
for the real world. To connect, so, like,
all IOUs, so, created, all IOUs created
within some T, with chain reserves. But
different economic is connected. So that's
possible with ergobots. Yeah, the problem
is cognition now, I believe. So people are
considering that there is crypto is doing
something but what exactly I know for the
proposition crypto that these days aside
of just speculative creation assets some
assets so yeah but but it's hopefully now
tens of different entities around the
globe so let's see it's anything but yeah
it's time it's time for Ergo to get
recognized.
So we got another question. What sort of
applications do you think will benefit
from sub-blocks?
Exchange, I think like DEX and so on.
Yeah, totally. It's general transactions.
You don't have to wait for like three
minutes.
Yeah maybe on ramp so you don't have it
for minutes when you are with this person
in the f-rides, for example, you don't
need to try it for minutes. Yeah. A forum
post on what to do for such deals rather
than with sub-blocks. It's also quite
fancy. You can meet someone to get a bit
exchanged for cash and then you can get
ERGs immediately with sub-blocks and not
RSBTC but yeah basically it's payton RSBTC
from locked UTXO if no proof for bitcoin
transfer is printed within certain time
frame like six hours for example 12 hours
so the worst lock time I've the bitcoin
chain out four hours I believe, but often
you need to wait for two hours. It's quite
often. Bitcoin, blockchain or when you
exchange cash for Bitcoin, wait for
confirmation. Yeah, it's quite painful.
So everything should be a lot faster from
like Rosen to sending TXs, you know, even,
I guess our mining pool when we
distribute, everything will be a lot, lot
faster.
Yeah, otherwise I'm here because it seems
that there for quite a long time to
exclude any security on the blockchain. So
it's about Ergo.
There should still be something like
speed up though. I mean, just from a TX
perspective, like once they're done with
the security aspects and like, you know,
just from like, I would imagine maybe it's
minimal, just from like, I don't really
know what goes on behind the scenes, but I
would imagine just because you can
transact factor faster, at least on the
Ergo side, it'll be a little bit faster,
maybe not super noticeable.
Yeah, let's see. So, yeah, maybe it helps
a bit. In regards with mining pools, I'm
not sure, it's probably the same. So, I
don't know, the Sigmanauts mining pools
specifically. But for others, it's usually
just like few actions with two inputs and
very many outputs linked to mine and
they're doing such transactions I don't
know like twice a day something like that
and then yeah I mean from sub not getting
that much so you just transactions to the
network and they get into payments would
be a lot faster for sure. In a few minutes
and yeah, if it's not a few minutes but
faster, I mean, it's the same. Most of the
menus are not for payments, like every few
seconds. Every few minutes even, so
they're checking like once a day, so maybe
it's more or less the same after all. But
yeah for trade and so on it's better and
there were some games which now could be
revived like one it's by Hayley with some
kind of thing it could be revived on some
blocks I believe something like that.
Okay. Yeah. I think that, like you said,
like, you know, an on-ramp system would be
interesting. Like, like Stripe has a
payment system where a lot of people have
been using that for their vibe coded games
and things like that, where they put the
payment in there, put your credit cards.
It'd be interesting, you know, especially
with sub-blocks where you could reduce the
settlement time. be able to use Stripe, be
able to build something to on-ramp so then
people pay in USD and then you can send
them ERG or whatever they want, maybe
something with Rosen Bridge as well for
other specific coins or tokens.
Cool, cool. We have a question. How does
one get started with vibe coding for
ErgoTree and React? So I guess for React,
I would probably suggest using cursor, but
of course there's other AI agent coding
frameworks that you could use. That's just
something I use. You could also just use
the native Anthropic Claude, Claude.com.
And so basically, and I would even just
like, you know, look at the landscape. So
Grok is actually really good as well. And
so some LLMs are better than others at
doing specific tasks. So I would maybe
kind of think, play around with those sort
of notions. And so sometimes what I like
to do is I'll go in one LLM like Claude
Sonnet 3.7 and say, hey, I need to write a
prompt to do this. So, for example, I
wanted to make Sigmanauts mining pool. I
took a screenshot of our current
dashboards. I was able to say, hey, grab
all these metrics, understand what they
are, make them into a readme document, and
then build some sort of Markdown structure
and design of how it works and what we
need. And then write this prompt. I then
took that prompt and put it into
lovable.dev. And then lovable.dev then
created and generated the entire UI for me
in UX. And so React, if you wanted to make
a webpage, you could do that as well. I
did the same thing with this airdrop tool
that I made for like NFTs and tokens so
you can mass distribute that to people. So
in short, you can use lovable.dev to maybe
stand up some sort of front end. You can
then push that to GitHub, pull that into
Cursor and then develop the backend. So
there's a lot of different ways you can
swing with it. And so I would probably
suggest sort of come up with a simple
project and then kind of try different
LLMs and kind of see what works for you
and kind of go from there.
In terms of ErgoTree, that is something I
think we're kind of still working on. I
haven't really been working on that too
specifically, but really what you need
there is the context. And so as long as
you have the specific context, so like for
ErgoScript, you can give it GitHub repos
that have like legitimate smart contracts.
And you could say, hey, this is example
code. This is sort of what I want to do.
And then again, also maybe you could say
these example code, make diagrams out of
it so it makes sense and make sure it
understands the UTXO model. And this is
kind of what we're trying to do with the
Ergo MCP. And so the So it gives the
context to the LLM. And then from there,
when you actually prompt it, and it
probably won't be a one shot like, hey,
make this contract for like a dead man
switch. So if I die, I publish this stuff
to the blockchain. You know, probably it's
gonna be some fine tuning, some tweaking,
but I think it could potentially get you
maybe 50 to 70% of the way. And then the
rest you can kind of have to test out for
yourself. So, but again, I think it's all
about playing around and testing it.
I don't know, what are your thoughts?
kushti, have you tried Vibe coding at all?
Any AI tools have you used?
So I've tried to do some core
developments using, yeah, Sonnet 3.5 I
believe and yeah so it's and yeah I'll try
to to do some comps not but tests actually
for ChainCash and so all tests, it's
working very well. We generated some
tests, planned for change with just a goal
prompt and it worked immediately. It was a
very nice experience. Development, it
seems, it's not computable, so quite
subtle, but you are spending a lot of time
to figure out what's wrong with them. So,
yes, it's producing some complicated code.
It's looking okay from the first, but then
there are some subtle bugs, actually.
Yeah, it's definitely kind of an art, you
know. Yeah but for tests you know it's
working really great so yeah well most of
time I think tests now could be saved and
actually it's quite a big time saver
because all tests also are quite
complicated for the load and for the
interpreter. And for cache and DEX, all
tests are weathered, but length 3 or 4
lines of code per hour tests easily. It
could be because, yeah, you need to
assemble a transaction according to
different concerns and so on, then check,
succeed or fail. And then with the help of
LLM, you can ask for many hours actually
on that. So yeah, that's quite a great
tooling for standard coding, standard
kinds of coding. Yeah, maybe API. I will
try to do my API methods. Yeah, for
complicated stuff. Complicated stuff?
Yeah, algorithms are heavier. Yeah, it's
not that good. But yeah, that's quite
expected also.
Yeah, and it's like most tools. Not every
tool is a hammer. And so if you treat
every tool like it's a hammer, it's bound
to break, it's bound to not work. And so
knowing when to use AI and when not to use
AI is definitely a good skill to have. And
then I think relative to the more complex
problems, even with ErgoScript, for
example, it just doesn't have a lot of the
context that it needs. So for example,
like Python, You know, it was trained on a
lot of Python code within GitHub. There's
so much lines on there. Whereas
ErgoScript, there's obviously not too
much. And so there is a notion to where
maybe we need to fine tune a specific
model so we can train, say, hey, this is
how you make this specific contract. This
is how you make this contract. And so
that's something else we're also looking
at. I think MCPs might be able to get us
there before we do that. But if somebody
else wants to do that, by all means, send
it. We have about 190 ERGs when we're
ready to test and generate smart
contracts. And so that we're going to pay
some auditors. So once we get there, if we
can pay some folks to audit them, pay them
for their time, and then hopefully the
output is sufficient for what we're
working with. But only time will tell.
Yeah. So, to add more, you have a lot of
open so applications, open contracts and
so on. So, then, it would be very helpful
to LLM to produce ErgoScript LLM. I
believe.
Yeah, absolutely. Yeah, definitely. And I
think from a fine tuning perspective, you
know, it's probably sufficient with the
contracts that we have on the chain right
now are rather open source. So then that
way, you know, it doesn't sort of get
super confused. You can really like hone
in, so to speak on these specific
contracts and how they're written and how
they're executed. And so, but but but I
guess the problem might be. And so it
could maybe overfit. So, for example, if
you have like a pinlock contract, it was
trained on and then you say, hey, make me
another pinlock contract with a little bit
more extendedness. It will probably do
that really well. But if you try to say,
hey, make me write like a a dead man
switch, so to speak. It might not know how
to do that explicitly. But I think the
goal isn't to one-shot these smart
contracts. That's not my goal. My goal is
to make it 50% to 75% easier to write the
smart contracts. And so if I can get 50%
to 75% to say the first draft of the smart
contract, that works for me because then I
can finesse it or whatever it needs to do.
Ask kushti, do you write? Hey, what's
going on here? So that's sort of my goal.
It sort of speeds up the smart contract
timeline of development. And that would be
pretty powerful, I think. So then more
folks helps democratize in some sense,
sort of these coding abilities, maybe. And
maybe not everybody should be making smart
contracts, I suppose. There's some sort of
notion of security and safety, I guess,
with that sort of respect. Would be cool.
So somebody else says, let's see. I know
we don't do wash trading or other nonsense
like some other chains, but Ergo and
associated dApps have been stress tested
at any point. So I'm not sure. Have we
done any sort of stress test? I mean, I
know, for example, we've people have tried
to stress test, you know, fitting the most
amount within a given box relative to a
given transaction. So like, you know,
sending one input to like 10,000 outputs,
I suppose.
How do you stress test the blockchain, I
guess? Stress testing events, but yeah, so
for kind of synthetic stress testing, I'm
not aware of. There were a lot of
discussions and I think for our
sub-blocks, yeah, there would be needed to
do testnet stress testing. But first, we
need to get more realistic testnet
apologies, so we'll invite more folks to
the Testnet because, it doesn't make sense
to do stress testing. So that's the
problem with many, actually, papers and so
on, white papers claiming some high TPS
when you realize what they're doing they
just have few nodes or even many nodes
over the same data center and then yeah it
doesn't make sense because it's not
looking like a real peer-to-peer network.
So first we need to get a little bigger
testing network, but that's doable. And
then yeah, we can do stress testing.
Yeah, that'd be cool to do, you know,
especially to, to be able to, I mean, I
think you made a good point. The test net
topology, like say for example, well, if I
wanted to test out one input to 10,000
outputs, like where would I even get all
the 10,000 addresses? I mean, I guess you
generate them, you know, how would you do
that?
Yeah, so for main nets there were some
stress tests for many outputs and one
actually broken many notes because of some
back in light clients actually but those
light clients then broke full clients and
so and then yeah many pools we're
struggling yeah basically not we are
restarting out of memory, but that was
like four years ago, so like 2021, it was
some Aneta airdrop. And yeah, after that,
the network survived somehow, but yeah,
many nodes were under pressure. And Yeah,
after that, we did some fixes. And, after
that, I can't remember. So there were many
events like airdrops and yeah, there was
some events when a few thousands of
transactions was sent to the network at
one shot, but yeah, everything was sitting
smoothly by the network as well.
Yeah. Yeah. In terms of test net, I would
love to set up a Sigmanauts mining pool
test net, and then that would be kind of
interesting. Easier to set up maybe, I
don't know.
Let's see, so we got a couple questions
on sub-blocks. So will sub-blocks affect
scalability? You know, what if one billion
people are using Ergo and then can
sub-blocks TXs be chained within a single
block? Yeah, so can sub-blocks TXs be
changed within a single block?
Yeah, but so transactions can be chained
in a single sub-block. And yes, single
block also, because yeah, a block would be
just a sequence of sub-blocks mostly for
most of transactions. But, yeah, about
billions of people. So still there is need
for layer 2s and not just because of TPS.
So I think that would be quite natural
design. So today I tweeted diagram of how
our Hawala system works, conceptually. So
it's about, you know, some global network
and then local segments are connected to
Hawala, Hawala, so local exchange booth.
So, yeah, I believe it should be the same
here when you have some local segment,
which is mostly exchanging. with people,
actors, agents, mostly exchanging within
this segment. So they need for some
off-chain solution. There is no need for
global consensus. When you buy coffee from
some local supplier, I mean, why? Why do
you need for global consensus? Why some?
Why some miner in Argentina and some Ergo
enthusiast in Vietnam India or China
should know about that even so such
economic activity Should be localized I
believe ledger wise also and then yeah I
know for global consensus, we need to have
some, I don't know, events which are
really needed there on the global level.
Yeah, it makes a lot of sense. I haven't
really thought about it in terms of the
global consensus sort of versus like
local. That's a good way to put that
because I mean totally like why you know
from a local you know I am buying coffee
like why does the global Ergo chain kind
of care about that you know what I mean
it's like yeah just do it off chain and
then you know have that sort of segment do
that that makes a lot of sense.
Yeah I mean maybe there is need for some
settlements and clearing between different
local segments and so on and then yeah
there is need for global consensus. There
is need for global consensus maybe in
regards with some global events and so on
but yeah for For most of activities, like
real world activities, I believe there is
no need for global consensus, so he
immediately did a global consensus. So
there is no need to write that you bought
a cup of coffee from some local supplier.
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, that doesn't make sense
economically even, not technically even.
Yeah, I mean, even in the United States,
we've got the federal government, but then
we also have our local governments and
then our city governments. So it makes
sense. The federal government doesn't
really care what we do, so to speak, on
certain local perspectives. So it makes
sense to, as we scale up, we continue to
offload specific aspects to these other
layers.
All right. So one more question.
Looks like, let's see, how can both Ergo
and Cardano collaborate with each other
from a transaction happen on the chain, on
the respective chain? So I guess we're
kind of doing that with Rosen Bridge.
Yeah, but what I thought about actually
is can we have multi-chain Hydra, for
example. And as Cardano is supporting the
elliptic curve used in Ergo, secp256k1, I
guess that's doable in some form. I need
to recheck the Hydra paper. But that would
be quite interesting when you may have
some off-chain high-speed rails basically
for financial and not just financial
transactions, powered from both the chains
at the same time. So, it would be
interesting. Maybe it could be
collateralized from both the chains. So,
outcomes may happen on both the chains, so
some on Ergo side, some on Cardano side.
The other question is for some like
real-world use cases, not to have it just
as a quite, I don't know, exciting toy.
But yeah, it sounds interesting at least.
Yeah, let's see. Yeah, I think, in regards
with such stuff, there are a lot of
technical opportunities between Ergo
Cardano and other UTXO blockchains.
Okay, awesome. Awesome.
One last quick question, I guess. When is
the next P2P podcast? Yeah, we need to sit
down and record that. Me and Tim have just
been busy kind of working on a few things.
So hopefully within this next week, we'll
get something out to you guys.
All right. So do you have a guest?
We don't. We'll either just do it with us
or you're welcome to come on and we'd be
happy to chat with you.
Yeah, so we can do one. Let me think. So
yeah, the best time would be around wait
or April 19th, Saturday, or Friday before
18th. So something like that, yeah, would
be quite good.
Okay, cool. Yeah. I'll reach out to Tim
and then we'll start a group chat. But
what can we talk about? I can maybe
prepare some cool stuff in advance.
So I can check the Hydra paper and we can
have a talk about different off-chain
systems. So recently I've published that
off-chain design, a new one, it was a
forum post on Monday. So the idea is to
have a layer 2 where participants may
create IOUs, money off-chain and then have
on-chain redemption for them so it's a
kind of reverse of ordinary off-chain cash
schemes such as Fedimint or Cashew for
Bitcoin where you have on-chain reserves
and mint not against them so always
redeemable. notes so so so here yeah you
are going opposite so it's not always
redeemable maybe but you have more money
off chain which also does make sense i
believe in real world applications but
then yeah i'm also interested in those
schemes like Cashew Fedimint, Skridcache,
Lightning Network a little bit, but to me
it seems limited. Then Hydra and so on, so
like state channel kind of systems. And
more so I think there could be maybe
hundreds of different designs. It would be
good to think how to make them
interoperable. There are also, for
example, there is ARK on Bitcoin. I'm
studying a little bit, but it's hard to
say and it looks quite messy. I even asked
in the group recently, do they have any
white paper and security analysis and it
seems not really so just massive writings
and some codes you need to figure out how
security is by your own and sometimes some
issues found there so but still could be
considered as well and as I said there
could be hundreds of different off-chain
designs with properties maybe it's worth
to somehow classify them and yeah maybe
for auto generation of chain systems so
after okay. Lighting network failure,
which is what we are witnessing. Yeah, I
think even Bitcoin Maxis would be quite
open to more off-chain solutions. They're
open even now, so it seems ARK, for
example, is getting there from my
observations after visiting some there are
two events. I mean so, yeah, we may
discuss off-chain schemes, but we may
discuss okay, cool.
Yeah, I mean, I think the ground is super
fertile, and so we'll be excited to
explore that here with you. All right,
keep an eye on them. Yeah, absolutely. And
let's see. I think one last question. I
know I said the last. time. But someone
said, how do you incentivize testnet
mining? I just had this idea. And so we
could, if we had a Sigmanauts testnet
mining pool, we could see if your address
or you could prove somehow you're mining
to our pool and testnet and mainnet. And
then maybe we could give you like bonus
tokens or something like that for mining
on both of our pools, testnet and mainnet.
So that's maybe a way to incentivize that.
But any case, we can explore that.
I actually had an idea to build first
trustless bridge between Ergo mainnet and
Ergo testnet and then we can bring the
testnet ERG to the mainnet and then yeah
it's up to people how to incentivize so
maybe some people may put ERG along with
testnet ERG into a liquidity pool and so
on interesting to see possible
experiments. That would be interesting.
Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. It's fun to
experiment.
And yeah, by the way, I have some
question, if you mind, the last maybe. So
what's Sigmanauts mining pool doing with
the tokens they got from storage rent? Any
plans or any actions already aside of that
PHP?
Yeah, for sure. So we launched PHP, let's
see, probably a few months ago, and then
CannonQ locked that up into a liquidity
pool with most of it. And then so we're
distributing some of it to the miners.
We're distributing, let's see, I think
it's on Spectrum DEX. So that's like out
live in the ecosystem repurposed. We have
a couple tokens kind of here and there. So
we have like a Carbidge one, an Oracle,
test one and two, Felter Snatch. So
nothing really, I guess, of note, but we'd
be happy, I suppose, if somebody was
interested. sell them on MewFinance, maybe
bundle them all up, get it to the mining
pool. And then we distribute that into the
miners. but, the PHP token is the only
token where we've got the totality of all
of the supply for a given token. And then
that's where we're like, Hey, let's go
ahead and launch something. But, yeah,
it's been actually really great so far. I
think, I think the liquidity pool is like
20,000 or something like that for a PHP.
So that's, that's kind of neat to see.
Interesting. Nice. and some other random
tokens I'm looking at now.
Yeah, but it seems a lot of tokens going
to the pool. So you're collecting all the
tokens first. And then decide what to do.
I like to burn.
Yeah, well, I guess token-wise, we
haven't really set any rules or stuff,
whether do we want to burn it. Right now,
it's just sitting in our wallet aside from
PHP. And then the ERG is distributed based
upon the block and the miner's payout of
that, which is equivalent to their
participation. So for example, if you got
50% of the reward, we're going to wait
that one for 50% and then the next block
is say, you know, 40%. And then we kind of
average that with the rest of everybody
else. And then once a week on Tuesdays, we
airdrop that to everybody. And then the
pool will start taking 1% of that.
All right. Yeah, good. Okay, so we're
rocking and rolling. And so yeah, we got
150 last week, we probably have probably
got over maybe like 500 or since we have
started, probably more than that.
Nice. So it's a nice incentive for our
pool for sure.
And yeah, and I guess already maybe
hundreds of kilobytes of garbage cleaned
out from the UTXO set.
Yeah, definitely. It's pretty neat to
see. It's cool to see. Relative to the
Sigmanauts Monocle update, we're debating
right now. Do we open source it? Do we
create the steps? I think a lot of the
miners are under the impression, this is
what makes us marketable. Most of
everything's on is open source, but we're
not going to explicitly give you guys the
steps, I suppose, at least for the time
being. So we're going to continue to build
what they call the moat between us and
other pools to kind of make us more
marketable and bring more miners in. And
then once I think we are sufficient there,
we'll then distribute that or make the
steps, I guess, more transparent. But feel
free, if you disagree with us and you're
in the mining pool, definitely reach out.
We are going to put it to a vote. And then
from there, just reach out if you
disagree, you don't like that. But this
isn't necessarily just my opinion, this is
other people's opinions within the pool.
It's definitely a collective thought,
although I think qx() is very wanting to
release it to the general community. but
again, it's all open source. So if
somebody really wanted to try to do it,
they could. So it's not like any of it's
closed source.
So yeah, let's see. How's it going?
All right. So let's wrap up with this.
All right. Yeah, that sounds good. Well,
it's a nice chat with you, kushti. Thanks
for the questions, everybody.
Yeah. Good to see, the format and the
team always changing. And yeah, always
building at the same time. So, yeah, have
a good day, Marc, and have a good day,
guys. See you, everybody.