Hey guys, welcome to the dev update,
something like number, I've lost count,
130.
Tell myself I gotta check.
Well, I'm on the mend, and here we are.
We're landing on vacation, so we've
decided to poke our fingers into the
interface a little bit to kind of change
the look for the week.
Let's see how it lands, guys.
Very short dev update for you this week.
A lot of stuff always happened in Ergo,
but sometimes the devs forget to post to
the weekly dev update chat because they're
very busy.
But that's okay. Fear not, because if you
hang around in the ecosystem, you know
that things are bustlin.
One thing that was interesting today in
chat that we saw is, you know, community
is a big way to measure crypto, influence
crypto, uptick projects like that.
And once in a while, you know, usually
chats have their downtime. Ergo has theirs
at about 9 p.m. Eastern Time, which is
like 1 p.m., 1 a.m. UTC.
Gets a little soft, gets a little quiet.
And so you've got the normal fudsters
coming in around that time saying, where's
the community, when community, that kind
of thing.
And people started posting some things
and they were talking about future
finance, other things. People are pushing
sub-blocks and those kind of things.
And kushti said something interesting
that was simple and said, you know, we
don't need sub-blocks. You know, we have
at the moment, you don't have to wait for
sub-blocks. We have many financial tools
for experimentation.
And he's right. And it makes you think in
these times when, you know, let's not diss
other chains, but when a lot of other
chains are based on large money influxes,
money inflows, and large holders making
ripples in spaces, and then followed by
meme crazes and things like that.
You know times like these where the
market's down when it's supposed to be
waiting to go up and those kind of things
in flux, it makes me really happy to be in
Ergo if you take a peek down below me
right here you'll see I don't know what's
the first 30 or 40 projects that are
active on Ergo that were easy to pluck
right off the website or sigmaverse.
We have the meat, you know, we have the
fuel. We have the parts of the recipe for
anybody to come on and do this stuff and
by looking at the ticket below you can see
the amazing things that have been
accomplished so far.
So when the market fluctuates, when
CoinGecko makes my portfolio bleed and cry
a little bit, it doesn't bother me because
I know that I know why we're here. I know
what we've built and I know what we can
build.
You know, the snap of our fingers with
the tooling that we have. So that always
brings me a different perspective on that
kind of thing.
When I see people hurting in other
ecosystems, it sucks for them, I think,
you know, but Ergo keeps trucking, being
resilient and we keep doing what we're
doing and people keep catching on.
So it's an exciting, exciting place to
be, an exciting thing to be in.
All right, let's hit the dev update real
quick. It's short, as I said, and we won't
take up too much of your time. We'll hit
the cool change scene button.
Here we go. Ready?
All right, I hope you enjoyed that change
scene feature. Andy's going to probably
kill me, but you know, whatever.
All right, here we go. New format for Dev
Update Display. We've got kushti kicking
off the chat every Wednesday morning.
I think he's missed it once. And that's
only because I hit it at 8.02 and he came
in at 8.03 or something like that. So it's
not really a miss.
Alright, first up we have AnonBR with
Team Nautilus. For those of you not
familiar with Nautilus, it's like a really
good Chrome extension wallet. They're
working on a mobile version of course, so
stay tuned for that.
So AnonBR refactored Add Wallet Index
View component, refactored Create Wallet
View component, refactored Ledger Connect
View component, added Mnemonic component,
added 24-word mnemonic generation support.
Oh, very nice. Added several minor UI
fixes and code quality improvements. And
you can see a little graphic of some
things that he's done here.
Let's give him all the buttons.
Luivatra claims he's been busy. I think
that's up for debate in the ecosystem. I
don't know, you know, the European busy is
different than the busy I know about, so
we're not going to harp on them too much.
He says, I'm looking forward to trying
out the new execute from VAR function.
Plenty of Paideia contracts could benefit
from that.
If you haven't tried Paideia, do it. Spin
up a DAO. I mentioned this last week as I
did. Fantastic app.
All right, we've got qx() with ErgFi Dexy
Gold swap widget done. Bank LP widget work
in progress. ErgoPay in progress. Dexy
Gold swap test with fake tokens. End of
week. Awesome. Thanks, qx().
kushti is asking how he compiles
contracts. Let's see what else we have.
We've got kushti with Ergo protocol and
reference client R&D. Client 5.0.25
released. Recommended update nodes with
extra indices.
Yay, more indexing on your node. Love it.
Sigma SDK 5.0.15 released with Execute
from VAR. That's what Luivatra was excited
about in BigInt functions to deserialize a
script from context extension variable and
create BigInt from a script, respectively,
parsing contract template from JSON
string, box deserialization, W.js, along
with many other features.
So it looks like they've been busy on
Sigma SDK. That's awesome.
Fixed compatibility issues related with
new sub-blocks per block perimeter
injection and with that release 6.0.0 RC2
supporting 6.0 activation in public
testnet which as I said last week it's in
and votes are the voting is done to the
voting epic so it's live you've got 6.0
running on public testnet.
Anybody want to test that? It's required
for kushti's sub-blocks, which as we know
are looking forward to be much faster
confirmation times.
So yeah, that's really cool.
And here we go for sub-blocks
implementation. Made first test with AI
for sub-blocks application to fix behavior
of this functionality.
And working on properly processing
sub-blocks coming out of order with
delayed transactions, resolving
sub-blocks, forks, etc.
Once you get into speed and you get into
transferring TXs across nodes, it gets a
little hairy. I mean, that's one of the
reasons that kushti and the other core
developers settled on two minute block
average times, you know, it's kind of the
safety net between, you know, too slow,
which Bitcoin essentially, and too fast to
propagate to the node.
So every TX, you know, for the finality
of it needs to propagate to all the nodes
out there for consensus written into a
block.
But when you have nodes that are delayed
or can't propagate fast enough, you're
going to possibly run into issues there.
So that's one thing that kushti's figuring
out with sub-blocks, essentially.
All right, ChainCash started negative
tests with AI doing new paper, merge PR
with refund actions and registers. And he
removed this ChainCash pull 10. I'm not
going to click it, but I'm sure he had
good reason.
Dexy trying to figure out updated mainnet
deployment plan. And I don't know if he
mentioned it here. Let's read down below.
He didn't. I think on Thursday. Oh, after
the dev update. Yeah, Thursday, the
SigmaUSD Oracle group got together.
And we pushed a vote to the vote
configuration to the process. And it
passed, essentially. And everything is
good. Next up is we just have to update
our clients to version 2.
And as you've heard people say with Dexy
Gold, the reward token for client runners,
for server runners, for the protocol is
called GORT. But for SigmaUSD, US dollar
essentially ERG is going to be called
DORT.
So dollar oracle reward token. I like it.
GORT, DORT. Hopefully we see ORT, like oil
oracle reward token. LORT, lithium oracle
reward token. I don't know, it's endless,
right?
BORT, banana oracle reward token. I can't
really do a stable card. I mean, you
could, but you get the idea.
So you have all these reward tokens that
are possible by running version two of the
oracle, depending on what you're actually
announcing on chain for a price. So super
cool with that.
We've got the Rosen Bridge planning to
release Binance in the coming days. We
should see that anytime. We've been
hearing about it in chats. We've got a
warning in the guard chats about this. So
really, really looking forward to this.
Rosen Bridge watcher version two, add
observation status service in our
services, write startup and stop functions
in service, add dependency to my service
like TXPOT, DB service and scanner.
Add function for calls or queries in DB
service. The Rosen Bridge Rosen app.
Implementing the aggregation method for
public event status.
The RosenSoon, classic.
All right, let's see. kushti's giving
some advice. There's a suggestion for
Nautilus wallet. Easy to run out of node
with an empty wallet. I want the node to
be fully automatic without any revision in
computer startup. Getting some ideas for
that.
Would be nice to have an option to launch
automatically without having to type in
password. You know, I think there's a way
to do that from all the times that
Nautilus spoken out in support, so that
should be an easy fix, hopefully.
All right.
NodeView XYZ, I spoke about this last
week. It'd be amazing to have a node that
you could just have a interface on and hop
on. Much easier to install, even if it was
in the default package.
Added special address and transaction
detection for Spectrum DEX, Rosen Bridge,
SigmaUSD, and mining pools. Optimized load
times with caching ErgoTree to address
conversions.
Switch deployment and hosting of NodeView
XYZ for GitHub pages to Cloudflare because
of HTTPS issues.
Planning to make pop-ups to see
parameters or swaps in cross-chain
transfers. That's awesome.
If that's what parameters are swaps and
cross-chain transfers. That means what I
think it means. Let's see. Cool.
All right. What else do we have here?
We have CannonQ giving a little update on
bounties. There's Keystone Wallet
Integration, 3,000 ERG reward, there's
Fleet SDK tutorials, 775 SigmaUSD, and
this week, one bounty cleared, one bounty
added.
So guys, any of you devs out there,
anybody watching this on YouTube not
familiar with Ergo or anything, there's a
meat load of bounty updates just ripe for
the plucking.
Go and update some things. There's
tutorials for Sigma Rust or those kind of
things depending on what the update
requires. I mean it's just sitting there
guys. It's literally like money sitting
there for you to grab.
I can't encourage you enough to do this.
Heck even if it takes you two months to
learn some stuff, just hop on there, learn
it in two months. You'll definitely make
up your payday from that kind of stuff.
Let's see.
kushti released Ergo Protocol Reference
Client 5.1.2. They're identical to the
5.0.25 changes, but on RocksDB.
So that is a much more stable, I'd say,
database. Less compatible with many
different architectures, but a little bit
more stable than the current 5.0.25
database usage.
If anybody have run nodes, you may have
run into where you've run out of space or
something happens to your network
connection. It's mainly, I usually only
run into it when I run out of space on my
hard drive because I'm not paying
attention on like a little Raspberry Pi.
You know, that's a funny thing. You run a
node on another chain, right? You probably
spend a ton of money. You have a massive
hard drive. You probably have monitoring
tools.
Okay. You run a node on a Raspberry Pi
with like a SD card even if it will run on
the fast 10x or 20x ones. And then you
forget it, right?
And you forget it for too long and you
realize that you run out of space. So it's
a funny problem that an easy system like
Ergo nodes can run on anything. You still
got to kind of pay attention once in a
while.
So anyway, my original point is I would
run out of space, get corrupt databases,
have to resync. But RocksDB hopefully
should be a little bit better at either
fixing itself there or not corrupting at
all.
So that's great.
Oh, and kushti is announcing the good
news that the Oracle operators made the
update. It was not noticed as the ceremony
took about 20 minutes. And the update
transaction was right there.
Update is minimal but the script now
allowing for update to oracle version 2
and I think we're into a couple days here
now so that's it guys thanks for
listening.
We've got some things that are always
missed right? I mentioned Cyberverse,
don't forget to check out Cyberverse. They
had like a game night I think on Thursday
night UTC time where they played like the
bow and arrow game, they played other
multiplayer games.
Still a nice high watermark sustaining
through on Cyberverse, they're doing
great. It's good to see that, those guys
deserve the best.
MewFinance as well, they didn't do an
update this week but check those guys out.
They just supported a liquidity builder or
donation I forget which one it is for the
Sigmanauts mining DAO.
So it's really nice to be able to do
those kind of launch pads off there to
raise some funds for shared liquidity.
Sigmanauts Mining DAO is trucking along.
Mark's just upgraded the server to an
extra hard drive because you can bet that
those logs take up a lot of space when
you're running something like that with
that much hash.
So he's doing that. He's diving into his
Sharknet stuff where he's making these
branded packages based on that theme,
which is really, really cool.
So let me stress, even if you have just
like a 2070 or I don't know, a 3050, a
4050, 4060, 4060, something. But hop into
the mining pool, give it a low enough hash
to where you're not going to be burning
through electricity at this time, and join
the community.
Even if you don't have a card, join the
community. You don't have to be a miner to
join the Sigmanauts mining DAO,
essentially. I don't think Mark can
correct me there, but the community is
there and even if you have a small card,
point it towards a pool and together it'll
make a big difference than any big farm.
A majority of small users compared to one
big user always makes that big difference.
So yeah, feel free to dive in there.
I hope you like the new test format. Let
me know in the comments what you think. I
just whipped together a little bit before.
I can add some more fancy stuff.
Maybe make the background a little faster
moving. Maybe make my head less big. I
don't know if that's possible or not. But
you know, maybe we're shrinkage tools.
Thanks, everybody, for joining. We'll see
you in the AMA on Thursday. And if you're
up for it, join the Sigmanauts meeting
later today, later Sunday.
Check in the Sigmanauts chat or ask on
main chat if you can pop in. We're happy
to have people come in and listen since
the text is public anyway.
Ciao, everybody. Bye-bye.