Hello and welcome to a late night solo
dev update.
I'm qx() and I will guide you through the
ASMR developer update on the Ergo
platform.
We'll tone it down more once we get to
the actual updates.
And excuse my voice, still recovering
after a full month of being sick from
before, so working on that.
OK, so you'll notice what I have up on
screen here first is before the Dev Update
started, kushti and Unreal and on 2020's
mgPai, Luivatra are discussing the
SigmaUSD bank update.
So currently in the stages, Unreal, I
believe, is testing against testnet some
UI updates for it.
I wanted to jump in here because I see in
chat sometimes people are trying to
convert the SigmaUSD, a SigmaRSV, convert
back when they're confused about why the
price is different, perhaps, on MewFinance
or MewDex or Spectrum DEX compared to the
SigmaUSD bank or even TokenJ, which some
people don't even know about and how that
works.
So there's an amazing video that I spoke
with cafe and he explains that I'll put
that in the chat below.
If I remember, if it's not too late, if
not just Google it, it's on the Ergo
platform channel or the Sigmanauts
channel, I believe it was a dev update.
So it should be the Ergo YouTube channel,
but let's kick off here, right here.
So we have two different kinds. The first
kind.
The first way we can do it is we can go
to sigmausd.io.
Now the difference between sigmausd.io,
the difference between tokenj and the
difference between doing an exchange is
very simple, all right?
If you're trying to convert ERGs to
SigmaUSD or SigmaUSD or SigmaRSV to ERGs,
back the other way, you can at any time go
to something like MewFinance, choose ERGs,
Choose SigmaUSD.
And we can convert it anytime. We'll have
some slippage, of course.
We'll have a price impact because this is
an actual pool that people have created
and created liquidity for it.
So we're limited by the depth of the
liquidity. We're limited by the trades
that are going on in it right then as
well.
So you'll notice that the DEX price of
SigmaUSD slash ERG, that conversion rate,
will sometimes lag behind and be different
than the actual price of what ERG is.
So there's arbitrage opportunities
between here if you have SigmaUSD or you
have ERG because you can slide into one
and slide in the other.
If the DEX gets too far up ahead of what
the bank is, you can bring it back down.
If it gets too far below, you can buy it
back up.
Exactly like that.
Super, super easy beginner method of
arbitrage you can start with the SigmaUSD
bank versus the DEX to level those out.
OK, that being said, that's the DEX side
of things. We also have, back to these two
dashboards, we have a difference between
these two actual processes as well.
TokenJ, I'm not sure which one was around
first. Actually, I think it was SigmaUSD.
Right here, the SigmaUSD.io, perhaps.
Somebody can correct me if I'm wrong.
This uses proxy contracts. That means
your funds are sent into a proxy contract
first, and then it is pushed against the
bank itself, the bank contract, and you
are given your tokens.
If something happens, there is a refund
button that you can do.
So let's say we go to a stable coin. We
choose to go from ERG to SigmaUSD or
SigmaUSD to ERG.
Or we want to do the reserve coin, ERG to
SigmaRSV, SigmaRSV to ERG.
We purchase, we redeem.
goes into the proxy if the price of ERG
hasn't changed your funds will be in that
proxy and then you can refund them if it
hasn't gone through otherwise you'll get
your conversion tokenj on the other hand
does it a little differently
they directly go right to the bank.
So there's no delay, there's no extra
slippage or anything like that.
If your bid matches it, then it's going
to execute. If it doesn't, then it doesn't
and you get it back automatically,
essentially.
So that's kind of the difference between
these two products right here.
They both interact directly with the
contract, the SigmaUSD contract.
Now you may say, we can see reserve ratio
at 374%. What does that mean?
If we go over to here from the Ergo
platform website, we can see a cute little
infographic about when you can purchase or
redeem.
So if it's below 400%, we can only redeem
the USD or we can only purchase SigmaRSV.
If it's above 800%, we can only redeem
SigmaRSV. We can purchase and redeem both
SigmaUSD.
So that is like the logic built in to the
process of the protocol that keeps that
thing pegged where it's supposed to be.
If you want to get deeper on this part
and go into more arbitrage opportunities
and potentially gain opportunities with
minting and unminting SigmaRSV, SigmaUSD,
please watch that video I spoke about
earlier.
Cafe does a fantastic job of explaining
it. It's tricky. It's tricky. I don't
touch this anymore.
But there's a lot of people who do. And
there's a lot of misconceptions about RSV
being a long or that kind of thing.
watch that video that'll hopefully
explain a lot.
So if we test this, right, a reserve
ratio below 400, we should not be able to
purchase SigmaUSD at anywhere, right?
So let's see if I want one. Let's see.
See, unable, if you can read this, you
can barely read this. Unable to mint more
than zero SigmaUSD based on the current
reserve status.
It won't let us if you want to redeem.
Sure enough, it lets us redeem and that
matches exactly what this chart says.
So both of these are codified to match
the contract and the contract won't. So
somebody tries to bypass these UIs and
interact with the bank directly.
Won't do it. Won't do it at all. It's all
based on the smart contract code.
I'll put that video below, but watch it.
I know this is asked a lot in chat
sometimes when people are struggling with
what this is.
Sometimes people click on version one of
SigmaUSD, which you don't want to use. You
want to use the main link from the
SigmaUSD page or tokenj of course.
And I know a lot of you people already
know this already, but I think it's good
to have out there once again, because it
is a question asked very often.
All right, we've got a very, very short
dev update this week. We're gonna try to
keep this under 15 minutes. I think we can
do it.
Let's see if I have any voice left.
We have Anand Bihar from the Nautilus
team. And they have released version 0.2.0
of Ergo Ledger JS, added device close app,
device open app, and device get current
app info, OS level methods, improved APDU
logging.
Nautilus, refactored ledger device
component, moving all generic and state
management logic into it, refactored
transaction sign component, refactored
confirm address dialogue component, added
several minor UI fixes and code quality
improvements.
This is good. I haven't been paying
attention to this in chats or what they
were saying, but I imagine this comes from
the latest ask to fix some things perhaps
review they were doing so that's great.
Awesome. It'll be nice to have both
ledger and keystone options again, so
people have choice. That's always best.
All right, we have C8 with ErgFi, Dexy
Gold integration, ETA a few weeks. I see
it's usually pretty good with the
deadlines. So yeah, I believe that.
He's done five to five lib level actions,
LP swap, ERG-Dexy Gold, bank freemint,
bank redeem, LP mint liquidity tokens, LP
redeem liquidity tokens, in-progress UI
integration, ErgoPay, other things
required for release, mempool server
integration.
Very nice.
We have kushti with sub-blocks, which
people love to pass around as the next big
thing, which I think it is. It's going to
be amazing.
We spoke briefly about changing or at
least coming up with some sort of
alternative to an ErgoHack, like a spring
or summer of code where essentially you
target a theme and you get people on
board, you give them much more time.
So for example, HQx mentioned, why don't
we do a spring of code or summer of code
that is focused on prepping dApps for
sub-blocks.
So by the time sub-blocks come out, if
you've done this spring of code and you've
rewarded people that are participating in
that and learning ErgoScript and learning
how to code, and also people that come and
knowing how to do front ends and work with
code anyway,
A lot of these dApps that we have in here
will already be set for sub-blocks when it
comes online.
So that's the idea of that kind of spring
of code versus an ErgoHack where you give
a theme and people do it and you reward
based on that.
I feel in kind of these code sessions
where it's extended, you target college
groups, you target other ecosystem
developers as well as our own.
Everybody comes together for kind of a
goal and they're rewarded based on the
stages. Might get a little more progress
with these kinds of things.
Okay, great. So sub-blocks work and DAG
representation of input and ordering
blocks and RAM after completing first API
methods, best input block, best input
chain with just one local miner chain
representation is okay for initial
testing, et cetera.
But for P2P network, DAG storage is
needed.
6.0.0 RC to released with support for
public testnet or voting and activation
voting should be started soon in the
testnet next 120 blocks epic epoch.
So yeah, so he gave me a couple of days
after that released, I popped it on the
testnet I'm running the testnet and change
the code and immediately popped up that
said, 120 blocks for epic.
So should be soon. Super cool. It's
running, I believe, as I said earlier, and
Unreal was testing some UI things for,
what was it? SigmaUSD.
So that's great that that's working.
Waiting for 6.0 fix PRs review.
But Paideia. Oh, nice. But Paideia. This
is Luivatra worked with CannonQ to debug
some issues in the create DAO process.
I tell you guys if you haven't used
Paideia. I mean, even if you just have
groups online of people that you work with
for fun, like D&D groups or record groups
or music groups or anything like that,
where there are decisions that need to be
made that are based around user consensus,
and you could potentially have funds
hooked to that too, it's the way to go.
It's worked amazingly well. We used the
hell out of it during the beta. For
Sigmanauts, the mining pool just jumped
over there as well, from the beta to the
final version that we're on as well for
the Sigmanauts.
It's an amazing tool. Hats off to
Luivatra, Marty, and the team that worked
on that. Fantastic.
We've got kushti with SigmaUSD pool.
Prepare data for mainnet pool update to
refresh update box and open possibility to
update the pool to V2 and next voting,
ChainCash, updating the paper.
We've got Voryu Jack with Minotaur.
Select addresses from the address book.
Allow to archive some wallets. These
wallets are not displayed in wallet select
page by default.
Favorite wallets are displayed in start
of wallets list. Great, great. Toggle
display archive wallet.
If you guys are interested in running
desktop versions of wallet, Ergo has too
many good choices. It's absolutely
fantastic.
You have Minotaur, you have Satergo, but
give them a try. I have many computers
that I use and I have Satergo on one.
I have Minotaur on another. I have
Minotaur Mobile on my, where is it? I love
showing this thing off.
Show it off every other AMA on my cold
wallet, which is just one of these little
palms.
When I bought it, it was like a hundred
and, I think I got it for 70 bucks. Now
it's a lot more where it was last time I
checked a little tiny guy running Android.
It's my cold wallet. Got Minotaur on it.
I push things to it via ADB cable as a
text file to sign things on the cold
wallet and push them back.
Super, super cool.
We've got an update from Rosen Bridge.
This is very exciting.
Rosen Bridge-RosenApp. Enhance the
logical structure of networks within their
specific packages to improve efficiency
and increase maintainability.
Implementing public event status or
services.
Rosen Bridge watcher version two. Write
observation-related queries and write unit
tests.
Write a job function and txpot and
callback of it.
Rosen Bridge Scanner added callback
support to extractors, added abstract
database entity in action to ease the new
extractors development.
Rosen Bridge Utils added callback logger
package to be used in log level health
parameter.
If any of you are being a watcher on the
Rosen Bridge, I had to do some sort of
database wipe on mine. I had to kill the
containers and redo it.
There's an issue with one of the packages
when you restart it. They're working on
fixing the instructions to include an
official repository to one of those
packages, because it's a third party
package.
I found one built into Docker that works.
I've been using it for three or four days
now. It works fine.
But there'll be an official announcement
that soon if they haven't already based on
this. So if you do find yourself in
trouble spinning up a watcher from scratch
right now, or rebuilding your container,
so then you're going to run into that
unless you do that fix.
Feel free to ping me or somebody in the
chats.
Oh, kushti is calling me out. I didn't
even answer that. Goodness, why we only
have 176 blocks a day in the testnet with
min difficulty. Any idea?
Probably because I'm only mining it at
like two megahash. Maybe I'll hit it with
a better card that's more consistent or
something like that.
Whoopsie. We'll answer him later. Sorry,
kushti.
Rosen Bridge continued. Rosen Bitcoin
ruins R&D. The research on integration
Bitcoin ruins with the Rosen Bridge is now
complete.
Over the past few weeks, we explored
various APIs and libraries to assess the
feasibility of this integration and how to
align the implementation with our overall
design detailed in a dedicated medium
post.
Despite encountering some concerns and
regarding rate limits associated with
certain APIs, we have decided to proceed
with the implementation phase.
As we develop the integration, we will
gather more accurate estimations, allowing
us to make informed decisions for
potential improvements along the way.
Currently, we are finalizing the
documentation and proof of concepts, and
we are looking forward to starting to
develop that development phase in the near
future.
This, I mean, this is awesome. Anytime
you can, not just in Bitcoin, but anytime
you can bring a store value over to
another chain like Ergo and get some
functionality of it, out of it, that's
more Cardano or to Ethereum or to where's
the next one, Binance, and get some more
utility or usage out of it.
It's a no brainer.
I think once people cross the bridge once
and they're like, oh, this is how it
works. I can see it all along the process.
I don't see a spot where it ever gets
lost or anything like that. I can see
exactly what's happening, if it's
processing, if it's in payment.
I think they get a little more
comfortable with it. So we just got to get
people out of that initial hump.
OK, kushti's talking about merging and
releasing some things.
Anything else?
They're updating an Ergo node interface
for us there.
Oh, Fanta created a new front end for
index nodes.
This stuff is exciting. OK, so right now,
we have the Ergo Explorer, the main one.
That's this one.
This is what I'm looking for. The main
Ergo Explorer right here.
This is not fun to set up.
It's not fun to set up at all. I created
a package for myself, and it's zipped up.
Essentially, you just put it onto the
server, update some DNS and nginx things
and you're good to go.
But it's not for the everyday person,
right? It's got some clunky overhead, and
it just keeps eating and eating and eating
space on your computer.
Well, I mean, so does a node, but not not
as much.
So you have things like erg explore,
which is an alternative, you have sigma
space as well, which is an alternative, a
fantastic, all fantastic, great, but
To be able to create a front end for an
index node, we all know how easy nodes are
to install, right?
With Satergo, it's like one click. Even
with a Java file, if you're not familiar,
you can barge your way through it, making
a config file and running the jar.
That's fantastic. But imagine just
running a UI just by a Docker container,
probably.
And all of a sudden you have a front end
that you can kind of understand and learn.
And it's yourself. It's hosted by
yourself. It's easy to set up.
These kind of things are like, this is
what makes a difference, right? For
usability for these kind of things. So
absolutely fantastic.
And let's see. Anything else?
I think that's it, folks.
There's some tech support chat in here.
Oh, Mark's looking for, this is a day or
two later, but he's looking for some Ergo
developers for building Sharknet. It's on
the Sigmanauts mining DAO.
If you're mining, if you have one GPU,
you want to point it, please, please
support it. Hop in there.
I think that's about it.
Yeah, we're several days ahead. They
definitely missed. Perfect.
All right, everybody. I hope you had a
good week. If you were in the United
States of America, you had your big Super
Bowl game a few hours ago.
I hope the team that you enjoy won or
you're not too sad that the other one
lost.
I watch some commercials. It's OK. The
game's somewhat all right. I didn't even
know the Super Bowl was happening until a
couple days ago.
That's how out of it I've been.
So we'll see you on Thursday for a video
AMA.
I've been thinking about putting together
a pool so that we could vote and bet on
who's going to show up to host the AMA.
So we'll give like five or six people and
what's it called?
And you send, you can send like a token,
a specific tokens to the wallet that's
worth some sort of value.
And whoever is right, that wallet, the
percentage of people that gave that you
gave,
You take all the other wallets and you
combine them and your percentage gets a
pull out of everything.
So essentially, if you win, you get from
all the other wallets that people voted on
a percentage that you donated to the
winning wallet.
So I think that'd be kind of fun,
something like that. Those are easier to
do with wallet voting and a transaction
builder.
Oh, almost forgot during the Town Hall
last week, I spoke about the Cornell BRICK
token.
That's doing great. We've distributed
maybe 30 or so interested wallets so far.
There's about 350, 400 architecture kids
ago. There's 800 students in total.
So slow burn, but that's fine. Once it
spreads, you can get free printing from
these initial tokens.
I think it's going to start slowly
catching more fire.
But we had several students use the
system already to actually redeem free
prints. So that was super exciting to see.
OK, everybody, thanks for bearing with my
chunky voice. This week, hopefully, after
my meds, next week will be a little
clearer.
Thanks, everybody, for watching. Have a
great night.