Let's see.
I've got you hear us, Andy?
QX, what did you do?
I didn't do anything. I don't have
control of this.
You're exactly, you're out of control,
man.
You're in. Andy, Andy, I've got YouTube
on, so I'm listening for free. Come back.
But Andy, you there?
There we go.
All right, you're good kushti we've got
volume now. All right. All right, so let's
repeat the introduction part otherwise say
it would be disconnected my part from
others.
I mean, let's try again. Let's try again.
Hello everybody. Good morning You can skip
you can skip that day and it was like a
five out of ten
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no,
Yeah, all right. Well, the sound is here
right now and... Hey, everybody! Welcome
once again to the AMA.
And so, yeah, I have... Well, you know,
now that we don't have contacts, I have to
my stage right, I have none other than
kushti. Say hi to everybody again, Alex.
Hi, everyone. It's my pleasure to be here
again.
Again for the second time today and to my
stage left I have a certain yahoo named
qx. Huge yahoo. Good morning everybody.
Yahoo, that's sometimes serious. So we'll
call them yahoo serious. Perfect.
Yeah, exactly. Anyway, all right. Well,
let's get started with the AMA. So as I
was saying before when nobody could hear
me except for Alex and our favorite Yahoo
QX.
Yeah, Alex, why don't you give the people
a little bit of a breakdown, a rundown of
what's been happening?
Yeah so a lot of things going on at the
same time on different levels. Well in the
first place there are a lot of talks in
the community now about positioning, you
know, the Ergo movement. So it's kind of
free movement so everyone is free to
position himself and his own group in any
way, but yeah well there is also need for
coordination.
Well, there are certain requests about
that, certain demand, especially these
days, you know, when, yeah, well, many
people have feeling that, well, it's
another pivot point for cryptocurrencies,
right, cryptocurrency movements because of
many events going on at the same time.
So yeah, please join discussions and I
believe we need to organize some more
calls like town halls as soon as possible.
So then, yeah, in regards to the
development, there is good progress with
sub-blocks. So I've got my own local
miner-based DevNet just today, well,
correctly generating input blocks,
sub-blocks with transactions and creating
proper commitments.
And then as a next step I'm thinking
about adding APIs for applications
immediately, so some early version may be
available in just a few days. And only
after that I will jump on actually hardest
and very time-consuming parts, but also
invisible to application developers such
as peer-to-peer network optimizations and
so on.
But, yeah, well, application developers
at least will have a possibility starting
from, yeah, very soon, TM, to play with
single nodes, local miner-based testing
environments, at least, to check how to
speed applications up with input blocks,
sub-blocks.
Then for 6.0 audit is going on. I think
there is one small issue left now. We are
discussing different issues and aspects of
design but currently there is one small
issue left unfixed and then we are good
with doing public testnet deployment and
also then it's a good time to reach mining
pools in regards with all possible
activation dates.
So yeah, a lot of things going on. Then
some talks going on. I'm actually pushing
for some talks and some decisions in
Ergodev's DAO.
So, well, the point is, I'm actually
thinking to rework the DAO and make PID
based DAO. Well, I tried yesterday,
actually, but then I got into tokenomics
questions, so we are discussing it right
now.
What I'm proposing is to have just
temporary DAOs or Ergodevs 2025, to have
very concrete specific goals for 2025 and
then also pretty specific funding goals to
be met to reach the goals and then yeah
also to help very specific concrete
initiatives, education initiatives and so
on and also help the ecosystem with
touring, education, getting new
developers.
There are some proposals about having
something like Google Summer of Codes,
right? But yeah, it's winter in the
Northern Hemisphere now, so maybe it would
be Ergo Winter of Codes. I don't know.
Let's see, maybe Spring. Then, what?
Spring of Codes actually sounds good.
The Ergo Winter over discontent.
The idea is to have just a temporary
organization and then fire it up totally
at the end of 2025 and start from scratch
next year. What's needed, I guess, is also
to help developers with different means to
find ways to fund applications internally
and externally.
So I think this is probably the most
important matter right now. So there are
different talks. It's hard to coordinate
and organize this stuff in a totally
uncontrollable environment. So, let's see.
kushti, how do you manage the treasury
with a temporary DAO? Where do you put the
treasury? Do you just make sure you
transfer it to the new DAO as it hops
over?
Yeah, so the idea, you know, is to send
remaining treasury if there will be
remaining ERG at the end of 2025 to the
new DAO, right? But, yeah, having totally
new members, maybe, even. Right, so the
idea is that, you know, every organization
should have some limited time frame, I
believe.
And, yeah, so if there is something
persistent, such as treasury, yeah, maybe
it's better just to pass to the new
organization, right? Yeah, then, well, it
should work, right? If there are not many
DAO members profiting from treasury, at
least, right?
We managed to pull it off of the
Sigmanauts DAO when we went from beta to
production. But it was tricky because we
used the same token. So people would
unstake from the beta DAO before we fully
had everything transferred over. And we
had to rely on the last few people that
were still on the beta DAO to finish up
the token send on the DAO. So that was a
fun little test of that kind of theory.
All right. And then, yeah, so I think
also for, and here's where Ergodevs can
synchronize with Sigmanauts. So there is
need to have some vision, right, like
common vision. Well, what do we imagine
when we are talking about future of the
ecosystem, right?
Because the protocol, well, it's more or
less done, right? So, well, if one is
taking a look into EAPs, right, then,
yeah, it's easy to realize that, yeah,
well, all the modifications come so that
they are soft-forkish right so well 6.0 is
just basically adding new functionality
and tweaking existing one just a little
bit by fixing just very few things.
And then input blocks are backwards
compatible, so all clients will just
receive full blocks like they are doing
now. It's basically the same protocol,
just augmented with some peer-to-peer
machinery and, yeah, well, enforced in a
soft-forkish way, so only miners would
recognize the difference, right, because,
well, miners do need to generate some new
fields, right, but, yeah, all clients can
just skip them and that's it.
And the idea, you know, is to avoid
modifying the protocol so basically at
this point Ergo is already like Bitcoin
back in 2012-14 right so quite established
protocol right maybe still experiencing
some developments like what happened with
Bitcoin SegWit Taproot right so SegWit
soft fork was actually quite hard soft
fork yeah well maybe we had even harder
with 5.0 where all the clients actually
were downloaded to SPV security for all
the transactions.
6.0 would be like SegWit in regards to
the activation exactly. Yeah, well, only
for new kinds of transactions while using
new opcodes while existing clients will be
downloaded to SPV security, right? Just
blindly trusting the new nodes for
validation, right? But yeah, only for new
kinds of transactions. So I like helping
it with SegWit, actually.
And they are probably Taproot also, but I
am not quite familiar with Taproot
activation details, to be honest. And then
input blocks are just about modifying
peer-to-peer level, adding some new
structures to block extension, a section
of a block right and so it would be even
more soft right and then yeah so the idea
basically is to have a protocol which is
not touched a lot right and then which can
be evolved by building on top of it right
so without application developers having
fear that's you know the core protocol
would break everything like many
blockchains around actually can change
block time even where you know well it's
possible to do contracts based on block
height which is quite insane because
basically that means that during such
changes all the applications relying on
block heights have been broken and so on
but yeah that's what's going on but I
think the proper way is to follow the
Bitcoin way in regards to updating the
protocol in order to have global neutral
money.
All the Bitcoin issues basically like
scalability, bad support for certain
constructions such as sidechains and
security budget issues, absence of tail
emission or demurrage. All those issues
are fixed here, right? Yeah, well, in the
long term, well, this protocol, the Ergo
protocol doesn't have issues, right, but
yeah, it's still global neutral kind of
money, ultra-fixed money, as our demurrage
wizard Luis is saying.
And then, yeah, well, also on top of this
global ultra-fixed money protocol, you can
build other sorts of money, right, like
having good money for everyone, so you're
going to have stable coins right then
tokenized real world assets well with
insurance in form of algorithmic assets
right so you can have tokenized physical
gold secured with algorithmic gold stable
coin based insurance then.
Then, yeah, well, there are tools to get
more assets from outside, from the real
world, right, in the first place, but then
also from other chains via different
cross-chaining applications, such as
Rosen, right? And then, yeah, well, with
that, there are also tools, there will be
tools to do monetary expansions, such as
ChainCash. And I believe there is need
maybe for other systems.
Well, for example, to have off-chain
peer-to-peer cash based on on-chain
reserves, right? Or maybe even on-chain
manifestation of trust, right? So we can
imagine maybe in future even trusted
issuers like Tether, right? Well, issuing
notes in ChainCash on top of Ergo along
with other entities which may have
reserves right so on-chain reserves not
trust blind trust that we basically have
in case of Tether and so on right so well
this is kind of global ultra fixed neutral
money but also platform for producing more
money via different forms of monetary
expansion, right? That's some thoughts
which I would like to share.
I still can't wrap my head around
off-chain exchange of these notes. How do
you imagine that happening?
Actually, I tried, well, I spent a few
weeks, basically, I lost a few weeks back
in 2023 trying to get one form of exchange
of ChainCash notes. But the protocol got
overly complicated, so at some point I
just gave up because there were a lot of
security issues on the way, and by
resolving them I've got even more complex
protocol with even more possible security
issues, maybe.
But recently what I realized by observing
some other attempts like ARK on Bitcoin so
you can have completely simplified
protocol if exchange of considering
totally trustless off-chain protocol you
may assume payment servers in case of ARK
off-chain payment solution for Bitcoin.
It's called ARK payment server. You may
have a federation instead, like maybe
Rosen watchers even, to track the state of
off-chain. You may use those guardians of
off-chain states in on-chain protocols and
then yeah then it should be hard so I
don't have concrete contracts yet because
I'm currently fixing some other issues in
ChainCash contracts when I have spare time
and I don't have it basically but yeah
after fixing those issues I think to do
another attempt and yeah it seems doable.
As well it seems doable to do kind of ARK
on top of Ergo and it would be simplified
in opposite to the Bitcoin version and
also in regards with Ergo so what I'm
looking at is that you know you may have
not just simple off-chain payments right
like I'm just sending a payment to you
just like some value rights, like 5 ERG
rights off-chain.
But there could be actually some
off-chain contracts also with this. Well,
some on-chain guarantees. Well, I believe
I made one tweet on that. Yeah, one tweet
probably or something like that. But yeah,
at some point I will consider that
carefully and write down details how could
that be possible. And then you may have
programmable off-chain cash backed by
on-chain reserve. So basically, realizing
the initial dream of Hal Finney, right?
Not Satoshi maybe, but maybe Satoshi, if
Hal Finney is a part of Satoshi's
identity. So yeah, the idea was that, you
know, if one ledger is not enough, maybe
it would be just settlement layer rights
for basically banks. And then those banks
may have some protocols on top of that.
And that was understood by many.
Yeah, you know, blockchain is Bitcoin, at
least, you know, would be just, you know,
a network between traditional financial
institutions, right? And then they will
run Lightning Network channels with their
respective clients, right, and so on. But
I think it should be done differently,
right? So we need to have kind of free
banking network here. So peer-to-peer
banking network where everyone may become
a bank.
And then, yeah, it should be covered by
collateral rights or trust. So it's what
we have to some degree, but yeah, it's now
totally not formalized, right? And done it
quite broken way. Like, most of the crypto
industry is just blindly trusting Tether,
right? While, you know, blaming it. So,
it's kind of, I don't know, bipolar state
of crypto when everyone is hating Tether
and using USDT at the same time.
I hate you, but I can't quit you.
That sounds like a love story. You're so
bad for me, but I can't quit you. I wish I
could quit you. What was that line from
that one movie that the QX told me to
watch? Yeah, I wish I knew how to quit
you. What is it?
What is that from? I don't know.
That's from Brokeback Mountain. It's a
meme.
Oh, it is. I wish I knew how to quit you.
Yep. Yep. Yep. Great movie, Dan.
kushti, speaking of P2P stuff, I saw some
really cool, I think it was Reddit
yesterday or the day before. Somebody was
asking people to check out their app that
they're developing, and they developed a
reputation-based peer-to-peer on-ramp. So
what it does is it connects people, it's
just an app that connects people that want
to buy Bitcoin in cash, it was for
Bitcoin, to buy Bitcoin in cash and a
meetup space as well as reputation. So I
can understand that it's not a good idea
probably to meet somebody with a wad full
of cash to buy Bitcoin in a dark place,
but I guess that's where he's trying to
be.
Isn't that the same with local Bitcoins
though? Is that what it is there is
something already like that bitcoins I
don't know I mean it's probably still
around but I remember back in what like
2016 or something like that oh I remember
local Bitcoin back in 2012 yeah so it was
I mean they were they were already around
but for a while by then but I remember
like 2015 2016 I used to use local
bitcoins.
Yeah, yeah. Was it reputation based?
Yeah, yeah. So it had a rating and yeah,
it was since, I don't know, 2011, 12. And
yeah, but basically it got shut down.
It's, I don't know, like by the government
around late 2010s. Well, I don't know. It
was a soft kind of shutdown. So, I had
talks with the CTO basically back in 2015.
And so back in 2015, so the hosting
provider, Hetzner, got phone calls from
banks informing that whether you are
switching local bitcoins off or we are
switching you from credit card processing.
Yikes. But finally, they shut down
themselves after some European regulation
came into power, I believe. But yeah, they
had few steps, I mean, becoming more and
more shitty on the way, trying to be
compliant, more and more compliant. And
then, yeah, so they had some follow-ups
such as Hoddle Hoddle which is also quite
interesting because you're also using some
escrow contracts like multi-signature
based escrows and so on.
And yeah, it's a bit popular in certain
places as far as I know, but yeah, it's
nothing near local bitcoins. Yeah, what
was good about LocalBitcoins? So back
then, liquidity on exchanges was quite
crappy, right? Even on biggest ones like
MtGox, BTC back in 2013, for example. So,
it was hard to on-ramp, right?
Yeah, yeah. Back then, it was super hard.
I mean, because LocalBitcoins was actually
out here in Japan. You know, as well,
there was a, you know, you could find some
people doing local Bitcoins, but yeah, it
was, like, a lot of times it would price
gouge because it was so difficult to
on-ramp money for Bitcoin back then. Yeah,
I mean, you know, even now with hodl hodl,
they still try to, still try to bullshit
you about that.
So like once in a while you actually find
somebody who just wants to trade, you
know, he wants to like, okay, I got some,
whatever, I'll buy some crypto from you or
I'll sell you some crypto or something
like that. And they'll just basically do
it at whatever the rate is. But then
there's the people that do it for a
living. And I get paying a somewhat of a
premium, but some of these guys want like
10%.
And then they give you some bullshit
about it. I was like, oh, well, you know,
a cash, it's something really stupid, like
cash is difficult to come by right now for
Bitcoin. I'm like, no, it's not. What are
you talking about? No, it's not. It's not
difficult at all.
Yeah, so it's like HODL HODL is actually
pretty OK. But it's still like there's not
like sometimes you'll find somebody to
trade with right away and you'll find
somebody good. But many times like a
limited amount of times you'll find
somebody really good. Most of the times
you'll find somebody who does it for a
living and they'll want to get at least
five to ten percent commission from you. I
mean, I think that's okay.
There's a premium to pay for it on KYC
nowadays I think there's a market for that
10% really.
Oh, yeah, I hear you. They turn right
around and sell it at an exchange. I mean
10%. Yeah. And no, it's like, I remember a
few, I mean, I like, okay, I'd pay a few
percent, but not 10%. And 10% is
obnoxious. Especially if you're trading, I
mean, it's like, okay, you're trading like
some small amount or something. Still not
okay, but you know, it's doable. But if
you're asking somebody to, you know, to do
10% on like a $10,000 purchase, that's a
thousand bucks. I'm not gonna pay a
thousand bucks for that. For what? For
having some money on hand? I mean, and
it's not even that much money, so. Anyway.
I mean, we could do something like,
kushti, we could do something like this on
Ergo with once messaging is in place, you
could build a dApp that's self-hosted so
nobody can shut it down with, you know, a
special format of putting those
peer-to-peer on-ramps on-chain in a
messaging block and just do it that way.
You could build that on-chain.
Yeah, well, it was proposed by HQx to
use, unsurprisingly, MewFinance, so they
have some escrow contracts. And so, yeah,
I'm actually willing to try them. I don't
know. I need to check escrow contracts and
we need to think actually how to use. So,
yeah, I believe a lot of tooling is
already there, right, on Ergo. It's just
time to actually use it and find different
use cases for tooling available.
All right, and yeah, checking the charts.
Yeah, that is a good reminder from
CannonQ. So more than 27,000 ERG in
bounties are available for developers to
earn and move projects and ecosystem
forward.
There is link in the chat. I've posted
the link also just like one hour ago or
like that in the main group and yeah some
other groups and yeah it's also posting
Ergo developers and so on so yeah
developers we have more than 27,000 ERG in
bounties in different projects and yeah in
different form also so it's not just ERG
so there are bounties in the ChainCash
repository denominated in Gluon.
There are some bounties in Rosen
repositories, denominated in RSN,
unsurprisingly. Then there are GORT, Gluon
Oracle reward token denominated bounties.
I believe still there are some in Oracle
repository and maybe some other repos.
There are some issues in Ergo repository,
so protocol client, reference protocol
client repository, denominated in Gluon
also so Gluon-based gold stablecoin and so
on so yeah a lot of things going on so
then when can we pay bounties to
developers in lithium that would be funny
it's the gold of 21st century right?
Would be happy, actually. Yeah, for the
lithium-backed stablecoin. Yeah, that's
actually in development right now. Yeah,
after we have the initial... We're
actually talking to the same tokenomics
team that did our tokenomics zero one X.
And they're the ones that also did the
tokenomics for world mobile. So it's a
really good, it's a really good tokenomics
firm. There are partners.
And so we're going to, you know, I guess,
and also we'll plug you in and we'll talk
about initial kind of initial groundwork
for this because like they have, they have
a token right now on either ether polygon.
I can't remember exactly, but I think it
was polygon. But we were thinking about
bringing it over, but we might just have
to do a swap for the holders over there
because we probably just need to build it
from scratch to make sure that it does
what it's supposed to do.
But we'll see. Yeah, but very soon we'll
be able to do that. Very soon.
Right nice because yeah I think tokenized
commodities as well as cross-chain assets
is what's needed right for producing
different and good kinds of money on top
of Ergo. And also to build the different
DeFi and so on.
That's the thing. Legacy financial
markets aren't just built on the stock
market and the bond market, but they're
also built on commodity market by a huge,
huge part. Price of gold, price of silver,
price of copper, all this stuff as a big
influence on other prices, price of oil,
and just economy in general.
So if we are going to be kind of the
antithesis of that market by doing it in a
decentralized way, we still need to
maintain some of the same basic principles
of just how markets work. You know, like
money needs to be backed by something at
some point. And I mean, you know, and say
in some cases it is hashrate, you know,
some cases it is computing power. So
that's also a commodity, you know, of its
own. But that comes from a commodity
called, you know, electric power or
energy.
Yeah, exactly. So it's energy-based
money, basically.
Yeah, exactly. So it's still a commodity,
so even with mining Ergo, you're literally
still in a commodity-based financial
system. But it's just a different. Yeah,
but we just need to have other ones as
well. We need to have lithium, we need to
have gold, we need to have other metals
and commodities that are essentials. Yeah,
absolutely needed.
Yeah, and then, you know, so the point is
then, yeah, other forms of money such as
stable coins like the USDT and so on, so
that they should be... I mean, commodities
are really irreplaceable in many ways.
Just the same with, you know, with gold.
I mean, why is gold still so popular? I
mean, obviously, you know, it's not used
for making coins anymore as much, but it's
still a hot commodity. And that's kind of
the, you know, the nature of a truly base
commodity like that because even now that
OK, we might back something with it. Why
do we back something with it? Because it
still has. Obviously, internationally, the
world agreed on value. That's number one.
Number two, it still has high utility.
Even if you're not making coins from it,
like, say, back several hundred years ago,
you had gold coins people were paying
with. Now, you use it in electronics just
as much. In fact, right now, I would say
gold is more of an industrial metal than
than a jewelry precious metal. Again, I
don't know the statistics for that, but it
seems like the utility of gold in
electronics probably outweighs the utility
of gold in jewelry and just in its raw
form for monetary, for hedging value.
That's it. 500 years ago, who would have
known that gold would be supporting
electronic circuitry? And the same
circuitry that's actually being used to
mine Ergo right now. You need gold for
that. I mean, it's one of its unique
properties that it doesn't oxidize. So,
yeah, so that's yeah, it's it's like that.
And it's like that across the board. And I
think if we want to have a really a
thriving system, we need to adopt that. We
are adopting it as an ecosystem and Ergo,
you know, we have Gluon.
We're talking about algorithmic
commodities, which are actually really
interesting as well to explore. We might
even see later down the line to do a fully
algorithmic lithium-backed stablecoin
after we establish the Oracle network for
what we're doing. So yeah, quite a lot of
possibilities.
Yeah. And actually, I had a talk with
Anon Real recently. So he made the
pronouncement on Twitter already. So he's
working on index funds. So then you may
have for lithium, which is like 20%
algorithmic and 80% physical, or whatever,
50-50. So that's also quite interesting.
A lot of interesting stuff going on.
Yeah, we should see something really soon.
So I think the community is going to be
really happy once we have some news coming
out. But anyway, guys, listen,
unfortunately, I have to drop off right
now.
What about questions?
Well, I mean...
Ducking the questions. Classic Dan.
You guys can do the questions. Well, get
QX to do something. He hasn't been really
doing much.
All right, so we have 15 minutes for
questions, actually.
Yeah, yeah, guys. Guys, stay on. QX is
going to answer all your questions. Alex,
you're in charge.
Yeah, so then I will message you after,
but maybe tomorrow because it's late,
right? On your side, sir.
Yeah, yeah. Well, we still have a space
in about an hour. So yeah, it's okay. It's
okay. But anyway.
All right. So yeah, let's discuss.
Thank you guys. Yeah, thank you.
Bye, Dan.
Bye, QX.
So, oh, that's, there we go. Andy's got
to fix our pictures. Let me sit up so
people can see us. There we go. Well, I'll
talk while he's fixing this. So hey,
kushti, I introduced, yesterday was
Wednesday, right, Tuesday, I introduced
Cornell BRICK to, goodness, maybe 300, 400
students, the entire architecture classes,
and then some of our remote students in
New York City.
It was an interesting response. The
initial response, I think I saw some eye
rolls when I discussed that we were
integrating blockchain tech into our
stuff. And then I went on to explain a
little more about a system of trade value
between peer-to-peer people and a LETS
system, what we're trying to do. And then
their eyes lit up when they realized they
could use these tokens for credits for
free plotting, for free large format
printing initially. So that got their
attention. So right now, the system's all
set up.
I have the Tipperbot set up. I have my
front end and back end of the plot
submission stuff all set up to take the
Ergo payments for BRICK and so that's
ready to go and tested we just have to
work on a little bit of a tutorial to show
kids how to we've written text but these
guys like are visual so just need to make
a quick video on how to request or get a
tipper bot wallet and then we'll either
probably just tip out manually for now or
once that happens perhaps do an airdrop if
we can get kids to get their own address
and actually know what they're doing
that's.
I think they'll be better off with Tipper
Bot in the long run, but we'll see. So
that's pretty cool coming up. The funny
thing is, kushti, in the small group that
I was discussing this with, one of the
kids raised their hand and was like, can
we collect this and sell this? And I was
like, well, it's permissionless, because
you can do whatever the hell you want. But
if I find this token on a DEX and it has
some system of monetary value on it, that
may have some more tax implications that
I'm willing to deal with.
So I may just nuke the coin by reissuing
another one and airdropping it to
everybody that holds the old one. So we'll
see what happens. Hopefully it doesn't end
up on a DEX anywhere with a value attached
to it.
Yeah, but you know, so what's good about,
you know, that's a permissionless finance,
you know, I mean, like, like totally
permissionless. So, it's easy, you know,
to try to find market value, right, if
any. And then, yeah, we may expect people
to try to find market value. Then, yeah, I
mean, you can try to sell anything. The
question is who will buy it, right?
All right. So, yeah, let's jump on
questions. What do we have?
Oh, a lot of messages, but there are
other questions. Hi, just two basic
questions, please. What is the basic
difference between Ergo simple send
transaction process? And why smart
contracts are possible on Ergo and not on
Bitcoin. I mean difference between Ergo
and Bitcoin. So yeah, I see only one
question here, right? So difference
between Ergo and Bitcoin actually.
Well, the first, I guess the first one's
he's asking if there's a difference
between send and receive transactions,
which there's not there. You just making
new boxes all the time between send and
receive. It's all about destroying boxes
and creating new boxes with permissions
for certain keys to access those boxes or
ownership of those boxes. That's all send
and receive is with UTXO, so that's easy.
Sorry, kushti, go ahead and answer the
second part.
Yeah, so basically a transaction is
about, well, destroying old programmable
digital monitoring notes, right, and
creating new ones, right, so there is no
send and receive, right, if we are taking
it on this low level. And then, yeah,
difference between Ergo and Bitcoin and
contracts. So in the first place, Bitcoin
is allowing for contracts, actually,
right, there were lots of proposals for
Bitcoin and theoretically there are a lot
of contracts on Bitcoin utilizing
different techniques actually.
Yeah, in the first place, what's good?
So, everything possible on Bitcoin is also
possible on Ergo, right? So no exceptions
found to the moment. So multi signatures,
what else? Discrete lock contracts. Then,
yeah, adapter signature based how's it
called? Atomic swaps, yeah. And then,
yeah, simple hash-based atomic swaps.
Yeah, so everything is possible on Ergo
and Bitcoin, right? But, well...
Lightning Network channels, other layer 2
solutions, so they are possible. But Ergo
is allowing for a lot more because more
blockchain context is available during
transaction validation. There are certain
proposals for Bitcoin to be closer to Ergo
rights as such as exposing spending
transaction to spending script of
transaction input but yet still not there.
Then yeah, so simply a richer context and
then more opcodes and also, more
sophisticated cryptography, right, if
you're talking about Sigma protocols. So
you can easily do things which are hardly
doable or nearly impossible on Bitcoin so
for example there is Ergo Mixer right
which is non-interactive non-custodial
mixer and for Bitcoin there was a proposal
using a bit similar cryptography actually
yeah quite similar called CoinJoin but
yeah it was interactive in the first place
so there was need for some peer-to-peer
based bulletin board, right, for mixer
related messages.
And then, yeah, it also was quite hard to
implement, so there was some startup, but,
well, no delivery still. And, yeah, six
years actually passed since the original
CoinJoin proposal. So, Ergo Mixer
proposal, the protocol appeared around the
same time actually so 2018 right it was
when I came to the idea developing. So
Alex had some thoughts, but his initial
construction was based on non-existing
cryptographic primitive.
So I made a practical solution, then sent
it to Professor Rezin. And yes, some
modifications and then one of them was
implemented back in 2020, right? So just
months basically after the main net
launch. And yes, for Bitcoin CoinJoin
still there is no implementation. Yeah,
probably would never be. So, yeah, that's
the difference. So, in short, contracts, a
lot of contracts also possible in Bitcoin,
but in practice, we see only
multi-signatures and multi-signatures also
different on Ergo, more feature-rich.
And, yeah, Lightning Network, which is
not so popular for Bitcoin even still, I
guess. And so, yeah, it's not implemented
by anyone on top of Ergo. Still.
Well, I think just from an outside
perspective, not outside, but a general
easy perspective to point to, right? And
part of what you said, right, is that Ergo
uses the eUTXO set, extended UTXO, as
opposed to Bitcoin, just UTXO. So as you
said in your dialogue there, that Ergo has
a much more opportunity for more
feature-rich contracts built into that
with that extended UTXO set.
Making really cool things like escrow
contracts like you said the mixer like
what MewFinance is doing with our LP
fundraising all those kind of things it
makes for a very robust library of smart
contracts you can create compared to your
limitations on Bitcoin, so I think the
easy thing to think of is Ergo is kind of
like Bitcoin on steroids or Bitcoin 4.0 or
5.0. I don't want to say 2.0 because I
think it's more than 2.0, kushti.
Around the main net launch so Cardano
presented it as Bitcoin 1.0 because you
know the Bitcoin is still about 0.20. His
idea was that it's kind of like finished
Bitcoin, so Bitcoin 1.0, which may be seen
in decades if we are talking about the
grandfather. So, yeah, they're just
starting to discuss, possibility of
demurrage, tail emissions, and, yeah,
maybe they will spend, like, five to seven
years in another civil war on that.
Let's see. I mean, there's that advantage
about Ergo, how fast things can pivot.
Yeah, Ergo was made kind of complete,
right, like Bitcoin 1.0 since day one. And
yeah, happily, it was flexible enough to
allow for non-breaking protocol updates.
But yeah, actually Bitcoin is also quite
good at that. Well, what the developers
did, like SegWit and Taproot, so yeah,
they are pure acts of art of software
capability, let's say.
All right, more questions?
Let's see, we've got one. Oh, somebody's
asking about quantum processors again. I
know you spoke about this before, but
yeah.
So, nothing changed since the AMA. So,
but, but yeah, it seems dust settled,
right? So crypto is still standing. Yeah,
working and people now seem not worrying
so much, right? But yeah, there is need to
consider something.
We got somebody, Luke's asking about the
same comparison between Ethereum smart
contracts and Ergo smart contracts. Do you
have the bandwidth to talk about that,
kushti?
Yeah, but if we are talking about
Ethereum, so Ethereum is actually totally
different, right? So Bitcoin is following
a programmable money paradigm of Bitcoin,
and Ethereum is actually quite a different
beast. So yeah, it's how they call it, a
decentralized world computer. But yeah,
it's more like a replicated programmable
calculator, right? So very limited, kind
of computational device. Everyone in the
world has access to.
And so, yeah, they tried to sell
initially I know like yet decentralized
computer for all kinds of applications on
the blockchain so that that was the time
especially back in 2016-17 when yeah the
space finally got full with, you know,
enterprise evangelists, talking the same
mantra, basically, not Bitcoin, but
blockchain. And the idea was that, you
don't need for those, you know, risky
uncontrollable peer to peer money.
So while you, yeah, that's control.
Decentralized applications like
decentralized Uber, I don't know why you
need for decentralized Uber, I mean who
needs for decentralized Uber? Who actually
may care even? I mean who cares? I mean if
taxi is coming from centralized server or
decentralized and also how do you measure
this decentralization? So if that's, I
don't know, decentralized Uber is
controlled by a few whales, right, and
decentralized Uber, how is it different
from board of directors, right, and
centralized and so on.
But yeah, I mean, it's still alive, I
believe, but now in even worse form. So
Web3, right, so when, you know, I mean,
people are talking about Web3 projects, so
I think it's like grandsons of that
initial wave of absurd. But yeah, it's now
like complete absurd, so usually when you
listen about Web3 project, you may be
sure, I mean, it's pretty meaningless.
All right, and so, going back to
Ethereum, so, with time, all the
applications on Ethereum, after all, are
financial, right? And then the question is
why to build general purpose world
computer, right, which is still working on
financial applications on the right. And
so that actually was the Ergo value
proposition. That was our statement,
better to say, back in 2016-17, even,
right?
So it's a counteraction to all that's not
Bitcoin, but blockchain absurd. So, I say
it pretty clearly back then that, you
know, blockchain is totally inefficient
database, right? And, there is very little
hope it would