You'll notice the format's a little
different today.
We were hoping to do more of a community
structure.
Anybody can join the Zoom.
If you look in the lower right-hand
corner over there of the stream, you'll
notice a Zoom info.
So if you want to chat in person, you
want to come up and join the community and
give your point of view, ask questions in
person, that kind of stuff, then just join
that Zoom info in there.
Come in with your camera off.
As you can see, HQ and kushti's camera
are off.
Feel free to ask voice questions.
It doesn't matter.
Hop in.
So today we've got a couple community
members.
We've got Grayman, who's a Sigmanauts.
We've got Mark the Shark, who is at the
Mining Disrupt in Florida, sent by the
Sigmanauts.
For those of you who don't know, Mining
Disrupt is a big kind of ASICS mining
conference.
And Mark is going there punching GPUs
into everybody as he walks.
And then we've got HQ3rr, which is the
main core dev of MewFinance.
And then, of course, we've got kushti in
the upper left-hand corner.
So feel free to join and ask questions,
or pop them in the chat, or whatever you
like, or just shout them into a dark
closet or something.
I'm sure we'll hear them.
Why don't we start with Mark?
Mark, tell us about Disrupt.
What you found?
How are the people?
Any tips or ideas you have for the
Sigmanauts Mining Pool or anything like
that?
Yeah, I mean, obviously, so mining
disrupt it's a huge Bitcoin mining
conference.
So, you know, everything and anything
Bitcoin, I talked to some people, okay,
I'm here with Ergo, you know, GPU mining
chain, they're like, Ergo, didn't that go
to like, six, like years ago, it's like,
no, you know, some people kind of snobby
towards me, I asked him like some
questions about their pool, they're like,
you know, acting as it's like, Hey man,
I'm just trying to pick your brain here.
It's like, you don't have to be like, you
know, any type of way.
It's kind of funny.
But some other people have been very
nice, you know, so I was asking, you know,
what's their pay pullout strategy.
So a lot of people are using full pay per
share.
So regardless of we find a block, people
get paid upfront.
So that's what a lot of miners in the
Bitcoin space, specifically the pools are
doing.
There's another pool.
It's very similar to Lithos it seems but
they're more of a decentralized pool.
I think it's called Ocean and basically
allows their - and I'm not really sure I
guess how it maybe works on Bitcoin, but
the guy was suggesting the pool makes the
blocks on.
And so instead of the miners, well, the
miners make the that allows them to put
their name in the coinbase.
And so now they can install you know, the
name on the.
I lose you guys.
No, we're still here.
We heard most of it.
So you're saying the mining pools will
just pay out regardless?
Are they taking a hit there?
Like, what if they don't find a block for
days?
They're going to have to pull from the
bank?
I guess it all evens out in the end kind
of thing?
Or miners mining to a pool with
guaranteed payout, accepting less of a
payout so more profit goes to the pool
kind of thing?
Yeah, I think there's probably, I didn't
get to ask the fee.
I think the fee is probably a little bit
higher.
But it reminds me of the idea that qx()
had that he wanted to implement area
rather he did, but it's sort of like a
call option for the miners, right?
So if you want to take your money now,
it's like, well, we can still do PPLNS,
but if you want to do say pay per share,
you know, you have the ability to do that
with qx()'s sort of tool.
But I think technically the mining pools
would be taking a hit.
But it's really so the miners get paid
all the time.
And we had one miner was like, hey, how
come I haven't got paid yet?
And it's like, well, we're PPLNS.
So you don't get paid until we find a
block.
And he was kind of like disgruntled about
it a little bit maybe.
So something we should take a look at, I
guess, DX pool, I talked to the pool
operator there.
Pretty much same story relative to the
payout scheme.
And he said, you know, hey, I reached
out, I told the people to check out the
Sigmanauts mining pool and the reason why
there he said there's kind of like no
incentive there and so maybe there's not
enough information like what we're doing
with demurrage what we're doing with the
bonus tokens and then he even was
suggesting like well how can I tell how
can I trust that it's like reliable you
know if I put it there it's not going to
be you know my mining rigs are always
going to be up you know and we have a
pretty good up time we do I would say yeah
so no really concern there but I was
looking at other people's dashboards that
they have like on the screen and stuff and
you know, that's really like the first
thing that people see for our pool is like
our dashboards and our websites and stuff.
So I'm making it a point now to make it
think definitely is it needs it'll be a
lot quicker and faster.
And so I made a prototype yesterday.
I did it like a live stream.
I'm not sure how many people were
watching but it was fun I think like 50
people I saw this morning.
Yeah, nice.
And then there's another pool.
It's called Brains pool and they're
essentially made sort of this like Bitcoin
OS and I didn't really understand it,
whether it's like actually the miner
running where it's like that's what mines
it, or if it's more of like a Hive OS, it
seemed like it was like sort of both in
some sense.
But in any case, I was like, well, what
are your guys' monetization strategies?
He's like, well, it's the pool fee and
then this OS.
So you get like two and a half percent
from this OS.
And then, of course, the pool's fee.
And that pretty much pays for everything.
And they have they had like like five
people at their booth.
So I was like, OK, interesting.
So from the Sigmanauts perspective for
the mining pool, I know we can maybe take
a look at making some sort of system like
that, but I'm not really sure where to
start.
But just trying to think of different
monetization strategies, right?
Different marketing strategies sort of.
But I think I definitely got a lot of
feedback as to where we are in our
ecosystem relative to our pool and the
hash rate and then maybe how we can sort
of grab more hash rate.
You know, so from a security perspective
within the pool, you know, marketability
and then just reliability, I think.
My question is, how do we make them as
exciting as the Cardano people are bound
to their stake pool operators, right?
They'd wear shirts with their stake pool
operators face on it, for God's sake.
Why can't that be the same with mining
pools, right?
Allegiance, but I imagine it comes down
to miners are geeks. Well that too plus
but I think there's a lot more hopping
going on and mining than there is. Then
there is in the stake pool operation
outfit right because you may have miners
may hop from one coin to the next to the
next to the next whatever is profitable
and pay for their rigs and so there might
not be that kind of specific attachment to
those pools or those coins in that aspect.
Oh, we don't see that in our pool,
though. You know, we have a consistent
hundred gigs.
We did have 150 gigs like a week ago for
like a day. Somebody popped in with 50, 40
to 50 gigahash.
So that was really sick.
I'm not sure where they went but you know
and then even in the website, maybe we
need to have like a little like hey what
kind of feedback would you like to see and
then that's of space so we can be like hey
I like this or you know, some space, you
know, aside from Telegram for people to
reach out to, just less friction, I guess.
I think you were challenged last week,
Mark, to open up a Signal link, right?
What's that signal?
Yeah.
You can be right there with Donald Trump
and the secretary of defense.
Oh my gosh.
Yeah.
Our war plans will get leaked from the
Sigmanauts mining pool.
Yeah.
Oh boy, but you found a connector, right?
So anybody who has time can work with us
to make that connection happen if you want
to as well.
Or one of us will do it in our free time.
But yeah, super cool.
Did you say you met up with the DX pool?
What's his, did you mention demurrage at
all?
Yeah, I did.
Yeah, he actually is not really sure what
it is.
He actually requested some information
and materials about it.
So I was like, okay, yeah, I'll totally
like when I get a moment, I'll send some
of that information over.
But of course, we don't want. Selfishly
speaking, we don't want DX pool to have
demurrage because then it's like, well,
you guys are going to find all of our
blocks, all of our blocks of demurrage,
you know.
But I mean, I don't like that we're in
kind of, what's it called, what's the
word, purgatory right now with demurrage,
right?
Demurrage was made so that, well in mind,
it was thought of so that there'd be a
nice jump from when it was turned on to
actually pools utilizing it, right?
So now we're in a spot right now where
not just pools are utilizing it, but we'll
see a rogue person come on and just snipe
blocks from demurrage as well.
So non-miners are actually getting it.
So I feel that's a shame that non-miners
are losing some of that stuff.
So it'd be nice if more pools engaged so
that that wouldn't be possible and the
miners who originally intended to get that
are scooping up that demurrage.
Yeah, absolutely.
But it's only for a few blocks, I've
noticed.
Yeah, here and there.
Yeah.
It's like, I skipped a week and I came
back to the wallet and we had like 170
ERG, you know, over two weeks of
collection.
Yeah.
That is nice.
So I mean, that's incentive right there,
you know, get extra ERG or mining tool,
you know.
And it's not that difficult to run.
It's a modified node.
It's a modified, you don't even have to
modify mining core.
I think that runs on its own.
And then you put a config into mining
core or something.
And then you run a little storage rent
app.
And that's it.
It just does its thing.
Tell what wallet for it to collect to and
watch that wallet and see the stuff come
in.
Yeah, that's really a no brainer.
Oh, HQ is going to talk.
Let's hear HQ.
Go for it.
HQ, what's up with you?
How's MewFinance doing?
MewFinance is doing great.
I just wanted to share some idea which I
just got about ready to mining.
So as we know that we can see how many
blocks were mined by all the pools.
So how about we create a simple tool
where people can compare in dollar value
of how much they are getting for mining
and that's how we can show them.
We can show them that the extra bonus
they get, they are getting more profit on
mining with Sigmanauts pools.
Right, but actually the only thing we
don't know is how many people are mining
to that pool, right?
So we can't do that individual division,
unfortunately.
So we know that X amount of people are
mining to our pool, but we have no idea
how many people are mining to DX pool.
So while we would know the totals coming
in, we wouldn't be able to divide that by
a number to say, OK, the individual person
gets this much in this person's.
This pool's 1% higher.
This pool's 2% higher in payouts with the
bonus tokens of the thing.
But that's a good divide.
You can just divide the hash rate, and
that's it.
Oh, divide it by the gigahash.
So saying for each gigahash, it gets
this.
Oh, great idea, guys.
Fantastic.
Yeah, totally.
That's where the individual miners might
help you if you were trying to make this
into more of a social thing. One of the
problems is that you know who knows like
what was the blockchain that told
Herominers that if they didn't get some of
their people off line. I mean, are there
800 people mining there? And then all of a
sudden, like two or three are the vast
majority of the hash rate. So it doesn't
matter if 700 of the 800 people leave. I
mean, that's the problem with mining. It
goes with being permissionless and
pseudonymous.
Well, I understand that in other chains,
right?
Miners might not care and point their
rigs to wherever the profit is, which is
fine.
But on Ergo, at least miners need to
understand that they have a lot more
control over the network.
So it's in their best interest not to
saturate hash on one pool in those
instances.
So, I mean, that's a hope in the future,
right?
But I think we're in a long, not a long,
but I think we're a ways away from that,
where miners are going to start
recognizing that they can make those
parameter changes.
But HQ, I love that idea.
That's great.
That shouldn't be too hard to do either.
Yeah, for sure.
We could say, hey, our block reward is
like, I mean, what is it right now?
I think is it 15 or is it 18 right now?
I think we're about to hit 15, I think,
right?
Okay.
So yeah, we could be like, it's 18 plus
three, you know, or whatever on average
for the demurrage for the week, you know,
for our block rewards or, you know, bonus
tokens, that kind of thing.
Yeah.
Right.
Actually, I was, I was not doing it like,
like a future.
So we can do like a past in past 30 days
to have mined with one GB on Sigmanauts
pool, you could have made this much.
Yep.
And you have, you have made this much on
another pool.
So you will be showing the profit you
have made.
You could have made.
So people like to see those kind of
numbers.
So yeah, so we already have the price
feed for all the tokens we have in the as
supported tokens.
We did with the extra tokens we do.
So yeah, you just have to do the sum up
of all the plus all the all the tokens and
just show the dollar value of it.
You don't even need to show the value
because nowadays I think miners don't even
care about how many they're getting.
They will only care about how many
dollars they are getting.
So if you are showing them that you are
getting more revenue for mining with us,
then you will have more incentivization
for people to move to the pool.
Awesome.
You think you're going to have that built
tomorrow morning, HQ?
You've got enough time.
It's not too late for you over there.
Just a reminder, I'm a father now.
We're all fathers here.
Yeah, right.
But my kid is three months old, so not
like yours.
Ergo dad NFTs. That's no big deal. Wait
till they can crawl or walk. Yeah, you're
in for it then. Tell you that that's where
I'm in right now, dude. My little one. Oh
my gosh. She's all over the place dude
running around. Dad dad pick me up.
Nice. Very nice.
All right, let's hear about let's hear
about 6.0 from kushti kushti are there. We
put him to sleep.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I'm here.
Sorry.
Mic was off.
So, yeah.
Finally, it's time to activate it in the
mainnet.
So still, there are some things to check,
some things to consider, like mainnet
activation parameters, and we'll also use
a client suitable for the mainnet and do
some final audit.
And so on, but yeah, well, I think we can
think about proposing a voting starting
from early May, something like that.
So yeah, and with 6.0 done, we can
actually promote, well, different things
which are possible now with 6.0 such as
trustless Bitcoin.
Relay, not Bitcoin only, right?
And well, schemes based on that.
Then support for bullet proofs, right?
For verification of some zero-knowledge
proofs on the blockchain and so on.
And yeah, we can think about sub-blocks.
Well, consider some roadmap with public
testnet activation and so on after 6.0.
So yeah, well, it's been polished.
Time to release it finally.
And yeah, well, this week I will do
another release candidate, version
release.
Well, now with rules and so on, and yeah,
it should be close to the final version.
It should be more or less. So yeah, well,
and in Sigmanauts DAO, we also formed a
group to work with mining pools and
exchanges to inform them about 6.0
release, so to check that everyone Well,
for exchanges, it would still be better to
update the nodes.
Maybe not, because they actually will be
made from the transactions, deposits and
withdrawals, with 5.0 and 6.0 network
after the activation.
But yeah, well, anyway, there is needs to
inform and to track.
So yeah, well, it's going on.
And yeah, well, a lot of updates after
6.0 to be planned.
How many steps along the way will we need
to update Testnet?
I think I'm on 6.0 R2 and you have 6.0 R3
out.
What are the breaking changes that are
going to need to update along the way
there for your testing?
You mean for the mining nodes?
Yeah, so you would need to update to RC4,
which is coming soon.
OK.
So RC3, which was a little update?
Yeah, so it was just a little bit
different from RC2.
But yeah, RC4 would be different,
actually.
Quite different from RC3.
And yeah, well, there is need to update
on the mining nodes because for other
nodes there are 5.0 and they will be
there.
We will do some testing, well, how 5.0
nodes would survive under 6.0
transactions.
And if anybody's running a node right now
on mainnet, you can run a testnet node on
the same network.
The more testnet nodes we have, the
better, because it gets a little tough to
sync if only a few devs are running
testnet nodes.
So any community members want to run
testnet node, instructions are up there.
Use a 6.0 R3 candidate that's there.
and spin it up, try to sync it up, and
join in and allow devs to successfully
test things so they're not continuously
using mainnet to test stuff.
Right?
Have you reached out to qx() at maybe to
see what we need to do to update our node
for demurrage relative to this new update?
No, I haven't. He's got an update coming
down the pipe that he was gonna I thought
he was gonna give us soon so I'll reach
out to him. I know he's busy on Lithos as
well so we'll ping him see what's up.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Nice.
What about, so for those of you that
don't pay attention to the forum or miss
some stuff in chats, one of the big things
that kushti and community members are
working on is the Ergo Book.
And one of the guys that's here is going
to be a contributor to it, Grayman.
You there?
You mind chatting about what your
contribution to the book's going to be?
Well, it's work in progress, so who knows
what it'll end up being, but what I'm
working on is more about the monetary side
of things rather than the technical side
of things.
And I'm sort of writing about the
development of King dollar as it came out
of the pre fed era entered the Fed.
And then post World War two and trying to
explain how a paper currency and then
eventually a digital currency overtook and
then replaced gold and silver and other
metals.
And then I'm trying to tie that back to,
you know, how did that happen and what is
the magic that they undid and how can we
bring that magic back with
cryptocurrencies as a way to sort of
defeat the king?
And I'm trying to frame it all around a
discussion of silver, because silver
coinage was very important to the
development of America's money system, all
the way from the beginning until around
1965, which was after Bretton Woods.
So after the dollar was established as
the unit of international trade, but
before Bretton Woods too, where we
officially reneged on the gold standard
and told people that they could no longer
convert their dollars into gold.
And so silver, all through this entire
process, was always sort of sitting in the
background, always sort of the second
thought of what is money, and yet there
the whole time.
And the other reason why both gold and
silver interests me is just because they
are way more decentralized and distributed
than any cryptocurrency, including
Bitcoin.
And both of them have larger market caps
than Bitcoin.
So if you talk to a Bitcoin maxi, they
will assure you that everything else is
going to zero because Bitcoin's first and
that's what the network effect does.
And my counter to that would be, I mean,
you haven't even beaten silver yet.
So and in terms of centralization, you
guys have a real problem.
And in terms of utility, you have
enormous problems.
So we are still in the infancy of the
digital money era.
And it's at this time that the
developments, the work that you guys are
doing make more difference than anything
else.
So you can go and go on Twitter or X and
listen to all the noise of people saying
this or that.
You know, listen to what's that guy,
Justin Bonds talking about how Solana is
cypherpunk and all that's nonsense.
And if you put it in context, this is all
just noise.
This is the stuff that a hundred years
from now, nobody's going to remember any
of that.
And what they're going to remember is
what are the concrete steps that were
taken by devs that changed the way that
money works and that eventually get
adopted because it becomes inevitable.
It's not about rooting for your team or
network effects or any of this or that.
It is about if you want to be able to
achieve this goal, then you have to do
these things.
And Bitcoin did the first two or three
steps.
I mean, it's remarkable and it's come a
long way, but there's a lot more than two
or three steps that need to happen for it
to become money.
And honestly, it's walking in the wrong
direction right now.
It's following gold.
And the dollar already beat gold.
It'd be interesting to get your take
between the gold and silver battle, so to
speak, relative to Bitcoin and AI.
At the conference, a lot of people are
worried about AI, but only in the sense of
taking up the electrical capacity of what
Bitcoin miners could be turning on.
Instead, they're making more money with
AI.
In terms of competing for, you know, the
resources and things like that, and like,
say, machinery, like, should we point our
machinery to gold or silver, you know, AI
or Bitcoin?
That'd be kind of an interesting, I
suppose, comparison, maybe.
Well, so Warren Buffett's famous for
saying that gold is just a shiny rock.
If I buy it and put it in my safe, at
best, it's held its value, but it doesn't
do anything.
And I think it was was it Margaret Mead
who said that, you know, people wonder,
like, whether or not a group of a small
group of people can get together and
change the world.
In fact, that's the only thing that ever
does.
So Warren Buffett and Margaret Mead and
most of modern Western society believe
that money is not just a chip that you use
to trade back and forth between a zero sum
game.
It is a tool that is used to create new
things, including new money.
And so AI corresponds to, it's more like
investing in a stock or in something that
actually produces changes to the world and
then generates income.
Whereas mining Bitcoin is just getting
your diminishing return on a system that
is I mean, theoretically gonna go for
another hundred years before the emissions
are completely zero, but I mean, that's
sort of dependent on the concept that the
price is gonna keep going up as much as it
has, and then eventually having a
ludicrous fee market, the so-called
security budget problem.
So you need the money to be flexible,
programmable, and to be useful for the
creation of new work, of new companies, of
new commerce.
And Bitcoin arguably is going in the
wrong direction, but GPU mined coins,
which can soak up the extra cycles from AI
farms that are idle due to lack of users
at the moment, could be quite useful
because it would give them a way to still
spend their energy that they've already
paid for in these giant, I mean, a lot of
these data centers are now getting their
own power stations to go along with them.
And so that's a cost and they need to,
they need that energy to keep flowing.
They need to spend that energy and turn
it into something.
Hopefully they're getting paid for
changing people's profile pictures to
anime, which apparently is the latest
excitement.
But whatever it is, when they're idle for
some reason, then it would be cool for
them to be able to not only secure a
currency network, but also to run the
security that's necessary to make that
currency network valid.
To rely on yeah, that's interesting.
I wonder how much idle time there are in
these farms that are dedicated AI. They
said at the conference not a lot like
they're they're always running pretty
much. And I was like I was kind of shocked
to hear that like they don't have enough
capacity. They're suggesting demand is
that high that it's always on. Wow.
I'm not sure I believe that, but it
wouldn't be buyer's remorse.
They spent like some ridiculous amount of
their pile of cash, like 80, $90 billion,
setting up this stuff in Michigan or
Wisconsin.
And it's just an, I mean, it might be
true for the guys that you're talking to
at this conference running relatively
small data centers, but you know, some
right now you've got, the competition at
the top levels of AI, at the corporate
levels of the people that are trying to
sell, not to you, not to somebody that's
going to tune their own LLM, but to people
like my clients that just want to run
their law firm or whatever it is and run
it more efficiently.
Microsoft's, whatever it is, Copilot
versus Google's Gemini, those are the
systems that are going to that are trying
to sell to those people and I bet you that
there's a huge amount of idle time on all.
Sure.
Yeah, totally.
Yeah.
And that is the vast majority of the GPUs
or I guess let's just say AI chips,
whatever they're used.
I guess these are not really GPUs, but
not ASICs.
Right.
Yeah, they were suggesting like it has to
be like a tier three data center has to
have 99% uptime because I guess like some
of these quant firms people I guess are
training their own LLMs and they'll run a
new model every morning or at a specific
time or they're training and fine tuning
as a model for like six to nine months.
And obviously if you have any
interruption in like that six to nine
month case, obviously that's devastating.
We'll probably get sued.
It's kind of what they're suggesting.
So it's kind of interesting.
I'm ready for the lawsuits when an AI
design bridge or building collapses.
All the finger pointing is going to go to
building, right?
Oh, jeez.
I won't be doing that.
Oh, boy.
Oh, well, that's pretty cool, Grayman.
We got a quick question in the chat.
12] **Kushti**: Yeah.
Just to add some notes, I think it's
actually quite awesome to write
non-technical, but monetary things,
monetary theory and practice related.
Because, well, I think we should be in
the space not for tech, but for money,
right?
But not in the sense of this retarded
crypto industry.
So, yeah, it should be about reworking
money, right?
And tech is just tooling after all.
So, well, if you are here for some tech,
then the question is, what this tech is,
what for?
What are you going to do with this tech?
You cannot just be tech for tech.
It's just like, I know, maybe be in a
hammer for hammer.
Yeah, but it's got to be solid and
reliable.
And in my opinion, open source at the
core level.
Right.
If not, it won't be money, right?
Nobody is going to the idea that people
trust Solana or any of these other closed
source systems.
The system is insane to me.
Like, how could they?
Yeah, so yeah, it should be open source
for sure.
But also it should be permissionless,
right?
Because well, it's truly permissionless.
Right.
No payment gateways as far as that goes.
Somebody wants to run something
themselves, they can spin up their own
node, mine it, and send their own
transactions through it.
And nobody can stop you.
Right.
Yeah.
And also, yeah, peer-to-peer.
So it's also doesn't matter a lot because
that's a guy that's a cypherpunk.
fake cypherpunk troll Justin Bond so he's
praising Solana and so on.
Scalable layer one and so on but in fact
so all those systems just threw away
peer-to-peer architecture, right?
It's very different story so it's not a
big deal to do a system which is operating
in a federated way, so peer-to-peer, while
a system which has some super nodes, some
parts will be peer-to-peer.
It would have crazy TPS and whatever, but
what's the meaning here, right?
There is no meaning, there is no value.
It calls into question the value of the
ledger that is created from such a system.
Same deal with DAGs.
I mean, or really any system that allows
pruning on the fly or these kind of, well,
the compromises that you make by trying to
shoehorn high TPS into something because
you think that you're going to compete
with Visa that way.
MasterCard, it doesn't work that way.
What we're trying to do is we're trying
to create a global ledger as a baseline
and then build on top of that ledger.
And that's, I mean, how do you do that
with a DAG?
You know, a chain of chains or a mesh or
any of these other architectures just seem
very, I mean, they would say innovative
and certainly they can lead to a lot of
speed.
But I really wonder in the long run
whether this, let's just say the security
assumptions are not clear to me in those
systems.
Oh, yeah, true, true.
And yeah, so well, I think it's worth to
do first some monetary design, some
monetary a kind of architecture, and then
yeah, tech would follow because we already
have well, like cameras and such.
It's not a problem to use them or to use
the solution.
Yeah, that's the problem.
should be quite clear what the space is
doing.
It's hiding the problematics of money
creating, good money and so on.
It's going to complete nonsense
sometimes.
I mean, are there any other chains out
there that are focusing on monetary
tooling and a new form of peer-to-peer
money and finance?
I don't know.
So, well, there are some quite exciting
private cryptocurrencies, right?
But they're just trying to do cash,
right?
But the question is how how do you
produce that cash, right?
Privacy of payments does matter a lot,
but first you need to solve quality of
money problem, then privacy of payments.
It would follow.
So, yeah, well, it's a different story,
still very different.
And aside of that, yeah, I don't see,
unfortunately.
Well, there are some efforts, but yeah,
they are small scale and usually, yeah,
well, not complete.
Right.
Also, very important.
Yes.
All right.
Someday it'll become sexy.
Yeah, we got a question in chat from
Richie.
He says, kushti, can Bitcoin forks like
Litecoin and others introduce sub-blocks
via a soft fork?
Yeah, actually, I'm in touch a little bit
with one Bitcoin Cash developer.
So we're actually thinking about a little
bit similar concept.
They have even a paper on that.
It's called Tailstorm.
And actually, he visited Ergo Platform
chat once.
That's a guy, Bitcoin Cash autist.
So, yeah, well, sometimes, so yeah, well,
it's kind of, I believe very generic
solution and it's also similar in some
aspects to layers, which is going to be
released for Cardano.
It's some Cardano network upgrade plan.
And yeah, so for Bitcoin, cash, Litecoin,
I believe even for Bitcoin itself, maybe
it's possible.
Something like that.
Let me think, because they already have
somewhat different from early days
transactions, block transactions, but to
say, propagation mechanism, called compact
blocks, right?
Block is generated they are not selling
all the transactions because well they are
using some protocol already and it's not
that hard to introduce different more
efficient there are actually a bunch of
papers on how to improve compact blocks
for Bitcoin and that's where I've got some
ideas for sub-blocks actually, so yeah.
The only question is yeah, well rewards I
guess how to reward miners?
It's even harder than a Bitcoin, but
maybe solvable.
I don't know. We need to check carefully.
All right, well it's hitting the top of
the hour and I have to go to a in real
life meeting.
I just want to say that, you know, we've
been trying different formats.
I love this format.
I love the fact that community members,
Sigmanauts, Grayman, HQ, Mark the Shark
come on and chat and give updates.
That's exactly what Ergo is and I think
that's ideal.
But I understand people also like the
other format, the more straightforward
people chatting at you with AMA style
formats.
So we'll see.
Keep tuned to the chats and we'll figure
out what's going on next week.
Yes.
So yeah, if there is a demand for some
classic format, then next week, maybe
there could be four of us again.
So Joe, you, and me.
Well, however, the classic may.
Why not?
All right, everybody.
Thanks so much for joining HQ, Grayman,
and Mark, kushti.
You guys all have a great rest of the
day.
Yeah, see you, gentlemen.
Yeah, thank you, guys.