Hey, everyone.
How's it going?
Good morning, everybody.
It's good to be here.
How are you doing, kushti?
Doing well, doing well.
How about you?
Doing all right.
No work today.
Today's Juneteenth in the United States.
So my place shuts down.
Federal holiday.
I think a lot of places do.
Oh, is it some holiday today?
Yeah, it's the emancipation of
recognition of the emancipation of slaves
in Galveston, Texas in 1865.
So, yeah, so they recognize that here in
the U.S. as a federal holiday and
everybody gets the 19th off for
recognition of it.
All right, all right.
So, yeah.
How's it been, kushti?
How's your week been?
You been busy?
Yeah, busy and today is also busy and I
think there will be final 6.0 release
today, finally.
So, yeah, just checking some things and
yeah, I think it will be released today
along with instructions for the mining
pools on how to work because, yeah, I
guess since
2022, probably every mining pool has
forgotten, right?
The latest soft fork was in 2022.
In 2023, they were only, well, very
major, but client-side only updates such
as support for
NIPoPoWs bootstrapping and bootstrapping
with UTXO set snapshots right and then
yeah well since 2024 there was work on 6.0
and then yeah on sub-blocks slowly so now
we are going to roll out 6.0 soft fork
update, waiting for it, and then yeah,
well, sub-blocks, there will be another
DevNet release call for testing DevNet
probably next week, but let's see.
So I'm currently even doing some load
testing locally and yeah, there are some
inefficiencies found.
as well as some probably bugs to discover
and so on.
How do we know the difference in releases
between one running on RocksDB and one
running on the other database so that we
don't mess it up?
Yeah, so there will be two 6.0 releases,
6.0, 6.1 probably.
But yeah, well there was 5.0.27 release
yesterday as well and well 5.1.4 I believe
is postponed a bit so I need to get
So in the latest RocksDB release there
was an update from RocksDB dependency
version 8 to version 9 and there were some
complaints so now it would be good to
discuss whether we roll back to version 8
or we'll update it further to version 10.
So your 0.1 releases are the RocksDB
database?
Your 0.0 releases are the old database?
LevelDB, yes.
So yeah, the original DB.
Actually, not the original, but yeah,
well, the very original database was on
key-value database called IODB made in IO.
Then, yeah, we switched to LevelDB
because, well, that guy was not very
stable in maintaining IODB.
Quite a famous guy, but yeah, also quite
unstable in regards with maintaining his
product such as MapDB, IODB.
then yeah so our LevelDB and yeah so
still we are on LevelDB since 2019 and
yeah well as support for LevelDB is also
not so quite good right so we are still
using drivers from 2018 so yeah well how
after all yeah we started
Gradual switch to RocksDB, which is at
least well maintained at the moment.
Well, 5.0 is about LevelDB, 5.1 is about
RocksDB, but then, yeah, well,
unfortunately, less platforms supported at
the moment.
And, yeah, well, there are also some
complaints about the latest version,
introduced an update to a newer version of
RocksDB, but we have even newer version.
So, yeah, well, some testing is needed.
in regards to that.
But yes, 6.0 will be released for
LevelDB.
So to the best of my knowledge, all the
mining pools on LevelDB version, at least
mining pools I will touch with.
So yeah, we are going to release 6.0 in
the first place.
Something like that, so yeah, it's the
whole zoo of different versions, so
hopefully after 6.0 we can do something
with that.
Let's see.
Cool.
Looking forward to it.
We have a modified node for SIG's mining
pool, so we'll have to be on top of that
to make sure that that gets modified, the
new one.
Oh, so is it 5.1?
no no we're on 50 something 50 5018 or
5019 something like that oh maybe even
5020 yeah in the first place it would be
good to update to 5026 like some mining
pools already did which is introducing
periodic regeneration of can block
candidate which is providing quicker
confirmations.
Oh, great.
It's a good point.
Yeah.
Oh, we're going to see if you can update
the 6.0 to
So 6.0 is five or 26 based after all.
So, yeah, a lot of things like that.
Then, yeah, well, about one week ago,
well, SigmaChain's refactoring plan was
published and, yeah, it's also on the
table.
So, currently investigating and
discussing with people
Well, I had a talk with Bruno, for
example, just one hour ago about Zephyr
and so on.
Zephyr is a Djed-based, somewhat private
stablecoin, actually just fork of Monero
with a Djed implemented in client code.
But yeah, so we discussed and yeah, it
seems it's possible to do more interesting
things and so on.
But yeah, well, from following that plan
published, I think, well, merge mined
sidechains probably is a low-hanging
fruit, right?
And well, we can propose actually a lot
of designs more interesting than Zephyr
and so on.
to to the different to to the world right
to the different teams and then yeah well
maybe some will be implemented by
how to call it the developers we know
right like in inner circle well community
Ergo community let's say and then yeah
well also discussing yeah then different
funding options right for implementing
such things and so on
So let's see, there is also an
anniversary coming.
Are you going to do any video for it?
Yep.
We've got Dan and at least Dan and I
reached out to pixel as well to do some
videos.
So, so Andy's got a big list that he went
through.
I believe Angie and him curated it.
And we were looking through it last week
to figure out what we could do and what we
could refresh.
So, yep, there'll be some things coming
out soon.
That'll be good.
Some new content, I guess you could say.
Yeah, don't we need to give Yuri some
ERGs for a cake, kushti, isn't that
tradition?
Sorry, cake?
Don't we need to give Yuri some ERGs for
cake?
No, it's not Yuri, it's who's the guy
that we give money to for a cake?
In Gulag.
Oh, that's Raro.
Yeah, Raro.
Don't we need to give Raro money for
cake?
He usually gets a cake if we give him
some ERGs and then sends us pictures.
We've got to remember to do that.
He celebrates it every year that I
remember with a cake.
So we'll make sure to do maybe a hop and
gulag in a little bit and send him some
ERGs.
Nice.
Yeah.
So that's, that's going to be great.
A lot of video content that you should be
seeing up on YouTube.
I don't think, when's the anniversary
exactly, kushti?
What day?
July 1st.
Yeah.
So that is June, July.
That's two days before our AMA.
So maybe, maybe we move the AMA to the
first and kick it off, kushti.
Possible.
Yeah.
That'd be interesting.
Yeah, kick off the video sequences with a
live AMA on the first, and then let the
videos run the rest of the day on release.
That might be a good idea.
Cool.
Great.
Yeah.
What else?
We've been talking to Glasgow.
All the details have been sent to the
listing.
So congratulations on everybody for
fundraising at the raffle for the US
on-ramp.
That's going to be great, except for
three states.
Unfortunately, New York, I'll have to
enter someplace else, but that's fine.
So all the details have been sent there.
The agent that they're working with has
said it takes a few weeks to bring back
the finalized contract.
From there, so we should be seeing it
soon.
I'm hoping hoping maybe near the end of
July We'll see that on ramp fully
functional where people can hop in and not
only I'm excited about that on ramp.
I'm excited that There's potential to
integrate that puppy into things.
So how cool would it be to?
On ramp right from Nautilus or on ramp
right from Rosen Bridge in there That's
really what I'm excited about, you know
ease of use for people
as opposed to going to their interface.
What else we have?
Last weekend was Father's Day.
Happy Father's Day to everybody that is a
father.
So I didn't show up to the SIGS meeting.
I was spending time with the family.
So we did not finalize the schedule for
the Ergo meetup, but that should be done
this Sunday.
We'll finalize that puppy, and we'll pump
it out there along with the two more
sign-up links, the GitHub sign-up link and
the Google Form sign-up link.
So you guys can sign up and come but as I
said the weeks before
we are doing a we're going to try to live
stream as much as we can to involve the
people that can't be there right so we're
going to live stream all the talks we're
going to live stream the hackathon we're
going to try to involve the people allow
groups outside of the place to that are
streaming to participate in the hackathon
as well so we'll have two groups in person
one of the AI coders one of the core dev
coders or the original coders
And then we'll have two groups online,
which are the AI coders and another group
of manual, original coders.
So that'll be good to involve that.
It'll be a whole production.
We can't live stream you dinner, so we're
really sorry about that.
I guess we could, but it wouldn't be too
tasty.
So stay tuned for that.
That'll be a good event as well that
everybody can watch from the comforts of
your couch if you're not going to make the
way over to sunny Colorado.
Always sunny, sometimes Colorado.
Isn't that what Charles says all the
time?
Something like that.
Yeah, so that'll be fun.
What else?
Rosen Bridge is nearing their Doge
integration.
They got through some tough stuff that
was taking them a while to figure out.
So that should be imminent for those of
you watching that.
Guards are locked and ready, ready to
update and push that through.
So if you're a watcher, please stay tuned
to that.
Any updates that are needed, please do
that periodically.
And let me remind everybody running
watchers or guards, it's not
It's a good idea to check in on it once
in a while.
I try to check in once a week when I fix
my USD Oracle.
I try to check on my watch or my guard to
make sure that it's running and as a
safety I usually bounce it.
because there have been some times when
I'm running the watch or running the guard
where the health looks okay, the health
looks fine, but then I bounce it and all
of a sudden one of my chains is, you know,
100 or 200 or 300 blocks, maybe even a
thousand blocks out of sync, you know, way
more blocks than it took to bounce the
thing.
It's perfectly healthy.
Just bounce your guard once in a while.
Bounce your watcher once in a while, just
on the safe side.
Set your alarm.
If you're going to, if you plant
something outside to grow, you don't just
leave it and forget it, right?
You've got to put a little water on it,
that kind of stuff.
So give us some TLC and you'll make sure
to get all the transactions you can
instead of missing them with an out of
sync watcher.
What else we got, kushti?
Actually, just some thoughts.
It's quite amazing how AI coding on Ergo
is being developed, right?
So it seems like crazy, quick progress.
So I'm not quite following all the
possibilities here but yeah it's quite
amazing so I think Ergo is actually quite
friendly right to AI extremely friendly
the endpoints make it so easy and the
tools like even with the Python
integration just you know writing a quick
AI thing to integrate with that it's it's
easy
Yeah, and also ErgoScript, I think, well,
and the approach, right, so yeah, it
should be very AI-friendly.
Then, yeah, so for Rosen, yeah, well, I
asked Joe directly, like yesterday, maybe
even two days ago,
About Zano and Kaspa, so yeah, it seems
they're in touch, right?
But yeah, well, it depends on the teams
how quickly integrations will be done, but
yeah, let's see.
Kaspa just launched a mixer last week.
Did you see that, kushti?
No, not quite but yeah, it seems it's
it's like bitcoin bitcoin like like
coinjoin rights approach the mixer the the
mixer, right?
So yeah, it's not really Kaspa.
It's it's it's hosted essentially Yeah,
it's hosted on their end.
So I wonder how that's going to work and
they have
And they had what I read while I was
reading through the thing you have to
agree to before you mix.
And one of the lines was, we cannot
guarantee privacy or tracking of that kind
of thing.
So we can guarantee anonymity.
So I was like, oh, that's interesting.
Maybe they'll work on it and figure it
out and figure out how to make a
non-custodial self-download one like Ergo
has.
That kind of stuff is, you know, given,
but it's a good start.
But actually, yeah, so they cannot, I
think, in the first place because for
coinjoin, like mixers, so... Well, the
biggest issue is networking layer, right?
So that there is some service you need to
work with, right, in order to coordinate
mixing efforts with other platforms.
I gotcha.
and yeah usually yeah what surveillance
is doing like specific agencies and so
on, so they're tracking interactions with
those services specifically, right?
And it's not something which could be
avoided by the services, right?
They don't control networking layer.
So yeah, well, in case of
working with our Ergo node, Monero node,
right?
It's quite different.
So, yeah, well, in Ergo, it's service,
but you're working with some nodes, right?
But your own node, and then, yeah, it's
more controllable at least.
Could be made better, but yeah, I mean,
In Monero, actually, it seems based on
available information, it's also kind of
the weakest part of the security chain.
Well, the networking layer, so if you're
working with, so especially if you're
using Tor along with Monero, right, so
well, it seems certain agencies are trying
to connect interactions with Tor with
transactions on Monero based on some
incidents.
which took place in EU, for example.
So, yeah, then maybe it's better to avoid
using Tor even, right?
But then, yeah, you are going to somehow
Make private communication on your own.
It's very tricky, especially without
knowledge.
So, yeah, well, privacy guarantees is a
very tricky point, actually.
Even if there are some on-chain
guarantees, then, yeah, well, it's not
just about that.
True, very true.
And yeah, about those services.
So yeah, well, I don't have any
information about Kaspa, but for Bitcoin,
those services were under close
surveillance even back in early 2020.
So yeah, I had some talks about that with
some
Well, research labs doing this, actually.
Yeah, I mean, they're always...
Sorry, go for it.
So yeah, tracking activities and yeah,
well, doing
Well, on-chain transactions with
off-chain activities like communication
with state service.
Oh boy.
It sounds like it's always...
It's always a struggle to attain that
perfectly.
I mean, even with a perfectly designed
system, with a knowledgeable user, you're
still at risk of exposing yourself if
you're not careful, even no matter how
perfect something like ErgoMixer is or
other things.
but if you're working with your own notes
and mixer and yeah for sure for sure but
i'm talking about the simple things as far
as like cross-pollinating a clean wallet
or something stupid like that like how the
bridge chain guy was caught with the nfts
mixing his funds he just made a stupid
mistake pollinating a wallet the wrong way
and then it's over you know just
user error, nothing to do with the mixer
really just screwed it up.
So I think there's plenty of ways to
expose yourself even with a pretty solid
system.
I mean, using your code, then, yeah,
well, it's two connections.
Like, one or two connections.
Something, but, yeah.
I mean, the point is, if you're having
collections, then it's supposed to
the opt-in info, which started a certain
well, according to some.
So that's better to avoid thing just by
transaction.
So then they will start in case of
kushti, you're breaking up a little bit.
You want to switch internet connections?
You hear me?
Let's see.
Yep.
Hopefully he switches internet
connections.
Andy, you're still there?
We're still live?
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
So what kushti gets his internet
connection fixed.
Let's see if we can hit some questions in
the meantime.
Let's see if there are non-kushti
questions here.
Oh, yeah, well what kushti was saying as
well when I was breaking up and what we
were talking about is No matter how fit
the protocol is There's still user methods
that can expose you on mixers, right?
And he was speaking of the type of mixers
that Oh, there is gone.
See if Andy fixes me.
There we go.
We'll go we'll bend down like this
And even if there are, you know, pretty
fit mixers, like the ErgoMixer, where it
hosts on your own machine, you send the
stuff out through your own node, there are
still ways, not protocol-based, that can,
you know, expose you.
And there have been examples that are
already on the chain of people trying to
hide themselves and messing up, not
mixer-based, not mixer-related.
Based on that they just were sloppy in
doing it and didn't really understand what
the function of a mixer works or how it
works So so there's that kind of stuff you
got to be careful with as well Let's see
we have Somebody asked about the
Most body max fitness
We talked about this earlier when we
started BodyMax, talked to Glasgow.
It should be about a few weeks.
They have all the information and they're
sending back the contract soon and that
should be signed and good.
So I'd give it, I can set up again.
Great.
I'd give it a few weeks.
So it's open probably the end of July.
We should see something like that come
forward.
So looking forward to that What else do
we have?
You guys like my visualizer in the back.
This was a quick AI coding thing It shows
the mempool you can click on you can click
on a thing and it shows you the actual
transaction orange or peer-to-peer
transactions yellow are
Gold oracle transactions.
You can see all the gold there It's just
something cool that I have up During the
day so I can see how busy the Ergo chain
is And the matrix out the green supposed
to represent hash And I hope to actually
connect it to the SIGS mining pool so we
can actually get a reading of those
outputs And do that.
All right, move it on.
Let's see.
What else we have We have
A body max fitness looks like he's upset.
We'll come back to that stuff.
And he needs on the launch of sigma
quest.
I believe that is another thing to Timur
the game.
I don't have any update on that.
I think he was working on patching a hole
before release, so last time I knew he was
still working on that to patch it.
You know, that is one of the issues with,
I will say, I notice with AI coding, when
you're doing pure AI coding, it takes a
lot longer to fix something that AI codes
than it does if you wrote it yourself.
I use AI a bit at work to program my Perl
scripts to build some and I know it takes
time to build it from scratch, but if I go
back to something that I didn't build and
I'm looking at it and trying to fix it for
an error or a bug or anything like that,
it takes me a considerable amount of time
to figure out exactly what the hell is
going on.
So I imagine that's something similar
that Timur is going through right now,
depending on his coding skill, with
looking at that and trying to fix
something that somebody else built,
especially when it was AI-coded, that kind
of stuff.
So, yeah.
kushti, welcome back.
You switching internet connections?
Yeah, not yet.
You seem to be pretty good right now, but
I see your eyes Maybe I'll switch over my
eyes to until Andy fixes us.
Let's see kushti here.
Let me let me join you in the in the
broadcast Here we go There we go kushti
now we're twinsies now it looks
intentional Perfect.
I kushti we got some questions.
You ready?
Yep.
All right.
Here's the one from Luke Gratesmith.
It's getting very, very out of the
blockchain.
Ready?
What subject did you all like best when
you were in school and what subject do you
like best to do with your free time now if
you want to learn something?
You first, kushti.
Oh, but I don't have free time, so
usually, yeah, I mean, when having free
time, would be happy to actually catch
with some stuff in cryptography, so a lot
of things going on.
And yeah, well, for some topics, I'm well
out of state of arts.
What about when you went to school?
Back in the day, kushti, when you were a
youngin?
Well, mathematics, physics, something
like that.
All right.
Oh, there we go.
Andy's awake.
Andy's fixing us.
Thank you, Andy.
Let me fix me as well.
Sorry, one second.
Center me up here.
There we go.
OK, perfect.
All right, my favorite subject in school?
You know, I was a music student in
school, so that always came naturally.
That was my favorite subject.
And then I started dabbling in Java
programming, which also came easily.
So that was a lot of fun.
Just able to kind of hyper-focus on that
stuff.
So I'd say those two.
And music history was fun as well.
We used to do fun drop needle tests on
every single piece of music that's ever
been written, all the way from Gregorian
chants up to, you know, the Renaissance or
even probably the 1800s, early 1900s.
So those are fun drop needle tests where
you just sit there and you drop a needle
on a random record and you get points
Whoever guessed the composer or the era of
it.
I think you had to guess both at the same
time Well, I guess if you see the
composer, you know the era but but yeah,
so so that was a lot of fun
Now, in my free time, how do I like to
learn?
I come from the school of bash your head
against it until you get it, right?
I have a small patience for reading
things thoroughly.
So if there's documentation on something,
I'll try my best to skim through it before
my attention just starts going off to the
wayside and just losing interest.
So I'll do my best to try to read up it
to get a general idea of it, and then I'll
try to utilize it and beat my head against
it until I figure it out.
So that seems to be my method of learning
throughout life, and it seems to be
alright.
I notice that it does leave holes in my
knowledge, so while I will be able to do
something and seem somewhat masterful in
something that I do,
It still leaves pretty big holes in there
kind of thing.
So that is one of the weaknesses of it
But it's a method that seems to work so
far for for what I'm doing Yeah, good
question Luke non blockchain related.
I like it All right.
Let's see what else we have
Bevis asks, any updates on Kraken listing
for Rosen-ERG?
Has voting finished?
Yeah, let me tell you about this, buddy.
I have, what's it called?
Let me see, can I bring this up on the
screen?
I think I can.
Let's see.
Can you guys see?
Let me move myself for one second.
I can remove myself for this fancy stuff.
There you go.
Look at that, folks.
Zero comments.
I invited the community last week to come
comment on this stuff.
Right now, the only person that's
commented is in the lower left right here.
right there, it's been CannonQ, who's a
Sigmanaut, right?
So he has vested interest because he's
part of the, you know, he's Sigmanaut in
the Sigmanauts type of guard set.
But my goodness, people, I invited the
community to comment on that stuff and
nobody's commented it.
So it's interesting where I see people
show interest in chats and show interest
right now in, you know, the AMA.
I'm not dissing you, Bevis, not at all,
you know, I'm just saying in general.
Please take that interest and take it off
chats and take it to the actual Paideia
and comment on the thing.
Even if it's like, this looks great,
let's go.
You know, that's much better than seeing
zero comments on the thing.
Then we know, okay, we've got 30 people
that said, great, let's go.
Then we'll turn it into a vote and we'll
push it.
You know what I mean?
Engage, please guys.
We can't rely on other people to engage
for us.
Even if something looks good and you
agree to it Don't rely on that Don't be
passive be active, please.
Great.
Thanks for bringing that up Bevis All
right.
Oh, here's a good one from Luca Chinese
stablecoin.
Do you think it'd be worth creating an
RMB stablecoin?
Maybe, I don't know.
What's the demand?
But yeah, I guess it could be some,
right?
I mean, there's some nationalistic aspect
there, right?
Where Chinese citizens might be more apt
to convert to your Chinese stablecoin as
opposed to a US dollar stablecoin, no?
I don't know, but usually RMB, to the
best of my knowledge, is tied to USD
anyway, but sometimes the rate is changed.
But over the years, from my observations,
it's anywhere around 6 or 7 CNY to USD.
6, 6.28 probably.
But yeah, I don't know.
So maybe it makes sense if it will be
more independent, right?
Well, how do you feel about the latest
craze, kushti?
It seems like the latest craze is
corporations creating their own
stablecoins lately, and I imagine that's
going to either fizzle out or go full
steam ahead for the remainder of this
This market kind of thing.
What are your thoughts about having an
Amazon stablecoin or a Walmart stablecoin
or something like that?
So, that's a bit expected, right, to me
at least.
So, well, as I say, it's in regards with
ChainCash, not once even.
Well, we are back to free banking era,
right, in one way or another.
So, this also quite following the trend.
I don't know, I guess free banking in the
sense that anybody can do it, but I think
engaging in something like the Walmart
stablecoin or the Amazon stablecoin, I
don't think there's anything free about
that, man.
I imagine there will be some serious
guardrails and restrictions on some of
that stuff.
Yeah, but that's the first step, right?
So, well, it was started by Tether,
right?
But if Tether is doing billions on
stablecoins, then yeah, you can expect...
That's true, that is true.
It's a tasty fruit hanging there.
Literally every corporation is chasing
billions as well, right?
Because that's how it works.
Then, yeah, well, in regards with Chinese
stablecoins, yeah, I think, well, Chinese
corporations also will jump on the board,
especially considering, well,
how developed fintech they are right with
Alipay and other companies so yeah
actually a lot of big fintech corporations
are now there and yeah well they also
expanding I believe to Southeast Asia at
least and so on so
Africa also.
So then, yeah, probably makes a lot of
sense.
And yeah, especially when they see Tether
doing billions, then yeah, well, it's
quite natural to chase this path.
That's true.
All right, we've got Bevis again with a
good question.
kushti, giving you a good runway here.
Can we expect sub-blocks to be fully
deployed by the end of this year?
That's six months away, kushti.
What's your thought?
Probably.
That's good.
That's a good answer.
Good enough, kushti.
Let's move on.
Yes.
So I think we can start injecting
sub-blocks, supporting nodes to the
public testnet around somewhat July even.
But then, yeah, a lot of things to take
care about.
And yeah, so some weeks and months it
will take.
And yeah, actually, it makes sense to
activate
sub-blocks after 6.0 activation right but
yeah can be done before maybe even with
but
No, I'm not sure about that.
So, yeah, probably after 6.0 activation.
So, yeah, if we will start voting on July
1st, for example, then activation will
take place on October 1st.
But then, yeah, well, in somewhat October
even, we can do Mainnet activation.
Let's see.
Awesome.
All right.
Follow-up question.
Any updates on Rosen going live with
Doge?
I think I spoke with that earlier when we
first started.
Update from Joe is a work in progress.
It should be soon, hopefully.
So we're getting there.
We are getting there.
What else do we have?
We got some semi-spam here, frustrations
being expressed.
How are BRIC going from Earth to Miner?
Kids are gone.
Students are gone for the summer.
We have high school students here.
So we have a program where there's high
school students that come here, about 80
of them.
In our program and they spend time on
Like a 10 week 12 week architecture
program.
There are also some other small classes
that take place in the summer Like the
master students come to a facility in New
York City.
So those guys will be getting BRIC soon
But I'm not gonna give the high school
students BRIC.
I mean, I guess
That'd be interesting, but they don't
plot, unfortunately, so there'd be no real
point to giving them BRIC.
But we'll see.
Every year they kind of enhance what
the...
what's it called, what the high school
students are doing.
So when the first year they came, first
time they came like years ago, they never
even used computers.
It was all like hand drawing and that
kind of thing.
Now they're using laptops and they're
using Rhinoceros and AutoCAD and those
kinds of things and printing some things,
usually tiling.
So it wouldn't be out of the world to
have them start plotting big time.
So if that happens, potentially we will
hand them BRIC and ask for the department
to pay for it essentially.
So give us funds.
Here's the BRIC.
Students can print via the blockchain
since they don't have a Bursar account.
So actually, BRIC's a perfect thing for
that kind of transaction.
So we'll see.
We'll see in the summertime.
But yeah, we're gearing up.
We've changed our rules a little bit for
next semester for how BRIC are handed out.
And we'll hit it full force when it comes
in.
Mark the shark says qx doesn't read my
messages.
Oh, did he send me a message?
Let me see.
I wonder what I I am bad at reading
messages How many unread messages you have
are so many kushti?
Yeah, so Sometimes yeah, i'm finding some
messages from like weeks ago.
Yeah, whoops Sorry, sorry Mark.
I'm not sure what you're commenting.
Maybe you're commenting on
Maybe you're commenting on the AI coding
stuff.
Maybe you're that Mark.
Mark's big thing with AI coding is
context, context, context.
You have to give the AI code, you have to
give the LLM context about what you're
doing, how to do it.
And he says it does worlds, worlds
better, right?
It's night and day difference between AI
coding with no context and AI coding with
context.
take be like Mark give your LLM context
and You'll be very happy.
Oh, yeah, he's commenting that I don't
read documentation.
Yeah, I don't sorry.
Sorry, buddy QX show is the mempool
visualizer sir show us I did didn't I show
you guys it's right here kushti did I show
you here?
I'll show it again for people that joined
late real quick.
Let me hide myself one sec
Let me take a screen capture.
Let me make it smaller so it can actually
be seen fully on screen.
There we go.
So, let's see.
Oh, as soon as I do it, the mempool
clears up.
We'll put, we'll put it back on until
the, until we get some hits with some
mempools coming up.
But, let me know when that happens.
All right.
What else do we have?
Oh, here we go.
Yeah.
First of all, this is a topic that was
that was had in chat the other day.
Can you talk about the concept of a
private DEX?
Can this help with avoiding something
like a sandwich bot or snipers?
But I mean it depends on how you define
private here.
So how would you do that?
Would you whitelist addresses to work
with a smart contract essentially?
So you can whitelist, for example,
off-chain batchers, right?
And encrypted requests, for example,
right?
that they can do something.
There was some design of private
perpetual DEX proposed recently, but this
is about actually some centralized server
providing some proof of something, but
this server is actually controlling
So, actually doing sniping and MEV and
whatever, right?
So, well, at least now such things are
transparent, but so trackable.
But yeah, it's easy to introduce
something centralized, but yeah,
quasi-private.
And then, yeah, well, a certain entity
will do that, right, without even being
traced.
So, the devil is in detail, how privacy
is defined exactly, right?
Well, definitions are quite subtle.
So, kushti, how is a sandwich bot
successful on a UTXO chain, and especially
with a block time of two minutes on Ergo?
So I guess you hit the slippage or, I
mean, it's not like you can pack something
before and in the same transaction, right?
Like how do you, how does sandwich bots
work successfully?
I thought they were much more difficult
to do.
Not the same, but yeah, you can do, so if
slippage is long, you can do separate
transactions, right?
And your pool puts a little bit higher
fee.
So it's not quite different here, right,
with AMM.
Then, yeah, well.
There are different things you can do,
but yeah, they also probably are not quite
different here, right?
But yeah, so for private DEX, well, for
most of efficient designs, right, so you
adjust
tying to some batchers and sending them
encrypted requests.
But then what?
So then they can do some commitments,
right?
So I need to think actually how it could
work.
But yes, something is possible when you
fix batchers.
But then the question is, do you really
want such a design?
Okay.
Hard to say.
I mean, it's about different trade-offs.
So if it's about, I don't know, the truly
decentralized setting, then the question
is, well, what kind of privacy are you
trying to achieve here?
I mean, public privacy from home and
privacy.
So if it's about privacy of your actions,
then yeah.
How are they clear?
How are they executed?
Okay, so currently the way for the
community to avoid these sandwich attacks,
if they're being happening, is to set your
slippage just to a low amount and that'll
just, your transaction will fail, but is
that the key?
Right, but actually you can avoid proxy
contracts, like Spectrum DEX is doing, for
example.
So in Dexy, for example, the current DEX
interface for Dexy,
which is a part of Spectrum DEX.
So there is no proxy, right?
And then, well, there is no sandwiching
possible, right?
It's not possible to insert any order
before.
But then, yeah, you can have transactions
failed, but without on-chain footprint,
unlike EVM blockchains.
Right, right.
We're not losing any funds.
So yeah, well, the current design with
proxies is maybe not very Ergo-oriented,
right?
So maybe direct execution is better.
There are some discussions in the chats
about that.
But even if you are doing
Proxy, for example, you can set, software
can set slippage to avoid any order
appearing before you, right, going in the
same direction.
So you can allow only four orders going
in opposite direction.
For example, then, yeah, I mean, still
there is chance of failure.
But maybe direct execution is better.
Just so, and even so you can have more
sophisticated software, maybe which can
retry right attempts, but use direct
execution.
And then for sandwiches, it would be
quite hard environment.
Still, I believe.
All right, what else we got?
Mark wants to know if we have an EIP for
creating side merge mined chains.
Would that be a good way to codify the
process for others to follow?
Sorry?
Is there an EIP for sidechains, for merge
mined chains?
And if not, is that something that can be
done so other people can try to follow
this and help?
Yeah, so there is only a document on how
to do a merge mined sidechain from
ErgoHack 8, maybe.
Yeah, it was 8, I believe.
So yeah, from autumn... autumn 2023.
So, yeah, well, but you can do some more
detailed documents and, yeah, if there are
some guys with ideas on, well, merge mined
sidechains would be happy to cooperate
with and, yeah, well, expand the
documents.
But yeah, please refer to ErgoHack 8
submission in the first place.
And yeah, it was about merge mined
sidechains and also trustless pegging for
such.
Okay, so in this case, it's possible to
do two-way trustless peg.
It seems so, which is quite, quite great,
right?
So something which is not possible in
Bitcoin still.
All right, we got one maybe that Bruno
Could answer How the stablecoins fit into
the ecosystem with the major fiat back
stablecoins would be BRICS be interested
in Gluon Gold Dexy the BRICS group, which
is what that's the BRICS is a group of
nations exploring stablecoin development.
So has has has
Bruno ever thought to not just develop
protocols, but actually to do outreaches
and try to engage those kind of things at
that level.
Bruno I know he said the other day that
you know somebody asked him how come
you're not making a front end for this and
he says my forte is just designing this
and and doing that the base of it and
somebody else can make the front end of it
so I imagine perhaps outreach and
front-facing and engagement might not be
his real house either for this kind of
stuff
Right, but usually, anyway, so big
players are interested in centralized
stablecoins, right?
Maybe it makes sense, but also due to
capital inefficiency, right, of solid
algorithmic stablecoins, which survived
over time, right?
But then you can use such stablecoins in
conjunction with centralized stablecoins.
So do something like ChainCash, right?
So have multiple issuers backed in
different ways, even together along with
Amazon and Google, right?
You can imagine them as well, just
different issuers in ChainCash along with
smaller players, right?
Even individuals.
So in this regard, yeah, well, ChainCash
is kind of a great equalizer.
And then, yeah, well, algorithmic
stablecoins also can be used for some,
well,
Settlements, right, some buffer, right,
which you maybe don't need for usually, so
you need for smaller amounts, but yeah,
it's better to have less trust also, more
guarantees basically.
Yeah.
All right.
We got one more kushti This is a very
difficult question might take you a while
to answer What's your favorite fruit?
Favorite fruit What really yeah, Ursa
wants to know your favorite fruit Maybe
wants to send you a basket a fruit basket
kushti Do you eat kushti?
How often do you eat once a week?
No like you have time to eat
Yeah, yeah, but about fruits, I don't
know.
Maybe mango, but... Oh, nice.
Good call.
Yeah, yeah, mango's great.
Peach, peach, yeah.
Similar, similar.
I'm a fan of the... Something like that.
In the U.S. we call them limes, but in
South America they're just lemons.
The green, the green lemon, those are...
Oh, yeah.
Limes.
Oh, so good.
Well, that's a good way