Hey, everyone, how's it going?
Good morning, everybody.
How you doing, kushti?
Doing well, busy days despite summer but
yeah it's going really well so delivering
a lot and just like two minutes ago 6.0
RC6 released hopefully the latest release
candidate version, which is different from
the final release in regards with
maintenance warning height.
But yeah, so we are doing some additional
testing. So let's see. But yeah, well,
it's hopefully final.
Should we push that and test that?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Then what else? So yeah, well, Sigma 6.0
released and well, I've published some
texts, I believe. I don't know whether I
made anything public, but yeah, we've
written a lot of stuff also recently. If
it's not public yet, then yeah, it will be
made so in coming days.
So, yeah, then there are some things I'm
preparing under the hood. Yes, some will
be announced soon and some probably close
to September, so finalizing conference
schedule. So, yeah, well, in September, I
will visit Korean Blockchain Week. So,
yeah, currently making some arrangements
with Korean peers.
And yeah, also, I will be in Dubai in
July, surprisingly. Yeah, I hope I'll
survive. So if everyone will be around in
July, not sure about that. So yeah, let's
meet maybe.
So yeah, a lot of updates and yeah, it
seems community is quite buzzing these
days again, right? So a lot of
conversations and so on. Some new faces in
the developer's chats and yeah, actually,
there are some new faces in the developers
chat, some brought by Bruno because he has
a couple of Google Summer of Code projects
bringing new contributors to existing and
new projects.
And yeah, well, aside of that, there are
some new faces as well. And yeah, well, a
lot of interesting things going on.
Yeah, we have some, the hackathon brought
on some people that aren't even really
normal developers, you know, everyday
developers. So with the AI themed, it's
not just, remember, it's not just AI
themed, as in let's work with AI in the
blockchain. It's also let's utilize AI
tools to help create and build something
for Ergo, for the hackathon.
So you'll notice that I think Mark got
two Sigmanauts mining pool miners to build
some apps as well in the hackathon. So
those are completely new people testing
the DevWaters with the augmentation of AI.
So that was really, really good to see.
And I'm scanning through the entries in
the Discord. If you guys have the time,
swing into the Discord and Glasgow's got
them all listed there right under, right
near the general chat. You'll see
everybody's hackathon project and you'll
see the submissions and there's a lot of
working examples that you can click on and
actually use their product.
So if you want to participate in, we're
working on doing a community vote as well,
like we do every time. So there'll be, we
just have to vote on that in the
Sigmanauts. So there'll be a reward for
community voted projects on the hackathon.
That's neat because, you know, you have
the hackathon requirements which are
awarded by the EF and then you have
community projects where we can use
different metrics and standards to rank
and grade and have you vote on. So it
gives everybody more of a chance at the
uniqueness of their project to perhaps
receive a reward for their efforts.
But there's a lot of cool stuff. kushti,
did you take a peek at some of the
hackathon final projects that came out?
Yeah, well, watched probably, so all of
them published over the Ergo platform
Twitter. So, yeah, well, it's quite
interesting what people are doing with AI
and Ergo. So I'm also trying to use AI,
but... For testing, right?
You use it for running test examples?
To write tests, so some trivial code, but
yeah, so I tried to write down some
sub-blocks related algorithms
implementation. Yeah, it seems, well, it's
about, you know, some pretty dangerous
hallucinations. So yeah, I found, well,
it's probably more productive to write
codes manually, right, than to get through
reviewing AI-generated code with some
subtle issues, but they're actually quite
critical ones.
Right, right. It gets very difficult. I
find that if I write something from
scratch and something goes wrong, it's so
much easier to debug it as opposed to
having AI spit out an entire app, and then
you're literally going through the app as
if somebody else wrote it because they did
and you're kind of learning and figuring
it out. It takes much, much longer to bug,
debug and troubleshoot an AI app as
opposed to writing your own code.
But that being said, I think I said this
last week, I can't remember if I said it
in a Sigmanauts meeting or an AMA, but
I'll say it again. The interfacing with
Ergo platform, kushti, when I use AI to
code, or even when I don't, it's the easy
part. It's insane how easy it is to
interface with the tooling and the
blockchain, the node, the explorer, all
the API endpoints. So easy. The hard part
is the actual app itself.
So I always find myself wrapping up the
endpoints and how I'm going to interact
with the chain, and that's done super
quick. And then the rest of the time is
spent trying to get the damn front end to
work properly or the back end and that
kind of stuff. So it's really nice to be
on a chain where integrating with a
blockchain is not the issue ever, usually.
It would be interesting to get into some
high-level definition of financial
contracts using templates, contract
templates we have in Ergo. AI, so probably
then not so much, you know, freedom for AI
to get here into its hallucination, so it
would be quite interesting, and yeah,
well, results should be solved, but yeah,
well, we need to do some things, but yeah,
well, there are some MCP efforts for
getting LLMs working with ErgoScript and
yeah, I haven't tried them yet, to be
honest, I need to do.
But yeah, so what's great about AI, you
can do some trivial things like tests,
right? So when you have like five tests
already and I need to do like five new
ones with just different conditions for
inputs and outputs, then yeah, well, it's
saving hours, right, easily.
So, well, you can do copy-paste, right,
and then going through hundreds of lines
of code to find those conditions and save
them, and it's quite boring, and AI is
reducing efforts heavily there. So yeah,
that's great, and also using AI for now,
well, writing some proposals, right, but
it's not I think quite useful to use its
output right to just hide in our code
space and send like some people are doing
but yeah yeah yeah well you can prompt and
then get some structured ideas right and
then just fill your document but actually
with your own wording because well AI is
too kind of lengthy and
Double explains things, double reasons
things. It's fairly somewhat obvious at
this point still, especially if you're in
correspondence with a person already. I
got an email the other day from somebody.
They were requesting something. It was a
couple of paragraphs long. And I wrote
them back on Teams. And I was like, did
you put this through AI to make this
request? And they're like, yeah. I was
like, ugh. So it can be pretty obvious
sometimes.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's too wordy usually,
right? Too much water and sometimes also
some hallucinations there.
What's your tool you go to when you do
use AI? Is it ChatGPT or Claude or
something else?
So for text, it's just DeepSeek. So,
yeah, it's free and it's... You want me to
click? No, just the websites. They have
this quite interesting reasoning mode,
which is quite funny sometimes. But yeah,
I'm not using it heavily, so it's just, I
don't know, maybe once a week, once a
month, something like that.
And for all codes I'm using, yeah, Claude
Sonnet and Cursor IDE. Also tried IntelliJ
IDEA with its own AI assistant, so it's
front-end. So many back-ends, I believe,
such as Sonnet, DeepSeek and so on, but
yeah, it's not working so well for me at
least. It's quite interesting but also
quite limited.
You need to be inventive to bypass the
limitations, to boost your productivity
and not to have it downgraded.
Yeah, no, no, exactly. When I was coding
with Mark and Kenan for the hackathon, the
tools were using OpenWebUI and LiteLLM.
There's a certain way you can get them to
kind of talk to each other. And the AI
platforms I was using really thought it
knew how it worked, and it did not. And I
find myself arguing with it at 2 a.m. and
I was like, what am I doing? Just stop
wasting your time and just write the damn
thing yourself.
So that's what you end up doing, but you
get to that threshold and you're like,
okay, this thing obviously thinks it knows
what it's talking about, but it obviously
doesn't. So I think that can be dangerous
to somebody who doesn't know what they're
doing and it's gonna waste a lot of their
time.
All right, and yeah, so a lot of things
going on around, right? There was some
buzz on Twitter in regards with Kaspa
integration into Rosen Bridge and Tari.
Right, that'll be great, yeah.
Well, as far as I know, both are now
communicating with the Rosen team.
I just hope that people can really get
over this siloed approach of tribalism,
right? I think we see that again. I saw
that on Twitter the other day when Kaspa
was posting about somebody's posting about
Kaspa joining Rosen Bridge and something
and somebody posted from Kaspa about how
much better Kaspa is and that kind of
thing. And I had to switch off the main
account, switch to my own account and make
kind of a not terrible comment to them,
but just a reminder that there's no need
to beat your chest about this kind of
stuff. Like, come on, bud.
It's just such a waste of effort to see
that happen. There's no need for tribalism
in that sense. Especially when Ergo is
better than everybody else, kushti, you
know?
Right, but also, I mean, so you know, if
there is news about, you know, integration
with some centralized exchange, so no one
would say that, I don't know, like Kaspa
is better than Binance. I mean, it's
similar. Yeah, true, true. I mean, Rosen
Bridge is just application. So yeah, so
it's in the same field as centralized
exchanges, right? Not chains. So I mean,
what's the point to start a holy war here?
Talking about centralized exchanges,
they're disgusting. I'm not sure what's
bad they did in the last days since the
last AMA, but I'm pretty sure they've
committed to a lot of nasty things as
usually. Like, I don't know, launched 100
meme scams from their own department labs
and so on. Just every day they're doing
some pretty disgusting stuff.
All right, so do we have Dan now?
We have Dan the Man Freed Man.
Wow.
Wow. And you're talking about doing
disgusting stuff. What did you do QX? What
was that? What happened? We talked about
this already. We talked about the stuff.
It's great to see you, Dan. I've missed
you since last week. What's new in Palm
Economy, Dan? How's it going there?
You know, it's going all right. There's a
lot of palms. A lot of palms. Yeah. A lot
of palms. Actually, Theo just came back
from Africa, from Nigeria. And so we are
going to be onboarding cocoa and
pineapples.
Nice.
Two of my favorite things. Yeah, yeah.
Cocoa and pineapples. I said cocoa, not
coke. But unlike when you see these are
pineapples, not pinecones, which is
probably, you know, what some people call
you. Now, pineapples over there, they
apparently have a problem with... Well, so
the supply chain has a problem with
standardization, so they don't have agreed
on standards and QA for these pineapples.
There's actually a photo that Theo took,
that he took in, I'm not sure if it was
Benin or Nigeria, it was either Nigeria or
Benin. I think it was Benin, actually,
where they literally throw away like some
ridiculous amount, like 30% or something
like that, just because they can't
standardize it.
So this is actually one of the reasons
why they're so interested in Palmer Pro is
because it'll help them track the entire
process so that they can do QA a lot
better, as well as other things that are
needed for soft commodities operations to
keep track of stocks, keep track of
growth, processing, and all these
different things.
So, yeah, there's a lot of interest
there. And also, in Nigeria, the cacao
trade. I don't know if people know about
this, but cacao is chocolate, and people
know chocolate. Well, chocolate is
actually, there's quite a lot of shady
shit happening with cacao because of the
various different regions and middlemen
between, say, the west where a lot of this
is used and a lot of the African countries
that produce this cacao, some are actually
government-controlled monopolies. Some of
them are actually suppressed.
There's a lot of well, not a lot, but in
some regions, there's a lot of
manipulation going on. And so what that
does is it actually creates real
inequality about the cacao farmer, what
they get versus what this stuff is sold
for. And actually, the prices of cacao,
are you paying attention, QX? What are you
looking at? Somebody giving you a treat?
You look like a Doberman that's about to
get a treat.
I put you up on this big screen over
here, Dan. I have like three huge screens
in front of me. I have like a whole
console.
Don't put me up on a pedestal, okay?
You're already like 5'3". You don't have
to. Keep going about like a cow. Yeah, the
cacao, the cocoa. Yeah, and so the
international prices of cacao actually are
going up. It's getting more and more
expensive. But that really does not
translate to the producer. And a lot of it
is because lack of market access,
gatekeeping, and also lack of quality
control and assurance mechanisms.
And so again, that's something that we're
going to be providing for them through
Palmyra is those mechanisms through
Palmyra Pro using tokenization and
basically track and trace using Lithos
Protocol to standardize these things and
to give them a better chance of just a
more equitable, because I don't like to
use fairness because it's like who decides
what's fair, right?
But if you actually create a more
equitable situation, right? So where you
have the opportunity for people to
participate at their capacity, not at like
what some middleman says or government
says they can and how much, you know,
like, okay, so how much is the government
gonna rob us today? Cause they're the only
ones they can get the stuff out of the
country.
You know, once this kind of stuff is kind
of mitigated by the technology that we
have, and I think, you know, I mean,
that's kind of the ethos of what Ergo is
about. I know Alex is really passionate
about Africa, and I mean, I think that's
kind of like the, some of our core values
are about that, right? So you kind of give
them the tooling, create an equitable,
opportunity-inclusive environment and give
people the opportunity to kind of take
advantage of it.
Did they take advantage of it? And, you
know, just kind of leave it up to their
initiative, right? It's the same with
Ergo, because, you know, we actually have
these conversations at the office. I
talked to Luca about this quite a bit, you
know. And that's just about Ergo. It's not
really specifically about Ergo. It's just
about just in general ethos of the
blockchain space.
You know, there is this sometimes, not
all the time, but sometimes in some
ecosystems, what you get is this like
sense of entitlement. Like we deserve to
be here. You know, we're, you know, like
why did these guys get to have all the
fun? We deserve this space. We, you know,
we're getting, we're oppressed, we're
suppressed.
And to a degree that might be true, you
know, with various different micro or
maybe some macro environmental, you know,
I guess, whatever you want to call them
causalities. But for the most part, you
know, it's about providing the, a
blockchain is supposed to provide the
tooling and the environment for innovation
to thrive. What happens after that is not
up to the blockchain.
It's not up to Alex to go out and tell
people to use Ergo. It's about people
using Ergo and then doing business on Ergo
and then getting that business out there,
right? And this is why I chose to start a
business on Ergo and this is why I chose
to, instead of going out there and
evangelizing or whatever the word is, Ergo
to the masses and saying use Ergo, I'm
using Ergo.
You know, I thought that that's the best
way to lead is to I create an enterprise,
a real enterprise, the kind that I keep
talking about, and I've been talking about
for years, on Ergo, and I do it myself.
You know, this company was built, was
started around Ergo technology.
And this is actually what I hope others
would do is take the initiative to start
their own business using this technology.
And so like to get back to what I was
saying, you know, we have to kind of stop
with this feeling of entitlement. You
know, nobody owes us anything. You know,
we owe it to ourselves. We owe it to
ourselves to use technology to build
stuff.
This is why I'm such a big supporter of
something like ErgoHack, you know, because
that's the community taking initiative and
building something and building something
and then then kind of deciding, you know,
if it has legs, if it doesn't have legs,
right? And a lot of really cool innovation
came out of that. I mean, they're building
things like, say, Rosen Bridge, for
example, you know, and that came out of, I
mean, and that's, you know, that's an
innovative new technology that is really
pretty much one of a kind.
So yeah, it's like we should all not have
that kind of feeling of bitterness and
saying, well, these guys are bigger than
us, they don't deserve to be there. It's
like, no, fuck that. It is what it is. If
you think that this blockchain is so good,
and it is, Ergo is that good, build on
Ergo. Go for it. Do it.
And even if, you know, maybe Ergo is not
gonna be number one on the price charts
right above Bitcoin, but you're gonna get
enough business through Ergo for Ergo to
stay relevant and stay strong and evolve
for a long, long time. I think that's the
best way that you can assure that this
ecosystem stays relevant and blossoms and
the rent.
Good rent then.
Right, so yeah, it's about giving the
same access, right, to free markets to
everyone, well, regardless of color,
right, and other factors.
It's transparency as well, right? Same
access transfer. So the thing that I think
humans in nature, especially when you get
up into the level of middleman as Dan is
talking about, there's ultimate like
temptation for corruption, right? Look at
the olive oil business, right? Look how
fucked up that is, right? You know, just
opportunities to keep on shortchanging
people.
And whatever, if you want to do that
stuff, great. But make it transparent to
the user. Whereas, you know, the
blockchain hopefully can do that,
especially with what Dan's doing. So if
you want to sell shitty olive oil, great.
But let the consumer know that they can
trace it back and see which part is actual
real olive oil and which part is, you
know, pine oil or whatever the heck
they're using as a substitute.
And then let the user choose if they want
to buy a cheaper version of that as
opposed to the real thing. Same with
cacao, same with pineapples, all that kind
of stuff, whatever. Corruption will be
visible at least in that aspect. And if it
works out and that's what people want,
then so be it.
And that's actually a really good point.
If we are going to be in this kind of
decentralized new way of community-driven,
non-communist type of community-driven
stuff, right? If we're actually gonna do
it like, you know... in a sustainable way.
You can't on one hand, you know, not want,
you know, or want minimal government
interference or minimum regulations or
minimal like control.
And on the other hand, wait for somebody
to come and wipe your ass because it's
like, those guys are doing bad stuff. You
should really, you know, you should really
like, like that's not, you know, somebody
should tell like, Mom that they're selling
fake olive oil is like, well, you tell
people that are selling fake olive oil
because you're going to use the technology
that is at your disposal to show that you
have real olive oil.
And this is what we're doing in Greece
because we're working with the producers
over there. We're helping them do that
because there is actually a huge problem
with Greek olive oil, just like there's a
problem with Italian olive oil as well.
Just a lot of fakes out there, a lot of,
you know, it's kind of like the Egyptian,
some of it is like, kind of like the
Egyptian, what is it, the Egyptian linen
or the Egyptian silk, whatever it was,
that effect.
The Egyptian cotton, yeah, yeah, it's
like, if somebody Egyptian touches it, it
already becomes Egyptian cotton. Doesn't
matter. It's like kosher, kosherizing
things. Like the rabbi winked at it, it's
now kosher. Anyway, but I mean, actually,
actually, that's actually something else
that I've been really considering getting
into is kosher certified kosher
certification, because I mean, that that's
like, that that's like a given thing. And
you know what, actually, you know, us Jews
are actually pretty industrious and that
kind of stuff, where like, we don't fight
against technology.
So I think actually, and I haven't really
kind of, you know, put my feelers out, but
I think that potentially could also be a
really interesting field to get into and
to kind of like kosher certification halal
certification you know you could track
your favorite rabbi and only buy goods
that he certified like baseball cards for
rabbis yeah that'd be awesome you know
it's you can like track them like an uber
You know, there's a rabbi within five
minutes away from you. They can certify
your stuff kosher. Anyway, yeah, there's a
lot of opportunity out there. But like I
said, we just can't expect on one hand to
be free and on the other hand to expect
somebody to come and wipe our asses. I
mean, yeah, like you said, going back to
what you said, they can sell shitty olive
oil all they want, but it's up to you to
say, well, you know what? They're selling
shitty olive oil. I'm selling the good
stuff. I can prove it. They can't.
And then the consumer decides maybe they
still want to buy shitty olive oil. You're
not going to force them. You're not going
to guilt them into it. But sooner or
later, if it is a competitive product,
then they, you know, they will switch to
it. They will start using it the same,
like say the same thing with like electric
cars, right?
Just think about, look at the electric
cars, look at the Tesla, right? Electric
cars have been around since like the
beginning of the 20th century, literally
from like the teens. I think the first
electric car was something like in the,
like literally right after the first Ford
started to come out, there was actually an
electric car already that was already
advertised.
And some said, oh, well, the technology
was suppressed by the petroleum industry
and the internal combustion engine
manufacturers and blah, blah, blah, blah.
But bottom line is that technology was
just not mainstream consumer viable. These
things had really short range. There was
not enough infrastructure set up for them.
They were too expensive. They were too
toxic. They were too impractical.
And for years, they were like that. They
were electric cars in the 70s, in the 80s,
in the 90s. And why did Teslas actually
become, and even before that, you know,
they were like the Honda Insight or
whatever I think it was called before the
Teslas came out, you know, that was kind
of a thing thing, but not really a thing.
But why did the Teslas really blow up?
Because it's a mainstream viable product
that makes sense to people versus an
existing competitor like internal
combustion.
A Tesla makes sense because I can
actually use a Tesla the same way I can
use a car, you know, whatever around town.
Because there is a network, I can fuel the
thing up with, you know, I can charge the
thing up. It's got range, it's got power.
It's affordable. There is a support
network that makes sense.
And, you know, it's kind of like the same
thing with this, you know, it's when you
bring a mainstream viable product to the
market, even if that product is nouveau,
it can still penetrate the market really
well and become an actual real competitor
to the you know, to what's already out
there, if that is, like the support system
is there for people to say, okay, you know
what, like I said, going back to olive
oil, yes, there are all of these different
things, but if I get the good olive oil,
number one, it doesn't really cost that
much more. It doesn't really cost much at
all. There's like, you know, the price
difference is laughable, number one.
Number two, it's better for me. Number
three, I'm actually getting real olive
oil, not getting like bullshit with olive
oil flavor. So that's just like, it's free
market competitive viable products that
are utilizing the technology that will win
this fight.
Yeah. Yeah, I agree with Ergo as a
backbone for sure. All right, so we've
got, let me jump in to say that we've got
some preliminary things for the Ergo
Meetup 2025 in Colorado. Dan, are you
going to be able to make it?
I yes, potentially I can actually October
September something like that September.
It's like October 11th or something like
that October 11th now. I just want to
confirm. I just want to confirm so there
was the What was that movie with with with
ice with iced tea? Surviving the Game
Is that like a Disney movie?
No, it's not a Disney movie. It's about
like he's this this like homeless guy that
gets a job and he thinks he's a guide in
like, like a camping place. But he
actually is like hunted by a bunch of rich
people. He actually is like, yeah, because
because he's like, you know,
But Joe's got a bunch of rifles, so we
might be able to do that if that's what
you want.
That's what I'm saying. I just want to
make sure that it's actually not a way for
Joe to trap us on his mountain and to,
what was it, the deadliest game? The Most
Dangerous Game or deadliest game?
Yeah, something like that.
The Most Dangerous Game, yeah. I just
hope it's not that. Or I hope it's not
like... what... Hunger Games. It's not
Hunger Games either.
It could be.
Alright, awesome, awesome. So we have
preliminary, we have, I'll just bank
through it really quickly, but we have
Friday. When people arrive, we'll set a
time where we can kind of group up at
either a local bar or a local pub just to
say hi and meet and greet the people that
have showed up on Friday. Saturday morning
breakfast. That'd be on your own. We're
just going to start the thing at 10 a.m.
for kind of a meet and greet, and then the
first speakers will come on. First
speakers are LGD, LDG, and MiGoreng.
They're going to talk about the uniqueness
of palm staking and perhaps gluon theorems
as well, so that'll be a cool talk.
11 a.m., a little after 11, we're going
to try to get a food truck on site. and
that's when the beer can start flowing as
well. Joe is working or he obtained the
liquor license for the event, for the
venue. There's going to be a speaker at
lunch and that's going to be qx(), if you
guys are familiar with qx(). He's going to
talk about Lithos. He's going to do a
protocol deep dive on Lithos.
At 12:30 p.m., we're going to do
something unique. We're going to try
potentially a hackathon kickoff, a short
one that's an hour and a half. It's going
to be called AI Hobby Devs vs. Old Timer
Devs. And the rules are that it's going to
be a sealed envelope with a dApp that
nobody knows about that's going to be
doable by hand coding devs in an hour and
a half.
And it's going to be unsealed there and
read to the two teams. And the
stipulations are that AI devs, when they
create the app, they need to try to mimic
what a front-end would look like if a dev
was hand-coding it, and I'll get to that
later. Non-AI devs are allowed to pillage
Stack Overflow or their own code from a
project to make it faster, of course.
Judging will be done by three selected
members of the community who will do so
blindly, meaning they cannot watch the
hackathon. They have to go get a beer
somewhere or get a cigarette for the hour
and a half or whatever. Just don't look at
the screens when the hackathon's going on.
I know, right?
So the team goals are build the best app
with the least amount of UX bugs and try
to fool the judges into thinking your
build is actually the opposite team's
build. So judging is based on best app
with the least UI bugs. That's one point
per judge per team. And number two, the
judge has to name the team who designed
the dApp. And if the team fools the judge,
then they get that point.
So the winning team will get a donation
from the Sigmanauts, an award from the
Sigmanauts. We have to vote on how much
that is. So I think that'd be kind of a
neat comparison hackathon. Let the core
devs and the hand coding devs do their
thing. Let the AI kind of hobbyist devs
crank some stuff out. See if they can fool
the judges to see who wrote what. And also
create a neat little dApp that will
actually function well.
So that'll be a fun little thing to watch
while we're all drinking a lot of beer.
2:15 will be an afternoon speaker. That'll
be Aaron on VR. He's going to talk about
Machina Finance, which would be very nice
to hear in person and ask questions about
because we don't know a ton of that. We
just know what Joe's posted on Twitter and
all that kind of stuff.
4 p.m. will be a group hike. We're going
to go to the Paul Intamin Nature Trail,
suggested by Mark the Shark. I hope that
dinners at 7 We can do IHOP on Saturday
morning, Dan. Saturday morning will be
IHOP. I'll put that in there.
I like where it's going.
7 PM will be dinner. We're still taking
suggestions for where that is. And
Sunday's breakfast at Urban Egg. We have
to do a group reservation there, so we
need to know counts. But I was going to
say, kushti, are you able during this time
to zoom in and give an afternoon welcome
or something like that?
Oh, let's see. So I'll try to get a visa
in the first place in July and then, yeah,
let's see. I mean, the chance is probably
minimal, but let's see.
That's amazing. If you can't get a visa,
then that'd be great if you could zoom in
and we'll have you up on the screen. We'll
also live stream. We'll live stream all
the talks to the community. We'll also
live stream the hackathon. I'm going to
bring my gear so we can extract the
people's monitors, essentially. And we'll
live stream all their code monitors on the
screen so you can see the two different
teams.
So it'll be quite the watchable event
from off the in-person event part of it
too. But super excited to see people that
are coming and see everybody there and to
execute this thing. So that'll be fun.
Great. I'm glad you two are going to try
to come. That's fantastic.
It's in October, I think, because I'm
going to be in the US in August for Rare.
Actually, I might have to be there in
September because there's a tea thing.
Anyway, yeah, I'll do my best to make it.
I think I can work it out. Yeah, just like
I said, make sure that Joe is not going to
hunt us. Just make sure, okay, QX, you
left now, but then, you know what?
If he invites you back up to his mountain
resort, he probably should be worried.
Okay, so I'm not going to brag, but I do
cardio. And I tested it. I don't really
exert myself in just running through the
station or whatever. But I have put it to
the test before, and I'm just like, holy
shit, I'm not dead. So I don't know if
you're there yet or not. I don't know how
far you can sprint away from the men
hunting you, QX.
You just have to be faster than the
slowest guy, Dan. That's it. That's the
only requirement. So I think we'll be
fine. So that's what I'm saying. Are you
the slowest guy? I'm pretty fast. We'll
see. We'll have to do a foot race. Let's
drink a lot of beers and do a foot race.
You're pretty fast at IHOP. That's about
it.
All right. We got a question from
Kufurums. He wants to put some Ergo miners
in Argentina. Is there any source where I
can read like a step by step? That's
awesome. I would say Kufa, you should join
the Sigmanauts mining group. And even if
you don't mine to that pool, there's a ton
of channels in there where you can talk
about mining, you can talk about card
tuning, you can talk about what rigs to
do.
Mark the shark's in chat here. He runs
the mining pool. So yeah, jump in the
Sigmanauts mining pool. I think you'll get
a lot of community response there and help
you out. It's very non-competitive, very
accepting, very, very welcoming. What
else? We got any other questions, Dan?
All right. And that time, so just now,
Ergo Foundation, it seems, announced a
raffle for Banxa integration. QX, maybe,
you know, more details about that?
I don't.
All right. So guys, please check the news
channel. Let's see.
That is Banxa, OnRamper and Banxa
integration. Oh, interesting. This may
have been what's been in the works for a
while. Yeah. I didn't think this had US.
This is fantastic. Oh, yeah. I don't think
it has New York. This is fantastic. Yeah,
it doesn't have New York or Hawaii or LA.
So there were a few. Yeah, I remember
Glasgow talking about this. There's just a
few US restrictions, but that's OK.
I have my Peruvian passport to buy this
stuff anyway.
But they're everywhere, right? This New
York. But can you actually go from New
York to some upstate town by there? That
doesn't work.
You could know you need to put in your
driver license on this site,
unfortunately. So it gets you. Yeah,
unfortunately. But it's OK. You know, I
still have my path, at least. I can either
buy it with my wife's Peruvian passport.
She buys it or else I buy it through
Coinbase. I do the ADA. Well, actually,
smarter, I buy stable coin and then
convert it over to after it gets out of
Coinbase. I'm not going to say why I do
that, but I think people can understand
why someone would do that.
Why do you do that?
I think you know, Dan. That's awesome.
That's fantastic. Great. Yeah. So
everybody go to ergoraffle.com. I'll
actually post a link right in chat right
here. There we go. If it'll let me post a
chat. There we go. I just posted it in
chat. Go ahead. Let's, let's community
race for this puppy. 20K is a drop in the
bucket to give direct on-ramp access.
And what would be awesome too. So Joe and
I were both looking separately as well for
kind of like MoonPay US on-ramp options.
And the option that I found, of course, a
while ago did not have US yet. They were
planning to do it but you know that was a
year ago and they still haven't executed
that plan so and Joe found one as well
that was fairly around this price as well
but I can't remember what the deal with
those is but this would be awesome could
you guys imagine something like this
directly integrated into Rosen Bridge you
go to Rosen Bridge you click what you want
on whatever chain you want you type in you
hook up your credit card you make the
payment boom you exit from Rosen to
whatever chain that is connected to that
you want. No more like Coinbase to
SimplePay or whatever the hell that stuff
is, you know, off, you're just boom boom.
Fantastic.
Now, guys, don't get your hopes up too
much. The fee on this is probably gonna be
a little bit more expensive than like
going through a centralized exchange, but
that's very attractive to a lot of people,
especially in a market as it is now when
the token prices are supposedly going to
be much higher in years from now. So yeah,
awesome. This is fantastic. Great job, EF.
This is great.
All right. Good job. Good job.
We got any other questions, Dan, kushti,
that you want to answer?
Yeah, yeah. Do we have, so, yeah, we have
10 more minutes, so let's take two or
three questions, because... All right,
let's see.
This one's for you, kushti. How do you
think ChainCash and Dexy will play in the
market? Any chance at attracting users
that weren't here before, essentially, new
users? Getting new people because of it?
Yeah, so, well, for ChainCash there is
need, right, to find end users because,
well, it's kind of like assembly language
layer for monetary systems, I believe. So,
yeah, you can use it on very different
levels from small communities to, well,
international trade between corporations
and so on.
You think there'd be like an opportunity
with ZenGate or Palm Economy? You know,
they're already in those kind of places
with suppliers?
That's what we're actually discussing and
that's what I'm also talking about with
some parties, but I cannot announce
anything. Yeah, well, you know, we have a
variety of assets, good assets now, well,
available. For example, if we take Africa
for international trades, like tokenized
real world assets, right, and well,
cryptocurrency for forecasts. And then,
yeah, they can be combined using
ChainCash.
There are some other schemes on Ergo,
which are of interest. In particular,
well, insurance with stable coins, that's
where I think Dexy Gold, and then Dexy
Silver, Dexy Lithium, and so on. Stable
coins would be useful, right, so not just
to be used in DeFi, right, just as a
hedge, for example, if you hold some
portfolio, so you may have some, well,
ERGs there, right, and also some gold,
right, to hedge.
Stable coin based gold algorithmic stable
coin based but I think another good option
is to have a buffer rights and trading
physical assets by using stable coin
digital twins so for example using Dexy
Gold to do insurance for physical gold
non-delivery, right, non-delivery risks.
And yeah, to also sell, for example,
non-produced tokenized lithium, right, so
you may use, well, Dexy Lithium buffer for
insurance. That would be quite
capital-efficient, right, even considering
capital-inefficient designs such as, well,
Djed, Gluon, right, for security, but
basically in most of algorithmic
stablecoins, right, for security of
pegging, you are paying with capital
inefficiency, but then there are some hot
talks, I mean, how to use them in real
world applications.
And I think this is not an issue, right?
If you are using algorithmic stablecoins
as a buffer, right? So you just need for
some are not so big amounts, right, to
provide insurance for non-delivery, right,
and like that, right, you can also use
them for settlements on the right. So,
yeah, well, there are lots of different
possible applications here.
So, I'm discussing and there are also
some simplified designs such as basis,
which is mostly off-chain simplified
variant of ChainCash proposed recently
over the forum. And currently, some pals
of mine are working on Gitcircles, which
is kind of framework to create community
currencies for developers of open source
projects, right, using similar ideas, but
actually they think to start even with
simpler options, so with just on-chain
tokens and on-chain DeFi, such as using LP
pool, just right to sponsor an open source
project, for example, but yeah, I think,
well, off-chain option would be quite
appealing in the future, right? And yeah,
so for ChainCash itself, so yeah, well, we
are doing different talks under the hood,
and then probably it would be better to
consider some concrete applications,
right, and make initial UIs towards that.
Awesome. All right, we've got a couple
more.
But maybe Dan also can have some opinion
on the Dexy Gold and the other algorithmic
stable coin assets in the presence of
physical twins.
Yeah, so this is actually something that
I spoke about before. This is kind of like
the continuation of what I spoke about
when I mentioned this months ago on
socials that we would be working on a
hybrid lithium, pegged lithium backed
stablecoin. And so this is actually what
kushti's talking about right now. So we
actually, you know, I spoke with kushti
about this several times, spoke with Sam
about it several times. It took a little
bit of time to flesh it out. And really, I
mean, that's what, you know, that's
essentially what we're talking about here.
Yeah, and so I think that this is
actually, this would be very big player in
regions where you have restricted
movement. In the case of lithium, for
example, if you have, for example, market
manipulation, and so you have restricted
logistics, for example, you have a smaller
lithium mining facility and you are being
thrown, you know, monkey wrenches in your
plans because the logistics corridors are
controlled by somebody, right? That
happens.
One of the biggest issues with lithium
mining is actually logistics. And in fact,
the big companies, you know, the Chinese
companies and whatnot, they actually bring
in their own logistics. They literally
just bring the whole thing in. They don't
even bother trying to put it together
locally. They bring it all in just with
them.
So if you're a smaller organization,
that's actually a big major thing for you
to consider is logistics or lack of
logistics. And so again, what that creates
is a delay in delivery. So it's not a
complete inability to deliver, but it's a
delay in delivery. Another one is
potential price manipulation by some
adversarial actors.
So you have some of these bigger
producers or lithium producers, they will
manipulate the price because they control
a good chunk of a certain region's lithium
production. And if the lithium price is
too low, they'll stop producing the
lithium. Right, and since they actually
have the logistics network and the smaller
places don't, the smaller places won't be
able to take their lithium to the buyer.
And so they're going to have to wait. And
so even if they have a buyer for the
lithium, they won't be able to make
delivery. So what do you do in that case?
Well, in that case, you still want to keep
your operation going, right? You can't
afford, if you're a smaller operation, to
shut down like the big ones do. And if
you're a multi-billion dollar operation,
yeah, you can shut down and whatever, you
know, you, you, you'll be okay. It's all
kind of balanced out, but a smaller guys
is going to kill them.
So what do you do? Well, if you have
this, lithium peg, lithium backed stable
coin they're using, and you have this kind
of this, you know, insurance feature built
into it where you can actually still get,
still get payment and utilize the
stablecoin based on promised reserves.
But for the coin to keep stability, it
has to then accommodate with pegged assets
and with algorithmic assets, then that way
you can basically have a chance to sustain
your business until you can actually
fulfill that. And so it becomes
algorithmic at that point. You can still
pay for new things. You can still utilize
the asset. And then when you make
delivery, then it goes back into the
reserves.
So that particular part of the lithium
can go back into the reserve. We can
basically fulfill a lithium delivery so
that it becomes backed again instead of
pegged. I think there's quite a lot of
real-world practical applications for
this. Of course, it needs to be fleshed
out, logistics of it and everything needs
to be fleshed out. I think this is a big
deal and it could potentially really
create that opportunity inclusion that I
keep talking about. I'm just really
excited to be able to work on this with
kushti.
Wow, he just spilled the beans. Alright,
it's 10 of 2. Let's see, we got anything
quick that we can do? It's like 3am for
Dan there. He's got to be tired.
Yeah, I got I got a I got a Palm Discord
AMA right now that I'm Oh for so All
right.
Sounds good. We'll wrap it up. Just
reminded everybody to please I spoke with
Joe this week after the AMA last week. We
are going to put his medium votes for
Rosen up on Paideia for votes. So if
you're a Sigmanauts we have to vote on our
decision there.
And just in short, that's part of those
proposals is to provide liquidity to the
DEXs, as well as do some air drops to
Cardano side with Rosen ERG so that we can
buff up our wallets for potential
centralized exchange listings. So if
you're not a Sigmanauts and you don't have
power to vote, you can still rally the
Sigmanauts. You can still rally all the
GARD's that are also voting.
You know, think of them not as your
representative necessarily, but if you can
give them a compelling reason to vote for
why you think they should vote for that,
then don't be afraid to talk to them. Get
out there and campaign, essentially. But
yes, great.
And I'll post something on the web with a
tentative schedule, as well as the GitHub
sign up and the little document sign up
for the Ergo Meetup. So please sign up and
join if you're going to make it. Great.
Close it out, kushti, please.
Yeah, so have a good day, Ergonauts, and
yeah, well, have a busy time, and yeah,
well, let's get the wider adoption
together.
I'm all for that. Let's do it. Great.
Great to see everybody.
Yeah. Thanks a lot, everybody. Yeah. So I
guess what? Next week, same time, same
place, same channel. You got it. Sounds
about right, yeah. Probably the same
people.
Maybe, probably, would be good to see Joe
again.
Yeah, let's see Joe. Let's get Joe here
as well. We got MiGoreng can warm up as
well for his speech at the meetup. Yeah.
Get them all tuned up.
Why are you going to let this guy on?
Yeah, he sees all right.
He's all right sometimes. All right guys.
Ciao.
All right guys. Thanks a lot. Good day.
Bye. Yeah. Barely alive from Japan signing
off.