Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, everybody.
Long time no talk.
Seems like I haven't spoken to you guys
since last year.
And that's probably because I haven't.
So it's the first AMA that I am on for
this year.
Glad to be here.
And so with me, of course, I have kushti.
Say hi to everybody, kushti.
Hey, everyone.
How's it going?
All right, so what's been happening?
Tell me what's been happening.
I've been away, I feel like I've been
away forever.
Yeah, so Happy New Year, Happy Orthodox
Christmas.
And before it was, how's it called?
Protestants, Catholic Christmas, I don't
know.
Probably both, right?
And yeah, so soon in three weeks, we will
have Chinese New Year.
So a long holiday season.
All right, so a lot of things going on.
I believe on your side as well, right?
So how is Lithos flowing?
Right, right.
So we have quite a lot of smart contract
dissection and the auditing and things
like that happening right now.
So this is with Palmyra and we've been
going over our, well we're getting all the
smart contracts audited right now. We have
several utilities going on live. We're
gonna have the full traceability suite
also being basically going online and
going live and we're introducing a new
product that is going to be utilizing it
heavily.
So we have to make sure that everything
is working right.
And it is, there's no big issues or
anything like that.
But it's going to be really exciting
because we're going to have a new product,
part of the Palmyra platform that is going
to utilize the blockchain for traceability
on a more regular basis.
So that's exciting.
Now from the lithium side, so that's also
very interesting thing that we've been
doing right now.
So the first thing that we started
working on, well, I think the first of
many vectors, of many vertices that we've
been pursuing in Argentina is the
decentralized lithium pricing index.
And so this is actually going to be an
opportunity to utilize Ergo oracles
because there's going to be a need for
many different types of oracles.
And it's basically going to be kind of
almost a fee market type of system.
And the oracles, various different
oracles are just going to have a chance to
participate and to utilize a reward
system.
And so to kind of give the basic
breakdown of what it is.
With commodity trading, there's a lot of
times, most of the time, in fact, pretty
much all the time, with major commodities
out there like gold, silver, copper,
there's an index.
There's a unified pricing index that
basically says that the price of gold
today is this much.
LBMA gold, for example, and this is where
everybody goes and checks and trades and
kind of knows what's going on.
This does not exist for lithium, and as
weird as it is, as big as lithium is, this
does not exist for lithium.
There are many separate pricing indexes,
but they're fragmented.
There's one for the LME and the CME, the
London Mercantile Exchange and the Chicago
Mercantile Exchange.
There are some that are being tracked by
the S&P.
In fact, our partners, Atómico Tres, they
are actually the ones that report to the
S&P.
They're the pricing providers for the
And so it's pretty fragmented.
And so what happens is, because it's so
fragmented, it gives a lot of room for
price manipulation.
And so there's regions out there that are
less than honest about their price
reporting.
And so they try to manipulate the price
to make the price go up to get things
going along more so they can make more
money.
And so this screws it up for everybody.
And that's why there's no unified price
index because you don't really know who to
trust.
And so you only can go to only a select
few parties that you can trust.
And so this presents an opportunity to
create a unified price index that is going
to be utilizing a reputational scoring
system, and also utilize a specific
algorithm that was designed by Atómico
Tres that will actually basically
compensate for expected price manipulation
and kind of balance things out.
And so we're going to be putting that
into effect.
And so for this, we need oracles.
These different oracles, they need to
basically, they're going to be getting all
these price feeds from all over the world,
and they're going to need to bring those
price feeds on chain.
for the protocol to be able to average it
out.
And so there's going to be a lot of
opportunity out there for this.
And so for the price oracles, so how is
this going to make money?
The way it's going to make money is it's
actually going to be like a Bloomberg
terminal, which is a subscription service.
And so there's many different parties
that are looking for this.
They're looking for a clear, unified
price index.
And this one is going to be
decentralized.
It's going to be on chain.
It's going to be auditable.
Very transparent, and this will attract
players into this ecosystem to utilize
this.
Because like I said, this is a big
problem in the industry.
So decentralization is going to be a big
aspect of it.
And so the fees are going to be coming in
from people utilizing this.
And then these fees are going to be
partially distributed to the various
different oracles that are in the
ecosystem.
So hence, you will have this really
healthy Oracle ecosystem that is going to
be supplying information and bringing it
on chain.
So it's a very exciting project.
So we're at the end of the preliminary
planning stages right now.
We're going to start banging out some
code and some prototypes really soon.
And yeah, I'm really excited, like I
said, because it gives us the ability to
utilize various different types of
Oracles, including our Ergo Oracles.
And it'll also give incentives for people
to spin up more oracles.
So yeah, just a really exciting project
to be able to spin up.
And that's not all.
That's only the beginning.
I can go on about all this other stuff.
But that is really the first thing on our
plate right now.
So yeah, that's what's been going on in
the world of lithium and whatnot.
So, yeah, how about you, kushti?
I mean, what's been going on in the
ecosystem?
Yeah, first of all, that's quite
exciting.
So I think, yeah, Oracle pools is quite
natural design for multiple oracles,
right?
So submitting lithium prices.
And then, yeah, it would be good to have
lithium-based stable coins, right, for
different purposes.
So for clearing physical lithium and so
on.
So yeah, that's quite exciting.
So this will actually give us a base.
It's actually really neat. A tool to
create then the lithium stable coin that
we've been talking about, because we'll be
able to then get these unified price
feeds, so we're not going to have to kind
of guess who's giving us the right
information, who's not.
So yeah, it's a big, big value add I
think and that's why we're starting with
this and not with the stable coin.
We're starting with the lithium index
because there's going to be an immediate
impact with it.
Right so yeah actually that makes a lot
of sense that's how we started with Ergo
actually so we started with oracles right
oracle pool design and then yes stablecoin
followed so that's yeah understandable
especially if there is no well established
price feed right as you told I mean if
there are multiple sources of truth then
yeah the first question is which one to
project on the blockchain right right yeah
that's yeah very interesting so in regards
with Ergo ecosystem so
Yeah, well, it's like, you know, there
are no holidays, so a lot of updates.
So, yeah, well, in the first place, I've
published, well, a near final draft of
sub-blocks CIP, right, and doing some
prototyping codes now.
So that would bring maximum performance
possible for proof of work peer-to-peer
network right real peer-to-peer network
and real proof of work so the design is
based on distinction between input blocks
and ordering blocks and I believe for
other networks also going this direction,
right, like Cardano.
So I've heard that they also are planning
to use similar structure, but also well in
touch with Bitcoin Cash folks, developers
and so on.
They even have guys well somehow
associated with Bitcoin Cash, even have
some papers published on quite similar
design called Tailstorm.
And so on.
So, yeah, it seems different.
Ideas are converging, which is not
surprising considering that we are in mid
2020s, right?
So, well, this field is established quite
well now if we are talking about
peer-to-peer networking and consensus.
Well, still a lot of things going on in
regards with cryptography.
So we had extensive chat before New Year.
So that's for you then, probably not for
community.
So, well, we had a community chat on
post-quantum options, right, which was
quite hot topic in December because of
some new quantum hardware appeared.
Then there are actually a lot of new
cryptographic schemes appearing like every
day.
So just yesterday there was a new
announcement of well-efficient zero
knowledge scheme for incremental
verifiable computation called Micronova.
It's quite efficient even for validating
proofs in Ethereum contracts.
It could be adopted for verifying
something on Ergo as well.
So checking stuff like that and then yeah
so for our 6.0 well there is a security
audit ongoing right now so well Dusek
found a few issues to the moment, so I'm
finishing working on fixes and then we
will have public testnet deployments.
So, well, protocol client version for
public testnet 6.0 client, I mean, will be
published around the beginning of the next
week, if no more issues will be found.
Then, preparing also new minor releases
for Sigma interpreter and the protocol
client.
So Sigma interpreter will contain a new
ErgoScript function, basically a form of
macros for, well, deserializing well,
typed scripts, which is useful to do kind
of P2SH contracts even in ErgoScript, so
before they were made in ErgoTree, so kind
of low-level language.
Now it's possible to use, well, all that
stuff.
like P2SH contracts in a higher level.
Language also, Merkle trees, finance
state machines and so on.
So actually a lot of exciting stuff.
Then, yeah, a lot of things going on in
the community as usually.
So, just few days ago, liquidity pool was
launched for the first storage rent meme
coin, PHP, so someone minted PHP coin back
in 2020 and four years after miners
collected the whole supply of it and then
it was relaunched as a meme coin which is
quite interesting that you can recycle
tokens being lost and may make them meme
coins even.
Then a lot of things going on in
MewFinance land.
Check the vibrant community, the groups.
A lot of things going on there.
Then, well, there is community attempt to
launch Oracle Pool version 2.0 based
oracle pool for USD so yeah well there is
a group for that please join also if you
want to participate and
Yes, so in Dexy developers group we are
now talking how to deliver UI that there
is need for contributors to finish,
publish UI and to launch Dexy Gold.
Finally, then hopefully Dexy USD and Dexy
lithium and so on Dexy silver so for
silver well connectors done so well now
it's time to launch an oracle pool
There is some progress with Nautilus
mobile.
Finally, a contract is signed with a
counterparty.
Audits of ledger code, so hopefully in a
few weeks then Ergo will be in Ledger
Live.
Keystone integration also going quite
well.
There is initial draft of PR in the
repository and IgniFox is working on
completing that.
There are some positive news about
Binance Smart Chain Bridge testing.
And so on.
So a lot of news, well, getting on my
radar.
So probably much more is happening.
So check the updates published weekly and
check community groups and so on.
So yeah, well, it's quite busy time
despite holidays.
Yeah, it seems like I'm not as active as
I was a few months ago actually in the
ecosystem, although we're obviously still
working on Ergo tech.
So we're obviously active, I'm just not
as hands-on as I used to be.
Which is unfortunate, but I hope that in
this new year, I will have more time to
really kind of be hands on again,
especially with this bull market coming.
I think there's going to be a lot more
excitement coming in.
We can participate in some ErgoHack plus
of course, mgPai is now in the EF.
So we have our own part of being part of
the EF.
which is cool.
Yeah, yeah, it's very exciting to see.
Actually, I was approached by a
Argentinian firm that is looking to mine
Ergo, and so we're trying to figure out
how we can make it work.
It's a Bitcoin mining operation, and they
actually have a huge like a huge
operation, huge hash rate, but a lot of it
is ASIC.
And so they can't use ASICs for Ergo, so
they do have non-ASIC mining rigs, not as
many, but some.
They're still very interested in mining
it, especially since we're building on
Ergo.
That's something that I'm really looking
forward to bringing into our ecosystem
once that progresses more, but we need to
talk a little bit more about me and you,
kushti, and I'm also talking to I was
talking to qx() about it.
Who else was I talking to about it?
A couple of people.
Yeah, so we'll figure it out and we'll
get them to participate in the ecosystem.
So it's super exciting.
So we got some questions here.
Let's get to them, I guess.
Well, I mean, we got this.
Yeah.
And so for miners and so on, yeah, it
would be good.
So currently a lot of discussions how to
get more players in the ecosystem because,
well, it's what's making it actually
decentralized, right?
So, well, decentralization is not about,
like centralized team consisting of devs
cable connected with, I don't know, VCs,
maybe even producer.
talking about decentralization.
But yeah, well, it's about many players,
right?
Well, it's good to have many big players,
right, in the ecosystem.
And then the question is how to onboard
them and how to make them...
It's a bit challenging because so many
are just set up for ASIC mining.
Even though they want to come to Ergo, a
lot of times it's a bit challenging.
These particular guys actually, they said
that they actually see a lot of potential
in Ergo and they don't mind that they're
not going to be making a killing doing it
right now because they know that it's
going to increase and there's going to be
a lot of opportunity there for miners
going into this market right now.
So yeah, like I said, we'll figure it
out.
I guess the will is there.
We'll find a way.
So, yeah, good.
So, yeah, well, we need to get more and
more big players in the ecosystem, right?
Yeah, and these guys are big, like I
said.
Like these guys are actually pretty big.
Like I said, the problem is that they
just don't have that many non-ASICs
machines.
Like most of their mining operation is
ASICs, so it's...
Yeah, but they do have some, we'll make
those work and then we'll see maybe what
we can do with the ASIC machines later on
down the line, figure something out.
But yeah, yeah, the hashrate there with
ASICs is humongous, it was like some crazy
number.
Before I found out that about like 90% of
those machines were ASIC machines, I was
looking at this, I'm like, holy crap,
like, these guys are gonna be making a
killing.
Do they have hydro in Argentina I believe
a lot of hydro they're right I mean I'm
sure they do you know one thing about
Argentina and I guess that was kind of
like me well I mean it's like no duh but
you just don't really realize it how big
it is until you get there and it's huge
you know Argentina is a damn large
country.
And so you get all sorts of climates out
there.
You have Buenos Aires, which is actually
a lot like Los Angeles, climate-wise.
Really sunny a lot of times.
The weather is really good.
But then you go to other regions, and it
could get really hot or really cold,
because the South is so close to the South
Pole, that there's a lot of places that
are snow on the ground all year long,
mostly.
But yeah, there are places with
hydroelectric.
There's also places with hydroelectric, I
believe, in Paraguay.
So there's quite a bit of opportunity
there.
Plus, they're also really into
sustainable power generation, so low
carbon footprint stuff, carbon credits,
and so they have all these other means
like wind and solar.
There's solar farms out there because
there's a lot of sun.
in Argentina.
I mean, there's really large patches of
desert.
Like Catamarca, Catamarca is, a lot of it
is desert.
Like a lot of it is like, I would say
Eastern California going into Nevada,
Arizona and Nevada, it really reminds you
of that.
There's high elevations too that are not
as hot, but a lot like where we were in
Catamarca and then in Jujuy and Salta,
that was just straight desert, no doubt
about it.
It was high desert, but it was desert.
And so there's a lot of solar farms out
there.
And obviously wind, there's quite a bit
of wind over there.
So yeah, a lot of opportunities, I think,
and I think they're really hungry for new
opportunities out there.
That whole economy is just really booming
right now.
There's a lot of people kind of waking up
and saying, hey, we got all these things
that we can offer to the world and all
these things that the world can offer to
us.
And let's see what we can do.
So, so yeah, very exciting, good stuff.
And a lot of opportunity for Ergo.
Oh, we got, we got Jume.
I think he used to work for the CIA.
I'm not sure.
Yeah, this guy, I don't know about this
guy.
Anyway, let's get into some questions.
We don't have a huge amount of people
here, but we do have some really good
questions.
So let's go to Augustus Kent here.
So block rewards reduced to 18.
What effect does it have on the hash rate
and sell pressure?
So what do you think, kushti?
All right, so around the past weekend,
well, emission dropped to 18 per block
from 21.
And we are going to have a party in
coming days.
It was proposed by Chris Ray because,
yeah, for him, it's kind of a
psychologically important level, right, I
mean, to have emission falling below 20
and well if it's important for him then
why not to have party I mean it sounds
like a good reason to have party after all
right if it makes at least some community
members happy then why not.
So yeah we will have a party in coming
days in form of I don't know maybe Twitter
spaces or zoom call so please join maybe
with your favorite beverage like carrot
juice I don't know maybe tea with lemon
something like that so
Yeah, then, sorry, what was the question
about?
It wasn't a pear juice, but yeah.
Yeah, so it's wonderful.
It's wonderful.
Yeah, refreshing and healthy beverage.
Yeah, also helping to have parties, for
funny parties after all.
All right, so the question about the hash
rate.
Actually, well, the hash rate was quite
stable, even increasing, because there was
a price increase around the same day.
So, yeah, it was very okay, the
transition to lower emission.
Then, yeah, the question is also about
sell pressure, right?
So, well, effects are not visible.
maybe about this particular drop in
emission but yeah I think overall so you
know like three years ago we had 67.5 ERG
per block going to miners and now just 18
and well yeah well effects are quite
visible if you are tracking deposits to
exchanges right so well it's now
definitely much much more rare event,
right, when you see like, I don't know,
50k ERG transfer to centralized exchange,
right, from a miner address.
So three years ago that happened like
daily, right, because the emission was
about 50k a day.
So now well, there were a lot of small
deposits, but for big miners there were
big deposits happening regularly.
So now, well, the emission is just about
13k a day and definitely much less
deposits.
And so if you if you visit ergo.watch
website, then a chart which is about total
amount of deposit addresses.
on centralized exchanges.
So, you see that currently, well, number
there is about early minimum value, right?
So, well, emission is going on, but yeah,
well, more ERG actually extracted from
centralized exchanges.
So, then, yeah, well, definitely, there
is a factor of reduced emission, so that's
quite visible.
Well, centralized exchanges' balances are
going down and reaching minimum values,
breaking early lows.
Well, week after week, basically.
Which is quite exciting because, well,
centralized exchanges are not good, right,
and, well, if miners are using them, then,
yeah, well, reduced emission is helping to
extract, right, ERG from centralized
exchanges, because, well, having millions
in centralized exchanges is creating
certain risks, right, for possible
redistribution of ERG towards hackers and
so on because, well, centralized exchanges
are being hacked regularly, right, or
being shut down or whatever, so yeah,
folks better to avoid holding on
centralized exchanges.
So yeah, better to pull your ERG out of
So yeah, well, in short, effects are
visible for emission reduction and well,
hash rate is doing well.
All right.
We actually got another one here.
Let's see from Alex C. So any plans to
update the SigmaUSD protocol to mitigate
future bear whale attacks?
Yeah, so there are discussions happening
in the developers' community.
There are five update key holders, so it
depends on the decision.
There are some proposals.
about introducing limits just for minting
both SigmaUSD and SigmaRSV.
There is probably better but also more
complicated and still not formalized
proposal about introducing dynamic fee
rights then making SigmaUSD closer to
Dynamic Djed, right, Gluon to some extent.
So yeah, well, I joined Ergo developers
group and SigmaUSD group.
So for some reason, talks while migrating
from one group to another and then back.
So yeah, well, it's better to follow both
groups to follow all the discussions.
Yeah, then next question.
What is the feasibility of a private
blockchain messaging on Ergo?
So, yeah, that's possible.
And there is, I believe, I reviewed once
an EIP draft about that, so how to get
shared secret key from, well, your key and
just public key of another party.
Right, and then how to derive encryption
key from that, and then how to encrypt
messages.
So, yeah, I forgot an EIP number, but you
can find it.
Well, about concrete implementations, I
don't know.
Well, maybe there was some implementation
done, or some hackathon, but I'm not sure
about that.
Oh, next question to Dan, finally.
I'm talking too much probably.
Dan, you're muted.
I'm not muted, I'm speaking to you
telepathically.
This is common knowledge.
Fine, I was muted.
Well, actually I wasn't, but I'm trying
to make you feel better.
Let's see, yeah, finally one for me,
although I think I like questions for
kushti more because it's much more fun
listening to him explain.
All right.
How many languages do you speak?
Which one do you speak most eloquently?
So let's see.
I speak fluently.
I speak Russian, English, and Japanese.
I speak Ukrainian or used to speak
Ukrainian.
But I'm really rusty, because I just
don't have anybody to speak Ukrainian to.
But it's like one of those things.
It's like riding a bicycle.
Anytime I'm in that environment, it comes
back.
But again, it goes away again.
So it's a weird thing.
But mainly, those three and a half.
Ukrainian if I had more if I had more
opportunity to just speak it would be four
But yeah, the ones that I use every day is
three English Russian and and the Japanese
Which one am I most eloquent in I Mean it
depends
I guess equally English and Russian, I
would say it's about the same.
I can be eloquent in Japanese, but
sometimes I have my brain farts and then I
say something and it just sounds kind of
dumb.
And then I later on, I think about it and
I say, what the hell?
Wait a second.
I know how to say that.
Like, why did I say it like that?
I know how to say this stuff, right?
So it's a never ending battle to not
sound stupid.
Yeah.
So I think that takes care of that
question.
Alright, let's...
Okay.
Well, let's take this question.
I know we get these, but let's maybe
address it.
So yeah, Nabil's right.
Yeah.
So, what do you think about the current
marketing efforts in the community?
And would you have any suggestions for
improvement?
Okay.
So, I mean, again, what has been, I
actually, this would be a really good qx()
question.
Unfortunately, he's not here because
there's something about him and I don't
know.
He caught Ebola or something.
I don't know what the hell is wrong with
that guy.
But anyway, yeah.
So what's been going on with marketing,
kushti?
Have we had any kind of new marketing
pushes or what's been happening?
Yeah, so about suggestions for
improvements.
I actually can talk a lot about
suggestions for improvements.
But then we had a community town hall
call on marketing back in November.
I guess, yeah, it was November probably.
And then, yeah, well, I tried to suggest
some things, but, yeah, it seems, well, a
lot of other people also have a lot of
suggestions and then, yeah, well.
quickly I've got lost in the talk so it
was about one hour and a half so well it
changed well topics and well a lot of
things were discussed and so on so yeah
that's how well things should be maybe
right if we are talking about well
community which is not controlled by a
certain party right which is well
decentralized so well you may have a lot
of suggestions right the question is who
is going to hear them right and consider
Still, I think there is need to improve
some things.
I am working on some improvements
personally.
My main focus at the moment is about,
well, promoting Ergo from a developer's
perspective to developers right.
So as we are now having some positive,
well, pricing right and, well, some buzzes
going around.
Time to get more developers and well if
some people in the community are talking
about well very strange kind of talk so
which fiat price is possible for ERG token
rights
Which is, I don't know, quite strange to
me because any fiat number is just a
mental trap, I guess, right?
So I mean, you can call any number and it
will be reached at some point, but what's
the point in any concrete number even?
That's quite strange to me at least.
But yeah, so what I'm thinking about is
how to get 10x developers right in 2025
for core and ecosystem development.
That would be much more solid right so
talking about well recognition and so on
and then so what's needed I think is some
strong messaging right so I'm looking at
some successful communities around, such
as Bitcoin to some degree, and now Monero.
So what they are good at is about sending
strong messaging about pushing the memetic
warfare around, so that they're filling
Twitter now acts with memes that they're
filling other social networks that they
have.
Well, strong supporters about pretty
simple and powerful messages, right?
Well, Bitcoin maybe not so much these
days, but yet 10 years ago it was the
case.
Bitcoin was very strong memetically.
That's why people did stick with it, like
me, right?
Because, well, their community was pretty
small back then.
Actually, it was quite strong, right, in
their messaging.
The same, well, I see now.
to a certain degree in Monero community
and well I think how to achieve the same
right and I'm pushing people around well
about achieving the same so about well
forming some strong messaging and creating
memetic warfare and spread it around.
It could be on different levels, so you
can attract developers.
with a certain kind of, well, memetic
push even, right?
And then, yeah, well, just ordinary users
like, I don't know, traders, enthusiasts,
hackers, and so on.
There are different audiences, right,
with different requests.
the different needs, new needs for
messaging, including.
And yeah, well, we have already some
brilliant people.
messages around, like Demurrage Louise,
for example.
I'm trying to do some things, but we need
some more, right?
So, well, unlike privacy coins, Ergo,
maybe it's quite complex, right?
Like, well, financial and monetary
systems are, well, very complex as well,
but you can just, well, push some aspects
of it, right?
So like Demurrage Louise is pushing
demurrage narrative to Bitcoiners and so
on.
Because Ergo is quite unique here.
Joy is pushing quite successfully
peer-to-peer finance.
narrative and so on.
So, well, there are many levels here,
right?
And many, many angles.
You can take a look at Ergo tech and not
just tech ads.
So, yeah, those are my thoughts.
So, what do you think about the question?
You have mutes again.
It's only 15 clicks to unmute myself,
sorry.
I mean, I think that, and what's
actually, this is actually, there's
actually really good comment from Wendy
Moon on this.
And so this is actually the very bottom,
sorry guys, I'm gonna go to the very
bottom of the comments here.
She says, when it comes to strong
messaging, Bitcoin has a simple message,
digital gold, money, Monero is privacy,
but Ergo has more complicated message
because it can do so many things.
How do we convey Ergo's message?
I kind of thought about that quite a bit.
And this kind of has to be improved.
But to me, Bitcoin is digital gold.
Ergo is digital clay.
That's what it is to me.
You can, it's ready to create and mold so
many different things and you can make it
in so many different shapes and things
that to me is digital clay.
And I know that might not be the best
kind of marketing phrase, might want to
come up with something a little bit more
eloquent or a little bit more.
I don't know.
I don't know a little something that
something that sounds a little bit more.
But just like I said to me, it's digital
clay because it's Bitcoin, it's Monero,
it's all these things put together.
And it's our thing has always been Ergo
was launched ready to go right out of the
box.
We had all these different things that
other blockchains took time to deploy.
They already deployed on Ergo from the
get-go.
Just like clay.
You can take a piece of clay and build a
house with it.
pot out of it.
It's so versatile.
And that's really the message of Ergo to
me is versatility.
And I think that we are the community
kind of what you were talking about, the
what some call tyranny of the majority or
herding cats, which is basically
centralization, trying to come up with any
kind of unified decision and decentralized
communities like herding cats.
But from that also comes a very, really
clear diversity message.
So that thing that I said where it's so,
there's so much that can be built in it.
That's why there's all these voices here.
It's not just one voice for this one
thing that everybody's obsessed over like
TVL or something.
or I don't know something else that the
other guys are all obsessed about
transactions on chain that's all they care
about Solana's like all Solana made a
gazillion transactions on chain who gives
a shit did the garbage
It's the most disgusting messages from
the messaging probably, right?
Well, that's the thing, and but that is
really the narrative of today's blockchain
field.
Unfortunately, at least, the popular the
popular kids, that's what they keep
talking about.
And I see this stuff, like the Solana
Foundation out there was, I think we were
just talking about that, right?
Just a little bit ago about how, like
Solana has crossed Ethereum in
transactional volumes.
Like, okay, who gives a crap?
A bunch of those transactions fail.
most of them are bots, and they're shit
to begin with.
And it's just like, okay?
It's, I mean, like, just because a city
is filled with people doesn't mean it's a
good city.
So, yeah, it's, with Ergo, it's
definitely different.
With Ergo, Ergo attracts a different type
of contingent.
And so this is why, like I said, the
message is this, a message of versatility.
And I think that's what's gonna work for
us.
It's a longer, it's a tougher message to
get across.
But I think that in the end, it will be a
message that works for us.
I mean, that's what my thoughts are.
And so for Bitcoin, there were many
messages, actually.
So digital gold, maybe not the first one,
historically.
So I've heard about magic internet money,
right?
So that was back in 2011, 2012, something
like that.
Then, yeah, well, money without central
bank, that's what I bought.
So to me, it was mind-blowing to have
money with emission not dependent on any
trusted party.
Somehow, this is not surprising people
these days.
This is, I don't know, quite like a
normal thing, but back in 2011, that was
quite revolutionary to me to have emission
without any trusted party for real.
So we don't have any illusion here.
without any trusted party which is not so
quite visible so maybe influential or
maybe replaced with federation or whatever
so no just no trusted party at all right
and algorithmic emission you have and you
have working kind of monetary system
around that then yeah digital gold
Then, yeah, there was a push about, I'm
not sure about timing, about, yeah, just
21 million, right, so usually it works
well during high inflation period for fiat
currencies.
Yeah, and for Ergo, we also have a lot of
messaging rights, like Demurrage Louise is
pushing for money with fixed supply.
The only one kind of money with fixed
supply, unlike Bitcoin, which supply is
going to zero.
My initial presentations back in 2019
were about digital gold with contracts.
Right, so when you have digital gold but
also with possibility to have contracts or
to build trustless derivatives and so on,
so to have a high-level money systems.
Then yeah, a platform for money right for
monetary systems maybe it's quite complex
but yeah also working for some people then
yeah i mean a platform for peer-to-peer
finance platform for peer-to-peer
financial interactions and so on so well
there are different messages here right
and when you know some blockchain is if
the community is just saying I don't know
we are web 3 layer 1 project with
bazillion TPS I mean
This is just nothing, right?
I mean, you guys are just, I don't know,
trumping the air with unnecessary words,
right?
They're not telling anything, really.
It's smoke and mirrors, that's all it is.
It's smoke and mirrors, it's just, it's
things that people that are perceived as
smart because they're smarter than other
people, they're just kind of hijacking
this narrative and the narrative itself is
really dumb.
But because some people are just too
intimidated by, oh, this guy's so-and-so,
he did so-and-so, they buy into this shit.
And then in the end, I mean, in the end,
it does nothing.
In the end, it's moot.
And you are right, the messaging does
change.
It's not always the same messaging.
It's not always the same thing that is
being said.
And it changes throughout the years.
And so, like I said, it is...
Look, like I said, it's all about the
versatility of the ecosystem, and that is
our strongest suit.
However we choose to describe that, to
me, is digital clay.
To others, it's Bitcoin with contracts,
digital gold with contracts.
It doesn't have to be all the same.
It can be several different ones and it
can be targeted for different groups.
But one thing is certain is that the
versatility is our strong point of
versatility is what we should be pushing.
All right.
Yeah, I think it's about a good time to
wrap it up.
And oh, here's a nice message from White
Cat.
So thank you.
Thank you, White Cat.
It's great to be back.
And yeah, thank you for watching the
documentary.
Part two is coming.
Part two is going to be we're going to be
filming that when we go back to Argentina.
And this is also one of the reasons why
it's so important for us to start working.
And we are working on the lithium index
and all of this.
all this stuff, because when we go back
to Argentina in late March, early April,
we're actually going, we're already going
to deploy this so that we can then expand
on our efforts for that sustainable
lithium mining, because we're going to
have this index, most likely going to have
the stable coin launched, we're going to
have different projects coming on in
endeavor to utilize the STO and the ETO
platform.
Gonna have other projects utilizing
Palmyra Pro, so it's gonna be very
exciting and it's gonna be really cool to
be able to go back there and to really
continue the work because it is super
exciting and you're making a difference.
You just see that you're making a
difference.
Anyway, guys, thanks a lot.
I will do all I can to be and go ahead.
Then maybe last question for you.
Do we have one minute?
So it's from FC.
Then when token launch for Palm, how much
has been raised from a stake pool, funding
crowns, grants, etc.
How many miles you racked up in 2024.
So three questions, so you may cut me.
Right, right, right.
So the Palm Token launch, so it's coming
up really soon.
In fact, we're actually going to drop the
dates, I think, later on.
Well, I guess it's whoever you are in the
world.
In the next few hours, we're actually
going to drop the dates for TGE.
And so that's coming up real soon.
So just watch out for that on Palm
economy.
But like I said, I'd love to say right
now, but I'm going to mess up our entire
marketing comms.
And they're going to be really pissed off
at me if I just drop it right now.
So I'll give them the chance to do their
jobs, wait a few hours.
It's going to be announced.
But it's very soon.
We're basically kind of like the finish
line right now.
There's a lot of stuff in the pipeline.
We got the centralized exchanges,
although we don't like them much, but we
have to work with them.
We got some nice ones for people to trade
on.
We got also DEXs that we are going to be
launching on.
There's going to be liquidity that we're
going to be providing for this.
So there's going to be quite a lot of
action.
for the Palm Token.
Staking is going to go live soon.
There's going to be a new product that I
was talking about that's going to be
utilizing Palm that is going to also
utilize a lot of traceability, that is
going to also be a big value add for the
Palm Holders.
So how much has been raised?
So through everything, I believe it was I
have to look at the numbers, but I believe
it was somewhere in the neighborhood of,
1.5 million ADA, I believe, because we had
several different rounds.
But yeah, altogether, I think it's about
1.5.
And yeah, and so there's gonna be one
last tranche for the public sale that
we're gonna be doing right now.
This is gonna be part of the announcement
as well.
That's gonna be happening in a few hours.
Yeah, and so that will lead us into TGE.
And so yeah, TGE is happening, whether
you like it or not.
It's happening real soon.
It's happening.
Well, you'll know when it's happening,
but it's all lined up.
So just like I said, just wait for that
announcement and I think you'll be very
happy.
And again, thank you for hanging with us,
it hasn't been easy going getting through
the bear market right now.
One of the main reasons we kind of made
sure that we launch in the right time is
because, like I said on our discord, I
just.
could not, it would be irresponsible for
me to launch into the depths of the bear
market.
And I think that the Palm holders
appreciate that.
And I think they will appreciate it even
more because, but once we actually pulled
the trigger and a lot of these things that
are ready to go.
So yeah.
I'm really happy that we are doing it now
and that we have a lot more opportunity
for everybody to have a really, really
happy TGE.
And how many miles have you racked up in
2024?
So, okay, so I have been racking up a lot
of Emirates miles.
But the problem is that only six months
ago that I discovered that I could
actually earn Emirates, because Emirates
are the most difficult miles to get.
But I was able to understand that there's
actually a way to get Emirates miles from
like booking hotels and stuff.
If you go through booking.com, you can
actually earn Emirates miles if you go
through their app.
So I just started earning like a lot of
Emirates miles.
So you would think I have a lot, but
they're all scattered all over the place.
Yeah.
I got KLM, I got Emirates, I got
Argentinian Airlines, I got like everybody
in Air Canada, but they're all just like
little by little by little.
I got Alaska Airlines.
So now the mission for this year is to
have like one unified place where I have
my miles.
It's most likely going to be my Emirates
miles.
And yeah, we're going to finally going to
be able to, I'm going to finally going to
be able to utilize that for if I take 50
flights, I'll probably be able to get an
ice cream or something.
Anyway, all right, guys.
Well, I think this is a good place to
leave it off for this week.
Thanks for all the questions and thanks
for all of your for all your input for
participating because that's what it's all
about.
All right, and so yeah, thanks for
joining kushti.
Like I said, I will be at many more of
these this year.
I will make sure that I make the time.
And yeah, and so until then, so I guess
what?
Next week, same place, same channel,
possibly slightly different time?
Possibly?
I don't know.
We'll see.
Because it is kind of late for me.
It's already 12, 10 a.m.
So yeah, hopefully we can do it a little
earlier next time.
But anyway, guys, thanks a lot.
And yeah, this is Dan coming to you
Barely Alive from Japan, but still
kicking, signing off.
Everyone.