Happy New Year, Ergo.
Welcome to 2025.
How you doing, kushti?
Happy New Year, guys.
So yeah, I'm now trying to update a
pinned post in the Telegram group.
What's a pinned post in the Telegram
group?
Oh, so this is my announcement, actually.
Oh, nice.
Perfect.
A bit late, but anyway, so yeah, it's
just January 2nd, right?
So everything is still quite chilling.
Yeah, catching up on sleep, starting a
new year. Have you done anything
fascinating already this year, kushti?
Not quite, so I'm actually working on
sub-blocks CEP, so planning to present it,
I don't know, like tonight or tomorrow,
something like that, but yeah, just slowly
working on that.
We've been interrupted constantly, so
yeah, let's see.
Not sure it will be done today, but yeah,
I'm working.
Well, that's exciting. You think
sub-blocks will see them, we'll see them,
at least some proof of concept testing
soon.
Yeah. So what I'm working now is how to
pack transactions into input blocks
sub-blocks right and yeah then how to
update state and yeah, what could be rules
for different transactions because some
transactions are depending on, well, block
header contents, right, so predicted block
header, so basically next block and, yeah,
so validity of transaction can be changed
from one input block to another.
So, well, the current proposal is to
allow them in order or ordering blocks
only so well full blocks right in
terminology so like every two minutes on
them but they are like 99% of transactions
it's possible to well, confirm them
immediately.
And then, yeah, the question is how to
update state, how to form candidates and
so on. So you're working on that.
And yeah, so once this is fully clear and
there is some prototype code, then yeah, I
think other parts are quite
straightforward.
But yeah, still a lot of work, but yeah.
I think in a few days it would be quite
clear how to get and what could be time
estimation about getting through the
hardest part.
So these transactions forming and state
updating and then, yeah, it's more or less
straightforward.
A lot of work, but yeah, quite
All right. So is my sound good?
It sounds great, kushti.
It's doing great.
Well, on our side, the Sigmanauts mining
DAO is launching a meme token that we
found during storage rent collection.
So for those of you that don't know, if
there's a box that's reached its age of
four years and it doesn't have enough ERG
to cover storage rent, the whole box is
destroyed and claimable by miners.
And if that box contains any tokens,
those tokens also go to the miners.
So there's a token that CannonQ launched
with the new launch platform and it's a
PHP token.
It's meant to be a meme token that is
gonna be educating.
So I think there's still some room left
if you guys want to help out with that
launch.
But it's kind of a cool concept as we
come along.
I think we got lucky with that. I think
we got the whole supply of PHP.
Somebody had made it as a test token four
years ago and left it in one box.
We're not going to get that lucky as time
goes on, but there are some cool tokens
that were made early on that we will
hopefully grab if we do happen to get
those blocks stuffed in there for that.
So super, super fun concept. They're kind
of recycling and rebirthing these meme
projects as storage rent collects them.
Super neat. Do you remember what that
was? Do you remember what that token was
back then, kushti?
No, any idea who minted it.
I don't know. He found the wallet. He
found out where it came from, what
exchange it came from. They brought money
from an exchange and bought ERG from an
exchange, brought them over and minted the
token and then send the ERG back.
And that was it, I think for that
transaction. So specifically who it is.
Yeah, I don't know if you show me
address, maybe I can tell because back
then there were not many people able to
mint tokens, maybe.
But actually there were wallets back then
with token minting, so.
Oh, wow. So somebody may have just been
playing around and hit a button and then
exited kind of thing.
Pretty neat. Yeah. What do it stands for?
If it's like the web PHP or some other.
Who knows, I mean, that's just me today.
But yeah, I mean, there are some addresses
I can tell about, like Scala Hubs, for
example.
And yeah, there were a few other folks
playing with tokens back then.
But they also could be just some coin
barn wallets user.
So yeah, that's what it's supported.
Talking meeting back then.
Okay. Interesting. Very cool.
So there's that. We also in the mining
pool, we had a fun little bet that I
offered in chat.
I said if we mine a token within the
first 69 minutes of 2025, I'd donate 50
ERG worth of project tokens to the bonus
token wallet.
And we found one with like four minutes
to spare.
So Mark, I think it's going to be
distributing those over some new, I sent
over some Paideia, some air Doge, or no,
some Bober and one of the things as well.
So Mark should be sending those out soon
to current miners of the Sigmanauts mining
pool.
Oh, Kevin says Philippines is what PHP
stood for. It must be in the description
perhaps. Super neat.
So he does now Philippines. Yeah, well,
no idea. But yeah, so probably some
Sigmanauts from Philippines then.
Gotcha. So that's Sigmanauts mining DAO.
That's going nice and strong.
Oh, I got a Christmas present, kushti.
And it's like a handheld gaming computer.
But here's the first thing that I put on
it fully.
Oh, nice.
Yeah, so the thing runs, let me click on
it. The thing will run with controller
mapping, which is really handy.
Nice here.
Everything works very nicely, very
smoothly. You can remap the E and the K
keys. You can car race.
I find it much, much easier on a device
like this.
So I can't wait till Cyberverse comes to
mobile.
That's going to be fantastic.
And speaking of Cyberverse, they also
have their Ronin Mint coming up on, I
believe, the January 6th, where they're
doing cross-chain.
Everybody knows they're on Cardano
already, but also the Ronin network, where
they won that competition and placement
there.
So there's going to be a mint there. So
if any of you guys want to get some
exclusive NFTs that are just minted on the
Ronin side, then you can follow their
tweet and whitelist your wallet.
And have fun over there as well. Super
cool.
But I mean, it's hard to ignore the fact
of what the recognized value of Cyberverse
has done since Ronin, since they've won
that competition at Ronin.
So I'm really interested to see what's
going to happen. Right now there's almost
a hundred players live on a Cyberverse,
which is quite a high watermark, but I've
seen.
So super exciting for that.
If you have a Steam Deck or one of these
guys, try it out. Remap the keys. It's
absolutely fantastic.
It makes mining a breeze when you're
mining Cyberian Ores and watching TV kind
of thing. It makes it super easy.
Yeah. All right. What else? Sigmanauts
are doing strong with our new multi-sig.
I think we started a transaction to send
some tokens for a little bit of
liquidation or donation. I think it was as
a vote upon idea that we pass that we're
just executing.
So that's going very well.
I've also tried to set myself some goals
for 2025 quarter one at least and that is
one of them is to help organize the Rosen
Bridge guards a little better see if we
can get some automations there and get
that going as well as some other things
But yeah, that's pretty much it for the
initial start of the new year trying to
wipe the sleep off my eyes kushti, what
about you?
What are your plans besides the blocks?
Yeah, so discussing with developers in
Ergo Developers Group what could be
realistic and nice plan for 2025.
Which is, yeah, so what I proposed and
what I'm thinking about is mostly oriented
towards what I'm calling peer-to-peer
digital free banking, including options
for peer-to-peer smart contracts powered
on ramp for Ergo and also cross-chain
tests, which would be huge, especially for
assets which are now well-being ignored,
right, censored by centralized exchanges
such as privacy coins, right, and well,
proof of work assets to some degree.
Then, yeah, so I think well, with
sub-blocks still, there is need for some
layer 2s, right? Well, the only question
is what are desirable properties and
what's concrete layer 2s, right? Would be
beneficial.
So I think there is I need to start
discussions, right? Well, applications are
already there and we can think about
optimizations about it.
But yeah, so the idea is to have, what do
we need to have is peer-to-peer on-ramp,
right? Uncensorable, decentralized
on-ramp.
Yeah, I mean, for most of DeFi, the Ergo
network is already working quite fine,
right? So, well, getting along in minutes,
right, is already... I mean, in
peer-to-peer setting, I mean, like issuing
bonds and getting it filled, like it's
already a big deal.
Well, we need for speeds, maybe low fees,
specific use cases like, well, money
transfers, right? where some stablecoin
based layer 2s would be beneficial than
what's on ramp contracts.
Maybe, but yeah, so if it's about
multi-sig escrow, then yeah, so even
current network is enough probably.
So how do peer-to-peer via on-ramps work?
Also, there is a forum post by Mr.
Stahlfeiger on Ergoforum, but basically
the idea is to use somewhat like Bisq,
maybe a UI like that, but yeah, with
on-chain escrows.
So we're talking that miners would, let's
take miners for example, if people are
mining 20, 30 ERG a day with their big
rigs and they have, you know, saved up
hundreds and thousands of ERG and somebody
comes in on this peer-to-peer fiat arm
ramp, essentially it'd be a bid.
They'd say, okay, I'm selling the ERG for
this much or I want to buy the ERG for
this much.
And the contractor would look for some
off-chain oracle that this cash
transaction happened in the fiat world, so
it would release the ERG? Or how would
that work?
Oh, so, yeah, well, maybe it's better to
put ergoforum post from Mr. Stahlfeiger.
But yeah, basically it's like a multi-sig
escrow, right, from participating in the
exchange.
Yeah, and maybe some arbiter party.
So that's how hodl-hodl, for example,
working for Bitcoin.
I see.
And yeah, so there is need for UI, but
maybe even MewFinance is cross would be
not.
But yeah, I mean, we need to find, we
need to start experimenting and then find,
right, so what could be proper UI and
well, concrete schemes around that.
Then, yeah, so transfers, Then there is
need for more stable coins.
There are already talks started about a
new USD pool.
Finally, here people are organizing the
Then there is some work towards silver,
right, oracle.
Then there are plans to tokenize lithium
with also having physical lithium in the
equation.
And then, yeah, so with all those assets
and cross-chain assets, the next step I
believe is to have well-expanding tools
for well monetary expansion right for
expanding monetary supply on top of
monetary base which is about ERG and other
blockchains like ChainCash and so on but
yeah that's the next step right so it's a
bit later to get done.
So yeah, well, that's what I have in
mind.
But there is a lot of other people in the
community building with different visions.
I don't know, physicals, right? Selling
physical stuff.
Right, right. We just sold, we sold three
Mac, no, four Mac Pros, I believe. We
shipped one to middle Europe, three to the
US.
And then I just sold my wife's personal
M1 16 inch MacBook Pro from 2021 or two or
whatever that year is. as well because she
got a new one for Christmas it was amazing
it was fantastic I'm actually about to
ship that out today after I leave work to
Western Europe so it's insane how easy it
is to do you know mint a token with the
information
Post it up on MewMart and then just wait.
It is interesting though, kushti, it's
kind of a game to where you're like, okay,
do I list it in ERG so that it's more
attractive for people just to swipe it up?
Or do I list it in SigmaUSD because I'm
worried about maybe a 10% price drop or a
10% price increase, and then I'll have to
be listed after that.
So it's interesting the process of
listing, of choosing what you're going to
do.
I decided to list in ERG just because it
was easy, and the price did dip a little
bit from when I listed it.
But I was watching it and then of course
it went back up now.
So it doesn't matter in the end but it
was super neat.
So yeah, I encourage everybody if you
have items that you want to sell ever and
you want to become a seller talk to HQx at
MewMart and get certified for a seller
I think he's got a robust list of
personal questions about your... No, I'm
just kidding. I don't know what he asks.
But it's going to be based on trust, of
course.
So if you screw people over, you're going
to be pulled immediately.
And if you're an unknown entity, you're
not going to be probably allowed to list
there.
So that's kind of the trust thing there.
So yeah, I encourage you guys to go there
and look at it I'm gonna probably post
some more things kicking around my house
and I think we have some Mac minis I said
here that we can raise money for the
Cornell DAO as well That we can post as
well, you know those kind of they're like
i5 Mac minis with 16 gigs of ram or
something like that good for good for
little headless servers somewhere Yeah, so
stay tuned for that physicals are really
really cool.
It's so nice to not have to you know, I
guess a good thing for the, for the
seller, at least my wife was saying, oh,
should we, you know, should, do we ship it
yet?
Do you know the money's not in our bank?
Should we ship it yet?
And I was like, yeah, yeah, we can ship
it.
I said, the money got sent via a smart
contract.
I mean, it's in my wallet.
It's not like PayPal can claw back.
It's there for good.
You know, so it was a really nice as a
seller to know that, you know, the buyer's
not going to screw me over at all.
But here, Escrow also could be used,
right?
You could, yeah, 100%. Teller and some
trusted watcher, right?
Yep, yep. Speaking of that too, I spoke
with, speaking of Escrow and fundraising
at least, I spoke with Quokka for an
update as well as Crass and
And Quokka sent me the front end that
he's been working on that's done
essentially for the new Sky Harbor and the
guy working on the smart contracts.
I think the deal was they had an in real
life job that was extremely demanding,
which I mean, an excuse is an excuse.
And it's been a while since the
fundraiser.
But I'll keep pushing on them on quokka
to get that out.
And that brought up another topic,
kushti, about some sort of escrow
fundraising.
So the idea would be, at least we
discussed it in the Sigmanauts.
The idea would be that if you fundraise,
those funds could go into a smart contract
and then a third party could say, okay,
here's a milestone you've met, we're gonna
give you a third of the fundraising.
Here's another milestone, we'll give you
another third of the fundraising.
Here's a final done, okay, we'll give you
the last third.
So I think that's a great way to go in
the future.
Then we're not stuck at these periods
where, hey, where's the product?
You fundraised eight months ago, and it
should have been done in three months, and
you still haven't done it kind of thing.
So we can avoid those things.
Manually, I think Sigmanauts are
positioned to be able to do that right
now.
If anybody wants to fundraise as a
project and do that, you can put our
treasury as the address.
We can track it actually in a sub
address, a derived address in our
multi-sig, and we can track it.
and release based on the terms set in the
auction that people agree to.
So happy to do that now as Sigmanauts if
anybody wants to fundraise and kind of do
that.
But of course, probably HQx might be
working on something else as well at some
point, as if he's not busy enough with his
new life kind of thing.
So yeah, that's really exciting and super
fun, I think.
Yeah. What time is it? 9.25. We got maybe
got some questions.
Yeah, so not so much updates this week.
There was no developers chat yesterday,
obviously.
Yeah, holidays really take a burden on
people, that's for sure.
looking forward towards 2025 so it seems
that there is increased interest now and
yeah it's getting well more and more hot
topic so
Well, people do understand the value of
decentralized communities, right? Well, it
seems again.
It's funny, kushti, it's funny you say
that, because I think people understand I
think people understand their desire for
one, right?
But I don't think they put a definition,
at least mainstream.
You see influences every once in a while.
I'd say every week.
There's some sort of eureka moment by
some stupid influencer who's like, oh, you
know, if only there was this project that
was decentralized and peer to peer and
didn't do rugpulls and didn't do this and
actually had utility and was doing stuff.
And it's like, OK, you know the issue,
but you're too daft to understand or
actually participate in the execution of
it, like Ergo and those kind of things.
So it's funny.
I think people recognize the lack, but
slowly, slowly we see them trickling over
and making that connection to the actual
realized product, which is Ergo.
So I always laugh when I see those posts.
Yeah, so actually, well, I'm
participating now with talks with some big
influencers, right?
And yeah, it seems that they see value,
right? And all that stuff.
The only problem is that they are trying
to extract value as well as they know how
to do that, right?
So I mean... They do. just to find Ergo
and making a deal so I mean it's quite
interesting that they are looking for a
project what they call a blockchain
project without basically then they are
trying to make a deal with it right there
so
That's a little bit skinny. Right. Yeah.
I mean, that's the current state.
So I think it would be, we will get back
to 2019, 2020, something like that.
Hopefully in coming months.
We need to have all those people, so it's
not just the own issue.
That's how the whole space was shaped in
the last few years.
For example, centralized exchanges.
like everything in the space is just
blockchain with team it's not even to
explain them that the different options
then yeah well influence and so on so the
so well getting corrupted with it's right
but yeah well I'm quite positive about
Well, what's known in the community,
right?
How well, different, mechanism balance
and check forming and, how are different,
coming, wouldn't, do, any demo to, to, to,
to eat with, ERG right financial interests
or what's the business financial interest
and so on so when i used to be a pro
phonics so yeah we had some big guy you
know coming and making calls developed
co-co-op receiving for some reason and
well
Half of developers were anonymous, they
made some type instead of jabber chat.
Even in such environment they tried to
get some commitments from co-developers
showing the rights of certain players.
with a core development space.
Hopefully we will see it here, but we
will prepare anyway.
I mean, we need to prepare for a big,
because anyway, they will cut it.
And then, yeah, the query is how to avoid
corruption.
Yeah. You're breaking up space. You're
breaking up a little bit, kushti. You want
to kill some bots on your machine?
Oh, I have a few problems here that are
kind of critical, so probably not now.
Let's continue. I mean, if it's, if it's
okay.
No, you're okay. You're about 90%. So
it's not terrible. We get what you're
saying.
Yeah. Back to influences part. I'm
hesitant to, I was hesitant to call them
in floors, influencers when in actuality
they're not influences.
They're promoters. They're being paid. to
promote a product, whether they believe in
it or not.
I think a true influencer is trend
setting and setting a trend based on what
they believe in and what's great and
something that's actually that they're
involved in naturally and organically.
That's an influencer.
So these things we see on YouTube and
Twitter, those people are promoters.
They're paid promoters.
So it's a really I wish people could see
the difference.
There are people out there that are
influencers that take the time, that
discover things and are doing it because
they actually utilize the product and
maybe have self invested in the product
because they believe in the product and
then they preach about it.
That's an influencer and they set trends.
Most of the stuff we see out there right
now are promoters, that's for sure.
It's given me really sour taste for those
kinds of things, at least.
Oh, kushti, we have to pick some random
numbers for the ErgoSanta for MewFinance
right now.
All right. All right. Yeah. So it's got
to be the range.
Why don't you pick a number from 25 and a
half to 50 and I'll pick a number from one
to 25. and a half you ready so from 25 to
50 yeah you go 25 to 50 I'll go one to 25
all right let me think so you start on me
I'll go first I'm going to pick 13 all
right 13 is my number what's yours kushti
13, so let's... 25 to 51.
25 to 51, so 48.
All right, 13 and 48, there you go, HQx.
So for those of you that don't know,
ErgoSanta is a fun little thing that's
been running for a couple years now.
People donate things to projects and
people donate things to an address.
And then you go and buy tickets and you
open those tickets and it's part of that
distribution.
And then there's some grand prizes.
So we just drew the random tickets.
I'm wrong, HQx? Oh, whatever. 13 and
what'd you say 48 kushti? 48 yeah yeah so
yeah perfect all right yes h here we got
you 51 buddy
Perfect. Great.
All right, what's next? Should we try to
hit some questions, kushti? Let's see what
we have.
Oh yeah, let's try.
Okay. I've been told to stop swearing
because kids are watching. Noted white
cat.
I will refrain from the field of F's that
I've been saying.
Let's see. We have, Jonas, Jonas would
like to know, do we have multi-sig wallets
on Ergo?
We do. We do. We have a very cool
multi-sig called Minotaur right now, which
is on version two.
Huge upgrade from version one.
They're still, I think, in the pipeline
working on built-in messaging so that you
don't have to manually transfer the
signatures to each other with Google
Sheets or something else like that.
or the commitments, but it works very
well.
We just did a transaction test a couple
weeks ago on version two of the Sigmanauts
treasury.
We pounded it out in like 30 minutes
after some struggles with learning, but
it's pretty good.
And then kushti, we also have MGPi is
kind of on the back burner, but he's
developed a multi-sig called Moria.
which is a web-based multi-sig.
You go there, you connect Nautilus to it,
and right now I think it's a test version
of Nautilus, a special build, because
there had to be a little tweak to it to
work.
So you connect that to it, and that's
your signing key, and the server handles
the rest of the stuff.
So you sign, it tells you who's next, and
then they sign, it tells you who's next,
it stores it all, and then it submits it
for you.
That will be a much, much easier
multi-sig experience than Minotaur and
passing the signing keys around or the
signing JSON around yourself after you
sign it.
But I think we're waiting on some code
being inserted into the final build of the
production.
Yeah, there is need for centralized
server here.
I know. Yeah, there is.
Yeah. But yeah, I think there is also
some alternative work on multisig server,
right, for Nautilus, but I've forgotten.
Maybe by Captain Nemo even.
I mean, well, the trick is centralization
of holding those JSON signatures and
commits while it's in the process.
So for those of you that don't know how
multi-sigs work, you have a wallet that's
your signing key that's essentially your
password, right?
And then it combines all those public
keys of your signing keys and creates a
smart contract that's the multi-sig that
only allows threshold spending based on
four out of seven, three out of six, three
out of five, depending on how many yes
signatures you need to push it forward.
So there's two rounds in these scenarios.
There's a commit round where you sign it.
And then there's a signing round where
you continue back up the tree and you sign
again to actually sign it after the
commit.
And then the last person in line
publishes it.
So the idea is you have to pass around
this sometimes you know, 50,000 character
string of JSON file, and it builds as
people tack their signatures on.
So right now, we use Google Sheets for
Minotaur and most of the multi-sigs that
I'm part of, and you just paste it in the
cell and you copy the previous one and you
do that and you copy the previous one,
paste it in, that kind of thing.
So that works, but sometimes when you
have a lot of outputs, and a lot of
inputs, you run into a 50,000 character
limit in a cell in Google Docs.
So then for the old Sigmanauts multi-sig
that we had to extract everything out of
to the new one, we ended up just passing a
text file around in the chat.
Yeah, there's the issue of, like Moria
Finance, do you centralize that process
and go from there?
Or do you develop some sort of on-chain
messaging system, which I thought was
Captain Nemo's or Minotaur's idea that
they would try to implement something like
that in the future where there's some sort
of on-chain messaging where maybe the JSON
is submitted to a block and that's looked
for and brought up there kind of thing, or
maybe it just hits a mempool and then
vanishes, who knows?
It could be anything, but yeah,
definitely trade-offs in that, kushti.
I mean, what are the chances that if I
start a commit, kushti, and I'm multising,
there is not much a centralized entity
could do to screw with it, right?
If before the next person commits to it,
right? They would be known that it was
messed with or could it be messed with
along the pathway?
Yeah, but so you know what's good about
multi-sig and Ergo.
So what makes it unique in comparison
with other blockchains?
So here is threshold signatures is real
cryptographic threshold signature.
So it is preserving zero knowledge,
right?
So for example, if there is you, me and
Joe in a signing rig and two out of three
signatures are needed, right?
And you and me are signing them.
Not any external observer knows that,
right?
And if we are doing that complicated
procedure, then yeah, well, this privacy
is preserved, right, in the ring.
So only three of us.
I actually know, right, who are your real
signers, right?
Because, well, in this case, Joe also
knows that, you know, he didn't sign.
And then, yeah, it's possible to conclude
who are the signers.
But, yeah, it's not possible to prove,
maybe, but you need to check, actually.
I mean, Joe cannot prove that to outside
world.
But I need to check that.
I mean, if just two of us were in the
signing ceremony.
But yeah, so the server also knows,
right, who are the miners for real.
So in addition to Moria and Minotaur
wallets, which is usable and actually
quite good right now, I'm using it.
So there is also alt application, desktop
application, zero knowledge treasury,
which can be used.
It's kind of simple DAO tooling, so you
can create proposals there.
And yeah, basically what with
multi-signature.
Is that what the EF used?
Not yet, so it was used by some Dark
Funds, Zero Funds, which was made of me,
Philippo Units, Martin MX, back in 2020.
So we donated some money, received some
donations to support some privacy-oriented
projects on Ergo.
And yeah, so this tooling is using
multi-sig for kind of voting rights.
So you can create proposal and then,
yeah, other signers are signing or not.
And if enough signatures collected, then
payment is done.
So kind of a very simple DAO tooling,
actually.
And yeah, also with preserving privacy of
waters, which is quite, quite interesting
also.
Speaking of privacy, kushti, I saw a
question on the line yesterday. I think it
was. They're running the open source tool
mixer.
And they're wondering if they could
change the hops after they've already
submitted.
So if they wanted to augment or increase
the amount of hops it takes while they're
in the middle of a mix, do they have to
wait for the mix to finish?
Or can they change that on the fly?
Do you know? Have you ever come across
that before?
Yeah, so I think you need to wait and
start a new mix.
Gotcha. Okay. That makes sense.
All right, let's see. White cat wants to
know is Dan still in the team?
I'm not sure what he means by in the team
in the team. He's an Ergonaut or not.
Yeah. Dan's sleepy. It's like 2 a.m. In
Japan right now.
And Dan's been doing a lot of traveling
to Argentina, for the lithium, lithium
mining kind of stuff that they're working
on with Palmyra.
So Dan is very much around.
I wished him a happy new year, Merry
Christmas.
And he was alive and well.
So I think he's in Japan right now.
So I think he, I think he got back near
Christmas time or so.
Yeah. Dan and Japan. Yep.
So we'll try to have Dan on again. It's
interesting, because either people hate
Dan or they ask where he is.
There's never an in between for Dan.
So this will make Dan happy that he's
wanted by white cat.
I'm going to picture this and make an NFT
out of it for Dan.
All right, let's see. Oh, here we go.
qx() and kushti, what are you guys
grateful for on this new year period?
This is from Gabno.
What are you grateful for, kushti? On or
off chain?
Is it the question?
Yeah, yeah. What are you grateful for? On
or off chain?
Well, he didn't say, so I'm going to say,
I'm going to leave it open for you.
I mean, what do I prefer on chain? What
do you think?
What are you thankful for in life and in
crypto in your experience with crypto in
life?
Give just what do you what are you
thankful for? Are grateful for? I'll go
first.
You want me to go first?
Yeah, so still, well, what I'm interested
in is, yeah, to have crypto for real, you
know, so for like, I don't know, so, you
know, there are a lot of interesting
experiments in how to call this even, like
virtual space, you know, like, I don't
know.
Well, those games like CryptoKitties,
then what do we have?
like i don't know so some tokens with
meme coins without utility and so on,
right?
But yeah, so what's good, what I'm
interested in connecting, right?
Like, well, cryptography and
cryptographic assets, cryptographically
secure assets with real world, you know,
needs.
So that's the most interesting thing.
So then, yeah, cryptography per se, but
yeah, I mean, there is need for
applications, right?
Otherwise you can spend decades with just
playing fancy.
games here like I don't know like
iterating our different cryptographic
schemes and so on like well discussing the
properties maybe proving something coming
up with the new schemes and so on but
Yeah, I mean at some point I think there
is need for real-world applications
otherwise it's just I don't know so it's
about getting grants or just I don't know
some game in isolated space which is not
very interesting to me.
But then, yeah, also, well, software
development programming. But yeah, it's
also that there is need for real-world
applications.
All right, cool. Cool.
I would say I'm most grateful for the
time that we're, I guess, the timeline
we're in, right?
So sometimes I think, you know, it's hard
because, how do I put it? How do I put it?
You know, this is something totally new
and totally like, even though it's new,
it's still, and we have a lot of adoption
in the meme space and the speculation
space.
Ergo is even kind of still true and new
to that.
So here we are kind of swimming against
currents of these things that degrade what
cryptography is and degrade what actual
these decentralized and peer-to-peer
financial tools are.
And we're fighting against that all the
time.
I don't know how many times I've been
somewhere and somebody will say something
like, oh, somebody got scammed on crypto
or look at this scammy crypto.
When they look at me, I'm like, That's
not what I do.
You know what I do is totally different
than these other kind of things that
you're hearing about.
So then I think about like how hard it is
to start these kind of new revolutions.
We're bucking against a system that's
been in place for a long time by very
powerful forces.
So here we are trying to come up with and
promote and encourage actual value that is
owned by people themselves, as opposed to
being at the will of people who have more
power and money than you.
So that's going to be another current
that we're hitting as well.
So I'm grateful that I can experience
that and we can experience that all of us
as part of Ergo right now in this
timeline, right?
So this is, this is a hard part. This is
like the fight. This is the struggle
where, you know, you see in the past
people give up and that's it.
And then some things never, you know,
keeps going.
That's where we're at. I feel in Ergo
because we're fighting against the general
idea that we need safety, we need some
bank to hold our funds and be responsible
for them for us.
We're fighting against a current of crap
tokens and meme projects that are just
extracting value and scams.
So it's not easy.
But at the same time, I'm grateful that
we're here to experience that because it
just strengthens my resolve that this kind
of stuff is what's important and what we
need.
All right, let's see. Oh, HQx messed up,
kushti.
He's 61 entries.
So we have to take 61 and divide it by
two.
So 30 and a half.
Why don't you go from 30 and a half to 61
and I'll go from one to 30 and a half.
I'm going to take 27 is my number.
Oh, but mine is still the same.
So you'll stay at 48. Okay.
Okay. So 27 and 48. There you go. HQx.
We've done it legitimately.
So we have the NFT wizard, new to the
channel has a few questions. What's the
high level mission statement of Ergo?
You want to take that question?
High-level mission statement of Ergo. So,
yeah, well, there is Ergo Manifesto,
right, about that in particular, and we
are doing Ergo Book to include more
materials, like Grassroots Manifesto,
which is not so-so known, right, by Joe.
So I think in very short, the idea here
is to provide grassroots-based
counter-cyclical tools in the form of
peer-to-peer digital free banking.
which means a lot of things when you are
going to unwrap it, such as unsensorable
nature of interactions, right?
And then, yeah, well, you need to have
features which usually only banks have,
you know, even more.
You have your, well, passing money
emission rights to these peer-to-peer free
bankings.
So not commercial banks we have now,
which are emitting most of money and so
on.
Then it means new principles of emission
and so on.
So yeah, like hundreds of different
things, but yeah, in very short, well, the
mission is like that.
Well, to me, I guess.
So what about you?
To me? Yeah, I would say a lot of that, a
lot of what Ergo's high level mission to
me is what I just spoke about earlier in
my rant about five minutes ago.
I think I think humanity at least has
gone through a period of uneducation,
right?
The removal of self-custody and the
removal of the importance of that.
They've traded comfort or power over
themselves and their own entities, right?
So, like I said, they've traded the
ability to know that if they screw up or
if they put their credit card number on a
wrong site, they can call their bank and
say, this was a fraud, and that kind of
thing, and get it pulled back.
So there's comfort in that, right?
I think the opposite should be true.
I think we need to re-educate, and it's a
slow, long road.
And I think there goes a position to do
that, as well as perhaps some other
projects.
re-educate that you're in control of your
funds on a network that I can trade and
create value for with everybody else in
the world, right?
So that means if I screw up, I screw up.
And it's a hard lesson to learn, right?
But it's gonna be a lot of that early on,
I think.
So I think Ergo facilitates that.
Ergo facilitates and puts the power back
into the people's hands.
It allows somebody like myself to run a
Rosen Bridge watcher and verify on chain
that funds are being transferred in a
certain method and release those funds to
other people, essentially.
It allows me to go on to a decentralized
peer-to-peer website like SigmaFi.
and loan somebody, you know, a thousand
SigmaUSD.
or going to DuckPools and dump my
SigmaUSD into the DuckPools pool to earn
interest on it that nobody can really stop
because it's a smart contract.
So those kind of things are super
invaluable to me and Ergo facilitates that
100%.
It puts the power of finance back into
the people's hands that's been
intentionally de-educated, uneducated,
this is a word I'm thinking of but I can't
think of it, over the years, intentionally
to keep people in control, in control and
continuing to make money off that.
Like I just saw the other day, yesterday,
right?
I saw the other day that a bank right a
bank that already makes interest off the
money that you put into it right so you
put money into a bank they invest your
money lend it out correct so a bank is
just had an announcement the other day
that a lot of banks do this of course with
with their pro checking accounts but
typically they have a free level of
checking account but they're removing
their free level of checking account and
making it so that you had to either direct
deposit into the account
or you had to carry a balance over like a
thousand dollars or they charge you a
certain amount for a month like that is
insane like this is exactly why
self-custody is important right where
they're already making money off the money
that we put in there and now they're just
pulling more and extracting more value out
of the money that you've earned that
you've put in there so
Hopefully, crypto will change that.
Hopefully, Ergo will be part of that, the
drive there.
It certainly has positioned itself to do
so.
And it's proven itself over the last four
or five years that it's resilient.
And it doesn't matter about market
conditions on the outside or perception of
crypto as a whole.
That's what Ergo does.
So that's my rant, kushti.
All right.
I think, I think we've hit all the
questions. well, is Keystone integrated.
Do you have an update on Keystone? Do we
know?
Is that C8 that's working on Keystone?
Yeah, there's, there's updates one week.
Oh, fine. It's, but well, it's, it's still
as far as I know. recently,
Well, it's with deterministic signatures
solved for the consistent environment.
And then, yeah, Keystone. So, latest
update. Making good progress with the
Keystone integration.
SDK part is mostly 10 PR is opened
against the case.
Still being in the final push of
displaying transactions, signing data and
testing.
Pull request can mount here. Some link,
but is not updated for the latest changes.
So yeah, it's still quite well.
Did you see the nice, the nice design on
Twitter the other day with the Ergo logo
across the back of the Keystone?
That was pretty nice looking.
Yeah. Yeah. And the view is selling, I
believe, Keystone pieces with something
like that are going to, do you know what's
going on?
I don't know. I think it was just a
promotion. I don't think it's live yet,
right?
I'll buy one as soon as it is.
Oh, so, yeah. It's all right. Yeah. All
right.
Well, 10 o'clock, I got another meeting
to run to kushti. I think your mic's
starting to finally break up a little bit.
So I think it's a good time to end it for
the new year right on time.
All right. Bye guys. Thanks everybody for
joining. Ciao.
Bye guys.