Awesome. Where were we? I was talking
about... Gosh, I even forgot what I was
talking about.
You were looking for people for your...
Yes, thank you. You're young. Vigiloso.
Yeah, perfect. So that's a general idea,
if anything just got cut off or not. This
person will take a little cut off each
sale. Right now we have a healthy stock of
it looks like we're back on YouTube. So
that's perfect. Great, and you don't
forget to send me question links. And
sure, I still have the old list it's okay.
I'll keep them up Andy. Perfect. Thanks.
So yeah, so I have all the stock we have
a plethora of Make mining great again
hats. We have sweatshirts that have the
Ergo logo on them and we have t-shirts
that have the - kushti is there a name for
that guy? What's the name of the astronaut
Sigmanauts that old little thing?
That old do I have a sticker here? Hang
on. Yeah, right here in my drawer.
What's his name? Does he have a name,
kushti?
Oh, but it's just Ergonaut.
That's just Ergonaut?
Yeah, on the moon, yeah.
Ergonaut, the first.
Moon mining, yeah.
Moon mining, perfect.
Ergonaut, yeah.
So we have t-shirts with that logo on
them as well. Yeah. So if you're
interested, please reach out to me on
Telegram or respond to that Twitter
message. As I said, there's already one or
two people interested, I think. So
hopefully that'll look up, take a lot of
burden off, spread out the burden, which
is good in a decentralized community like
this. So super cool. What else? Oh, I'll
show you guys this. Do I have? I can't
show you guys this. But I'm looking at
loading, I loaded Cyberverse before I
started up, and since their cross-chain
launch, they've, they're, I mean, it's
what, 9:26 on Eastern time? And they have
132 players live in there. Yeah, it's
fantastic. So the streets are busy. You
hit them, you hit the over you map and you
can see little pink dots walking around.
You know, the green dots are AI, not AI,
but computer players, NPCs and the pink
dots are users just bouncing around the
screen. So it's really, really cool to see
that kind of success. And I think it just
proves that you know, sometimes these
things take time, right? Not everything's
catch fire and burn fast and this is a
this is a prime example of a product that
has stayed true to their values and Ergo
values and just continued to push and
build and they're recognizing success.
Yeah, super super cool Christian we got to
get you on cyberverse man.
Yeah, well, hard to find time, but I'll
try maybe this weekend.
Watch it. kushti discovered Cyberverse
and sub-blocks are in five years. Node 6
is like 10 years away now. He said, look
at my player level 20 guys. And we're
like, kushti, go back to sub-blocks, man.
We're going to have to, we'd have to get
Mr. Pixel to shut the servers down.
That's a fine time, yeah, really.
So that's really exciting. What else?
Sigmanauts mining pool is still trucking
along. We are at, let's see, what
gigahash? We're at 72 gigahash this
morning. Usually we ride around 94, 95,
but sometimes people shut them off for
night time or daytime, depending if their
electricity costs are high. Mark wrote a
script last week that automatically clears
out the logs because we you know we're
running logs on storage rent as well as
mining core so so those guys can build up
and when we're trying to keep the price of
the servers down we only have about 40
gigs of playroom so sometimes after a
couple after a month or so those those
drives can really fill up. So he's written
a script that wipes those logs every once
in a while to keep the server in tip-top
shape. So that's great. What else? Oh, so
students come back. Gosh hang on maybe
that's why I feel so depressed lately
Students at Cornell come back come back on
Tuesday because we have Martin Luther King
down I believe but the good news is that's
when That's when they'll be introduced to
the Cornell BRICK. So I'm really excited
to see how was that Wait, where have you
been? What rock have you been living under
this year?
What a rock. So Cornell BRICK is our idea
of trying to stimulate a local economy at
my college. So the idea is we have, unless
it's a useful token, then it's never going
to get used. So we're providing a use for
it. And that use is that I've rewritten
the front end and kind of a little bit of
the back end of our plot submission
process. So right now students go to a web
portal, they submit a plot, it goes to the
back end, our student workers look at the
plot, they open it up, they send it out,
the students are notified all along the
way and they go pick it up at a cubby when
they're done. So the idea was to integrate
the blockchain into that. So I've modified
the front end and like a side bot that
monitors a chain. So when students print,
they can choose blockchain payment. And as
soon as they choose it, they submit it.
They get a pop-up in the payment channel
in our Discord. We have a Discord that's
used by, gosh, we probably have about
1,800 alum and current students in there
now. So they're gonna pop up there that
says hey so-and-so, you know Your plot
number was this the cost is this if you
want to pay in ERG copy this text if you
want to pay in Cornell BRICK Copy this
text. So all it is is code for the tipper
bot So we're gonna introduce everybody to
the blockchain via the tipper bot. So they
basically yeah Pacing the code and whether
it's BRICK or ERG and the back end knows,
you know, it's like it's like auction
house not auction house Ergo raffle where
it's like five digits of a unique So
that's how we tell who it is, you know
what I mean So once the scanner sees that
it marks the plot as plottable and then it
shows up in the back end to the to the
student workers to be able to send it But
yeah, so we're going to first of all,
we're gonna give BRICK to our student
workers so there's we have an 18 student
workers that we're gonna give them to so
that'll hopefully kind of started that
way, as well as we'll have some incentives
to hand it out to the rest of the student
body as well, maybe a handful to
everybody. So everybody gets a couple free
plots at the start of the semester if they
use that system. And then we'll find other
ways to hand them out. So the idea is that
the plotting center will give this token
kind of a value. You know, like, this is
valuable to me because instead of spending
$12 on a plot, I'm going to use a couple
of these tokens. So there's some value
right there for the tokens. So then the
idea is not everybody's going to use them.
And there can be developing some sort of
trade in between, like, can we have this
book or this tool? Can I swap you this?
Oh, here's a BRICK for that or that kind
of thing. So that's going to be fun and
interesting, and that'll of course wrap
into the Cornell demurrage hierarchy as
well.
So what is the plot exactly?
Oh, it's just like a 42-inch wide piece
of paper by seven feet. Think about
architecture plans like, you know,
blueprints, kind of thing. Well, the
students weekly, every bi-weekly, you
know, several times a month, they'll have
these critiques where they have to lay out
the boards of their projects, so they'll
have different views of their building or
their design and different cross-sections,
and they'll put it all out neatly on a
thing with maybe some explanation
sometimes. No, usually not text. And
they'll put it up on the boards, and then
the faculty rake them over the coals and
tell them why they're wrong and why it's
awful. It's all part of the learning
process in architecture. So that's a plot.
That's interesting.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, so it's a busy thing in
architecture school. Since 2020, we have
64,000 plots that have come across our
desk that we've printed for the students.
So it's a lot. Yeah, it's a main part of
the thing. So yeah, so that's super
exciting when that When that happens a
little nervous, but I tested the code as
much as I could and it seems to be working
So I mean, it's a good thing about being
in a controlled environment like a school,
you know, if it breaks You know what's
gonna happen. You don't have like
investors coming at you yelling at you. So
you just I don't know and say sorry guys
We're working on fixing it and then you
fix it So there is that leisure that you
have when you're doing something like an
academic thing like that
Yeah, so I think such environments are
well experimentation friendly, right, by
definition. Also, so, well, no issue,
right, if something would be buggy. Well,
it's quite exciting. I mean, so finally,
Ergo is going to real world, which is more
important than even more important than
just, you know, games and, well,
blockchains and boxes like, I don't know,
like having DeFi applications disconnected
from the real world, right? Well, finally,
we have, you know, honey been sold on
Ergo, and Macbooks, and now also students'
currency and so on. So, yeah, that's a
very important step forward.
And I think I mentioned this maybe in
Sigmanauts meeting, because I don't think
I was in the AMA last week, but the really
cool thing about MewFinance is seller
protection, right? Right now, you know you
read horror stories about eBay where the
the buyer gets an item and they're like
Oh, it's not the right one or I don't like
it They send a bad one back eBay sides on
the case of the buyer because they don't
want to scare away the buyers, right?
There's always some seller to come so it's
a buyer's you don't want to scare away so
with MewFinance, it's a combination of
Trust I guess but what's the word I'm
looking for? Reputation, right? So if
Sigma Shop starts screwing people over,
we're done. You know, that's all we have
is our reputation. And then as a seller
too, it's amazing that the money comes in
directly to our wallet and I don't have to
worry about a bank clawing it back or eBay
clawing it back because somebody bitches
kind of thing. So, it's a great
combination of reputation of the seller
and the seller actually providing and
feeling safe that the money's there and
it's not going to be clawed back. So, I
think it's better than eBay in that
aspect. So, I encourage everybody, if you
have stuff, anything, stuff you're not
using, stuff you want to get rid of, see
if the Sigmanauts, if you can't get a
store yourself on MewFinance, see if the
Sigmanauts will co-sign. Yeah, that's the
word for it. Consigned there we go. It's
spelled similarly Consign it for you. So
you'd essentially just ship it to us We'd
look it over make sure it's okay and then
post it for you at your price Take a
little bit off the top, of course for a
service and do it there. So please I mean,
I'm sure the stuff you guys are sitting
around on like look at this Do you know
what this is MG pai I Don't know looks
like a plastic BRICK to me.
Alright, let's see. Alright, so Andy says
that we should get some questions in the
old question chat and then he's gonna
refresh it so that we see the new chat. So
let me look through the old questions.
Let's see if it'll work. Oh, it still
works. Alright, here we go. I don't think
any of it, well, mgPai should know this.
When Palm Token will be available to trade
on DEX, MG?
So, I mean, of course I can't reveal
anything but I can say that there is a
public sale happening I think next week or
so something like that so I think in I
mean if you want like all this like type
of alpha knowledge right you got to join
the spaces that Palm hosts right we do
spaces on X quite frequently so I believe
it was said in that space that Like within
a month or so, Palm should be available to
like freely trade some things along those
lines. But I can't give any accurate
details on that, but it is of course very
soon because the public sale is next week.
Alrighty. Let's see. kushti, maybe this
one's for you. It doesn't make sense to
me. Do you have public block producer
calls? If so, when and where? Are they
speaking like just like phone calls or
calls like programming calls? API calls.
Is that what it is?
Or a block producer calls. What do they
mean?
probably actually mean like that like
phone like zoom calls meeting yeah yeah
yeah block producer but no we don't know
what does that mean it's like miners or
mining pools I don't even have contacts of
all the pools now so recently I've asked
qx() about one right Yeah, the biggest
one, actually. So, yeah, well, and about
getting them on the call, I mean, why?
Good luck finding them, I mean. Yes, so
some guys are pretty anonymous, and then
you have a way to make a call even. Yeah,
it is tough. Everyone is doing its own
business.
Yep, we have about 50, 60 people
connected to the Sigmanauts mining pool.
And I'd say only a dozen or so are very
active and chatting, right? So the rest of
them prefer to stay in the shadows and
watch and continue to mine. So yeah, it
would be interesting. And that's just our
pool. That's just a Sigmanauts pool across
the board. I think it might be a little
interesting, that's for sure. Some sort of
block producer group. that has generally i
don't know i wonder that seems to organize
alex that seems against not against but
that seems anti what what it is i guess i
don't know interesting it would be
interesting yeah but also yeah i mean why
to do that even so yeah yeah what's the
incentive i mean i guess it'd be nice to
like when node updates come up alex so you
could like have a reminder hey guys update
your nodes and the mining core
Yeah so currently well so last time we've
asked pools back in 2022 so yeah well
during 5.0 soft fork update right And
yeah, before it was NIPoPoWs merge sudden
hard fork and before it was EP27 soft
fork, right? So well, yeah, all those
updates were back in 2022. And yes, since
then, so well, I'm not in touch. Yeah, no,
no, not just me. So back then like half of
connections I was made by Joe probably so
Yes since then so I I don't know even
which versions they're running Five or
somewhat probably but maybe five one zero
So, I don't even know, and also why. So,
well...
You know, speaking of mining, I do have a
question for kushti. So recently, I think
there was an issue on with nodes that if
you submit like a transaction right now,
it's not going to be included in the
current block, right? It always gets
included in like block N plus one or N
plus two or so on. Right. And there's an
issue that's fixed. That's the issue has
been fixed. What are your plans on merging
that into the main node and having the
pools all update their versions? Why are
we holding up on that?
Well, one of the reasons is because you
and the other guys are not reviewing PRs
even earlier.
Oh, burn!
So, yeah, I mean, do your job for V3. We
don't do releases. So, I'm not, you know,
like... Yeah, I can't do releases without
reviews. I mean, it's... So, you're
waiting on a review for that? Not for
that, just for previous releases. The plan
for the next one is to include fixes for
indexer. There are, I believe, a couple of
other PRs for next miner releases. And
then we can do that release with only PR,
which is about regenerating block
candidates. So the plan is to have only
this PR and inform mining pools about that
and all that stuff. Before that we need to
release other minor versions, so there is
some logic in development as well. Okay.
Yeah, it's at all. It's then depends on
the reviewers like you basically.
Yeah. So we should say, yeah, we should,
I should certainly prioritize reviewing
that I think, and whatever is sequential.
So I guess before that, because this will
be a huge like quality update, right? When
transacting on Ergo, it'll appear that
your transactions confirm much faster,
right? Because it will get immediately
included in the current block or the next
block instead of like block plus current
block plus two. So this will be a huge
update to everyone and this is a very
low-hanging fruit so we should certainly
attack this.
Yeah, I mean a lot of things to be
checked also so this should be a
well-dedicated release. And yeah, well,
there is some logic, you know, in
development, so there are other things,
and then, yeah, we are blocked by, well,
absence of reviews at the moment.
In the new chat, guys, we've got a whole
minor chat going. They're talking about
cards and clocking and locking the memory.
Super cool. Super cool to watch. Alright,
let's see. We've got the big 3d says any
updates. I'm cracking exchange listings
and you know what the big 3d when I
reached out to mark mark greenberg our
buddy our ergo holder mark greenberg now
after he left he said he was going to try
to talk to dave brumfeld if it's dm
brumfeld i believe right crypto dave to
open up his dm so we could chat with him
and crypto dave hasn't yet so while you
guys were arguing with each other and
kushti was insulting you mg pai for not
doing reviews I pinged Mark again and
asked him, I told him I hope his new job
is treating him well and it's everything
he's ever dreamed of. And then I reminded
him about getting Brumfield to open his
DMs or chat with us. So hopefully we get
some word there and we can... Continue
that conversation get it kicked up again
and again Kraken listing is for access
right? We're not looking for we all know
how disappointing it is Most crypto
exchange launches right everybody gets
this big high bow the price is gonna moon
and that kind of thing so Everybody should
look at this kind of stuff as you know,
we're getting more access for US customers
for people who are to use Kraken
specifically To ERG, which is very great
spreading liquidity across those
exchanges. So super cool If he does that.
All right, let's see sub-blocks kushti
they want to know how sub-blocks are going
Yeah, so
Well, there is progress, right? Polishing
EAP still needs to include arguments about
security, right? Because, well, it
shouldn't be done like, I don't know, most
of protocol updates in the space, like, I
don't know, developers are doing something
And then, well, it's just getting shielded
by marketing folks, right? And that's it.
So there is need for security arguments
for treatment. So, well, we will check
papers on similar constructions. like
Tailstorm, but Prism probably, so Prism
has somewhat satisfying, well, security
arguments. Then, well, then, yeah, writing
the code, so, yeah, well, hopefully, well,
so currently I have already local miners
generating sub-blocks, input blocks, but
the contents are not valid, just basically
empty. So now the idea is to properly
spread transactions according to the EEP
draft and properly form I needed fields
and well there are a lot of things to get
done on the way especially about well
updating proofs well state transformation
proofs which is actually one of the
reasons why well transaction is not
getting into a block immediately so well
that there is need to check state
transformation proof. In ergo we have a
lot of modes of operation, so it's
possible to run what like 90 percent of
people are doing, so they're just running
with default settings and not which is
holding QTXO set, right? But also Ergo is
supporting stateless clients, right? It
was the first cryptocurrency with
stateless clients. And actually, still, I
believe the only one where stateless
clients are based on just hash-based
cryptography. So not any MoonMath
cryptography. So, well, just very simple
actually, hash-based cryptography. And
then, yeah, it's also then possible to use
NIPoPoWs. right and so on and well yeah
it's a lot of complexity so well we are
discussing possible nodes not alternative
node implementation maybe in Rust right in
coming years as well Sigma Rust is making
progress but then yeah well with all those
mods it would be quite tricky so maybe it
makes sense to do some I don't know
dedicated clients just like maybe nippo
pole based for status right suitable maybe
for very limited environments maybe where
internet connection is well near to none
Going back to sub-blocks, we are now going
to handle state transformation proofs and
transactions and all that stuff. In case
of luck, maybe next week there will be a
local DevNet on my machine with all those
things done with transactions properly
going into input blocks. And then, yeah,
well, there is need for polishing and then
a lot of details to be considered like
updating how to update stratum proxy for
miners, right, if we are talking about
external miner, how to update APYs, right,
how to add support to applications and so
on. Yeah, a lot of tricky details. How to
do pruning, by the way, because, well,
with more transactions going into blocks,
maybe, right, there is need for more
aggressive pruning. Yeah, it also depends.
So I'm now asking application developers
like qx(), for example. So what are their
plans in regards with using Corollaps and
so on, right? Because, well, based on that
we may will handle some things ahead of
time, like roll-up constructions. So it
could be done much better than done in
Ethereum, for example, in regards with
storing blobs and pruning them and so on.
So yeah, a lot of tricky details and then
Some things also to be considered for the
future, such as supporting
sub-block-based, input-block-based
sidechains. How you can make a sidechain
progressing sub-block-by-sub-block
basically. which is probably requiring to
add something to validation context, but
that's pretty tricky, but yeah, there are
some things too. to be considered here,
maybe even in a velvet-forking way after,
well, sub-block deployment. But then there
is also question how to do that right in
so soft-forkish way. So yeah, a lot of
questions. So yeah, I'm continuing to
write down details and well, some plans
for our future into EP. And yeah, the
court is progressing.
While you guys were chatting, I checked
out my Rosenwatcher and I try to check out
my watcher once a week to make sure it's
running. I have a watcher on Bitcoin, ERG,
BTC, and Ethereum. But mainly my ERG ones
are Bezias. And every week it's between
150, 250, Rosen which means that I'm
making 12 to 15 ERG per week Running this
Ergo watcher. It's it's absolutely
amazing. I mean, that's hey, you don't
even do anything Well, come on. I'm doing
something MG by it's some work running
this passive Yeah, so it's super super
awesome, you know just make sure to reboot
it once in a while that it's running and
Make sure the node it's connected to is
functioning and good. So yeah, I mean it's
it's it's it's amazing. Yep. Yep. So I
encourage people who aren't doing this to
do this because I mean, we're in the
infancy of this thing and I'm doing 12 ERG
a month a week. Sorry.
I mean, if you're not selling Rosen,
right, there's always upside.
Yeah, yeah. No, I've already taken my
last big batch. I just added it to a new
permit. Once it got to 3000, I just pumped
it back into one of them. And this is only
on the Ergo side. I am only running Ten
permits on the Ergo side. Yeah, and the
most at any time And this is when the
bridge was waiting for funds to transfer.
I think I had five or six permits out So I
haven't maxed out on that yet. So so yeah
encourage people who have rosen sitting
there and aren't doing anything with it
Please, you know spin up a watcher. We
have videos from version one That are
pretty similar to what it is now to set it
up. The instructions are pretty good tried
and tested Give it a go.
All right and by the way about input
blocks and well some additional source of
income. So currently well miners are
packing right input blocks but what I'm
thinking about maybe to add to outline how
it could be done in future so maybe in
future like everyone can do an input block
basically right along with zero knowledge
proof of its validity and sent to a miner
for inclusion right and then a miner It
needs to just check proof and includes
everything. And then you can basically
earn from generating zero-knowledge
proofs.
I like that. I think you can encourage
people to run node, right? Based on that
idea, because you can just have like the
node software itself be the one to
generate. Right.
So there are lots of tricky details here
for sure. And well, I'm well tracking the
state of zero knowledge proof. So maybe
it's still too early, right? especially if
we are talking about, well, retail
capabilities to generate proofs. But,
yeah, well, it's progressing, so maybe in
a few years, yeah, that would become
reality.
Yeah, so I guess basically the idea is
you get paid to run a node and the
possibility of that, so... That would be
quite, that would be pretty amazing. It's
not very much seen in the crypto space,
right? To get paid to run nodes, right? So
that would be pretty nice.
Yeah, because it's quite tricky to do,
right? Well, yeah. If you are willing to
pay for a node, then this node should
produce some verifiable work. Otherwise,
it probably would be always not resistant
to civil attacks, so you can always
generate a lot of nodes. Yeah, do
inflation basically just by spamming a
network with nodes created just in order
to get tokens, right? Yes. That's actually
how the first proof-of-work currency
failed, I believe. I forgot its name. One
created by Hal Finny before Bitcoin, like
PoW Cash or something like that. So yeah,
the problem. There was basically inflation
when people... So there was no dynamic
difficulty and so on, so people just
created a lot of notes and the cost of
inflation. And then a few years after,
Bitcoin appeared.
Could you just CPU mine the node and post
that proof in a block so it shows you're
actually running and using the node? I
mean it won't do any good, you know, CPU
mining, but you could govern it to do 10%
of your CPU, show that it's CPU mining
your node and put that proof on the chain.
That would be proof that the node's
running, it's up to date, and somebody's
active on it kind of thing, no?
Yeah, actually, there are ideas like to
have a double proof-of-work system, right?
So first, a kind of actors doing
proof-of-work to pack transactions into...
it's called FRUITS. And then miners,
second-class miners are packing fruits
into blocks, right? So that's quite old
idea from 2016, I believe. 17 fruits
chain. And yeah, I'm not sure about
implementations, actually. Well, to the
best of my knowledge, midnight plans at
some point, but I'm not sure about now.
And yeah, so that's possible. But then,
yeah, so you have just competition in two
dimensions, right? So, well, in regards
with one kind of proof work and another
kind of proof work. And it's quite hard to
predict, well, how secure it would be, but
yeah, well, let's see, so maybe just,
well, approves generation. Well, this kind
of proof-of-work, right, kind of work
would be quite good for just, well,
forming, well, fruits, right, so, well,
parts of blocks with transactions, the
input blocks here in Ergo, basically. And
then, yes, the second-class managers are
doing kind of real proof-of-work, how to
like us. Iterations, yeah, well, they're
packing into blocks, right? They are
confirming them by using, yeah, ordering
blocks. So, like, for four blocks now.
All right, guys, we got a good question
here. From Augustus Kent, how easy would
it be for Bitcoin to copy Ergo's unique
features if they are proven to be needed,
i.e. could BTC just soft fork and add
storage rent?
Yeah, so I think, well, the chance is
about zero, right? So one of the lowest
hanging fruits which discussed in Bitcoin
community since 2000, Oh, 11, probably 12.
Yeah, so it is about, well, including UTXO
set confirmations. It was called in the
Bitcoin community to block headers, right,
somehow, or maybe other parts of the
block, so it's possible to commit maybe
even via Coinbase transactions, so not
breaking the protocol. Just soft forkish
or maybe even a little bit forkish way,
but yeah, it's still not there. But, you
know, well, it would be highly beneficial
for like hundreds of protocols. So like,
well, SPV wallets, well, light clients,
trustless relays, cross chains. And so on.
Well, sidechains. So a lot of
applications, but it's still not there. So
about, well, introducing storage rent. So
I see there are now a lot of discussions
in the Bitcoin community in regards with
what to do with security budget, which is
shrinking, right? And, yeah, well, the
most popular proposals are about
introducing storage rent or, well,
introducing Taylor Mission somehow. But,
yeah, I'm not sure it's possible to, well,
updates the bitcoin protocol here as well
right so probably that would create a lot
of drama on the way maybe maybe more split
so maybe we will see bitcoin demurrage and
then what else bitcoin telemission and
then yeah bitcoin classic i don't know
bitcoin core maybe let's see let's see but
yeah in general updating anything in the
Bitcoin protocol since like 2011 is nearly
impossible so there were actually quite
dramatic changes in early years like 2009,
10 maybe 11 like early 11 but yes since
then it's It's about soft forks only. And
yeah, well, soft forks of some specific
kind. So they are now, well, spending a
few years discussing whether it's worth to
reintroduce opcodes switched off back in
2010, right? So, well, it was easy to
switch them off, but to switch it on, just
one of them, which is well useful for,
needed for some roll-ups and so on,
roll-up constructions and so on. So yeah,
that's big drama, even that, even getting
back one opcode switched off temporarily,
actually back in 2010.
Have you guys, well we're getting near
time, but a couple more things. Have you
guys seen the C8's new project that he
whipped together?
Yeah, yeah, so... Just today I've tried
to create another row of transactions made
as quickly as possible. That was actually
quite an awesome experience. All of them
today are finished in a block.
That's awesome. So that's for people that
don't know, I retweeted it. I retweeted it
on the main account, C8sPost. He's running
a mint competition on his new ergify.xyz
site. So if you guys are up for playing
with SigmaRSV or SigmaUSD and converting
back and forth, that is a site for you.
It's with a new Nautilus. You can chain
those puppies and spam it, and it's pretty
neat. Give that a try see it's really good
at pulling those things out and getting
them up I think it's on alpha version 10
already and when I looked a couple days
ago, it's like an alpha version 3 or
something So he's really crushing out
those updates I Think that's it guys. It's
10 on 7 You want to call it Right Yeah,
who's gonna call it MG pie look I have an
Ergo hat now yeah Maybe I'll sell this one
Great All right. Thanks everybody for
joining MG pie. It was amazing to see you
back behind the camera again kushti
Awesome as always Thanks, all right Yeah,
thank you guys.
It was my pleasure to be here again and
yeah good quest as usually. So, see you
maybe next week or maybe there are other
folks. Sounds good folks. Yeah, there are
other folks waiting maybe for, for, for
being here. Let's see.
That'd be nice. Great. Ciao everybody.