Hello, and welcome back to the Ergo Dev
Update.
I thought no better way to bring this
back after a few months of hiatus than to
have the original, the OG, sipping on his
amber ale, Joseph Armeanio.
Good to be back.
How you doing, sir?
Good. Cheers, everybody. It's nice to be
back on the Dev Update. What's new in
crypto land these days?
Goodness. Wow. I don't know where to
start, Joe. I don't know where to start.
All right. What pops in your head first,
I guess. And we'll just paddle forward
from there.
Well, let me I got something. All right.
So here's here. So I've, a lot of you
watching maybe know that I've launched the
BRICK token. But the funny thing is, let
me open my I'm open my email here because
I want to read a verbatim. So I have to,
you know, you kind of have to launch this
stuff and send out mass emails to
students, which also hit faculty, which
also has staff.
So when I'm writing this thing, I'm
writing about blockchain usage. I'm
writing about Ergo platform and why we
chose to use it for this purpose. I get a
whole email done and I'm thinking for a
second, Oh man, it still reads like, Oh,
you're going to get airdropped and that
kind of thing. And it just triggers these
things in my head, like these meme token
crap scams kind of stuff.
So I literally, I put a message at the
end. Let me find it. I put one sentence at
the end of talking about Ergo, I said, and
yes, we're fully aware of how ridiculous
90% of the blockchain antics have been. So
welcome to some actual meaningful usage of
this technology.
So it's so sad that I have to put that
in. And then after that, I see like, what
was it? A couple of days ago, a Senator
released a token, USA token or something
like that. And we're going to make this
the best financial.
Every micro celebrity and influencer out
there has their own thing now, huh? It's
unexpected, I guess.
It is. I mean, this happens in the fiat
world all the time, right? So why would we
not expect it here in the crypto space?
I think that you just have to say, okay,
well, as soon as you create something like
that, what are you really doing as you're
creating a currency war, right? And so
then the assumption is going to be that
people are going to at some point, move
towards the better currency. I don't see
it as really any more complicated than
that. It's a weird space.
We're in weird time but it is there's
really there's really nothing like new
under the sun right just new front end I'm
just waiting for like a senator to do
something on pump fun or something That's
the next step right so that got me
thinking they got me thinking too like
what's
And I hope no central exchanges are
watching this right now, but I'm thinking
what's besides a fiat on ramp? What's the
usage? What's a forecast for a central
exchange in the future? You know, the only
thing that can come to my mind to think of
what these things will evolve into in the
future. The only thing that came to my
mind is most of these things are just
going to be
online casinos are going to devolve into
an online casino or evolve into an online
casino. You're gonna put your money up
there. They're not going to want you to
move it anywhere else because you're
there. You know, you're their cash cow.
And then they're going to want you to
spend it there. So what else, they're
going to turn into some sort of payment
portal where everything comes to then you
buy things you gamble.
Yeah, I mean, like, I don't know, I have
my own thoughts. I would say that yeah,
okay, you're probably going to see a lot
of, I don't know, ramping, which, one of
the useful things about centralized stable
coins is they have the ability to sink
liquidity into the bond market, right? So
if you look at USDC, USDT, what are they
holding? Government bonds, right?
So it is somewhat interesting to say,
okay, well, if I'm in government and I
have a lot of debt that I have to roll
over. Having these new ways of sinking
liquidity into the bond market to like
offset demand based on the amount of debt
I need to roll over might make sense,
right?
Then you also have like the custodial
aspect I think is kind of interesting,
right? Now you can say like Coinbase is
building out this entire suite that's like
onboarding I guess more traditional
markets and they're the ultimately like
the key holder in that situation. So maybe
that's useful for retail, but that's not
new either. I think a lot of people have
just used exchanges as their wallet,
hoping they didn't get hacked.
A lot of people just don't have the
ability to understand what self custody
is. I mean, I have these people that I
know that were family members from
marriage are into crypto before I was.
And, they called me the other day to help
them, recover funds from whatever that
payout was. It wasn't Mt. Gox, but one of
those kind of things where they're letting
you go in and pull out some USDT or
something like that in a fraction of what
you actually originally had.
So one of those things that I was helping
them pull it out and I was like, what's
your address? And they're like, Oh, my
Coinbase address is this. I was like, No,
no, what's your, what's your wallet
address yourself? Something like you have
a hardware key or anything like that? Oh,
no, I just keep it on the exchange. So
it's unfortunately just the exchanges job,
right? It's a keep you there,
unfortunately, and people don't educate
beyond that.
So yeah. I mean, the space is weird, man.
Like I onboarded into crypto by syncing
nodes. Like that was like my first
activity or touchpoint.
Was that your first wallet? A node
wallet?
Yeah, yeah. I was like, wow, this Bitcoin
thing is pretty interesting. I'm going to
sync a node.
Oh, wow, nice.
But that's kind of very foreign. Now it's
like the president has a shit coin,
everybody, quick. I don't know what to
say. Like those things happen. I'm like.
It's not even a sane response to that
kind of thing. The president of the United
States is rugged. Probably not.
Let's be honest. I don't see him having
like, Oh, no, not him specifically right
now.
He's not running the token himself. But
it's whatever whoever he's hired or
whoever he's given permission to do this.
I'm sure that's always the downside is
there's always coat tailors. Somebody
that's just around him that wants to
leverage that power privilege position,
whatever. But that's not new either.
No, no, that's true. It's just blatant in
the open, I guess. I guess it's
transparent, right? That's hell of a
transparent.
It seems to have really destroyed the, I
don't know, the meme narrative that was
going there for a bit. I guess a lot of
people put their liquidity into the Trump
token and then, that started dumping on
everybody and it seems to have pulled a
lot of liquidity out of other meme
projects and Who knows maybe Donald Trump
destroyed shit coins, right?
That's kind of a So went down 20% or
something when when the Trump token dumped
or something I forget I have something
like that. Yeah
It's a weird space like that. I mean, on
one hand, it's like we have these people
that are saying, hey, we're going to try
to build systems with open source code
that redistribute kind of power
assumptions and oftentimes offer like
privacy and utility. And then on the other
side, you have users that don't care about
code at all. I mean, a lot of times it's
just a picture. They don't really care
about assumptions. They don't really care
about privacy. They don't really care
about, well, much other than, is it green
or red? And these things happen.
I mean, the downside to financial
nihilism is equal to the upside, which is
kind of infinite. So there you go.
Well, in these situations, I tend to find
myself just putting my head down and being
on whatever track I was on before for what
reason I was on before. And that's
building on Ergo, right? That's finding
real life use cases for Ergo, finding
actual meaningful, as I said, reasons to
utilize the blockchain. And the other
stuff's just noise to me. It feels
temporary, right? It feels like, OK, this
is just the windstorm blowing over. This
is a hype. This is extra value extraction.
This is what these people are going to do.
Eventually, they're going to run out of
people to, maybe hopefully they're going
to run out of people to fleece down those
kind of numbers. And then, we'll still be
there. And projects like Ergo are still
going to be there building and way ahead
of the game who are just trying to value
extract. So that's the way I look at it.
I think that if you're going to look at
how you deal with things in life, you got
to have humor. Otherwise, it is a crazy
space. A lot of the times, if I'm talking
to like your average person, I just say,
Hey, I helped contribute to open source
software. And they say, Oh, well, what's
that? And it's like, well, it's free. You
can look inside of it and understand it.
And I start talking about closed versus
open systems.
Now I'm sure there are a lot of people
that their first touch point in crypto is.
A lot of these key opinion leaders who, I
don't know, based on the look of it, were
like fatherless or something. But I'm just
honest, and yeah, I don't know. It's a
weird space. And I think everybody should
have fair warning about that. And
hopefully, people do, that there is a lot
of just grift, vapor world.
So have we been in a situation
historically? And my memory is usually
always hard to remember these kind of
things, even things I read in history,
historically of this kind of not
necessarily in the financial market, but
in other markets.
It's been free banking before. where you
have a bunch of people creating their own
personal currencies and usually it's
rampant with inflations and scams and
things to blow up. But I think that
usually we didn't have the technology to
actually see and understand it. Now we
actually do, which is fascinating, right?
Like you can watch, I don't know, say you
pick a scam project on some chain. You can
actually look.
Throw dirt. You'll hit one, right? It
doesn't matter.
I mean, you can understand distribution.
You can understand like an element of
what's happening not that people pay
attention or that it doesn't matter I
mean, it's the same thing.
I mean with chains, right? We have full
transparency. We see what's locked. We see
what's not locked We see how many people
are holding the majority of the Treasury.
It doesn't matter the same thing happens
That would happen in a closed system where
people are fleeced out in the fiat system
world So it's the in that case. I feel
like for the normal person 90% of the
people it doesn't matter
You know, they don't understand what it
means that, oh, the token holder for the
Trump token owns 80%, has 80% of the
tokens ready to dump into the buy pressure
kind of thing. So I don't know.
Always great power comes great
responsibility.
I don't know. I just think Ergo has
always been in the right place. It doesn't
matter if there's a hurricane out there or
a tornado and people are falling for
anything. Ergo is still steadily building
and doing, I think, the right thing.
I think we just need to look at it from
the perspective of we're trying to create
an open neutral network, right? And
deliver assumptions that people that want
to understand will, right? Like, just
because blockchain is available to
everybody, probably doesn't mean everybody
should use it at this point, right? But
it's there, right? Having the code open
and available to everybody doesn't
necessarily mean that much to many people,
but it's there.
There are ways to implement it too that
are transparent to the user, but still
beneficial in the sense of using the
blockchain like when we were releasing the
BRICK token.
Listen, technology will not solve human
nature. That's the end all be all of this
discussion is that you have that side of
human nature where people will want money
in profit for no work, no input. We'll
have people that will try to grift other
people and try to take advantage of them.
I think ultimately it's about creating
clear trust assumptions that are available
for people that appreciate that. At this
point, many people won't. But historically
in crypto, the most valuable marketing
moments are not from the industry itself.
It's when there is some bellwether event
outside of crypto, whether it's Cyprus
screws over their depositors or Canada
starts censoring truckers' bank accounts.
And then people start saying, hey, wait a
second, what's the assumption that I have
as a user in this system? And they start
looking for something better. That's what
drives people into really looking at, I
guess, systems that distribute power.
So we have a tough battle with crypto
though, right? Because I don't think so.
It is, I think it's inevitable, but I
think it's a road ahead because those
people who are debanked or feel strangled
by that kind of thing, like you just
mentioned, They're not going to jump into
something that all they've heard about is
a scam or rugpulls or that kind of thing,
or, the consensus of what crypto is.
That's the beauty of an open network in a
way. Like if you have some regulatory body
that's like, Hey everybody, you have to
behave and act in a certain way. You just
kind of defeated the point. So that's the
downside to not having censorship. That's
the downside to not having a central party
that's babysitting everybody. And you just
have to be aware of that. Right. And
that's always going to be a risk in an
open system.
So to some degree, I would say, yeah, you
should approach these things with like an
element of caution and be aware of
pretentious malicious actors, but the
system itself is designed with pretty
clear assumptions of how it works in the
face of a malicious actor. That's more or
less the point.
Yeah, I'm looking at, well, you're
talking, I'm looking at looking at
DuckPools and I see that, it's crazy to me
that Sigmanauts pool and DuckPools has an
APY of 28.9%. Like in any market, any like
sane market, that's an amazing yield
return, right? But in crypto, you have to
like remind people that it's there,
that's.
I mean, I think you need to recognize
that yield is more or less an open term in
crypto. And it's important to understand
like where yield comes from first and
foremost, right? Like 28%, real yield is
pretty impressive. But when you look at it
side by side versus like money printing
yield from some token that just, put your
token here and give you more tokens. You
know, it is true. You got to know where
your yield comes from. Otherwise you might
be the yield, right?
Yeah. Let me show this, Joe. We'll take a
break for a second. I'm going to switch to
something just to show everybody. Let's
see if I can switch to this. Oh,
fantastic.
All right. So here's an example. So I
just want to show people how simple we've
tried to make it for students who are
using BRICK token to pay for their plots
for that incentive. So we filled out the
information. We've uploaded our plot.
We're choosing blockchain payment here.
We're submitting the print job, and gosh,
I hope I didn't submit something big.
Let's see. No, that was nice and small.
OK, so it instructs you to go to the
blockchain server on Discord. And if
you'll notice, there's a new message in
blockchain payments. And there we go. It
tells me that it's me, that it's six
bucks, and it's either 4.4 ERG or 54
BRICK. So I just copy the BRICK. And
before I do that, let's go to the admin
side. You can see that my print is not
there, right? This is what the backend
admin sees. So it's not released yet.
So as soon as we hit this, I have sent
the wallet the appropriate amount of
BRICK. And I guess we wait two minutes.
We'll check back in a little bit. We'll
see that that print should be released
soon on this page.
So the reason I'm showing this is because
what I mentioned earlier is that I don't
think you need to necessarily with
everybody, dive them into, not everybody
needs like, okay, here's your wallet,
here's your seed phrase, maybe explain how
that works. But an intro to the blockchain
can be as easy as this, right? None of
these students are knowing, essentially, I
mean, in the explanation video, I tell
them, here's how you setup, here's what a
seed phrase is, that kind of thing. But
they don't need to setup a wallet, right?
If they're doing these kind of simple
back and forth, peer-to-peer payments,
this kind of simple method, of course. All
they're using is Tipperbot. To them, the
blockchain is very transparent. For all
they know, it's some Discord app that
they're running on, right? But we're
running it on the blockchain, on
peer-to-peer nodes, so that, let's say
something bad happens, right? Let's say
somebody takes my token and makes an ERG
pair with it on Mew or something.
That's something I don't want to happen
because I don't want to deal with tax
issues in Cornell. So we'll just nuke it,
make a new token, airdrop it to everybody
except that asshole who made the trading
pair against our wishes on the DEX,
essentially, and just reprogram that with
a couple lines of programming into our
backend, and that's it. So that's the
beauty of the blockchain. It's such a
benefit to at least the developers and the
tooling that Ergo has. And to the
students, it can be very transparent and
extremely robust and simple to use.
So I think there's a huge use case in the
Ergo ecosystem. I mean, that's kind of
where you get into this idea of stateless
clients or ultra light clients. where, you
know, abstraction usually means you're
putting additional layers of trust in
between users and the blockchain, right?
So it's like you're tracking to a higher
layer, you're kind of further away from, I
guess, optimal security assumptions. And
our ability to build low, potentially with
like one click
applications where people don't
necessarily need to know that they're
basically operating with the assumptions
of a full node is pretty magic. I think
that's a huge green area for the Ergo
ecosystem to explore as a whole and I
really think that sub-blocks will be a
driver of that because then you're no
longer waiting for block time, which
again, if you're talking about general
users, I'd say a lot of them don't
understand the assumption of settlement
with no have no clue what that is bank
money anyway, I mean,
Well, even, even people in the
blockchain, they don't understand why an
exchange would want 10 blocks on Ergo or
20 blocks on Ergo or, a couple blocks on
Bitcoin or a couple on Ethereum. They
don't understand why that's important and
what that means for finality.
Well, go ask, go ask your mother what,
settlement looks like when you're trading
a stock. I have no idea. Most of them,
right?
No, right. with stocks, with stocks, it
gets hairy, right? Because, they're
supposed to transfer ownership physically,
right, at some point, or electronically.
And then then you have people lending out
those shares that you're actually having
on their platform without your knowledge,
or you sign something, you clicked, okay,
on a box somewhere, and now they can lend
your shares out to other people. So you
get these divisions. So that's insane. So
No, but it's the same concept really. I
mean, most people that operate within
traditional finance have no idea what kind
of demon is behind that door, right? And
that's true with the banking system.
That's true with most traditional markets
and, more or less people don't care.
Right. They just have an assumption. Okay.
Well, it should work and, hopefully things
settle properly. Right. And if they don't,
that's always its own rabbit hole. But I
don't think that's going to change.
Like we can have a system with clear
assumptions of settlement and kind of
looking at finality of proof of work.
blah, blah, blah, most general end users
are not going to really dive into that
rabbit hole. And I think we can still
deliver optimal security assumptions
without them needing to know. Which, I
think that's like the best long-term
course to say, okay, well, if we're gonna
look at this as a global, open, neutral
network, how do we protect users? and try
to build, systems that we would want to
use understanding kind of the back into
the system itself.
Yeah. It still seems so far away. But but
it seems it seems doable. That's for sure.
Or else I wouldn't be doing this there.
I'm sure, I have no idea how complicated
legacy tech stacks are at this point. how
many people does it keep to keep it from
self-destructing. Cause a lot of them are
quite old, right? They've been built on
for years and years and years and years
and years. And that's hard to say you get
into, some complexity with legacy software
that, I wouldn't want to do that. I
wouldn't want to manage it or maintain it.
So let's see.
So speaking of circumventing banks and
central exchanges, how is how's Rosen
going, Joe?
Good. Listen, Rosen requires a lot of
testing, right? Like, like open source
software is not sexy business. I hate to I
hate to inform everybody out there. No,
it's not.
It is tough struggle. Yep.
It is the least sexy thing ever because
you need to back test it to where you
release your code to the public and you
don't have vulnerabilities, both kind of
in the system that can be exploited. And
it takes a lot of testing, right? Build,
test, fix, build, test, fix, build, test,
fix, build, test, fix. It is not exciting
work, but I do think that the capabilities
if we build a lot of these systems are
pretty awesome.
So we did have a bug show up in one of
the rounds of testing in Binance Smart
Chain. And so then it took a week to say,
hey, we need to first figure out why this
is happening and then patch it and then
run end-to-end tests. And I think we're
good on that. So I'm going to say Binance
soon, TM, right? But to me, it's just
funny because ever since I've kind of been
around publicly, that's probably one of
the most
I'm like, listen, this is not, this is
not Asian Jesus, right? He's not even
involved anymore. Anyway, but, so for me,
it's, it's like a spiritual victory to be
able to say, okay, everybody gets Binance
and BSC environment now.
I think, I think, I think at least the,
the core people in Ergo now, at least have
finally understood what a listing means,
right? Not that it's, that it's not a,
let's pump it a couple bucks because the
listing is coming and that's, sure.
They're going to profit off whatever
they're buying and selling low, buying
high, selling low. Or the reverse, but I
think I really think at least the
sentiment seems to be that people are now
understanding that listings are about
access, right? It's about access to with
cracking. It's about access to US
customers and just getting it so that
people have a way on to the Ergo
blockchain from there. So I'm really happy
at the sentiment there because you're
right.
And I think that even Rosen has had
pretty decent ERG depth on Cardano like
that becomes an easier on ramp.
And that's what we said to, that's what
we said to, oh gosh, what's his name? I've
lost track of all the Kraken people that
we've been talking to. Peter, that's his
name, Peter Dimitrakos. So that's exactly
what we said to Peter, right? We have as
much liquidity out there on the Cardano
chain that we do, and at least it was on
Gate, a couple other exchanges put
together. So Gate put in two applications
recently, and I pinged the guy and he
said, thanks. Hopefully we hear something
back soon from that to get better access.
I know I'd love to Yeah, I would
definitely say that like historically
that's that's been one that I tend to
favor. It's an interesting business.
They've been in I don't know, position of
pressure, at least for the last, like,
political environment. And it's
interesting to see how that's going to
change moving forward for them, to be
honest. I know that, like, they're
bringing back staking products, which may
or may not even be good for proof of stake
chains. But, it certainly gives them a
little bit more room to try to innovate
and compete and, kind of build their own
thing. Let's see.
Let's see. It'll be interesting. jury's
out for me about what they'll turn into or
what they'll be in the far future.
But I think that sometimes we forget how
small of a space we are.
That is true, too.
Like crypto is its own little niche
environment where it is true that, if we
do have, changes to where you can, open up
a bank rails from your financial
institution to the back end of chains,
even if it is, some centralized shit. that
certainly opens the competition, wide
beyond where it is now. And, considering,
the financial depth of the purse of some
of the institutions around, Coinbase is
small beans compared to some of the larger
competitors. So let's see. Let's see. it's
one of those things where yes, they have
an element of like,
I don't know. They have Head Start, but
in terms of raw consumer base.
They don't have that. That's for sure.
They don't have anything. They're a
middle man. And if things move to where,
the bank infrastructure has some access
into crypto land, Rosen will back end it.
Like that'll be a priority.
Yeah. Let's take Bank of America Chase,
right? Let's decided to do direct Vietnam
ramps to places from the bank, Kraken
would be shitting their pants.
They do not have the element of power
that they, appear to have. The only thing
they have right now is, is a head start
and like they've had a certain like
regulatory advantage that might disappear.
So it might be a double edged sword for
them actually improved, regulatory
environment. Let's see. Business can be
like that sometimes, right? Where, it's
like, wow, this is going to be great for
this market. And it's like, well, actually
it just opened the market. So now you
actually have to compete. Let's see.
Well, speaking of sub-blocks, it would
have been nice to have sub-blocks tonight
because we got a long block. So I'm
waiting to show you the other end of this
process, but we got quite a long one.
One of the assumptions everybody should
have in life. I always do. Whenever I'm
trying to do something and I have
something else to do, it's always like the
long block.
A watched block never prints, right?
Yeah, you just don't look. You have to
pretend.
I've been refreshing for 10 minutes now.
Yeah, don't look. You're making it longer
now.
Damn it.
Difficulty adjustments are going up every
time you hit refresh.
That is true. That is true. All right,
let's jump in to see what we've got here
in the dev update this week. And I'll keep
the other thing in the background and pop
over to it when it confirms.
All right, I'll start off.
Go for it.
We've got C8 with Dexy Gold integration,
ETA, a few weeks. How's that a Rosen a few
weeks or you think a legitimate few weeks,
Joe?
It's done when it's done.
It's like something like that. So
Donnie's got porting end user relevant
Scala tester JS mock chain done UI concept
for user swap liquidity interaction. Don't
want to five lib level actions LP swap ERG
Dexy Gold remaining. Bank freemint, bank
payment, LP mint liquidity tokens, LP
redeem liquidity tokens, other things
required for release, mempool server
integration, and UI integration
miscellaneous, looking into ErgyPay
integration.
That's always great. I always forget, at
least, how much of the world is on mobile
phones. So that kind of stuff is
necessary.
Actually, that's one thing that surprises
me always. I don't know. Maybe I'm old.
Maybe I just lose my phone too much. But
for me, it's like that is a terrible idea.
Like the last cell phone I had a rental
with my car. Why would I want to put my
money?
Oh, here we go, Joe. It worked. We got a
confirmed block. So as soon as the block
is confirmed, The plot then shows up here.
So I have a scanner scanning every like 10
seconds to make sure the payment was made
and it was confirmed. And then the
students, the student workers that we have
can then plot this. So I'm going to delete
this before my silly student waste paper
plot. Let's go back up to this.
All right. You've got the, you've got the
next one with kushti, the man himself.
All right, so we're talking about input
ordering blocks. He's got transactions
packed into the input blocks properly with
ordering full block structures making
progress. Linking also works now in local
miner-based DevNet. He's doing an API for
best input block field and added to the
info made. So yeah, with Sigma, it looks
like all issues found in Sigma 6.0 have
been fixed. So we're going to proceed with
the public test net activation.
Awesome. Yeah, he's going to send me that
file today or tomorrow, I think. And we're
down to one miner on test net, just to
make it easy. And I'm going to spin that
6.0 up and mine to it. And then he's going
to do some tests. So really excited about
that.
All right, we've got Anon BR from the
Nautilus team for Fleet SDK, version 0.8.2
release, fixed zigzag encoding for ascent
type, fixed signed spite encoding, added
fuzzing tests for all numeric types. I
like the way Anon talks. Improved
round-trip tests by adding sigma state JS
serializer comparison to ensure that
encoding decoding output is the same in
both libs.
For Nautilus, finished the rework of most
of the most complex and time-consuming
component in Nautilus, the transaction
sign component. Migrated from dialogue to
drawer component for improved mobile
experience. Added several minor UI fixes
and code quality improvements.
Awesome. Well, it looks like next we're
going to cover ChainCash.
Oh, yeah. Looks like kushti removed the
refund-related registers and actions. as
refund can be replaced with note
redemption, added note registration
contract. And as always, he's continuing
to think about different L2 options.
One of the big benefits of Ergo is that
we have a footprint in the Bitcoin design
space. And there's a huge mind share out
there in terms of potential ways to build
on top of Bitcoin or improve Bitcoin.
generally never go anywhere, but it
creates a huge research and mind share
space that we can potentially draw from.
And it's nice to see, Cardano is probably,
ahead of us as well, with Midgard and
Hydra and different layer two options. So
it does give us like a nice knowledge base
to build from, which, sometimes that's a
great resource in engineering.
All right, what else do we have here? Oh,
kushti's done SigmaUSD Oracle Pool and
SigmaUSD Bank Update and managed to update
Oracle Pool in the testnet to v1 with
update contract allowing for the update to
v2. Next is mainnet update. Let's do a
mainnet update to the same contract for
now and continue discussions about limits.
Yeah, that's going to be a nice
coordinated test. We have to drop down to,
I believe, four SigmaUSD Oracle members,
maybe even three, to test it out, update
the code all at once to make sure it
works. So it's going to be kind of like,
hey, let's be available this time. Let's
do it and get it done. So looking forward
to that.
Yeah. Oh, you got your buddy here.
Perfect.
All right, who's next? Aberg.
Oh, it's Beene, she's got Sigma Rust.
Revealed global deserialized and SS
strings PRS by two sec. But yeah, there
you go. Aberg all for you. Satergo.
All right. So with Satergo, the wallet
format update is done. What's left is
bring it all together. Releasing the
Android signer app APK native binaries for
Hetzner at API used for ledger. So hit the
cat button.
Oh yeah. Let's see what else we have.
Minotaur.
Oh, yeah. Minotaur 2.4.0 released. Minor
changes. Display token detail on
transaction signing page. Allow multiple
token burning on burn token page. Gosh,
Joe, it took me like, I'd say two years in
crypto before I trusted that burn button
in Minotaur. It does, right? I did it on a
wallet that just had like junk tokens that
I was trying to clean out. So I did it
there, got a little more comfortable,
reading the transactions, making sure,
yep, yep, here's the input, here's the
output, missing these, we're getting these
tokens back, don't worry, kind of thing,
and doing it, but that's funny. Sorry,
yeah, what's that?
I said I had a spam wallet for a little
bit where I would just send them and say,
okay, it's a miners problem now, right?
Yeah, yeah, it is. We'll pick it up in
the Sigmanauts pool, right?
I got a little overwhelmed. So I gave my
seed phrase to Rustin.
Every time people like to be nonsense, it
goes to Rustin.
So feel like that time you tipped out, I
don't know, $1,000 worth of GreasyCex to
somebody.
I see updated address asset details page
to display token icon and ID and name.
Display token detail and transaction
generate page. Updated transaction box
display page to display token ID and icon.
Display transaction details. Display all
values comma separated. Animated QR code
display and scanning. Ooh, fancy. Added
transaction display page.
I have, oh, this is my cold wallet right
here. It's one of these little tiny palms.
They were like, I bought it when it was
like 80 bucks. But then like six months
later, they are like 150. Maybe they're
back down now, but it's beautiful. It's
run on Android. But man, it chunks along
on Minotaur on this little tiny hardware.
So it'd be funny to see some sort of
animated animation. QR code scan.
Interesting.
All right. Patch changes. Do not display
token with amount equal to zero. Fixed bug
in the scanner. Fixed token select order.
Updated dependencies. Minotaur icons. And
that's the git, I believe. Right there.
I think that C8's message there is pretty
awesome. That I think is a long-term goal
for this year going for the layer 1 UX. C8
is championing that right with his Dexter
UI He's got a SigmaUSD bank UI that he's
doing. That's great, too where if we can
deliver people kind of this low layer one
user experience where things don't need to
be abstracted across
multiple environments and it is true that
mempool chaining and sub-blocks really
like take the idea of a stateless or ultra
light client that you can, get that type
of snappy UX is huge for the ecosystem.
I probably you read this. This year we go
for number one or shut your website down
and don't frustrate people. I think
there's
I think there's an element of truth to
that, right? Where, I don't know, that's
one of the messy things about crypto is
it's like you have to know all of these
websites and bounce all over the place,
versus having like these, the potential to
have micro clients that can just, interact
with contracts on chain. even the idea of
like a one click install node is huge.
versus, where we started, I was what, had
to make sure I had all the dependencies
and, run a jar.
Yep.
So, we've come a long way, but I think we
still have a huge green area in front of
us in terms of like the layer one UX. And
I do think that, C8 is right. That that's
like the optimal outcome.
Yeah. All right, we've got PGR four,
five, six from signature set. I'll kick
in. But with Keystone integration, looking
forward to get my hands on a Keystone
device. Former mostly done apart from some
bug fixing, testing, awaiting review by
Keystone team after holidays. Rust SDK
done and awaiting review. JavaScript-based
SDK done and awaiting review, remaining
WebUSB SDK, integration into wallet
software, Nautilus, Satergo, et cetera.
That's going to be fun. What's it called?
I prefer this over... My desk is messy. I
lost my ledger key. It's somewhere here,
Joe.
I prefer this to this, honestly, just UX
wise. You know what I mean?
I have big fingers. I don't like Ledger's
little. Oh, gosh. You're like, I've never
liked those little fiddly bugs.
Every time we do a, every time we do a. a
Rosen Bridge for GARD transaction man it's
like you're clicking like 30 times boom
boom except boom because you have to you
have to prove every single box that's
across so it's it's fiddly little fucking
things I don't like honestly.
You got Celaut right there with the
Celaut project. Writing ideas about the
service payment system, implementing a
service classification feature for a new
demo. Beene, which I'm going to assume is
going to be like Italian good. Finalizing
the UI fixes for the first version. From
there, we'll continue adding improvements
for the second version. Awesome.
Oh, and let's see. saying we should call
and talk about Ergo development and tools.
Awesome.
All right, we are Mark the Shark. Also,
he's been pumping away Mark's been pumping
crazy man. He's got his own like shark
theming. He's got like no shark eyes boxes
like bots going crazy in the channel. It's
it's amazing. I'm babysitting the he's on
break right now for the weekend. So he
asked me to babysit the mining server. So
I've been popping in and out of there
checking that out.
But yeah, so he's got miner rights
protocol, token flight, automated system
that emits a token to miners with a
corresponding rights token, integrated
pool and protocol feed to mimic an actual
proof of work emission. This could help
bring the concept of hard slash sound
money to native tokens. IgniFox tokens
were distributed to the miners of the pool
a month ago or so. But if miners want to
participate and don't have this token,
reach out and he'll send you one. Note,
this is only a prototype. No plans to do
anything with these tokens after testing
is done.
For further testing for the Hashmon
project, we will be creating another token
to test using NFTs as a rights token. Like
we'll be using the NFTs we have already
minted. They'll happy to mint another NFT
to distribute to current set of miners.
Containerizing code bases for automated
airdrops based on specific use cases, i.e.
bonus tokens and demurrage distribution
for Sigmanauts' mining pool. Note MRP is
already automated at the time of writing.
If you want to check out the code, feel
free to do so here. He's got his git
there. Note current MRP code is not in the
main branch yet.
Sigmanauts' mining pool deployed MRP
token flight as mentioned above. Miners
receiving the token Flame Shards if they
hold the IgniFox token and mine to the
pool when the pool finds a block. This is
fun stuff. The hope is to use this tool to
create more revenue for miners outside of
ERG itself. Mining pool received 2 million
RSV this from disco Solaris team and began
distributing these tokens as of this past
Monday. Again, mining is an amazing way to
token launch. Folks, even if you already
launched, it's an amazing way to
distribute these kinds of things.
Especially, especially looking at like, I
don't know, pump fun is a great example.
No, well, think about it. It's like the
largest incentive there is to have supply
dominance. You have supply dominance and
help something happens versus if you have
like proof of work, emission, you can
create a contract, admit it through time
to where its ability to come to market,
and be distributed is. Especially with
these these extra tokens, right? Because
miners are what miners are paying this
they have to pay their bills.
That's understood, right? There are
miners who speculate too, but if you give
a miner enough funds to pay their bill and
something extra, they have to pay their
bills. They're going to use it as a
speculative token to see if it's going to
rise in the future. And it's going to be
either a slower dump, but it's definitely
going to be a slower distribution. And
they're actually working for it, too.
They're actually converting electricity to
secure the chain. It's a great way to do
it.
Yeah, so the Marp software running on the
pool has been causing our disk space to
rise quickly and causes some down it
caused a few minutes of downtime to the
pool reached out to qx() about this and
working a fix. He works also mentioned
some other solutions which we're exploring
as well. I can't remember what I
mentioned. I forgot already.
Created the NurseShark monitoring bot for
pool-related TXs and notifications. I also
have integrated it with Anthropic's LLMs,
so as to query the LLM for wallet-related
activity. Not yet released on Git, looking
at integrating an open-source LLM so we
don't have to have users pay for their
queries. Amazing.
Hashmon not to be redundant, but
prototyping the MRP token flight with the
IgniFox and Flame Shards This tool will be
used to distribute our evolution shards
for this project, which will be used to
evolve monsters. I swear Mark the Shark
was like a world-class Dungeon Master in
his past right guy seems to have grown up
with these several facets and levels of
complexity to make these things fun
Protocol fields will be collected into
the wallet and initially thinking that the
first person who collects them all will
get the keys to this wallet. Oh, nice.
Need to finalize tokenomics with C8.
Looking to launch project end of February,
beginning of March. Example of using the
LLM for my grid trading bot. He's got,
what's he got there? Miner, it's protocol
token. He's got the shark bot right there.
And he continues thresher a reinforcement
learning agent project what aims is to
trade it to trade on DEXes created a
script to scrape the DEX wallet to use as
a training data for the RL training
environment. Agent environment works as
expected, but more work needs to be done
and have the agent learn effectively and
trade.
Some sort of interesting. Agents,
actions, buy, sell, hold, rebalance, agent
approvations, various buy and sells of ERG
and given native token, parallel
optimization runs on GPU, so to train
agents fast. Again, more works need to be
done on the reward environment, likely
another month or two work to be done so it
can effectively trade. Need to integrate
hyper parameter tuning so we can optimize
the various parameters We can change like
planning rate and real world structure if
you haven't noticed mark works with LLM's
for his fiat job So this guy's got the
chops to do this kind of stuff.
You could actually do some neat stuff I
know he's a he's a python guy and in terms
of work so I imagine if he can get some
LLM's and build some API's that are
getting fed information and build out some
more if statements, he could potentially
build something pretty cool with trading.
I think that's it for the update.
Yeah, I think that's all we got.
I'm going to end with something.
Wait, don't end yet. Don't end yet, Joe.
Don't end yet. We got, it's been a while
since we've done a DevOps, so I think it's
fair to remind people that I always try to
put Cyberverse into. They've been kicking
butt. They jump from average night of 40
users up to about 100. I think that a high
watermark in the high hundreds, and now
they're averaging 90, 100 users at any
given time. They just brought in a new
game that's archery. That's really cool.
You get one shot with an arrow. The
balloons go up. So you have to kind of
time it when you're shooting with other
people. Really cool mini game.
Just keep hitting a pixel and the team
here. They just keep kicking out of the
park. It's amazing. Another people that
keep kicking out of the part are Echo and
HQx with MewMart MewFinance the dudes are
like writing stuff like they post
something that they just wrote I go to bed
I come up in the morning and they've done
something else like Amazing like
fundraising LP buy-ins token launches
all that kind of stuff. He's looking into
getting Keystone wallets to sell on
MewMart as well so you can buy without KYC
or giving up your address to some
corporate overlords and get spammed for
the rest of time. So two projects that are
amazing. Hopefully they'll do an update
next week to catch us on the dev update.
But they are both fantastic. All right,
sorry, go for it. What's your ending, Joe?
My closing message is this. When I was in
the when I was in the Ergo Foundation, I
had to take like a position of neutrality
when it comes to mining pools. Right.
Because I had to I had to, ping them and
say, hey, we updated or no. Now I no
longer have to. So until until Mark's pool
is the leading pool in terms of hash rate,
if you're mining Ergo, what the fuck are
you doing pointing to any other pool?
I know it's crazy. You have a chance. You
have a chance to be part of a DAO, right?
You have a chance to run the damn pool
with everybody else. It's like.
No, I mean, there are people out there
that probably just set their rigs, but,
really stop this. I'm no longer neutral
because I no longer need to be until their
hash rate dominant mine to them. Because
the other pools are not contributing to
the ecosystem in any way. other than
they're making their rewards and earning
some money. And I guess periodically
they'll market something, this or that.
But until the active ecosystem is
dominant, don't waste your energy feeding
it into people that really don't care.
So miners out there, please consider
mining to community pools because they're
active and they bring value, they build
things for Ergo. They're not just a
service. And, the bottom line is we need
to put these services in a position where
they actually need to do something to
compete. So take that as you will.
I'm gonna leave it at that Joe. That's a
great place to leave it. Some good sound
bites for Mark to everybody. It's good to
be back with the dev updates, Joe. I
appreciate you hopping on the first time
back.
Have a good one.
Thanks everybody. Bye bye.