Good morning!
Good morning, everybody.
We've got a surprise guest today.
We need to thank Joe's dog for waking him
up early this morning and getting him onto
his couch.
Yeah.
That's a good boy right there.
Yeah, so it seems Joe's dog is truly a
good dog.
He works for the community, that's for
sure.
Joe, it's good to have you here.
What's new?
We haven't seen you in forever.
Oh, yeah, these are kind of early in my
time, so I've been a little lazy, focused
elsewhere.
Let's see where to start.
Well, let's start talking about the Ergo
event that we're putting together.
So qx() and I have been talking for like
a year.
Get the Ergo community together, have a
meetup.
And so slowly we've been lining up
speakers.
We've got event space right now in the
process of getting a liquor license, and
so I'm hoping that we can put together a
nice day where we kind of cover some of
the development that's going on in the
ecosystems, the security assumption, the
idea behind the project, why it matters,
etc.
You know, crypto conferences, they can be
pretty nice, right?
But they also can be kind of heavy on the
wallet.
That is true, especially if you're an
event host, right?
Especially if you're a booth holder.
Yeah, I get it.
I mean, for a lot of them, it's their
business.
And I think a lot of events, you know,
they do a good job putting together a good
show.
But barrier of entry is something where,
I don't know, sometimes you see the same
people, which, you know, I guess is nice
in terms of like networking, marketing,
etc.
But I don't know, I think opening it up,
making the barrier to entry lower, we'll
try to get broadcast online and it looks
like we're going to get a nice lineup of
people that we don't always hear from in
the Ergo community.
MiGoreng is going to make it, sounds like
qx() is going to try to make it, Allison
is going to try to make it and I'm hoping
that when the time rolls around, we can
highlight some MVPs that people are
working on in the ecosystem, cover some
projects, the what, the why, get into why
this matters for a peer-to-peer network.
It would also be great to get some
content from other applications of people
that are further away.
DuckPools is a good example.
Australia to Colorado is not exactly
quick, but it would be awesome to see more
content from at least that team.
I think others as well.
With Rosen, let's see, you know, right
now we're working on Runes and Doge.
Sadly, Doge has kind of been kicking our
ass because the nodes and, you know, the
explorers are pretty tight.
It's got some crappy infrastructure, but
nobody cares because it's a meme.
It doesn't matter.
Yeah.
How are discussions with new chains going
on?
Zano, Kaspa and so on.
Sure, there's been discussions between
our team.
We're trying to get them to understand
what Rosen is, why it matters.
I think one unique, let's say, feature
set that Rosen offers is this ability to
have unilateral access for both the
network coin and then tokens on top of the
network with relatively clear security
assumptions.
You know, I've always thought the
structure of like markets and let's say
the crypto space was a little bit weird.
You know, it's kind of a gatekept thing
where, you know, you have people that
will, I don't know.
It's like, let's delist Zcash, which has
really done some great work in terms of
research and cryptography and kind of like
the execution side.
And then it's like, hey, let's list fart
coin.
And that kind of tells you the incentives
and the alignment are screwy as hell.
But I do think that one thing that kind
of interests me with this idea of scaling
Rosen into new environments is you do kind
of get this situation where you have
non-linear maintenance.
So as a single team, as we add chains,
chains will update periodically the hard
fork infrastructure.
Every once in a while, we'll get
upgrades, etc.
And so the question has been, how do we
create the right incentives to where we
create external support for maintenance?
That's actually an interesting question
even with centralized exchanges a lot of
the times. Something we've ran into over
the years, I'm sure you know kushti has
some good stories about that where you
know suddenly something's in maintenance
mode and we're saying hey why is this in
maintenance mode and then we got to chase
down the engineers and you know what node
are you running and you know it's kind of
figure out what's going on.
So one thing I've been discussing with
MHS as well as MiGoreng and kind of our
own dev team is the idea of creating the
right incentive alignment, right, to where
it's like if, let's say, three, four years
ago, Ergo heard about this framework that
created cross-chain access.
What would it take for us to have the
right incentive to build it and maintain
it?
Personally, I'm a fan of this idea of
taking a percentage of outbound
transactions from new chains and having
them set up some sort of, you know let's
say a Paideia structure on Ergo something
like that where you know if things are
properly maintained and functioning they
can potentially earn a percentage right
you know and that kind of creates like
this, I don't know, let's call it like a
future dividend based on their work based
on you know keeping everything live versus
the traditional access is, you know, you
have a series of meetings with, you know,
marketing and, managers that probably
even, I don't know.
I'm going to say, don't know which end of
the hammer to use, but, how do you scale
that Joe without putting too much of
burden on the Rosen team or the guards,
you know, to keep it, are they keeping up
to date?
Are we managing individual people?
It's a, it's better to maybe create like
dead DAOs on each chain and then have the
DAOs themselves.
And then you withhold money if the DAOs
aren't doing a good job.
I think that, I think the simplest way to
streamline it would be to keep it on Ergo.
We have a lot of the tooling and also the
distribution cost is low, right?
So, you know, if you're talking about
paying people a regular transaction.
We have low transaction fees.
Paideia is a nice structure in terms of
having something that's transparent and
community oriented.
So I think that's a good structure for
that.
If you create proper open standards,
which I think started, I do think that we
could improve the Rosen contribution
document.
But having that public kind of allows
open specifications that if people can
meet, then it's just a matter of review
test, which is its own friction point,
right?
It certainly makes the barrier of entry a
lot lower than the standard listing, which
is you sign a contract that says we can
delist you at any time for any reason, and
you need to meet these market metrics.
Whether that's reality or not, you can
figure out how to plug that gap, which is
scammy as hell.
And then, you know, you also have this
idea that then you pass it to engineers
that you have no idea what you're actually
buying in terms of security, right?
The only time I've been able to
understand kind of the full exchange stack
and what's securing assets is after they
get hacked, right?
There's always a postmortem and say,
well, you know, our two or three multisig
failed and, you know, sorry, we've
suspended the thing and I don't know.
It's a weird thing.
You don't actually know what you're
getting into from a security perspective,
which is a terrible assumption, right?
You're signing a contract that says you
don't really get to see the security of
what you're buying, and we can delist you
at any time.
Yeah.
Also forget about privacy, about, yeah,
about everything basically.
Yeah, really anything, anything that's
like valuable or disruptive, you know,
we're going to delist you and you know,
here's a, you know, after fart coin comes
fuck coin, right?
Yeah, that's why I think fart coins are
very pleasant for them, right?
So they're not about any risks about
privacy.
So absolutely harmless farts basically.
Yeah.
So, so I've, I've always like wished
there was some mechanism to say, okay,
well, you know, there's, there's a lot of
like, if you're a fair launch project,
right, you automatically launch in a
market that has a ton of friction where
you're basically not going to get listing
until you, you know, can pay whatever you
need to pay, right?
And, you know, there are some exchanges
that I've talked to that are like, Hey,
are you post a token generation event?
And I said, well, you know, we're, we're
a coin, not really a token.
What's your contract address, Joe?
Yeah, and you know, well, we don't really
want to do that unless you're going to
give us like an internal allocation of,
you know, your supply.
It's like, oh, do you know how proof of
work works?
This idea of, you know, fair launched
cryptocurrencies.
We're in a weird space.
There's a lot of language, you know, I
don't know of any commodity in reality
where it's like, we had multiple seed
rounds, but we're, we're actually, you
know, the commodity, right?
It is what it is.
So how does that work with, I mean, let's
say, let's take Doge from that, right?
So let's say, you know, you're saying the
tooling isn't great, or the infrastructure
isn't great for Doge nodes and those kind
of things.
So that burden is going to go to the
guards, right?
Every guard is going to have to figure
out what node they want to run, how
they're going to set it up, if they're
going to use a public one, if there's a
public one, or run their private.
But the question is, so when chains like,
let's say Doge, oh, yeah, yeah.
So, so with Doge, Doge is just kicking
our ass, right?
There's no other way to say it.
Just cause you know, right?
Rate limits are super strict.
So we actually had to design a new module
for a multi-resource backend.
Right?
Like Doge became like an engineering
challenge to say, okay, well, if we want
this, you know, to, to meet like the
specifications and expectations of all of
our other implementations, we're actually
going to have to do some special
engineering.
So we're all Doge devs now at the end of
the day.
Is there a Doge DAO already, Joe?
No.
No, so my question, my question is, so,
you know, we're talking, you're talking
about exchanges delisting things and I can
understand.
You can see it both ways, right?
The cost effectiveness of keeping the
infrastructure and the security risks for
a chain that has very little movement
anymore is a risk for the exchange in
there.
But also you can see it as a money-making
endeavor, as the more the threat of
delisting is, the more the chain is going
to be used, the more money maybe the chain
will fork over to the CEX.
So I get both ways there.
I look at it a little bit differently, to
be honest.
I think that what's been happening in the
space is since the emergence of DeFi,
transaction volume has moved away from the
central exchanges and onto DEXes.
What happens is, if you look at the DEX
volume, five years ago versus today, the
growth curve on that is a magnitude higher
than the actual internal volume of
exchanges.
And so rather than saying, OK, well, we
can be entry points into these different
networks and they said, no, we're going to
try to directly compete.
And so then they start listing whatever
is popular for the day on DEXes.
And that's a losing proposition.
But the real interesting thing is going
to be just how rails change in the next
five years in our industry.
We're already starting to slowly see this
ability for people to move from their bank
to chains directly.
And at that point, I don't see much use
or utility for exchanges beyond
representing a mechanism to hold assets
for users.
They become a custodial venture rather
than more of an active trade engine
market, which even then, I don't know how
other than let's say liquidity that
they've already collected, I don't see why
they're any different than any other type
of OTC desk that people could potentially
go to.
I think it's an old idea that hopefully,
at some point, is just less popular, and
things are turning that way.
Well, yeah, I mean, you see these
exchanges going to more like their aim is
to keep the funds on the exchange.
So like making creating casino type of
things.
Creating their own kind of side chains
and sub-chains to keep people on their
system.
So, yeah.
But my question I was trying to get to is
I feel like with the guards, you know, if
we're going to take a different approach
than central exchanges where we're looking
at each project individually, we're not
looking at the interoperability, we're not
looking about connecting everybody like
Rosen Bridge.
So I feel the guards in order to not say,
okay, if we onboard a chain and in two
years that chain starts having very little
transaction going through Rosen Bridge or
the chain itself is lower, do we look at
it as, okay, as a guard, this node is
quite a burden to run now considering
there's no money coming in to support
running that node.
And we're going to prune it, or do we
look at it as, OK, the collective of the
interoperability and the network we're
creating with Rosen balances out?
Because we may have Ethereum, we may have
Cardano that's giving a lot of volume to
Rosen to fund Rosen, to fund the guards,
to fund the watchers.
And that would take care of smaller
chains perhaps at the cost of losing that
balance of money there between the two.
But the benefit is that we're keeping
this network alive between all chains and
giving a fair shot.
So I'm wondering how that discussion is
going to go or how that mindset is going
to go among the guards or the watchers for
that kind of thing.
Well, I think one thing that is a
constant disappointment in the crypto
space is that words don't really mean
anything, right?
I've even been in meetings where they're
like, oh, you know, coins and tokens,
they're basically the same thing.
And it's like, yeah, they're just letters
for people to speculate on, which is
terrible for a peer-to-peer network.
I do think that there's a lot of benefit
in trying to create an alignment for, I'm
not even going to say marketing, I'm just
going to say education, right?
Because marketing, I don't know, talk is
cheap and execution is priceless on chain,
right?
So I do think there's a lot of things out
there that oftentimes people don't really
explore beyond the five-minute chart.
There's a mentality in the space that you
just look at the letters and they're all
kind of the same thing.
There's a variety of different assets.
I would love to see more education, more
content, etc., long term, not just like
from within the Rosen team, but from kind
of the infrastructure around.
Like if you're going to be a watcher on a
network, it's kind of value alignment for
you to talk about the what, the why, etc.
Right?
And I do think that if you look at one of
the, I don't know, biggest failures of
education in the crypto industry, I would
say a lot of it is exchange, right?
They're the first point of like public
access.
And, you know, usually it's just garbage.
Yeah, it's very interesting and to the
best of my knowledge quite unique thing,
right, to have those kind of deep in
products like Oracle pools, like Gold
Oracle and Rosen Bridge network, right,
where people can, like everyone, right,
can earn some tokens just by letting some
software run on a computer.
And that's, I think, still super
undervalued.
Yeah, you know, kushti and Joe, we have a
ton of watchers, right?
We have hundreds of watchers out there
between the two chains or something like
that.
You'd think with that kind of amount of
people actively running machinery to
benefit a network, these people would be
the loudest mouthpieces out there, you
know, promoting cross-chain
interoperability, you know, preaching Ergo
to everybody, preaching Rosen Bridge.
But it's interesting, at what point can
we convince these people that the more
that they, you know, it's not just set and
forget with these kind of things.
You're running a tool that is directly
dependent on your participation and your
promotion of it.
So I hope to see that.
I feel like it's somebody like baking
bread and selling it and never putting a
sign out of their shop that they're
selling bread kind of thing.
A lot of bridges in the crypto space are
designed to be optimistic to basically
offset computational cost.
And the idea with Rosen is let's move
computational costs to another layer,
spread it out across a set of actors, and
then create an incentive for them to run
that part of our system.
So yeah, I kind of look at it in my own
weird way as like your verification
mining, right?
And I would hope that as things take off,
that kind of grows in popularity because
it is something that as Rosen sees more
activity, hopefully those verification
miners earn more.
I do know that one thing that we've done
that is not popular so far is we have
avoided stable coins.
And the reasoning behind that is if you
have a foundation that can be frozen,
seized, etc., you cannot really honestly
claim that it's backed one to one, right?
Because that's subject to change at any
time based on, you know, the whims of a
central actor that you don't control.
That's something that, you know, people
do get pretty excited about this idea of
freeze and seize stables.
But I see that as one of the most like
underappreciated risks that's not really
priced in.
And I don't know.
Let's see how that evolves as regulations
evolve.
But that's certainly a weird stack.
But then you can bring something like
USDM, right?
Well, Zano has freedom USD, but yeah,
it's quite new.
It's a little weird.
So it could be risky, per se, because
most of such private stable coins failed.
There's a few problems on, yeah, just
because you have some boxes and so on.
Yeah.
And you know, I would love to see Dexy
USD at some point.
You mean private version of it?
No, I mean, we're, we're going to launch
Dexy Gold, right?
And I think at some point we could update
the Oracle and.
Let's see.
So tomorrow we'll have a call with Dan.
So yeah, let's see.
So what's our plans there in regards with
Dexy lithium and so on.
Then, yeah, Dexy silver, need to get some
clarity here.
And then, yeah, Dexy USD, we can launch.
We need a little bit of inputs here.
It'd be good to see Dexy Gold in the wild
anyway, to be honest.
Some managing efforts for the updated
Oracle pool and then launching Dexy USD.
It's quite straightforward, I believe.
Just a different oracle and, yeah well
the contracts are the same basically. What
are the what are the chances of running
multiple data points on oracle 2.0 so that
the Dexy Gold people could also report USD
or no it's, it literally it has to be or
more security wise should be separate
oracle?
I don't know, it's actually hard to say
about security, but also if it will be a
gold pool also delivering USD, then yes,
USD bank to be updated.
But yeah, if we are going to update the
current USD pool to version two, then
yeah, well, that the bank can continue to
work with this.
So, yeah, it's probably better to update
the pool, right, to version two.
Just that.
We'll update in the first place.
So yeah, please reach me if interested.
Yeah, there is a telegram group on that
where we can now revive efforts to get
Dexy USD and some.
All right.
So Joe, back to the meetup real quick.
We're almost we ran over everything again
in the Sigmanauts group, Joe kushti and
We've got mostly a finalized schedule, but
not quite to release it.
We might take one more stab at it on
Sunday And then put it out into the wild
along with the booth signups again as a
reminder But I'm excited.
It's gonna be fun.
I will try to, we're going to try to
stream as much as we can enjoy like what
you said about getting people like
DuckPools involved even though they're not
coming.
I think we create create a hybrid event
to where in between so for online people
there will be you know 12 hours of pure
conversation and pure presentations to the
people in person it'll be just the four or
five presentations that we do and in
between the spaces like when we do the
hike do the dinner do the lunch we can
have people like Kras come in and jump in
and do the online part presentation about
So I think that brings a good point that
we can probably try to do that.
So to the outside, if you are not at the
event, they'll have a good five, six,
seven hours of straight talking from Ergo
from those kinds of people.
So yeah, great point, Joe.
We'll try to get that to happen.
I would love to give open source
developers a platform to speak and address
the problem.
You know, it's, it's honest when you go
to a crypto event and it's like, okay,
well, what do you do?
I've, you know, basically build open code
and then it's like, okay, well, you can
pay, you know, 10, 20, sometimes 30,000
for a booth.
That's not like the most exchange, but it
is what it is.
Any luck you're still thinking about
coming?
We'll check in July.
July.
Okay.
All right.
That'd be, that'd be amazing.
That'd be really cool.
Yeah.
So, can not, check your, what's, what's
possible.
Let's see.
Then, yeah.
What's happened in the dev down, what's
happened in the Ergo development
ecosystem?
A lot of things.
So, there is a need to, release 6.0
finally.
So, yeah, there is a new code for 5.0.27
and so 5.1 somewhat new release also,
right?
So hopefully it can be done around
Monday, right?
So it's finalized and yeah, please help
with testing.
So yeah, I will test on 102 nodes.
And then, yeah, well, 6.0 hopefully will
be released next week, maybe closer to the
end of the week if no more issues will be
found.
So, last week Dusick found some
consensus, possibly critical vector to
split the 5.0 and 6.0 nodes, but yeah,
it's hardly exploitable probably.
You need to do proof of work on two
different blocks basically.
But yeah well anyway better to fix all
those vectors so oh yeah it's done now so
hopefully it's the last issue and yeah so
we are good to go and then yeah well
We need still to set activation dates.
Currently I'm thinking about something
like June 25th to July 1st.
And then in July we can start to deploy
sub-blocks supporting nodes into the
public testnet as well.
So yeah, it would be good to mix nodes,
not updated like yours, maybe mining nodes
and also new nodes with sub-blocks
support.
To see how it would take place in the
mainnet as well.
All right, so yeah, well, I'm currently
doing some fixes and optimizations with
sub-blocks.
And well, hopefully in the next few days,
there will be another DevNet update.
And then, yeah, well, we can start
releasing maybe versions since the public
testnet, right?
Like 6.5 maybe.
Let's see.
Still I'm not sure about versioning here.
And then, yeah, there will be a need to
formalize security, right?
And so we'll discuss designs with people
around.
And yeah, then let's see what could be a
mainnet activation date about.
Then also published sigma chains
refactoring plan.
So it seems it's actually not so much
work to do to start at least some merge
mined sidechains, right?
The simplest option, actually.
And then, yeah, well, think about support
for dedicated sigma chains.
So, yeah, it seems there is some interest
here, right?
And then, yeah, it's also worth to think
how to scale it and how to organize
development.
So we'll publish some thoughts on that.
Hopefully in coming days, but let's see.
So also thinking which videos to do for
the anniversary.
So probably there will be two videos, one
about sub-blocks and so on.
And another one is about the end game,
the end game for crypto and crypto.
And yeah, I think that the progress is
good in regards with development.
Probably the bigger issue now is to find
something for this, right?
Tech for real, like, I don't know, like
BRICK.
Hell yeah, BRICK.
I tell you, we had to cut those kids off.
We had to stop it because kids were we
had to just freeze BRICK collection or
distribution because kids were going out
during cleanup on the on the milestone
plate behind me and just taking
everybody's scrap papers and trying to
turn them in for more BRICK even though
they weren't their plots so we had to be
like yeah it's done for the it's done for
the semester guys oh that was funny
Let's see, we got, oh yeah, let me
mention too, guys.
I put it in chat.
15,000 ERGs have been collected so far
for the raffle for the Fiat Unwrap, the US
Fiat Unwrap.
67.99 ERG to go.
Now, I'm not calling out all you people
that keep asking when US access, when US
access, but it has to be, I'm looking at
the numbers here, there are, 1400 tickets,
94 backers in my whole lifetime here at
Ergo.
I think there are way more than 94 people
that have bitched about not having us
access.
So what are you guys doing?
Put your money where your mouth is.
Donate to this damn raffle and let's get
it taken care of.
All right.
Get it done.
I'm sure you've heard thousands of users
bitch about us access guys, right?
You've been here longer.
Yeah.
You got to use HQx's new chat.
That way there's a cost of whining.
Yeah, that's good idea.
He should, HQx should run it through AI
before it pops up the wallet.
And if he notices it's a whining post,
then he should charge triple for the
transaction.
That'd be ideal.
Marketing, but that's us.
I just talked about watchers and how they
should be promoting the chain and how they
should be engaging more.
Great.
All right.
We got some questions, guys.
You want to see if we got some questions?
Yeah, let's go through.
That's why we're here.
Let's see some chats not really Paul
starts asking for time frame for Banxa,
Banxa I guess on ramp integrations, I do
not know that'd be a question for Glasgow
pop it in the chat. Joe's no longer paying
attention to EOP's shenanigans yeah
Ask anybody on the EF that MiGoreng or
Glasgow.
They'd be able to get back on that kind
of thing.
Let's see.
Mark's asking more about Doge.
He's saying, since Doge is a fork of BTC,
why was development different?
Or has Doge implemented different tooling
that Rosen has to interact with that's
different from BTC?
No, it has to do with data collection,
scraping the chain.
So you have the blockchain, then you have
infrastructure that's wrapped around the
chain that's constantly calling it and
reading the chain, putting it in a better
format.
So a lot of that infrastructure around
Doge itself It's pretty strict, right?
They have pretty tight rate limits.
And so then it becomes hard to extract a
lot of data from Doge because the
infrastructure doesn't really support
that.
All right.
Zurich says that sometimes they
hallucinate that Doge becomes an Ergo
sidechain.
Let's see.
You got anybody else?
They're asking about Keystone
implementation.
That would be through...
I haven't heard anything.
You hear anything through that, Joe, for
the finals of that?
kushti, anything from the DevDAO?
Yeah, let me check the chats.
Some fresh messages there.
One second.
Keystone.
Joe Byron says you've abandoned us.
I don't think Joe's abandoned us, guys.
Joe's one of those that are still in
chat, still hanging around, still
answering questions.
It's just a time thing.
He likes to sleep in past 6 a.m. Colorado
time.
Yeah, when the AMAs are at 6 a.m.,
there's a certain incentive where I just
kind of don't want to look at the screen
like an idiot, you know?
I need some time to warm up.
Here we go, Joe.
This is for you from Ursa Minor.
Can a token like Rosen have a... Oh,
sorry.
Go for it.
Go for it, kushti.
You got it up there.
So, yeah, for Keystone, yeah, seems there
is some chats.
Yeah, something about USB feature, key
stock connection entry.
So yeah, it seems, yeah, well, some parts
still under implementation.
But yeah, most of it done, I believe.
Nice.
All right, let's see.
Ursa Minor is saying, can a token like
Rosen have a bigger market cap than ERG?
It's a good question for both of you.
I don't know.
I think that relative to what it offers,
ERG is very mismatched based on the rest
of the crypto market.
That's my opinion, especially someone
who's dug through different stacks and
kind of working with interoperability
between chains.
I think a lot of it is more, maybe as an
open community, we're not as good at talk
and hype and marketing, but I don't know,
like off-chain, like promises and talk is
cheap and honor is priceless, right?
And I would say on-chain, you know,
marketing is cheap as hell, but execution
is priceless.
And I think we do a pretty damn good job
in terms of execution.
Execution research implementation.
I think we punch way above our weight.
So I would say that the mismatch there is
probably Ergo itself.
And that is what it is.
Maybe it's a function of awareness.
I think that's probably the largest.
Access is definitely something as well.
That's a struggle.
But, when you have something that's some,
you know, vibe coded white paper with some
vibe coded shit, that's for a billion
dollars, that's not even real.
You know, the markets, you know, there,
there, there's a certain, I don't know,
belief that, you know, the market is
always, you know, right.
But then it's also always changing.
So I don't know.
To be honest, I, for most of the time so
far with Rosen, I haven't really been
tracking the token too much.
I've been focusing on execution, right?
Just because I would rather there be like
software.
I don't know, when I joined the crypto
space, it was about like, okay, we're
going to have this distributed network and
then we're going to have distributed
software on top of a distributed network.
And so that's really been more my focus
than, I don't know.
Number go up.
Yeah, like I feel like an idiot if I talk
too much about something that doesn't
exist, right?
Maybe that's me, but you know.
I think that the execution side is the
most important thing I can contribute.
We do have some open discussions and
proposals in the Paideia DAO, and I'm
hoping that the community is paying
attention and is going to give feedback.
I sometimes I drop ideas and it's like
the best thing I hope for is just
feedback.
Like I'd love to hear like, Hey,
Armeanio, this is a very stupid idea.
Oh, you know, and this is how to make it
better.
I'd love that.
So feel free to like, no, refine it.
And the first part of that question, Joe,
he was targeting essentially if Rosen gets
bigger than ERG what's that say for the
security of ERG like Ergo will that in my
personal opinion i think those things go
hand in hand i don't really see rosen
getting out of hand compared to ergo where
the where what's it called where the hash
of ergo is so far down yeah i don't i
personally think they go hand in hand
I don't think long term that makes too
much practical sense, but maybe in crypto
sense, I mean, weird shit happens every
day.
But I do think that one thing that we
haven't really discussed long term with
Rosen is this potential to take a lot of
the stable coins that we've been playing
with for years on Ergo and putting them
into new environments.
Right.
And I think that once you know, as we
continue to iterate, you know, perhaps
Gluon scales well, perhaps Dexy scales
well, etc., that we have the ability to,
you know, offer some unique value
propositions into other ecosystems,
especially as kind of the centralized
stables become more regulated, more
monitored, more AML KYC, more, you know,
of the kind of old banking system coming
into play, which I think is probably
inevitable looking at how bills or
legislation is advancing.
So I think one unique thing about Ergo is
we are kind of gray.
Nobody's heard of us, which is a certain
advantage, right?
We have a lot of things that just people
aren't tracking.
And I think that kind of gives us some
room to play around.
Yeah, and that's how you can actually
play and try what can scale.
Like Bitcoin was in shadows also before
the Wikileaks blockade moment, right?
So when Wikileaks got cut from Visa,
MasterCard and so on.
And then, yeah, it was the first probably
big marketing campaign for Bitcoin,
actually.
So, yeah, well, with tech stack, maybe
it's about time, right, to get also some
big marketing campaign of that kind.
All right, let's see what else we have.
CannonQ posts, for people, there's a free
play sponsored by the Sigmanauts today at
5 p.m. UTC in Cyberverse.
If you guys haven't played Cyberverse for
a while, hop back in.
I mean, they're still doing update after
update after update.
Very, very cool game.
Multi-Chain, Cardano, Ronin, Ergo.
But you don't really notice when you go
in the game.
That's the cool thing about it.
So hop on their free play sponsor for the
Sigmanauts.
What else?
JayL says, I hope Joe still loves us.
Zo says, Joe, can you guys speak about
liquidity and a hole on Rosen Bridge?
Before you do, let me just remind people
that the idea discussions are up.
I'm going to post it in chat right now.
Please, please go, please chat and look
at the discussions.
Engage the people.
I see, oh, there's two comments on
Treasury proposal number one.
So that's good.
At least somebody's kind of chatting it.
I just put it in chat.
Please go there, talk about it.
But yeah, sorry, go for it, Joe.
Can you speak about liquidity and a hole
on Rosen Bridge?
Sure.
You know, a large part of our focus thus
far has just been base scaling across
chains, right?
And one thing that we definitely need to
play catch up on in terms of like access,
which Rosen at the end of the day is
infrastructure, right?
I think it would be great to see Rosen
integrated into more wallets in different
ecosystems.
That way, you know, the like user barrier
to use it is lower.
I do think that continued dApp
partnerships is really important, but one
thing that I think sometimes is overlooked
is Capital flows to where it's respected.
I think that's a good starting point.
And let's say we have access to Bitcoin.
That is a great starting point.
And it's a question of saying, OK, it's
ease of access plus incentive.
And I do think that having more
incentives across applications for
liquidity is going to be quite an
important part of how Rosen scales now as
like the team. One thing that we see in a
lot of infrastructure is you know you say
okay well we built this and then we go
find you know one or two entities that
basically hold ninety five percent of the
value of the bridge. You know there's a
lot of bridges around that like like more
or less it's couple large funds I'm gonna
say kind of farming everybody right and
you know that is
I guess good for really rapid growth and
TVL and bridges, but it also is something
where it's dependent on select few.
I've always hoped that with Rosen, we
create something unique in terms of open
specs and we scale first more laterally
into different ecosystems, different
chains.
And as we do that, gains in a certain
popularity and marketing, etc., comes once
there's something to execute on.
And sometimes crypto is very backwards,
where you have massive liquidity for a
promise.
They have massive liquidity in a project
that's like, hey, we might build
something.
It's closed source and hopefully we
deliver it to main net.
And there have been times where it's like
they quote unquote run out of money or
quit and they don't even open source what
they did do.
So how do you know there's even work
there?
I don't know.
Again, I've always thought that if you
want to look at organic growth, execution
has to come first for long-term
sustainability.
That's not popular in the crypto space,
but I do think that it opens us up to this
potential where, you know, at any moment,
you know, Rosen could get marketing and
then we have like the foundation, to
actually make that scale.
And I do want to play around with things,
right?
It's like, okay, well, if we, support
Monero, I think that would be pretty cool.
If we, you know, back into a lot of the
exchange layer twos, it'd be a little
funny to relist Monero.
But from a marketing perspective, that's,
It's not my strong suit.
I think that the most important thing is
just to have solid execution and then you
have something to market.
Because how many crypto narratives have
people heard where it's just like drum
beats, oh, this is so sexy, this is
amazing, da da da.
And then at the end of the day, the
narrative changes, right?
It's like, well, what actually got
delivered?
What can we execute here?
And I get tired of that.
I've been, I don't know, maybe I've been
in crypto too long where it's like your
white paper and your marketing is cheap,
execute.
You know, and then you have something
that, you know, if it's done well, you
know, it'll last.
And if it's open source, people can make
it better.
Yeah.
Grayman wants some clarity.
Some more clarity.
He wants to hear from kushti real quick.
Maybe that's the last one about the
security hash.
If Rosen gets above Ergo, essentially
he's saying, can the market cap of all
tokens in Ergo exceed the market cap of
ERG?
And if so, does that compromise security?
Is he answered different in proof of
stake networks?
kushti?
No.
But how?
I don't think so.
So even more in the long term, a big
market cap of tokens also does mean a big
amount of storage rent, which is
increasing security actually.
So here is dynamics may be different from
other blockchains because of storage rent.
But here, so well, tokens do contribute
in the long term.
Well, actually already contributing to
the security budget, right, of mining.
So just in recent weeks, so there were
like meets of SigmaUSD and meets of
SigmaRSV collected and so on, like all the
NFTs, right, which can be sold on auctions
and so on.
So, yeah, well, with time, well, a big
total market cap of tokens is actually
good and adding to the security, I think.
So yeah, well, here Ergo is quite unique,
right?
So it's, it's different from, I don't
know, from like every other blockchain,
because of demurrage components, which is
adding a new variable in the mining
security budget equation.
And I, you know, it's weird.
I was reading through the, I think they
call it the clarity bill, which is some
legislative bullshit in the United States
that they're talking about.
But it seemed as though it shifted the
incentives, you know, It's basically how
are we going to distribute regulatory
oversight of these new digital assets.
And it did seem to create an incentive
for app chains, which maybe people are
around in 2017 when there was Like, I
don't know, let's just say a lot of great
looking white papers and a lot of promises
sold and then shit execution.
And then it kind of created this fear of
like, oh, well, you know, maybe everything
needs to be in L1.
And so, you know, You know, this idea of
like application specific chains kind of
popped up.
And I do think that, you know, having
proof of work is like a base is a great
thing to point to in terms of like, you
know, it's an actual like fair launch
commodity versus, you know, in the crypto
space.
I don't really know how you spend the
narrative that it's like, oh yeah, we see
around 80% of supply, but it's a
commodity, right?
Some mental gymnastics, but it is what it
is.
I do think that there's probably going to
be a growing use case for
application-specific merge mined chains,
and if we can create a package to where
that's easily deployable, we just add to
the security budget of Ergo and we create
some cover for people in certain
jurisdictions that want to play around
with Ergo itself.
Yeah, not that hard to do that even.
I mean, from what we do have at the
moment, it's not a long path even.
So, well, it's possible to run some merge
mined sidechains somewhat like weeks.
Yeah, I would say, you know, as the mice,
we need to be aware of the cat, have new
tactics to deploy, right?
And I think that increasingly that'll be
a powerful tactic.
If there are a couple of developers and
so on.
So, yeah, well, even one maybe in a few
weeks.
Yeah, but well, with knowledge, right, of
Sigma Rust and so on.
Sigma and then yeah Sigma Rust baby. So
yeah yeah quite quite doable i think and
yeah it's it's like a good direction right
to to explore well guys it's 10 o'clock my
time
Two o'clock UTC.
It's quitting time.
Do you need to go to some meeting?
Every time, kushti.
I don't know how it works out.
Every freaking time.
All right.
Okay.
We'll have more reports next week on a
finalized schedule for the event meetup.
And guys, again, fill these in the damn
raffle.
Yeah, and also we will have our
anniversary on July 1st, it seems, so
yeah.
Yes, yes.
We got that coming up.
Andy just shared a big list of videos
that we went through to try to figure out
what videos can be put out there.
So that's going to be exciting.
I'm going to meet up with Dan and try to
meet up with Allison as well and get some
Machina Finance and as well as some Winter
Protocol and why Ergo was amazing and make
something like Palmer possible.
So those are just two of the many videos
that we'll see on Ergoversary that are
new.
Awesome.
Including yours, kushti.
All right.
Nice.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, yeah, stay tuned.
Have a good one.
Ciao.